<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Culture War - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-30T02:47:08Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii7nojw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Have you stocked up on microchips yet? 

Many believe now that the war over Taiw</title><updated>2022-07-30T02:47:08Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><content type="text">Have you stocked up on microchips yet? 

Many believe now that the war over Taiwan will start in 2022 and the casus belli will be Nancy Pelosi.  

- “Chinese state media just suggested the PLA should shoot down Pelosi’s plane if she travels to Taiwan. This would be a direct act of war. The U.S. does not take foreign policy demands from Communist China or any other belligerent bully”,  says [U.S. Senator Marsha Blackburn](https://twitter.com/MarshaBlackburn/status/1553077081633873920).   

- A post appeared on Jul 29 on the official account of China&#39;s 80th group of People&#39;s Liberation Army, saying [«Get ready for war!»](https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202207/1271742.shtml). 

- During Nancy Pelosi&#39;s supposed visit to Taiwan, a U.S. Navy strike group led by the aircraft carrier Ronald Reagan [will move into the South China Sea](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-07-28/us-aircraft-carrier-enters-south-china-sea-amid-taiwan-tensions).

- The Chinese army, on the other hand, is actively [relocating armored vehicles to Fujian](https://twitter.com/gusten777/status/1553107420054016003), the nearest province to Taiwan from mainland China. Unscheduled exercises will start tomorrow.

- [Another word to the staff of Global Times](https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202207/1271745.shtml): 

&amp;gt; &#34;Don&#39;t say we didn&#39;t warn you!&#34; - a phrase that was used by the People&#39;s Daily in 1962 before China was forced to fight the border war with India and ahead of the 1979 China-Vietnam War, was frequently mentioned during a forum held Friday by a high-level Chinese think tank, as analysts warned that open military options and comprehensive countermeasures ranging from the economy to diplomacy from China await if US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi gambles with a visit to the Taiwan island during her Asia tour.
&amp;gt; Sending fighter jets to intercept Pelosi&#39;s plane, declaring air and maritime zones around the island of Taiwan as restriction zones for military exercises … China&#39;s responses will be systematical and not limited to small scale given the severity of Pelosi&#39;s move and the damage to the political trust of China-US relations, Yang Mingjie, head of the Institute of Taiwan Studies in Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, told the Global Times.  
&amp;gt; [...]  
&amp;gt; The 80th Group Army posted a comment saying, &#34;we must bear in mind the fundamental responsibility of preparing for war and charge on the journey of a strong army.&#34; The comment has received 8,000 thumbs-up.

Well if Marsha Blackburn on Twitter and 300000 Chinese people on Sina Weibo agree, I guess this is it. Should I buy USD, gold, Bitcoin, RTX 3090, or buckwheat? This is the question...

----

It&#39;s possible to frame this in a number of ways. Old clueless women and frenzied nationalists stumbling into abyss, pulling their country along; something something our rights, freedom, liberty, Communism vs. Capitalism, Tyranny vs. Democracy; Thucydides Trap... You all follow big brain bloggers who can pontificate on that (or *are* such bloggers) and I don&#39;t have the energy to go though it all. (Frankly I&#39;m sick and someone else should write a proper post). 

My hypothesis, of course, is that the US is actually ran by hypercompetent people, and they will crush China without breaking a sweat – or, more likely, force it to back down in humiliation, although they would accept sacrificing not just Pelosi but the majority of the world&#39;s population including most Americans to achieve their goal of total hegemony if that were the cost. How those competent people have paved the road to the provocation with Pelosi is the content of a bona fide **conspiracy**, and we&#39;ll never learn of it. 

The war was generally pegged to happen in 2025-2026 or later, as implied by Chinese-American power differential and rates of military buildup – at the schedule most convenient to PLA. (Alternatively, the «declining power» model [is purported to yield much the same result](https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/09/24/china-great-power-united-states/)). Just like with AI forecasts, it was naive and didn&#39;t account for the trivial notion that interested parties are aware of this basic scenario and thus anticipate its turns. Google *can* in fact keep scaling transformers; USA can in fact accelerate the schedule of the conflict to settle it on preferred terms. 

And right now the terms are excellent. 

Taiwan is very defensible. According to (picked at random) the *Naval War College Review* issue from 2001, titled [«How China Might Invade Taiwan»](https://digital-commons.usnwc.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2535&amp;amp;context=nwc-review), “Just to get ashore, the landing force commanders would have to improvise extensively to deal with the inhospitable Taiwanese west coast, which is mostly mud flats, with significant tidal ranges. **The Chinese would also have to contend with two monsoon seasons, from August to September and from November to April**; it would be restricted to two “windows” of attack, from May to July and the month of October.” 

Moreover, they&#39;re just strait up not ready. For example, according to the *Southern China Morning Post*, [China’s Fujian aircraft carrier doesn’t have radar and weapon systems yet, photos show](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3185845/chinas-fujian-aircraft-carrier-doesnt-have-radar-and-weapon). «The Fujian was [launched a month ago](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3182032/china-launches-fujian-pla-navys-3rd-aircraft-carrier?module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=article), and military analysts say the process to get the warship ready for active service could take several years – from the fit-out to testing and sea trials». They didn&#39;t rush it enough. What does this say for their chances to attain air superiority?

Can they fight the US in their present state? Their main ally is in no shape to help or even lend them arms, battered and discredited in Ukraine. Their economy is buckling under the strain of Zero-Covidiocy and bursting housing bubble. Their military still is half-baked, their industrial capacity – wasted on high-speed rail, other infrastructural grift and gimmicks for Westerners instead of leapfrogging the US by mass-producing autonomous weapons which are [only now reaching proof-of-concept stage](https://interestingengineering.com/china-drone-swarm-forest). It doesn&#39;t look good.  

On this note, back in the December of 2021 Telegram military analyst Atomic Cherry (known here through his coverage of Ukrainian conflict) has said: 

&amp;gt; In 2018, China was not just deprived of access to advanced chip production technology - Beijing was literally kicked to the curb on the eve of a new round of microelectronic evolution. The mainstay of this trend in recent years has been the 7nm chip process (China still has not received the technology to manufacture such chips). A few days ago, however, TSMC began test production of 3nm chips. IBM unveiled a prototype 2nm chip back in May, and is now working with Samsung on a unique VTFET (vertical transistor arrangement) technology which will eventually break the 1nm (!) barrier.   
A special zest to the appearance of these technologies is that they will be launched into mass production at about the same time as the U.S. will finish and start up new plants in the microelectronics industry - that is roughly 2024-2025.  
Probably not all readers understand what the evolution of chips is all about. So as not to bore you with nerdy theory, I will explain the difference in simple and understandable categories.   
▪️ 100-nm technology makes it possible to produce, for example, cruise missiles similar to the American Tomahawk of old modifications;   
▪️ 40-nm technology makes it possible to make missile launchers similar to the older versions of the Javelin or, for example, the Predator UAV;  
▪️ 7-nm technology is your ticket into the world of multi-platform kamikaze drones and compact reconnaissance drones.   
Not to say that the PRC had any chance at all of changing the current strategic environment - but now there is none at all. 

And a few days ago we&#39;ve learned that they are in fact producing 7nm class chips... for Bitcoin mining ASICs. In a year or two, perhaps...

It&#39;s like watching [AlphaZero clobber Stockfish](https://youtu.be/lFXJWPhDsSY). 

I am not sure how it&#39;ll go, but I think they&#39;ll blink, like they always do when this issue is raised and the US clears its metaphorical throat. If they don&#39;t... it&#39;ll be even worse for them.

Xi is – or [was](https://www.cnbc.com/2022/07/29/chinas-xi-faces-major-economic-challenges-says-investor-david-roche.html) – expected to secure his third term [this November](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/20th_National_Congress_of_the_Chinese_Communist_Party) on the 20th National Congress of the CCP. His entire schtick by this points amounts to pandering to nationalists, «little pinks». Can he survive disappointing them – by giving Taiwan up symbolically or losing it in an open conflict? *Probably.* If his grasp on power is comparable to Putin&#39;s, he can. It will necessitate turning the country into a comparable one-man show, with crippling brain drain from leading corporations  (sanctions will follow, of course), economic collapse and irrelevance.  
It won&#39;t be *that* bad. USA-developed AGI will take care of manufacturing – the fraction we&#39;ll still need after degrowth explained away by Putin&#39;s aggression and COVID-caused (actually it was lockdowns) recession. 

Meanwhile, if he can&#39;t stat on top, his faction gets replaced by a more pro-Western one, and the next GenSec is probably [someone like this guy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wang_Yang_(politician)#Political_positions_and_public_image). 

I&#39;m not AlphaZero of politics nor Von Neumann of Machiavellism and I can&#39;t tell how it&#39;ll play out. But they, too, have deal with uncertainty. What matters is that I don&#39;t see any winning moves for China. 

Do you?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii7nojw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii78aft/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">In another &#39;what the fuck is even going on&#34; news from Ukraine, [someone killed \</title><updated>2022-07-30T00:42:46Z</updated><author><name>_Cullis</name></author><content type="text">In another &#39;what the fuck is even going on&#34; news from Ukraine, [someone killed \~53 Azov POWs in a makeshift detention camp in an industrial building 15 km from the frontline.](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/07/29/europe/donetsk-prison-strike-ukraine-russia-intl/index.html)

Ukraine says Russians did it themselves with IEDs,[covered by sound of a MLRS battery firing nearby.](https://twitter.com/wartranslated/status/1553037563065155585)

Since Russia has been very clear they&#39;re in Ukraine to &#39;denazify it&#39;, killing their own nazi-tatto covered walking propaganda prizes they could have hanged at their own leisure .. doesn&#39;t make a lot of sense.

Russians say it was Ukrainians using GMLRS missiles and have produced some wreckage. There were some POWs videos of Azov prisoners recently, but I don&#39;t really see the motivation - nobody with a brain should take POW videos seriously; people under duress will say anything.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii78aft/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii70gtf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Has our concept of fundamental rights in the United States changed since the day</title><updated>2022-07-29T23:40:53Z</updated><author><name>TheWhiteSquirrel</name></author><content type="text">Has our concept of fundamental rights in the United States changed since the days of the Founders and/or Reconstruction?

And by that, I mean rights with *bipartisan support*. Certainly, the Red Tribe rejects many rights that the Blue Tribe asserts, perhaps most loudly the right to abortion. And the Blue Tribe also rejects rights that the Red Tribe asserts, perhaps most loudly the right not to vaccinate. I’m talking about whether we have a universal understanding that the scope of fundamental rights can change—whether we can gain new rights that weren’t there before, even if we disagree on which ones.

I’ve been thinking about this in light of the current Supreme Court majority effectively answering this question “no.” In three of their major, controversial cases last month, they applied a definition of fundamental rights that relies on historical tradition. I could cite multiple examples, but here’s Alito in *Dobbs:*

&amp;gt;\[The Due Process Clause\] has been held to guarantee some rights that are not mentioned in the Constitution, but any such right must be &#34;deeply rooted in this Nation’s history and tradition&#34; and &#34;implicit in the concept of ordered liberty.&#34;

In my reading, Alito’s opinion limits the doctrine of “substantive due process” to those rights that have a historical basis in this country. Substantive due process is the doctrine that courts can identify and protect fundamental rights other than the enumerated ones in the Bill of Rights (and later amendments), and it has been used as the basis for SCOTUS decisions in *Ro*e and *Casey*, as well as gay rights cases, marriage rights cases, and more. Alito would apply it more narrowly, to exclude abortion rights. Kavanaugh assures us (without explanation) that the *Dobbs* decision *definitely* doesn’t threaten other substantive due process rights, but Thomas rejects substantive due process entirely.

I disagree with Thomas (at minimum), but for a different reason. I tend to look at rights first through the Ninth Amendment:

&amp;gt;The enumeration in the Constitution, of certain rights, shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people.

It honestly surprises me that this isn’t invoked more in legal arguments because it just comes out and *says* that there are other rights besides the ones that are spelled out--and by extension, they need to be protected. (For example, Justice Arthur Goldberg used it in his concurrence in *Griswold*, but it wasn’t the controlling opinion.)

In practice, I think this may actually be the same as the substantive due process argument. While it reads as an open-ended grant of rights, in order for the Ninth Amendment to have any teeth, a right has to be identified and protected. Protected how? Presumably by due process. The protection that the government may not “deprive any person of life, *liberty*, or property without due process of law” implies that *any* right must be so protected, not just the enumerated ones. But the usual formulation of substantive due process never even mentions 9A. (If it did, it would be a stronger argument against Thomas.)

Except there’s one complication, one that Alito invokes in *Dobbs*, but I think is more obvious when 9A is in play: *Which* rights?

The Ninth Amendment was written in 1791. The Fourteenth Amendment, which is the last Constitutional word on the subject, in 1868. Should they be interpreted, as Alito says, according to historical tradition of what people said fundamental rights were in 1791/1868?

Other amendments have been interpreted broadly to keep up with the times. The right to free speech has been extended to radio, television, and the internet. The right to bear arms has been extended to repeating firearms and then semi-automatics. The right against unreasonable search and seizure has been extended (albeit less successfully) to electronic communications. Should 9A likewise be interpreted broadly to encompass what people say fundamental rights should be today.

No, that’s not exactly the same thing. And given the Culture War dispute on what “rights” exist or should exist, it seems like a moot point. But I think there is a test we can do to point us empirically toward a real answer:

Are there any rights that *both* tribes (in the United States) agree on today, which are not mere extensions of the enumerated rights in the Bill of Rights (or later amendments), *and* were not recognized in 1868, either because social mores have changed or because technology has advanced?

If we can name such a right, that would be evidence not of substantive due process itself, but rather that the way we *think* about fundamental rights today is consistent with the doctrine of substantive due process, either *per se* or as a consequence of 9A. But I’m having trouble thinking of any. I don’t know if that’s because I’m too deep in the Bill of Rights paradigm, or if there aren’t any, or if there *are*, but by definition they aren’t political issues, but I welcome suggestions on the question.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii70gtf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii6eqhf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I saw a recent bit of news being passed around, suggesting [a possible criminal </title><updated>2022-07-29T21:02:14Z</updated><author><name>tricksandcandlewicks</name></author><content type="text">I saw a recent bit of news being passed around, suggesting [a possible criminal investigation into DeSantis](https://grantstern.substack.com/p/top-desantis-propagandist-didnt-register). In summary, the evidence seems to be that one of his staffers did not properly disclose that she was at one point a foreign national for the country of Georgia, and he was aware of this and did not submit the proper form according to the current byzantine federal regulations on hand. In the substack article that was attempting to make them look as guilty as possible, I had to question just how serious they were trying to portray a crime that seemed to be the most banal of clerical errors.

That it was purely devoid of anything serious made me think it would be a nothingburger. At best, they would just fire or arrest the staffer, as there&#39;s almost nothing to charge DeSantis with. But some people seemed to think it was a real move to try and charge DeSantis with something so that the most aggrieved democrats could have something to say they have done, with the Jan 6 hearings currently going nowhere fast. I&#39;m going to follow this to see if my priors were correct, but I would be interested in hearing a steelman of whether there is anything seriously legally wrong here that a prosecutor could pounce on, both for DeSantis and for Trump over Jan 6.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii6eqhf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii5v75p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">TLDR: I think Deshaun Watson is innocent and is getting extorted by women who ar</title><updated>2022-07-29T18:50:27Z</updated><author><name>buttfaceszn</name></author><content type="text">TLDR: I think Deshaun Watson is innocent and is getting extorted by women who are essentially prostitutes but operate as masseuses

I am someone who is way too emotionally invested in sports, and Deshaun Watson has been my favorite player since he was in college. I am also very much against “believe all women”, or at least against the “bailey” of that statement which implies men are guilty until proven innocent. So I am overall extremely biased in favor of Watson here and perhaps this is all motivated reasoning. But I think his case is one of the best examples of the MeToo pendulum swinging too far.  

So Watson is(was) a young star at NFL quarterback, who prior to spring 2021 was known for being humble, kindhearted, and a strong leader of excellent character. Now those may be platitudes you hear about every athlete, but I think it’s fair to say that these traits were especially emphasized by coaches and commentators about Watson, given that he came from poverty and was raised by a single mother who was chronically ill with cancer for much of his life.  

Around February or March 2021, a story surfaced that Watson had been accused of sexually assaulting a massage therapist, and had refused to pay a low six-figure settlement before anything went public. His accuser enlisted the services of Texas mega/meme-lawyer Tony Buzbee (look him up), who immediately solicited other women who had been “sexually assaulted” by Watson while giving him a massage. Ultimately, there were something like 25 civil suits filed against him for sexual misconduct, most of which have been settled recently. One or two of the accusations allege forced oral sex, and the remainder allege some version of “he tried to rub his dick against my hand, he asked me to do X sexual act, he ejaculated while I was massaging him”. Additionally, 2 grand juries in Texas have declined to indict Watson on any criminal charges.  

The evidence presented by the accusers, at least what’s been seen by the public, is their testimony, and some Instagram messages or texts corroborating that Watson booked them for a massage. Almost all of these women are “unlicensed massage therapists” who operate via Instagram, many of whom were flown to Texas from out of state. Watson’s defense is that he did see these women for massages, had sexual contact with them, but that everything was consensual. He has also shown evidence that some of the accusers reached out to work with him again after the date of the alleged sexual assault, and that some of them bragged or spoke positively to friends about their appointments with him.  

“Only 1-10% of sexual assault cases are falsely reported. With 25 women accusing him, the chance that they are all false is infinitesimally small! And sexual assault is notoriously difficult to prove. The women who wanted to work with him again after being assaulted are just processing their trauma”. This is the argument you hear from NFL subreddit commenters, who from basically the very beginning have been thrilled to demonstrate how anti-sexual assault they are by condemning Watson as a serial rapist/assaulter/predator.  

Let’s take as a given that the stat about false accusations is true (I don’t think it is, and definitely not for rich/famous people). Well, the 25 women accusing him are not independent events- they all have the same lawyer and all but one or two came forward after the possibility of a six-figure settlement was put on the table. And sexual assault IS notoriously difficult to prove, but don’t the reasons that make it difficult to prove also make it impossible to DISprove? And to the argument about the women who worked with him after being assaulted just “processing their trauma in their own way”, I don’t even have a response because I can’t imagine being that charitable to anybody making evidence-free accusations.

So what do I think actually happened? Well it seems clear that Watson has some sort of fetish for sex with massage therapists. A little weird, but “happy ending” massage places are basically everywhere so not too out of the ordinary. “Unlicensed Massage Therapist who operates via Instagram” sounds a lot like “sex worker with a good cover story” to me. When those unlicensed massage therapists are getting flown from out of state to massage an NFL quarterback, I really have a hard time believing they didn’t know exactly what was happening.  

If you’re one of these “massage therapists” who has worked with Watson and you hear about this lawyer who is soliciting clients who have been assaulted by Watson: you know that you have evidence proving you met with Watson for a massage, you know that any discussion of paying for sex happened in person, you know that it will be impossible to disprove, you know that Watson will not use “I was actually just flying in prostitutes” as a defense, and you know there’s a very good chance of getting a six figure settlement for telling a story about how traumatized you were that Watson asked you to jack him off. Why wouldn’t you take that? 

To me, the most plausible scenario is that the first accuser was looking for hush money thinking Watson would just pay up, somehow Tony Buzbee caught wind of this and that Watson had hooked up with like 60 masseuses in the last year, and saw an opportunity for a big settlement and a whole lot of positive publicity. Every mainstream media source post-MeToo will reflexively support the accusers, Buzbee’s name will be all over the news, and you know if you just keep dragging this out you will get a settlement as Watson can’t waste his prime earning years unable to play football because of the 25 civil court cases. And Watson is now gonna be known as a serial rapist for the rest of his life when he’s really just horny for massages.  

Am I just doing mental gymnastics to defend my favorite athlete here? Or does my theory sound plausible?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii5v75p/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii3f5hp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I want to talk about how training is obsolete. Nobody can be trained nowadays. A</title><updated>2022-07-29T06:14:33Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><content type="text">I want to talk about how training is obsolete. Nobody can be trained nowadays. At my work, literally every new hire who is a programmer got locked out of their Outlook except OWA because someone changed my automaton scripts. Some JSON file got pushed out and everyone lost access. I was able to quickly fix it once it got escalated to me because I wrote the scripts and the Mac exception i could easily fix.

But it got me thinking. How is a normal person who edits my scripts supposed to know that Apple needs certain protocols turned on for certain users. Legal comes in and says turn off this attribute and some person changes my code.

My point is literally nobody apparently knows why my code does what it does. I try to write good comments but apparently people think they can change stuff if they have a change request. I respect the ambition but they are messing up everything.

My point is how can these youngsters actually get experience. They just get in our way, but we also need to hire them. It&#39;s a conundrum. And most aren&#39;t worth 2 shits. Just saying.



That&#39;s not my point though. New hires trying to change my code isn&#39;t a new thing. 

What is crazy to me is that one small change could mess up so many things. New people get out of college get aggressive and make changes they have no clue what will impact others.

Which brings me to my next point. Training is impossible in the modern environment. There is literally no way to teach these kids how to not screw up our code. We wrote an in house method for AD and these idiots broke it because our sys admins gave then to much access. But I&#39;m not mad because they found inefficiencies but broke stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii3f5hp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii1xays/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">If the rats in San Francisco get monkeypox, how bad will it get? The EU Centre f</title><updated>2022-07-28T22:45:20Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">If the rats in San Francisco get monkeypox, how bad will it get? The EU Centre for Disease Control has a [report](https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C31&amp;amp;q=%E2%80%9CImplementing+actions+to+minimise+the+presence+of+the+virus+in+the+sewage+system%E2%80%9D&amp;amp;btnG=#d=gs_qabs&amp;amp;t=1659048407870&amp;amp;u=%23p%3Dfzr8qRg_B9MJ) that reads —

&amp;gt;Implementing actions to
 minimise the presence of the virus in the sewage system, where numerous rodents are living, should be considered.

A Veterinary research paper on Monkeypox [from 2004](https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.418.2491&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf) speculated that —

&amp;gt; One can envision prairie dogs, perhaps infected with monkeypox, plague, or tularaemia, populating the sewers of Tokyo or Los Angeles, only to emerge to engender some new public health plague, as a sort of horrific life imitates art event, akin to a Grade B horror film

A doctor, though without relevant credential, had [the following tweet](https://mobile.twitter.com/denise_dewald/status/1552226260071366657) go viral —

&amp;gt;Once monkeypox is detectable in the wastewater, it’s game over for eradication; the sewers are swarming with rats. It will become endemic. We will need to resume universal vaccination against smallpox/monkeypox. Monkeypox has been found in the wastewater in San Francisco.

Lastly, San Francisco is going to declare a state of emergency.

I think people who do not know what San Francisco is like might not realize that there is sufficient cross-reservoir contact being rats and humans to cause a crisis. A pizza place on the block where I lived was shuttered because people saw rats on their counter at closing hours. The entryway was later inhabited by a junkie who spread his feces and needles around the sidewalks, where dogs were often walked. Vagrants are frequent flyers at the hospitals, sometimes against their will, meaning police snd EMTs will have to use full PPE. The public library will likely have to close because the homeless of San Francisco congregate there to use the restrooms and open doors (without washing hands) and occasionally picking up a book or using a computer. The restrooms at Starbucks are continually used not just by the homeless but by tourists and busy people.

Implying that a dozen heroin-using homeless individuals acquire monkeypox, my intuition is that it could lead to a sustained public health problem.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii1xays/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0uqkg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Kamala Harris recently did an event where, after disclosing their name and prono</title><updated>2022-07-28T18:31:08Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><content type="text">Kamala Harris recently did an event where, after disclosing their name and pronouns, [people announced what they were wearing](https://twitter.com/greg_price11/status/1551986134535884800). This boggles my mind. The only explanation I can think of is that they&#39;re trying to be sensitive to the visually impaired, but even that makes no sense. A person who was born blind has no idea what color is and will never be able to comprehend it. A person who lost their vision later in life probably wouldn&#39;t care what anyone at the table looks like, because they&#39;re there to exchange ideas. Moreover, if the goal is to tell people what you look like, then why focus on clothing? Do the people responsible for this custom have such limited visual imagination that they think a person&#39;s appearance can be compressed down to a handful of assumptions based on gender and color of clothing? (Come to think of it, that sounds like [Corporate Memphis](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporate_Memphis). Maybe there&#39;s a connection there)

Any explanation or steelman would be appreciated.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0uqkg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0b74z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Last week someone asked that we do a regular policy tracking/analysis thing each</title><updated>2022-07-28T16:27:02Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><content type="text">Last week someone asked that we do a regular policy tracking/analysis thing each week at the Motte and I think that sounds grand, so here&#39;s some updates.

Last night Democratic senators and the Biden team finally hammered out the long awaited deal with Senate final boss Joe Manchin.  The resulting Inflation Reduction Act is tiny compared to the price tag on the original Build Back Better Act but still hits at a lot of major priorities.  The [full text](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122281-inflation_reduction_act_of_2022) is here if you&#39;re interested, a breezy read at 725 pages.  This [one page summary](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122297-inflation_reduction_act_one_page_summary) gives a quick breakdown, and [NYTimes](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/27/us/politics/manchin-climate-tax-bill.html) has a pretty solid summary of the key stuff:

&amp;gt;The package would set aside $369 billion for climate and energy proposals, the most ambitious climate action ever taken by Congress, and raise an estimated $451 billion in new tax revenue over a decade, while cutting federal spending on prescription drugs by $288 billion, according to a summary circulated Wednesday evening.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;. . .  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The two health care pieces would allow Medicare to directly regulate the price of prescription drugs for the first time beginning in 2023. It would also extend through 2025 an expansion of premium subsidies that Democrats first pushed through in 2021 as part of their $1.9 trillion pandemic aid bill, preventing a lapse at the end of the year.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The plan would raise most of its new tax revenue, an estimated $313 billion, by imposing a minimum tax on the so-called book income of large corporations, like Amazon and FedEx, that currently use tax credits and other maneuvers to reduce their tax rates below the 21 percent corporate income tax rate in the United States.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;It would raise another $14 billion by reducing a preferential tax treatment for income earned by venture capitalists and private equity firms, which has long been a goal of Democrats.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;It invests $30 billion in production tax credits for solar panels, wind turbines, batteries and critical minerals processing; $10 billion in tax credits to build clean technology manufacturing facilities; and $500 million to be used through the Defense Production Act for heat pumps and critical minerals processing.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The deal also includes a means-tested $7,500 tax credit to make new electric vehicles more affordable, and a $4,000 tax credit for used electric vehicles, according to a summary of the package. Both credits will be offered only to lower and middle-income consumers.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The measure also includes a methane fee that will start in 2025.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Also included will be $60 billion to address the disproportionate burden of pollution on low-income communities and communities of color, $27 billion for a “green bank” aimed at delivering financial support to clean energy projects and $20 billion for programs that can cut emissions in the agriculture sector.

Relevant to our discussion yesterday about Trump and DeSantis, the bill also includes &#34;comprehensive permitting reform&#34; aimed at making building easier, though not a lot of details have been released so far and I haven&#39;t trawled the bill yet.

I&#39;m pretty into everything I see here at first glance, especially the provision allowing Medicare to negotiate prices and also the investments in electric vehicles and related clean energy technologies (as you might have guessed from my posts ranting about gas reliance always exposing us to international crises).  I see nothing about nuclear power in the summary unfortunately (edit: see u/ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr&#39;s comment for details on what they are doing).

I&#39;m a little surprised at some of the tax stuff - if we&#39;re going after paying back the deficit why focus on carried interest and not capital gains in general, one of Biden&#39;s original pledges?  Presumably lost in compromise I suppose.  I&#39;ve been unconvinced by the arguments that eliminating the capital gains tax will choke off investment since so much of venture capital is from already tax-exempt sources like pension funds, but possibly also they were worried about choking off investment at a time when fears of a recession are already growing.  Note that Manchin also put the kibosh on attempts from the coastal senators to raise the SALT cap, which I consider to be a plus.

Note  also that this bill isn&#39;t guaranteed; Kyrsten Sinema hasn&#39;t weighed in yet and we haven&#39;t actually heard from every other Democratic senator either.

This comes a day after the Senate passing an actually bipartisan (64-33) [industrial policy bill](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/27/us/politics/senate-chips-china.html) aimed at countering China and in particular onshoring the semiconductor industry:

&amp;gt;The bill, a convergence of economic and national security policy, would provide $52 billion in subsidies and additional tax credits to companies that manufacture chips in the United States. It also would add $200 billion for scientific research, especially into artificial intelligence, robotics, quantum computing and a variety of other technologies.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The bill calls for pouring $10 billion into the Department of Commerce — which would also dole out the chips subsidies to companies that apply — to create 20 “regional technology hubs” across the country. The brainchild of Senator Todd Young, Republican of Indiana, and Mr. Schumer, the hubs would aim to link together research universities with private industry in an effort to create Silicon Valley-like centers for technology innovation in areas hollowed out by globalization.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The legislation would steer billions to the Department of Energy and the National Science Foundation to promote both basic research and research and development into advanced semiconductor manufacturing, as well as work force development programs, in an effort to build a labor pipeline for a slew of emerging industries.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;. . .  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The bill also seeks to create research and development and manufacturing jobs in the long run. It includes provisions aimed at building up pipelines of workers — through work force development grants and other programs — concentrated in once-booming industrial hubs hollowed out by corporate offshoring.

I haven&#39;t read nearly as much about this one but interested and heartned to see any piece of major legislation passed with such substantial cross-aisle cooperation.  Apologies for the bare bones analysis but I need to dig into both of these deeper to have much more to say.  Interested to hear what others think.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0b74z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihzgukn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Is &#34;cultural genocide&#34; actually bad? I think it&#39;s non controversial that actual </title><updated>2022-07-28T12:56:40Z</updated><author><name>fkakenNfjakx629</name></author><content type="text">Is &#34;cultural genocide&#34; actually bad? I think it&#39;s non controversial that actual genocide, ala murdering/ driving people out of the area and taking their land is not good. However I&#39;ve been thinking about forced assimilation lately and how it gets a super bad wrap in progressive and even moderate circles. 

Things like taking indigenous children and forcing them to learn in  missionary schools are nowadays treated as a moral outrage. Whereas back in the day these works would be celebrated as a civilizing mission of the white man&#39;s burden. Yet I feel like for technologically &#34;backwards&#34; populations that would otherwise be outcompeted in the labor market, this type of cultural assimilation gives their generations children the best hope of succeeding in a competitive world.

One main point where I differ from my friends is believing that the Uyghur re-education camps in western China are probably the least-bad policy choice the Chinese government has to pacify the region. Yes it&#39;s heavy handed, and the implementation has likely been highly flawed, but fundamentally when you have a separatist minority that visibly practices different cultural customs AND every now and then commits domestic terrorism acts, either you lock everyone up ala manzanar or you do your best to use a carrot and stick approach to get them to conform to the same value systems as your majority population. Why is jobs  training and de-radicalization bad? I&#39;m sure as with any large scale government program there are abuses and corruption at all levels, but fundamentally teaching people the majoritarian language is something every state needs for state capacity.

 In China&#39;s case, the Hui are another Muslim minority but wholly integrated with the Han through the work of their leaders during the warlord era and even earlier. Would that not be preferred than having a separatist community with worse living standards?


The Europeans for example should do the same to their various underclasses (obviously less hamfisted since either don&#39;t have authoritarian control) like the Romani, and hope that in the future more Romani become lawyers or doctors to where the stigma of ethnic differentiation and prejudices goes away. 

When immigrants migrate to a new country most of them actively seek to conform because they chose the country they moved to. They will syncretize and being bubble tea and chicken biryani to our restaurants but still adopt our individualistic morals and watch game of thrones.

Any time where borders move over people, this is much more challenging because the people didn&#39;t choose to be conquered/absorbed. So if there is a risk of unrest, especially when a significant number of the conquering empires population has already moved in, the least bad option is assimilation and coexistenve as opposed to extermination.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihzgukn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihxe7kh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I saw this [Exclusive: Former Republicans and Democrats to form new third U.S. p</title><updated>2022-07-28T00:29:46Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><content type="text">I saw this [Exclusive: Former Republicans and Democrats to form new third U.S. political party](https://archive.ph/hCiRX#selection-435.0-442.0)

It&#39;s called the &#34;Forward party&#34; 

&amp;gt;The new party, called Forward, will initially be co-chaired by former Democratic presidential candidate Andrew Yang and Christine Todd Whitman, the former Republican governor of New Jersey. They hope the party will become a viable alternative to the Republican and Democratic parties that dominate U.S. politics, founding members told Reuters.

&amp;gt;The new party is being formed by a merger of three political groups that have emerged in recent years as a reaction to America&#39;s increasingly polarized and gridlocked political system. The leaders cited a Gallup poll last year showing a record two-thirds of Americans believe a third party is needed.

&amp;gt;The merger involves the Renew America Movement, formed in 2021 by dozens of former officials in the Republican administrations of Ronald Reagan, George H.W. Bush, George W. Bush and Donald Trump; the Forward Party, founded by Yang, who left the Democratic Party in 2021 and became an independent; and the Serve America Movement, a group of Democrats, Republicans and independents founded by former Republican congressman David Jolly.

It looks like it&#39;s composed of disaffected democrats and never-Trump Bush-era holdouts and Trump turncoats. Does not seem promising.  

Regarding spoilers, this will hurt democrats more than republicans. From what I have gleaned on reddit and social media like Twitter, Yang has sorta become today&#39;s Ralph Nader...a leftist that democrats love to hate and who is perceived as being unhelpful despite his good intentions. It&#39;s like &#34;go away Yang..your moment is over&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihxe7kh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihufhe3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">In 2017 Trump gave a [speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vwa0vC6mBuU) that </title><updated>2022-07-27T12:43:37Z</updated><author><name>stucchio</name></author><content type="text">In 2017 Trump gave a [speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vwa0vC6mBuU) that was very different from most of his other speeches. He talked in great detail about inefficiencies in the federal permitting process - applications being evaluated sequentially instead of in parallel, regulators dragging their feet with delays, no centralized dashboard to figure out where you are in the process.

Unlike most of his speeches, this one fit [Scott&#39;s early characterization of Trump](https://slatestarcodex.com/2016/03/19/book-review-the-art-of-the-deal/): &#34;the effect was that of an infodump from an autistic child with a special interest in real estate development.&#34;

Shortly after saying that, a bunch of reporters ignored the speech he gave and started asking him about racism.

About a year ago, Ron DeSantis passed [HB 1059](https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2021/1059) and no one seems to be talking about it. HB 1059 is important. Things it does:

* Localities have 30 days to respond to your housing permit application. Exceeding 30 days means they have to refund 10% of your application fee per day. (This is single family homes, rules and time periods are a bit different for bigger projects.)
* If your application is declared incomplete, and you make it complete, localities have 10 days to approve/reject. If the city takes 11 days, that&#39;s another 20% off the permit fee.
* Cities must post the entire process on an online dashboard for tracking.
* Counties must post a list of all required attachments, drawings, or other requirements for each type of application, on its website, as well as explicitly outline the procedures for approval/denial. (This makes it very easy to both a) submit a valid application and b) sue if the county denies improperly.)

As per an [analysis in the WaPo](https://archive.ph/aXfCK), it&#39;s working. Permit processing rates (in 30 days) have gone from 47% to 80%, 100% in some places. This is enabling a lot more housing permits.

At this point, it seems that to very little fanfare, Ron DeSantis has become a great champion of YIMBY.

While his culture war antics may get press (and cause YIMBY activities to ignore him cause &#34;ewww&#34;) DeSantis also appears to be a person actively focused on the details of governance. This is something something that should get significantly more attention than it actually does.

“Permit reform doesn’t sound glamorous. They won’t write stories about it; they won’t talk about it, but it is so important,” - Trump</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihufhe3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihpow7l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">**Has Modern Capitalism Lost Track of the Idea of the Gimmick?**

Wall Street ha</title><updated>2022-07-26T13:38:24Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><content type="text">**Has Modern Capitalism Lost Track of the Idea of the Gimmick?**

Wall Street had a day of talking about nothing but [Snapchat](https://finance.yahoo.com/m/054b5080-cb67-3e13-8265-dab2917f384a/snap-stock-tumbles-as.html) as its parent company lost 30% of its value after a bad earnings report. Advertising revenues are down across the board, as Apple and others have instituted better privacy protections for users, and the economy seems headed for a general downturn so ad revenues will likely follow.

[Snap](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snap_Inc.) for those of you that aren&#39;t aware, is a messaging app that send self-destructing picture/video and sometimes text messages. When it launched, it was the first service to really make the disappearing pic/video big, and that made it popular with teenagers/20-somethings who wanted to send pictures that they might be embarrassed by later. Besides the obvious sexting use-case (the privacy was of course much worse than promised), I also recall having a lot of male friends that loved to send me pictures of their giant poops as a gag, and people liked to use it at parties to send drunken videos that wouldn&#39;t last any longer than necessary. Its use was always casual, no one wrote a thesis on Snapchat the way they have on Twitter/Reddit or made art on it the way they have on Instagram/TikTok. Its primary use case was dicking around with your friends, and the professional ecosystem built around that because people were already on snapchat, at core it&#39;s a [Gimmick](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gimmick).

Somehow this got turned into a market cap of over $100,000,000,000; 80% of which has been erased this year. The company has only once turned an actual profit, and while the founders are now immensely wealthy it is as a result of selling equity in the &#34;future&#34; of Snapchat rather than from money actually paid by advertisers or users of Snapchat. Somebody is going to, or already has, lost a lot of money on this.

And it&#39;s summer, so I&#39;m thinking of summer trips to the Jersey Shore as a kid, and the Surf Mall on the boardwalk that was like a big pseudo-department store with every summer fad or gimmick of the year. I think I&#39;ve been inside it most years since about 1998 or so, and every year the majority of their entire stock of stuff is different. One year it&#39;s drug rug hoodies, the next year it is marvel themed sweatshirts, the next everything is in a certain shade of pink. Baseball cards become Pokemon cards become YuGiOh cards become Funko Pops (I think? I&#39;m still not entirely sure what those are beyond hearing them in sneers) comes all the way back around to first edition Holo Charizard Pokemon Cards. 

And I&#39;m thinking about it, the Surf Mall proprietors if you asked them would say they need to make money on whatever they are selling before it goes out of fashion, and run their business each year at a profit on that item. And their suppliers would say, we&#39;re selling these sweatshirts at a price where we can make money this year before they go out of fashion next year and then we&#39;ll make something else, whether they are manufactured in NJ or in Sichuan they are able to figure out what their customer will move to. I feel like that&#39;s what we&#39;ve lost in this business environment, you get a gimmick you and recognize it and you cash in while you can, then move on. Snapchat was a gimmick, it was always a gimmick, and anyone who knew teenagers using it would have said &#34;Yeah, this is a gimmick.&#34; A business like that should have been trying to actually make money off its business while the going was good. What is it that leads to this attitude:

1) Is it that everyone is trying to get the next Amazon or Google? Are all these investors just foolishly playing the lottery? Are they all lemmings following a few leaders on CNBC or whatever who fell for the lottery approach?

2) On a related note, cult of the founder? Snapchat&#39;s founding pair will always control 98% of voting shares, much like WeWork before them, were investors snookered by a few charismatic guys?

3) Generation gap expanding? Maybe middle aged businessmen get physical fads like Pokemon cards because they saw similar things when they were teens, but digital fads confuse them because they didn&#39;t experience them. This should become less true over time, as digital generations age, but it does not seem to be. It would have been obvious, in my mind, to any 19 year old sexting on Snap that Snap was not a $100bn company for the future, it was a fun thing you would stop doing soon enough. There&#39;s a disconnect between the customer and the investor somewhere.

4) Cult of the future? I&#39;m probably more plugged into fashion than most Motte-izens, and you see this as well in fashion companies where brands are constantly decried for not keeping up with the times, or alternatively for selling out when they get big, when the reasonable explanation for the vast majority of brands is that they&#39;re big for a while and then they disappear. Most apps are the same, they&#39;re a fad for a bit, then they fail. Why are we so consistently expecting top 1% scenarios from every business, rather than looking for 50th percentile performance?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihpow7l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decl</title><updated>2022-07-26T02:15:24Z</updated><author><name>ussgordoncaptain2</name></author><content type="text">A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decline&#34; which I disagreed with but the modal motte user agreed with.

Therefore I need to tease out what people meant by &#34;the west&#34; and meant by &#34;decline&#34;.

Survey&#39;s are popular so I [made 1](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScbtLqP8cf6ae4C3JeRXXXXNpCBlVF28B9QuDshf9oswPBHXg/viewform?usp=sf_link).

Most of the questions are replicated below.

1. What G20 nations are in &#34;The west&#34; (most notable countries, being Russia, Japan, and South Korea) 

2. What countries are in Decline? 

3. What do people mean when they say &#34;Decline&#34;? Do they mean relative decline or absolute decline?
        
       3a. A country loses her imperial holdings but the mainland grew 5x in the time period, did they &#34;decline&#34;

       3b. A global power grows 5 fold with stable borders but the rest of the world grew 10 fold, did they &#34;decline&#34;  
        3c. A country grows 5 fold in 30 years becoming one of the major powers, but then in the next 30 years grows only 1.5x and falls from 1/3rd as strong to being 2/9ths as strong as the main superpower.


When people say the west is in decline I tend to disagree, with the exception of the fall of the British and French empires, The west has not declined, merely risen slower than contemporaries. Even then since the fall of the berlin wall only 1 nation (china) has risen to surpass the Medium powers of Germany/France/Britan. Though Japan surpassed them as well, Japan also became &#34;west&#34; somehow.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihmd0bz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Reposting my link to a survey. I didn&#39;t get any responses from The Motte users (</title><updated>2022-07-25T19:55:56Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><content type="text">Reposting my link to a survey. I didn&#39;t get any responses from The Motte users (I got some from the other two subs) so I&#39;m posting it here, I think the CW thread might get all the traffic as opposed to the front page. 

Recently there was a post trying to survey the general knowledge of the motte. The post got removed. And various people accused the survey of having various shortcomings, from it being a troll, to OP having some kind of agenda with the questions asked. 

Therefore I created a new survey for general knowledge. 

~~1. Its timed. There are 39 questions. With 35 minutes to answer all of them.~~ 

~~2. They are all multiple choice, with only 1 valid answer.~~

There is a math, CS, geography, history and economics section.

I tried to design the questions such that they can be answered without any niche/esoteric knowledge. I did not include any of my personal pet questions or anything like that and tried to frame the questions such that you can use incomplete knowledge to answer them, as long as you have a rough idea of the mechanisms that guide those fields. 

Feedback appreciated. 

DISCLAIMER: Email only to log in, I can&#39;t see the emails. 

Link to the survey here. https://forms.gle/S2a8BY7Ln8kPcCpj9


________________________

edit - Very controversial. I will count more than one answer to the *vague* questions as correct when I do the final eda. My ultimate goal is to do a subreddit wide survey, not individual survey, so don&#39;t put too much weight into your own score. Add +1 or 2 points because some questions are vague, if you want a rough estimate of your score were the questions less vague.

edit2- Certain questions most people were getting wrong, people are getting right now. Either there is data leakage from the comments, or a different demographic is onto it. Hmmmmm</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihmd0bz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihllphv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So, you know how when you examine the porn consumption habits vs. political beli</title><updated>2022-07-25T17:02:29Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><content type="text">So, you know how when you examine the porn consumption habits vs. political beliefs, you can always find something worth a laugh?

[https://lawsuit.org/general-law/republicans-have-an-obsession-with-transgender-pornography/](https://lawsuit.org/general-law/republicans-have-an-obsession-with-transgender-pornography/)

Here it is again: Conservatives fucking LOVE trans porn, and liberals don&#39;t seem to know it exists. 

Likewise, conservative as a population love cuckoldry(BLACK), cheating, and Teen; while liberals seem to go in hard for BDSM, rape play, and power dynamic shit.

You can&#39;t really do anything useful with this other than score the meaningless dunks on the more naïve type of lib or con; but I always wonder if there is anything meaningful you can take from it?

That is, I don&#39;t really have anything interesting to say about it that hasn&#39;t been said, other than I still don&#39;t understand the why this would be the case to consistently and none of the explanations I&#39;ve heard have an air of truthiness.

Anyone have any links that they feel explain this well?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihllphv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub. </title><updated>2022-07-25T16:37:27Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><content type="text">There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub.  I thought I&#39;d share some thoughts on it.

There is a technique that old SysAdmins will recognize called tarpitting: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarpit_(networking)#SMTP_tarpits

The technique is to prevent spammers from being able to abuse a mail server (send too many messages) by simply wasting their time.  If the mail system detects something it believes is a spammer, it will simply make everything take a really long (relatively) time.

Instead of being able to send 1000 messages/second, it might limit you to one message ever 5 seconds (this is exaggerated).  The idea is that a normal user won&#39;t notice this, but a spammer trying to send thousands of messages will.  It&#39;s a very clever, and also effective strategy.  I like it.

There is something that I&#39;ve noticed especially on reddit, which feels like an evolution of Gish Galloping: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gish_gallop

The way it might go is that an uncharitable discussion partner will write long posts with very little substance in which they repeatedly ask the same questions, or sortof &#34;play dumb&#34; and ask for explanations for things which have been discussed *extensively* in the past.

I notice it here, but I notice it on other subreddits as well.  To put on a tinfoil hat for a short second: a lot of times the accounts which engage in this behavior seem to spend an almost *unbelievable* amount of time posting things on reddit, and often only on one subreddit.  So my tinfoil hat question is: are these really good GPT bots?  GPT-3 is *quite* good, and it seems within the realm of possibility that there are conversational-tarpitting bots that exist.

My question is: has anybody else noticed this behavior and charted it at all?  If so how do you identify it and what framework do you use for thinking about it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">*Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought th</title><updated>2022-07-25T15:10:46Z</updated><author><name>codergenius</name></author><content type="text">*Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought that it would be too culture-wary for the small questions thread*

**What is the actual difference between arranged marriages vs love marriages (failure modes, happy paths, why would be one be better than the other based on certain frameworks, and so on)?** 

After looking on the internet, I found that the differences account for context to be already present. I found out that I could not grok that context as I am too &#34;autistic&#34; (God I hate that word, along with nerdy). I am trying to understand it as an alien that has come to the earth for the first time or in the rationalist terms, I am trying to taboo the words &#34;love&#34;, &#34;arranged&#34; and &#34;marriages&#34;.   
  
I would really like views with the framework stated, if that is not too much or better yet, links to forums that you have seen where these concepts are discussed in detail. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/cul</title><updated>2022-07-25T13:31:45Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><content type="text">A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?context=3) about oil prices a few days ago.

One of the sub-questions I was curious about was why oil companies weren’t investing more in digging new wells.  A few commenters replied that this was probably because of Biden – he opened up his term by cancelling the Keystone XL pipeline, removing permits on drilling on federal lands and saying we should move towards fully green energy.  My reply was that Obama basically did all that stuff too and oil production doubled under him, so are these kinds of regulatory policy moves really that important to investors?

Users u/LeninLovedUncleTom and u/Pulpachair offered more information on how technology breakthroughs and the relatively high price of crude oil opened up the new shale market under Obama and led to that crazy growth.  But there’s still a lot of shale and crude prices are crazy high again and no one’s drilling.  I think [both](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih8bt2a/?context=3) [users](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih89f6l/?context=3) made compelling arguments (if i followed them), substantiated with the articles I can find with quotes from oil leaders, that the primary driver of investment isn&#39;t really regulatory policy, it&#39;s the fact that everyone is too worried about massive market fluctuations.  OPEC cratered prices after the initial shale boom and hurt a lot of investors, and Covid saw barrels going for negative prices.  Who wants to invest in drilling more when the market could switch up on you and completely destroy your profits?  [To quote](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-02-18/shale-wildcatters-send-bullish-oil-price-signal-with-output-restraint):

&amp;gt;“Whether it’s $150 oil, $200 oil, or $100 oil, we’re not going to change our growth plans,’’ Pioneer Chief Executive Officer Scott Sheffield said during a Bloomberg Television interview. “If the president wants us to grow, I just don’t think the industry can grow anyway.’’

I think here this offers us two possibilities, with two questions I’d ask everyone.

1:  If we assume government policy can’t make a huge difference on oil investment relative to the market, and the market experiences such dramatic fluctuations that investors literally won’t invest in drilling more even when it would be profitable, and that this common sense market rationale means we all have to eat high gas prices: is this not an extremely strong argument for trying to divest away from oil?  To invest full scale in nuclear and renewables (edit: and battery storage technology) and microgrids and the infrastructure to make electric vehicles possible and widespread?

Much is talked about the intermittency issues with renewables, but should the fact that Russia and China each control 15% of the world’s oil production, and petroleum sales can always be used as a carrot or stick in conflicts like the current one, and that we don’t have the ability to control OPEC with their further 44% of the world’s production – shouldn’t all this be seen functionally as an broad scale intermittency problem as well?  You can address shortfalls with wind and solar in a number of ways, like using combined heat and gas systems or only using them to complement nuclear power, but in crisis situations where 15% of the world’s oil disappears off of the western markets there doesn’t seem to be any quick fix – our oil companies outright say the won’t drill more no matter what the president does!

I’m well aware this would be a cost intensive and technologically challenging road, and that renewables in particular have other huge limitations and could perhaps never fully fill the gap fossil fuels played, but wouldn’t shrinking our fossil fuel dependency alone go significantly far towards reducing our exposure to these kinds of crises?  Would the eventual problems we might face in a country that invested to the hilt in electric cars, nuclear energy, renewable energy systems and decentralized microgrids be worse than what we’re dealing with now?  Would it be worse than the fact that our country is always vulnerable having the pipe turned off from the outside?

2:  Alternatively, maybe none of the obvious stuff Biden could do would help oil.  But let’s pretend he can - what if he did all the non-obvious stuff as well?  What if Biden completely deregulated oil, cut their taxes down to zero, gave them (more) massive subsidies and promised to insure any losses from market fluctuations, slashed wages, cut all zoning laws, worker’s rights, safety regulations and environmental regulations and finally got domestic oil production to rise.

Would it be worth it?

Sometimes I’m jealous of China’s powerful industrial base.  Then I think about their horrendously polluted waterways and their skies full of smog and their workers paid pittances to labor for crazy hours in often unsafe conditions, and I wonder if it would be worth having to do all that to compete with them on some kind of even footing.

Would it be worth producing two, three, four times as much oil, enough that we have dominance over the world price and never have to worry about this situation again, if we also had to trade away our centuries of hard-fought worker’s rights? If all of our gorgeous national parks were studded with oil wells and refineries and our waterways and skies groaned under the weight of their pollution?  This is an exaggerated example to be sure, but in a world where oil executives outright say the President’s normal policy levers won’t change their investment outlook, it bears worth asking: how much are we actually willing to give up to change that?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>