<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Culture War - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-23T00:03:08Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ile306e/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Stable Diffusion was released to [public beta](https://stability.ai/blog/stable-</title><updated>2022-08-23T00:03:08Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><content type="text">Stable Diffusion was released to [public beta](https://stability.ai/blog/stable-diffusion-public-release) today, complete with weights. In general, it seems comparable to DALLE2, Imagen, and Parti, beating them in some ways and losing to them in others; the most general comment I&#39;d offer is that it seems to do worse with semantic content and better with textures. This isn&#39;t too important: the next generation (which is to say, 6-12 months from now) will beat all of them in all their best aspects.

Aside from a lot of verbiage around using it ethically, the official and publicly hosted version includes a safety classifier that removes bad outputs. Yay? Of course, since it&#39;s open source, it&#39;s easy enough to modify the code, and the world got right to it. We already have the UnstableDiffusion and PornDiffusion subreddits, and there will be an proliferation of them and their content in the coming months without the need to dance around the OpenAI and Google ~~blacklists~~ blocklists. I mentioned this to a friend, and she said that at least we&#39;ll have a couples years before we could supply images of a person and have porn generated from them. I didn&#39;t have the heart to point her to [textual-inversion](https://textual-inversion.github.io/). Who&#39;d have thought porn actresses would be some of the first to fall to AI? If it&#39;s any consolation to them, many other occupations are going to be wiped out in the coming first wave.

It seems like society is not just unprepared for this but unaware of how far along we are in the automated generation of digital content. For awhile it seemed like the hope was that professional gatekeepers would protect us, but it was obvious that strategy just needed a single defector to fail. If it wasn&#39;t Stability, it&#39;d have been Yandex. If it wasn&#39;t Yandex, it would be a leak.

Regardless, now the cat is out of the bag. I don&#39;t think there was or is any way to prevent or stop this, or even that it&#39;s bad that it&#39;s happening. What does seem likely is that we&#39;re in for a rough ride as society reacts to something that&#39;s blindsided it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ile306e/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but</title><updated>2022-08-22T18:45:28Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><content type="text">Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but from my vantage point while opposition may have slowed its ascent, it hasn&#39;t managed to reverse the gains.

Case in point: https://www.aier.org/article/the-suicide-of-the-american-historical-association/

Basically, the AHA President dared to offer the mildest of critiques of the &#39;1619&#39; project and now his own members are baying for his blood in the form of a career defenestration. He has hardly any defenders within his organisation and he&#39;s the top guy, so what hope is there for someone with less status within the history profession?

DeSantis&#39; so-called &#34;anti-woke laws&#34; were all stopped by a federal judge. He hopes his voters don&#39;t pay attention and he gives no indications of trying to fight hard to overrule  any of these setbacks.

University of Tennessee - supposedly in a red state where the GOP has political control - has [massively ramped](https://twitter.com/JohnDSailer/status/1559605619857956864) up the DIE (Diversity, Inclusion, Equity) policies.

The GOP appears content in complaining but doing little to combat any of this by using state power. As long as this is the case, my prediction is that &#39;wokism&#39;, for a lack of a better term, is here to stay.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilc6r63/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Interesting discussion on SSC with regards to social mobility from this paper fr</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:18:48Z</updated><author><name>Just_Natural_9027</name></author><content type="text">Interesting discussion on SSC with regards to social mobility from this paper from Nature:

The share of high-SES friends among individuals with low SES is among the strongest predictors of upward income mobility identified to date.

[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04996-4](https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04996-4)

[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04997-3](https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04997-3)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilc6r63/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:31:11Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><content type="text">[Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-the-heat-level-of-the-terf)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[TERFs/trans issues\]

Article is in three parts.

(1) is a wall of snapshots from the &#34;trending topics&#34; bar on Twitter for the past two weeks, with dates, as well as a snapshot of Google Trends showing that (a) the war between the Trans Exclusionary Radical Feminists (TERFs) and the gender ideology wokes is getting extremely hot, and the burn rate keeps it pretty much squarely on Twitter nonstop, above Ukraine and guns and abortion. The Google Trends graphs show TERF &amp;gt; Intersectionality in interest solidly the past two months and has intermittent peaks well above it, landing the TERF wars in a position where they seem to be overtaking even the heat level of Whiteness related topics during Floyd.

(2) is a recap of the history of the TERF war that most people here can probably skip

(3) is analysis, wherein we attempt to explain why it&#39;s getting so hot, and make predictions about what&#39;s going to happen with it going forward into next year based on an analysis of motivations of either side. Key to the analysis is the presumption that personality traits are probably fairly fixed over time due to genetic factors, which means as religiosity has fallen over time, more people with the &#34;moral certainty and self righteous indignation&#34; traits have had to find another outlet, many of which fell into the Woke bucket. With a fixed (or growing) rate of these in the woke camp, they won&#39;t bend on trans ideology even in the face of all the new entrants to the TERF war driven by school board awakenings and JK Rowling acting as a rally point.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four differen</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:27:37Z</updated><author><name>EngageInFisticuffs</name></author><content type="text">So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four different kinds of writers on the culture war, or really any kind of commentary on conflict. 

1. Partisan propagandists. These are your Nathan J Robinsons. Their positions are predetermined, so their analyses are rarely anything but hackneyed. &#34;My side is good, the other side is bad,&#34; doesn&#39;t leave much room for nuance *or* actual insight. I used Robinson as an easy example, but there are plenty of weird Trumpists who somehow wanted to say that Russia were the good guys invading Ukraine. Although I&#39;ll totally admit that they&#39;re analyses weren&#39;t stale to start off with, they still quickly became predictable.

2. Cynics/insult analysts. I am struggling to come up with any examples right now, but there are a lot of these in respected editorial positions. These people sometimes have interesting analysis, but so often they resort to content-free insults in order to show their disdain and that they are above the conflict. Never do they ever have actually constructive things to say. They just tear stuff down.These types of analysts had their hey day in the 90s, but plenty of them are still going by inertia in respected legacy media even today. This is actually the group that annoys me the most and got me to write up this analysis because I always forget they exist, and I will be fooled into reading some article because it isn&#39;t just partisan drivel, only to realize that it is the equivalent of socio-political malingering and their delight in being unorthodox is an end-goal in itself.

3. (Un)orthodox ideologues. These are your Rod Drehers and Freddie DeBoers. Although they certainly have a side in the conflict, that side is just a means to an end, not a cause in itself. They have some greater vision that they are loyal to, and this allows them to see and critique &#34;their&#34; side in surprising and effective ways and see value in proposals from their &#34;opponents.&#34; These are the types of editorials that are really interesting to read.

4. Exhaustively fair analysts. These are the Scott Alexanders. This is the rarest type, at least in conflict commentary. Most of the people who do this are probably being paid plenty of money for private analysis. Or, if not private, at least largely wonky topics that most people don&#39;t care about. Still, these are the gold standard when it comes to commentary. Not just because if their analysis, they aren&#39;t necessarily any more insightful than the 3s, but because their attempts to engage with all opinions charitably makes them powerful when it comes to persuasion. 1s are also very powerful when it comes to persuasion with their audience, but only on whatever topics won&#39;t make them considered traitors to their cause/audience. Scott has no such limits, and as a result he has convinced people to change positions on all sorts of issues. He has made people more trans-sympathetic and turned leftists into free-market supporters.  But it is also the hardest to do. People have complained that Scott doesn&#39;t really dig in and engage with a lot of topics like he used to. This style of writing takes the most intellectual and emotional energy. It&#39;s much harder than when you already know everyone on the other side is bad and wrong and your side is good and right. Or everyone is just corrupt and stupid, no matter the side. Especially since it is hard to remain an insightful, charitable person once you have had the eye of sauron upon you. Just look at Jordan Peterson.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-a</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:22:47Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><content type="text">[Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-and-hot-air-balloons)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[pollution visualization math\]

Not sure this is totally culture war, except for the fact that nuclear power itself has been such a wretched target of environmentalist culture warriors that we haven&#39;t bothered to build any nuke plants in the USA in decades.

The article does the math to figure out how much power is generated by uranium and coal, and calculates an equivalent amount of pollutant for honest comparisons. Really pretty simple. Conclusion is that two nuclear fuel assemblies of uranium, each of which are about a half a meter long and ten centimeters wide, produce the same amount of energy as enough coal to fill up (with CO2) every hot air balloon at the  Albuquerque International Balloon Fiesta (largest hot air balloon festival in the world) almost 24 times over.

Then has some visual comparisons, so people can understand the scales in question.

I also reduced the article into image meme form:

https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/22543e64-aa06-47d3-8761-2207d8ee3e09\_5360x4320.png</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums </title><updated>2022-08-22T13:57:32Z</updated><author><name>jspsfx</name></author><content type="text">Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums looking for interesting nuggets of information? It’s rather like panning for gold. There’s a steady stream of dirt but almost on a daily basis you will find the seed of a worthwhile idea or some information that’s being suppressed/ignored in mainstream circles.
     
I suspect this is something most curious people do, even “intelligent presenting” people who keep their rhetoric straight and opinions inoffensive. I wonder if it’s an unspoken secret, some habit we engage with after dark.
    
During covid this became a daily activity for me. I hated it though. I hated that information and idea exchange were as locked down as we were physically. I knew any given /r/lockdownskepticism post or idea could be just as valuable as a post made in any mainstream subreddit - I could sort through the bullshit. But I also knew any information outside the establishment view was going to be tainted and treated as false purely by association being stuck in the conspiracy bin.
   
Many dissenting views and/or information which contradicted the dogma of the day regarding covid were relegated to the corners of the internet which the establishment media and institutions label as crazy and dangerous.
  
Essentially, in tandem with the government, social media companies helped create a rhetorical landscape where the only information the public would consume and digest through free discourse was information they deemed acceptable.
  
You could talk about lab leak theory but it would have to be next to the tweaker claiming *they* are transmitting covid via 5G Wi-Fi signals. You could talk about potential or active side effects of the vaccine but it would have to be lumped in with people claiming everyone who got it would die within a year.
   
This seems like the playbook for how “misinformation” is going to be handled online and it’s rather concerning to me. With that in mind I’m actually drawn to check in on these forums even more. Covid information control made me wonder what else am I going to miss if I just stick to mainstream sources… And where else am I to find this information but the black market of ideas?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">**Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:21:11Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><content type="text">**Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it not for the US**

Every so often, people bring up the fact that Taiwan&#39;s military spending is moribund, somewhere below 2% of GDP (China is at a similar level). The US is around 4%. They call for Taiwan to [get serious](https://international.thenewslens.com/article/123554) with its training and spend more on their own defence. It does not seem fair for the US to spend proportionately more for another countries security...

However, there is only so much that Taiwan can do when outnumbered 20:1 in GDP. Taiwan is totally dependent upon foreign fuel and foreign food. The island produces around 10% of their food, China around 65%. There is only one way Taiwan could hope to deter the vastly larger Chinese military: nuclear weapons. The US [shut down](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan_and_weapons_of_mass_destruction) the Taiwanese nuclear program twice. Now, the US has forward-based nuclear weapons to Taiwan in the past but it is unlikely to do so today, given that China now has the power to hit the US mainland. 

If Taiwan had nuclear weapons, there would be no potential crisis. China would not invade a country with a credible nuclear deterrent. The US enabled this looming disaster by suppressing Taiwan&#39;s nuclear ambitions and giving them vague, indefinite not-promises instead.

Since Pakistan and India acquired nuclear weapons, they had only one small skirmish when in the past they would wage full-scale wars. Naturally, the US [sanctioned and harassed](https://www.eetimes.com/u-s-lifts-sanctions-against-india-pakistan/) them for taking this step towards peace. 

There have been no full-scale great power conflicts since WW2, a 70-year historical anomaly. Nuclear weapons make it unprofitable to wage war, so states don&#39;t do it.

If my country, Australia, had nuclear weapons, we wouldn&#39;t need to fight in expensive, pointless US wars since we wouldn&#39;t need their nuclear umbrella or assistance. We would have genuine strategic independence, we could relax and enjoy mining rent.

Now, one counterargument to my nuclear panacea argument is the tail-risk of nuclear war. If the US weren&#39;t so irresponsible, there would have been a much lower chance of nuclear war during the Cold War. It was the US&#39;s decision to invent the Cuban Missile Crisis, violently objecting to internal defense decisions made by the Soviets and Cubans. There are obvious similarities with the current Ukraine war and there is the mitigating factor that Cuba was in the US sphere while Ukraine is/was/contested in the Russian sphere. I don&#39;t particularly want to get bogged down in the movement of spheres of influence though. The way the US handled the crisis was extraordinarily aggressive. The US imposed a &#39;quarantine&#39; of Cuba, an effective blockade. They flew [U-2 spy planes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuban_Missile_Crisis#Crisis_continues) over Cuban airspace and had the temerity to complain when one was shot down! They dropped dummy depth charges on Soviet submarines to force them to surface, pointlessly causing the drama that legendary Arkhipov had to resolve. The US took various steps to raise tensions, dispersing its bombers around civilian airports and keeping some constantly in the air. They made it look as though they were preparing for nuclear war.

The 1983 nuclear scare is also the US&#39;s fault. Why were they launching [psychological operations](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Able_Archer_83#Psychological_operations) and exercises right next to Kamchatka if not to spook the Soviets? Raising tensions in this way is deeply irresponsible, it erodes the commons of mutually assured destruction to eke out small-scale gains in analyzing Soviet military readiness, observing radar patterns etc... It&#39;s needlessly provocative to mock-punch somebody but pull your fist away at the last moment. SDI was similarly bad - if you don&#39;t want a nuclear war, don&#39;t invite a pre-emptive strike by creating a strategic defense system! Of course, the US is still doing it, they left the ABM treaty and have been building up a large missile defense apparatus via AEGIS and GMD.

While North Korean leadership is regularly labelled as insane, they have not invaded anybody since the 1950s. Iran hasn&#39;t invaded anyone either, though they do wage proxy war (an activity not unknown by the US). On what basis can we argue that they would be irresponsible nuclear powers? Occasional political rhetoric calling for the destruction of Israel should not come before the logic of MAD, which has a far stronger empirical and historical basis. The Israelis have their fare share of [religious terrorists](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_religious_terrorism), yet they have remained responsible with their arsenal. 

Obviously, it&#39;s advantageous for the US (and other nuclear powers to a lesser extent) to sanction and bully other states into refraining from nuclearizing. The more states that have nuclear weapons, the less powerful they become. If Iraq or Libya had nukes, the US couldn&#39;t have attacked them. The US of course has the strongest global power projection capacity and thus the most to lose from massive nuclearization. It isn&#39;t surprising that the US is the most eager to suppress nuclear weapons. 

But I think this is important to consider when we discuss the looming risk of war, of geopolitical conflict generally. The assumption of nuclear risk in my view is excessively high and confuses nuclear risks with US risks. If Ukraine had nuclear weapons, there would be no problem today. What is far more destabilizing are airy promises of unspecified support for countries far away from their nuclear patron. Taiwan is only the most obvious example.

If the non-proliferation treaty didn&#39;t exist, the world would be a much better place and there would be fewer wars.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](h</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:16:14Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><content type="text">Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/british-indians-racism-muslim-islamophobia-b2149026.html?utm_content=Echobox&amp;amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Main&amp;amp;utm_source=Twitter#Echobox=1660996247) that turned a lot of heads in Indian online space. Over the past decade, the political zeitgeist in India has been apparently captured indisputably by Hindu Nationalism in the national capacity, while still struggling in many states. Any strand of liberalism left isn&#39;t really a direction anymore, but pressure from above or outside. The term &#39;South Asia&#39; is not very well liked in India, which is seen by many nationalists as a reductionism of their civilisation to another geographic patch of landmass and above all, a tacit affirmation of the current nation states of India and Pakistan as equally legitimate in inheriting the cultural ethnos of the subcontinent.

But in more recent years, the term has produced another bone to pick. White liberals are largely seen as the new cultural imperialists out to atomise societies and rearrange social relations between the sexes, ethnic groups, etc. They&#39;re also seen as militantly anti-India on matters such as Kashmir, with &#39;South Asian&#39; think tanks being their academic arm to dissipate psyops against India. Finally, they&#39;re perceived to be tacitly pro-Pakistan. The last one is a litmus test for a lot of Indians as to whether its all about values or consumer demographics. Is Hindu Nationalism a genuine concern, or just another cudgel against Indians? If Indians are fair game to be criticised for their attitude towards Pakistanis, the reverse should be axiomatic, correct? Well, BBC and other media are seen as hypocritically smearing India over its domestic problems with communalism, caste, gender, etc., while violent crimes by Pakistani origin men in the UK are obscured, leave alone Pakistan&#39;s own social problems. Last year, NYT&#39;s [job listing](https://www.newslaundry.com/2021/07/08/did-nyts-job-posting-for-a-business-correspondent-in-india-deserve-the-outrage-it-got) for an India correspondent sparked a huge furore in Indian media. The part about India&#39;s South Asian neighbours especially raised eyebrows as to whether the implication was that India is the belligerent actor in the region, when every single one of the [Indo-Pak wars](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Pakistani_wars_and_conflicts) was initiated by Pakistan, one of which even involved a [huge genocide](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1971_Bangladesh_genocide) by the Pakistani Army. This event is not discussed in the media, and Indian syllabi consider every even after Independence as contemporary history, so its not discussed in history textbooks either. But ever since war ignited in Ukraine almost 6 months ago, and India&#39;s repeated refusal to condemn the invasion and continued purchase of Russian oil, 1971 has been resuscitated yet again, as was Soviet support to India at the time. Suddenly, many Hindu Nationalists who were previously indifferent to Russia, turned [Russophilic](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/03/29/india-russia-ukraine-media/). But I think this is largely out of hostility to liberals than anything else.

For now, it looks like Hindu Nationalism is not about to lose its political clout in India and this will continue to leave lots of annoyance with liberals. Even the BJP&#39;s political opponents have caved on key issues like the [Rohingya refugees](http://twocircles.net/2022aug22/446679.html) to pose any competition. In all, the Nehruvian era Congress elites simply did not connect to the subalterns in producing the cultural and economic prosperity that they had wanted, whether in their socialist shade during the Cold War or in their neoliberal shade since 2004. And the vacuum it left behind is no longer its own to fill.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>