<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Friday Fun - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T01:19:00Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He</title><updated>2022-08-28T01:19:00Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He may have used one of my requested questions, but I can’t tell as they were vague. Magnus is the most interesting case study of performance psychology because he’s so beyond his competition, in what amounts to the most competitive cognitive game in the world. 

Some interesting bits from the interview:

* Magnus does not like practicing with puzzles. Neither does he consider himself good at stand-alone puzzles. 

* Magnus hates strict, organized practice. He refused to do this as a child and instead enjoyed exploring interesting parts from books he takes a liking to. When he was younger he “fired” Kasparov as a coach (one of the best players of all time) because Kasparov wanted Magnus to analyze his past mistakes, which he found annoying.

* The above two bits are shocking as it flies in the face of our understanding of deliberate practice. But actually, maybe not! While it’s true that puzzles can be construed as very specific deliberate practice, you come across the scenarios in games anyway, in their “natural habitat” surrounded by other information; so playing difficult games is probably better than specialized puzzles. 

* While focusing on past major mistakes could be seen as optimal deliberate practice, it’s also highly demotivating. Magnus’ practice is odd in that he appears to choose the most motivating path. He reads from books guided by pleasure, and he ignores strict puzzle-based practices. He favors playing games, and if you notice, he very often plays these games with variable strategy in mind. Instead of focusing on one opening, when he plays online he frequently changes openings, tests out things he doesn’t know will work, etc. This is excellent deliberate, variable practice while maintaining motivation.

* While Magnus was the poster child of athletic chess players, in recent years he has fallen out of shape. I find it interesting that he favors sports games over weightlifting or cardio. This has a motivational component, because when he’s playing tennis for an hour or two he’s in a state of competition. I think this extra “competitiveness practice” aids him in chess. 

So I find it interesting that Magnus’ approach to chess prioritizes competition and motivation. I also find it interesting to think that if Magnus were placed in chess school with dry exercises and exams, he probably wouldn’t even make it in the top 200 students. He has a strong aversion to boring practice and is chiefly motivated by real competitive wins, and he’s not good at chess “practice puzzles”. This says a lot about modern schooling: what other talents are we missing out on because we focus on dry, boring practice problems that do not directly translate to real life? Have we missed out on Henry Fords and Da Vinci’s?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im0xsgc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">For the Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality fans here on The Motte, here</title><updated>2022-08-27T17:25:46Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><content type="text">For the Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality fans here on The Motte, here&#39;s [Daniel Radcliffe singing an appropriately scientific song](https://youtu.be/rSAaiYKF0cs?t=32).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im0xsgc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more fema</title><updated>2022-08-27T11:00:56Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more female attention than those who have a gym body. Think Timothee Chalamet or Ezra Miller, versus buff Chris Pratt. I think this is because such natural thin disposition signals good metabolic health. This sign of effortless good health trumps the gym body because it conveys greater reproductive fitness and gene desirability.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilyae70/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">A poem from Yours Truly on the Occasion of u/Tracingwoodgrains wedding  


[http</title><updated>2022-08-27T02:15:46Z</updated><author><name>KulakRevolt</name></author><content type="text">A poem from Yours Truly on the Occasion of u/Tracingwoodgrains wedding  


[https://anarchonomicon.substack.com/p/the-fox-and-the-hen?sd=pf](https://anarchonomicon.substack.com/p/the-fox-and-the-hen?sd=pf)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilyae70/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxhahm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">It seems like no amount of technological progress makes moving less terrible. I </title><updated>2022-08-26T22:28:29Z</updated><author><name>rolabond</name></author><content type="text">It seems like no amount of technological progress makes moving less terrible. I hate it. Listening to emo music because it fits the mood as I pack. Thank you MCR.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxhahm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommend</title><updated>2022-08-26T22:23:35Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><content type="text">This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommended reading. https://archive.org/details/The_Sims/page/n43/mode/2up

Reproduced in full: 

&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED READING
&amp;gt; Here are some titles that might enhance your understanding of some of the background and sociai issues entertained in The Sims.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Warning: all are filled with provocative ideas; Maxis disavows any responsibility for encouraging deep thought.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Home: A Short History of an Idea by Witoid Rybczynski (Juiy 1 987), Penguin USA; ISBN: 0140102310
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Notes on the Synthesis of Form by Christopher W. Alexander (June 1970), Harvard University Press; ISBN: 0674627512
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - A Pattern Language : Towns, Buildings, Construction by Christopher Alexander, Sara Ishikawa, Murray Silverstein (1977), Oxford University Press (Trade); iSBN: 0195019199
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Architecture : Form, Space, &amp;amp; Order by Frank D. K. Ching, Francis D. Ching (February 1996), John Wiiey &amp;amp; Sons; ISBN: 0471286168
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Housing by Lifestyle : The Component Method of Residential Design by James W. Wentling (November 1994) McGraw-Hill; ISBN: 0070692939
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Time for Life : The Surprising Ways Americans Use Their Time by John P Robinson, Geoffrey Godbey (Contributor), Robert Putnam (June 1997)Pennsylvania State University Press (Trade); ISBN: 0271016523
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Maps of the Mind by C. Hampden-Turner (March 1982), MacMillan Publishing Company; ISBN: 0025477404
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Hidden Order: The Economics of Everyday Life by David D. Friedman (September 1997), HarperCollins; ISBN: 0887308856
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Making the Most of Your Llama by Linda C. Beattie (Editor), Araneen Witmer (Illustrator), Kathyrn Doll (Editor), Dr. Linda Beattie (September 1998), Kopacetic Ink; ISBN: 0961963417 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Finding Your Perfect Love by Arthur Clark, Cassandra Skouras (January 1998), Rosebud Press; ISBN: 0965276902
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - The User Illusion : Cutting Consciousness Down to Size by Tor Norretranders, Jonathan Sydenham (Translator) (April 1998), Viking Press; ISBN: 0670875791

----

In other news, Will Macaskill worked as a stripper? 

https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/08/15/the-reluctant-prophet-of-effective-altruism

&amp;gt; In graduate school, “I started giving three per cent, and then five per cent, of my income,” he said. This wasn’t much—he was then living on a university stipend. “I think it’s O.K. to tell you this: I supplemented my income with nude modelling for life-drawing classes.” The postures left him free to philosophize. Later, he moved on to bachelorette parties, where he could make twice the money “for way easier poses.”

----

And finally, after playing with Stable Diffusion, I am blown away. A wholly original work of art created inside a minute. Yes, it is hit or miss, but it is amazing that it can hit at all. 

You are probably already saturated with AI art, but [here are a few of my favourites](https://imgur.com/a/lti20Ia). Perhaps you can tell something about a person from the kind of art they generate. Feel free to share your creations.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror </title><updated>2022-08-26T20:32:28Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><content type="text">I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror scenario with humor elements, before circling the entire thing around to be a jab at a certain politician in another country with whom I have no beef. Anyway, via the game [Space Funeral](https://thecatamites.itch.io/space-funeral), which is a free and excellent two to three hour experience that feels like you&#39;re traversing a slightly humorous nightmare, I&#39;ve become more interested in older experimental music as a means of communicating an atmosphere of horror so that I can bundle it up with my already growing pile of copyright infringement. This has led me down the rabbit hole of early synthesizer music, starting with [Delia Derbyshire](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XVsqxNy8kkg) with the BBC Radiophonic Workshop. Most recently, I&#39;ve been delving into Japanese Synthesizer stuff, which is frequently very pretty...

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q)

And then, there&#39;s 70s-80s French experimental music, which is good at stoking a sense of terror and sometimes downright miserable to listen to (as also is Derbyshire)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0)

Not all the music I&#39;ve posted is good. A lot of it is discordant. But Space Funeral is pretty fun and if you know any other cool early synthesizer stuff that&#39;s good at creating an ambience, please shoot it over. Anyways, I am complete newb to this stuff and am not sure of how much interest it would be to anyone else. At very least, it you need to terrorize trick or treaters or your significant other during Halloween, some of these tracks will do a good job.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvmmbv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So I&#39;m still greatly enjoying Xenoblade Chronicles 3, but I had to take a week o</title><updated>2022-08-26T15:05:01Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><content type="text">So I&#39;m still greatly enjoying Xenoblade Chronicles 3, but I had to take a week off to travel.

The job system hasn&#39;t really opened up as much as I&#39;d hoped.  I&#39;m like, 40 hours into the game, and all my jobs are still capped at level 10.  I can clearly see they go up to level 20, I just have no idea when/how I uncap them.  Will it be story related, or a sidequest?  I guess I&#39;ll find out.  But that obnoxious cap turns the job system from something fun, to a chore where I&#39;m constantly rejiggering my party&#39;s jobs because someone hit their cap, and I don&#39;t want XP to goto waste.  I can&#39;t fucking wait for the cap to go away.

The story is **very** Xenoblade.  If you&#39;ve played one, you know what I mean.

The geography and world design at first seemed very bog standard.  It&#39;s gotten much more creative and alien as I&#39;ve gone along.  It&#39;s funny though, because Xenoblade 1 and 2 both started off with monologs about &#34;This game takes place on the back of a giant titan(s)&#34;.  Xenoblade 3 just throws you in, with no explanation about the construction or orientation of the world.  I think it&#39;s still taking place on a titan?  Maybe the corpses of the titans from the first two games?  I don&#39;t know.  It&#39;ll be interesting if they just never fucking tell you, but I think I&#39;d like at least a few more hints.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvmmbv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt</title><updated>2022-08-26T14:51:58Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><content type="text">They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt;!The arrow was fucking *bouncing* in the original.!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/iluqofd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Is there such a thing as a family with higher/lower genetic variance?

I was at </title><updated>2022-08-26T10:50:02Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><content type="text">Is there such a thing as a family with higher/lower genetic variance?

I was at a funeral, big Irish family, and all the men in the family seemed to be at extremes. Either 6&#39;3&#34; or taller and muscular, owned businesses or served in the marines; or on disability with some variety of genetic defect that prevented them from ever holding a job. It was a striking pattern, I meet one son who has had nine heart surgeries, the other son is on a scholarship and looks like the guy she tells you not to worry about. One daughter has muscular dystrophy, her sister is a judge.

I&#39;m thinking of other examples in my life. Twins on my little league team, one batted third and one batted ninth. Law school classmates in the top-5 of our class, who had siblings in nursing homes.

Is there any logic to this or am I just seeing random statistical noise? Any studies or theories?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/iluqofd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilu3sxx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Why does conciousness matter anyway? It seems terribly inefficient for something</title><updated>2022-08-26T05:49:15Z</updated><author><name>LeftNebula1226</name></author><content type="text">Why does conciousness matter anyway? It seems terribly inefficient for something that we have so much trouble understanding, without any real benefits. Couldn&#39;t we reason and all that good stuff without this crummy &#34;what is it like to be a human?&#34; nonsense attached to it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilu3sxx/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>