<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Friday Fun - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-13T01:46:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2r0a7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Spent my day install a cell booster on my house.  Ever since a big storm rolled </title><updated>2022-08-13T01:46:32Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><content type="text">Spent my day install a cell booster on my house.  Ever since a big storm rolled through knocking everything over, and leading to some debate about whether we experienced a downburst or a tornado, my Verizon signal has been in the toilet.  So, $400 later, and some rather nervous work on a ladder, we now have a serviceable signal again.  It was a constant thorn in our side since moving out to the country, so hopefully that problem is fully well fixed now.

Been seriously binging Xenoblade Chronicles 3 more.  I got seriously side tracked by optional quests, and am now overleveled for the core story in front of me by about 10 levels.  The job system is **ok** so far.  I think what&#39;s hampering my enjoyment is the temporary cap of 10 levels per job I&#39;m currently laboring under.  So my characters max out their jobs rather quickly, and I find myself rotating them to new ones, not because I want to, but because I feel like I have to in order to min max.  And I&#39;m constantly running short of jobs I actually want to switch them into.  I&#39;m looking forward to the cap coming off.

Hit my first tantalizing and obvious reference to previous Xenoblade games, hinting at the world this is taking place in.  The trailer had hinted at things, and I&#39;m curious to see if the hints come to fruition.  But I think the Xenoblade &#34;timeline&#34; is a lot like the Zelda &#34;timeline&#34;.  Mostly bullshit theory crafting around thoughtlessly included references that give the games a unified feel, but aren&#39;t meant for serious theorizing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2r0a7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2c9wm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I think I have a leucistic duck on my pond. He is very cute and sticks out. I be</title><updated>2022-08-12T23:54:06Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">I think I have a leucistic duck on my pond. He is very cute and sticks out. I believe his probability is &amp;lt;1 in 3000. As someone who sees waterfowl every day this is a fortuitous development. I have been trying to keep him around with food and praise.

https://imgur.io/0zkaZIg</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2c9wm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik0elg5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I&#39;m replaying Mass Effect now that the remake/master/mass is out. Spoilers below</title><updated>2022-08-12T16:09:50Z</updated><author><name>cafemachiavelli</name></author><content type="text">I&#39;m replaying Mass Effect now that the remake/master/mass is out. Spoilers below. A recent thread on askreddit had people complain about the ending and since my reply inevitably got buried, I thought I&#39;d repost and expand on it here. 

I have a separate thought about the series&#39; politics but I&#39;m posting that as a reply.

The prompt:

    despite the lackluster ending

Ughhh the ending annoyed me so much.

Pretty much from the beginning I had my nerd guess for what was gonna happen:

It turns out that using element zero (which causes the &#34;mass effect&#34;) increases entropy massively. After all, all that energy has to come from somewhere. Use it too much and the universe runs out or [insert doomsday scenario]. So the leviathans build the reapers to find a way to fix or contain it, then the reapers go a little overboard and murder everyone before &#34;seeding&#34; new civilizations to gather data on the mass effect. Things are going pretty well apart from the everyone getting murdered at the end of the experiment cycle part.

I like that I could see an indoctrination ending as the &#34;good&#34; ending here - if you have to choose between trillions dying and the universe ending, maybe the former is the better option? But of course, who knows if the reapers will even find a solution, if the other civs can&#39;t do it on their own w/o regular genocide, etc. There&#39;s room for disagreement, which I think is a necessary component of a good RPG ending. 

The actual ending feels dumb even by soft sci-fi standards. It&#39;s almost literally [they&#39;re made of meat](https://www.mit.edu/people/dpolicar/writing/prose/text/thinkingMeat.html). Apparently &#34;organics&#34; and &#34;synthetics&#34; just never get along. Never mind that synthetic is just a short-hand for semiconductor technology since that&#39;s the level where our civilization is at, and never mind that we&#39;d totally make self-repairing computers out of wet hydrocarbons if we could. Also disregard the fact that organic/synthetic just describes what is essentially a manufacturing process and should have little impact on ones feelings / value functions beyond naive looks-like-me ingroup bias (and why would you put that in synthetic life anyway?). The entire universal conflict is sibling rivalry with some AI risk thrown in.

I grant that this can be read as an AI risk device - the Leviathans, demi-gods from Ye Olden Times, notice that whenever their thralls build synthetic life, the latter rebels against the former. This tends to result in genocide. Replace &#34;life&#34; with &#34;generally intelligent agent&#34; and it&#39;s not a strange prediction. It would be kind of a stretch to have the leviathans a) be smart enough to meaningfully resist the AIs of their thralls and b) decide that building their own AI in the form of the reapers is a great idea, especially since that plan backfires as much as it possibly could. But who knows, maybe all the smart leviathans are working on thrall containment policy and reapers are a big political mess.

It still makes the ending fall kinda flat, imo. The choices of &#34;destroy, control, do nothing&#34; lack meaning if all you&#39;re deciding on is how to deal with a malaligned AI. 

IIRC some other game had the entropy plot as its big reveal, so maybe ME didn&#39;t want to seem too unoriginal, but I think it&#39;s still one of the better choices: It&#39;s narratively cheap since much of ME&#39;s plot still makes sense in retrospect. Geth calculate utility and conclude that the reapers are correct. Organic life doesn&#39;t and is also highly interested in staying alive, so the only way to align them is direct mind control. In the anti-Reaper ending you decide that humanity can fix the Mass Effect on your own (Renegade) or with the help of the rest of the universe (Paragon). In the pro-Reaper ending you either zip humanity into a new Reaper or die honorably and let them deal with the problem. I can totally see myself playing both and that rarely happens for me with &#34;good/evil&#34; playthroughs.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik0elg5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik01wij/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Has anyone obtained value from the ikigai / kanban / self-authoring / etc progra</title><updated>2022-08-12T14:48:29Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">Has anyone obtained value from the ikigai / kanban / self-authoring / etc programs? My interest is piqued after reading that Shohei Ohtani used one of these programs (Harada Method).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik01wij/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijzpibv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">(u/ZorbaTHut) Is there a reason we usually don&#39;t see more complicated save syste</title><updated>2022-08-12T13:21:47Z</updated><author><name>thrownaway24e89172</name></author><content type="text">(u/ZorbaTHut) Is there a reason we usually don&#39;t see more complicated save systems in games than simple named checkpoints?  In particular, why does there seem to be little to no interest in systems that make branching easier?  Yes, interested users can roll their own outside the game (eg, using a version control system to manage a game&#39;s save files), but doing that outside of the game itself limits its effectiveness in a lot of ways.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijzpibv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijzbiz3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Has anybody seen the new Sandman series on Netflix and got opinions? I&#39;m quite f</title><updated>2022-08-12T11:18:18Z</updated><author><name>hateradio</name></author><content type="text">Has anybody seen the new Sandman series on Netflix and got opinions? I&#39;m quite fond of the grapic-novel, but I&#39;ve heard that the series-adaptation is supposed to be annoying in its waging of the culture war.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijzbiz3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijz922p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Last week, the Tim Dillon Show  [had a very special guest](https://www.youtube.c</title><updated>2022-08-12T10:50:59Z</updated><author><name>NormanImmanuel</name></author><content type="text">Last week, the Tim Dillon Show  [had a very special guest](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jpvUMaH17o).

As far as comedic value it&#39;s quite possibly one the worst episodes ever, but it&#39;s interesting as basically an introduction to Yarvin&#39;s ideas in a more palatable context than densely referenced blog posts.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ijz922p/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>