<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Friday Fun - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m se</title><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m searching for mellow upbeat music and anything with lyrics is about sex and crushes. It doesn’t *have* to be this way; I used to listen to post-rock and it was not very sexed. Hymns are rarely sexy. But I like the indie genre, I just get tired of music about girls.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10</title><updated>2022-09-03T00:33:43Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><content type="text">So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10MHz_832K_XTIDE_MultiIO_SVGA/p6083514_19777986.aspx).  It hasn&#39;t shipped yet.  But I like to be able to code on every piece of hardware I own.  So I began noodling around, trying to set up a cross coding environment today.

I started with Visual Studio Code since it&#39;s crazy flexible.  Then I set up a bunch of task to compile my ASM files using NASM, using the CPU 8086 directive and outputting as OBJ files which need to be linked.  I&#39;m under the impression 16-bit code is the default with this arrangement.  I found a free linker called ALINK which then links the OBJ files into an EXE.  Then I set up, in kind of a janky way, for the Run command to launch DOSBOX and execute it&#39;s debug command on my exe.

I still want to find a way to export my breakpoints from Visual Studio Code and import them into DOSBOX.  I see that this debug version of DOSBOX I have can import breakpoints, and NASM spits out dbg files which I **think** I can parse for the segment:offset&#39;s I&#39;ll need to breakpoint at labels in DOSBOX.  I just am not sure off the top of my head how to export the breakpoint lines from Visual Studio Code.  Oh well, some day.

Anyways, it was a fun day.  Threw together a pretty simple number guessing game program.  It&#39;s a good way to get a grip on the basics.  Reading the keyboard, processing input, converting an ascii number to binary, generating a random number, some basic math, printing to the screen.  Then cause why not, I started fucking around with linking multiple ASM files, with GLOBAL and EXTERN&#39;d functions.  Did some far calls across memory segments.  Wasn&#39;t as bad as I thought it would be.

Probably start fucking around with EGA graphics and ADLIB sound next.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated im</title><updated>2022-09-02T22:51:29Z</updated><author><name>prrk3</name></author><content type="text">Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated imagery? There are striking resemblances between commonly reported phenomena reported by lucid dreamers and people with above average dream recall and generated images.

The most interesting phenomenon to me is that counting and reading in dreams is impossible. Lucid dreamers use this by counting their fingers or looking at clock as their “reality check” to tell if they are dreaming or not. It seems odd to me that humans can just forget the number of fingers they have. AI generated images have a similar problem with not caring much about discrete units.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an </title><updated>2022-09-02T21:17:17Z</updated><author><name>stolen_brawnze</name></author><content type="text">A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an AI text-to-image generator to a state art competition and [taking home first prize.](https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/1/23332684/ai-generated-artwork-wins-state-fair-competition-colorado)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For </title><updated>2022-09-02T17:57:26Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><content type="text">Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For all our optimization/nootropics bros, what&#39;s the best way to adjust my early-bird sleep schedule to go out partying on one night or two and then go right back to my standard sleep schedule?

I&#39;m an early bird, I basically go to sleep by 10:30 at the latest and get up between 4:30 and 5:00 every day. Getting up early is important to me, I like it, I function well that way from years of farm work and crew practice growing up. But as I&#39;m getting into middle age, I find it is getting hard for me to deal with days when I&#39;m at a wedding or a party or a gala or whatever and I want to stay up later and find my body failing me. I&#39;m curious if there&#39;s any scientifically supported evidence for how to handle it beyond pounding a 5 hour energy a couple times in a night.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</title><updated>2022-09-02T15:58:31Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><content type="text">What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wi</title><updated>2022-09-02T14:14:20Z</updated><author><name>07mk</name></author><content type="text">Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terrence_Howard#Terryology), a form of &#34;math&#34; developed by Terrence Howard, the actor who played James Rhodes in the first *Iron Man* film before he was replaced by Don Cheadle in later films. It seems that he had an issue with the proposition that &#34;1 x 1 = 1&#34; and thus sought to disprove it; here&#39;s a quotation from an argument he claimed he had with a professor:

&amp;gt; How can it equal one? If one times one equals one that means that two is of no value because one times itself has no effect. One times one equals two because the square root of four is two, so what&#39;s the square root of two? Should be one, but we&#39;re told it&#39;s two, and that cannot be.

Apparently he had such a problem with the regular math being taught there that he dropped out of college. I don&#39;t know how much work into Terryology he&#39;s done, but he&#39;s talked about spending time constructing (physical plastic) models to prove his new &#34;math&#34; and once [Tweeted a &#34;proof&#34; of why one times one cannot equal one](https://twitter.com/terrencehoward/status/925754491881877507) in an apparent bid to appease his critics. It&#39;s only 4 pages long, but I&#39;ll admit I could only put in the effort to skim it because of how poor the quality of writing was. But to me it seems that he just lacks a fundamental ability to grasp what addition and multiplication are and ends up confusing the 2 with each other. I was reminded of a podcast I listened to many years ago wherein a physicist being interviewed mentioned how his office gets mail all the time from people claiming to have found some huge breakthrough that would revolutionize the field, and when he happened to read one of them, it showed that the writer had no understanding of momentum and velocity and kept confusing the 2.

Also, [apparently Terrence has discovered some new form of physics](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-44pljnxztg) involving hydrogen bonds that will enable a new way of flying. I don&#39;t know if this is directly related to Terryology or if it&#39;s a completely independent thing he came up with.

I don&#39;t know much about Terrence outside him being an actor, but clearly he&#39;s an extremely successful one. Say what you will about him losing out on the MCU gravy train, but being a major character in even 1 major Hollywood production like *Iron Man* is a level of success that the vast majority of actors can ever dream about. It&#39;s just fascinating to me that someone with this poor an understanding of math, to the extent that addition and multiplication are beyond his grasp, has been able to be not just this functional, but this successful in modern society. Then again, acting isn&#39;t a particularly math-heavy profession, and it&#39;s possible that he hires professionals to handle his finances. It&#39;s just, if he thinks what those professionals are doing is all false made-up bullshit, how does he trust them at all to do what&#39;s right for him?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/</title><updated>2022-09-02T13:47:43Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><content type="text">[Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/cereal_boxes.html). One of my online acquaintances is good at wrangling AI art generators to get surreal stuff. Here&#39;s the rest of [his DALLE-2 gallery](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/index.html) in addition to [Midjourney](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/midjourney/index.html) and [DALLE-Mini](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e_mini/index.html) generated stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/s</title><updated>2022-09-02T12:15:55Z</updated><author><name>Indi008</name></author><content type="text">Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/spliced

and some short stories:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/58017/the-dumping-ground

AND some poetry:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57952/nothing-here-but-hot-air

Free to read, and somewhat unrelated to this sub, but hey it fits the fun theme, and I&#39;m somewhat trying to write rational fantasy if there is such a thing. Not sure I quite achieved that.

Anyone else here a &#34;writer&#34; who studied science or engineering with the intent of writing technically accurate fiction only to find it&#39;s much harder than you think? I never know quite enough, and when I do, no one thinks it&#39;s a real thing. I once wrote a story about a mechanic and an actual issue I faced with my car and people thought it wasn&#39;t realistic, but my complete fantasy stories are apparently completely believable.

Edit: got a joke for y&#39;all...

Why did the cat fall off the roof?



.
.
.
.



Because it lost it&#39;s mu</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Satur</title><updated>2022-09-02T08:45:10Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><content type="text">I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Saturday nights, when the next SQS sticky is just around the corner, so I never post them, saving them for the next FF sticky. Now it&#39;s Friday morning, and my head is devoid of ideas beyond going shopping for a pull-up bar and discount male fashion.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>