<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Small-Scale Question - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-07T00:52:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if5bnke/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Why are there nearly no Revolutionary War films?

I was looking for something to</title><updated>2022-07-07T00:52:26Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><content type="text">Why are there nearly no Revolutionary War films?

I was looking for something to watch on the 4th and it seems the only (at least only big) film is The Patriot. There&#39;s also 1776 and Hamilton, but the focus isn&#39;t on the war, and then also John Adams and Turn though they&#39;re TV shows.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if5bnke/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if355gc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">What do normal Republicans and moderates actually make of 1/6? Do they see it as</title><updated>2022-07-06T15:44:49Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><content type="text">What do normal Republicans and moderates actually make of 1/6? Do they see it as a riot, or as an attempted coup? Do they believe Trump deliberately instigated it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if355gc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iexr7y5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">There was a post here some time ago about the ever-increasing health catastrophe</title><updated>2022-07-05T13:00:20Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><content type="text">There was a post here some time ago about the ever-increasing health catastrophe that awaits a culture which only produces 1-3 births. The argument was that there are too many immune and genetic problems being introduced into the population, since all births have a higher chance of living into teenage years, whereas historically about half died in childhood. The children that died historically were the most ill. Then you have fewer generally dying from disease. Then there are not enough maximally healthy people producing children, whereas in the past they might produce a dozen.

This was very persuasive to me, but I don’t know any data. It seems reasonable that to maximize genetic health you want (1) the least healthy not producing and (2) the most healthy producing exponentially. We see with all animal. I’ve been seeing it occur outside my window, as a single house wren family has birthed four babies each of the past four seasons. Of their 16 kids, surely not all are expected to continue living, and probably only a few would continue exponential birthing. 

Anyway does anyone have any relevant information to this question?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iexr7y5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ietsysm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Is there a compilation of all the discussions on this sub on urbanism and cars? </title><updated>2022-07-04T15:25:03Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><content type="text">Is there a compilation of all the discussions on this sub on urbanism and cars? Or just some links for me to read through. 

I want to start off with this subs pov because it seems to be a somewhat one-sided politically charged topic and there are a lot of sneaky politics on what should be otherwise objective discussions on the pros and cons of different types of design.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ietsysm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iesmh8u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Appropriate for the date:

Does anyone have any idea how my parents (in their ea</title><updated>2022-07-04T07:58:44Z</updated><author><name>Capital_Room</name></author><content type="text">Appropriate for the date:

Does anyone have any idea how my parents (in their early 60s), and some others their age, came by their belief that the American Revolution was fought — and won — entirely or almost entirely by independent, disorganized individuals armed only with their hunting rifles, slipping through the woods in primitive camouflage, picking off the British who &#34;were sitting ducks, standing in the open in neat lines wearing their bright red coats, like morons,&#34; and said British doing nothing but impotently protesting &#34;that&#39;s just not cricket!&#34; as these lone Patriots violated all the contemporary &#34;rules&#34; of war — &#34;were terrorists,&#34; as my Mom put it? In short, that the Revolution was fought and won through lone-wolf terrorism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iesmh8u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq8zqf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">(Not really a question.) I think as I’ve gotten older, I’ve realized that the pr</title><updated>2022-07-03T18:54:31Z</updated><author><name>2cimarafa</name></author><content type="text">(Not really a question.) I think as I’ve gotten older, I’ve realized that the primary reason (at least intellectually, I make no claim to deeper analysis of my subconscious motives) for my continued general agnosticism is that the concept of an afterlife (or really reincarnation or eternal life in any form) just seems too good to be true, and tailor made to what seems like a fundamental human desire for permanence in a world in which none exists. 

This is a relative of, although not quite identical to, the old le atheism “why should your god *specifically* be the one” line of questioning, but it isn’t really meant as a gotcha. Only that it should seem awfully convenient, terrified of death that we are, that life (in some form) goes on. I am quite confident that higher powers than ourselves exist in our universe. They may even care what happens here, though I’m less certain of that. But that they should be so attuned to taking care of our greatest fear would appear to be a stroke of luck too far.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq8zqf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq4k4r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m rereading Gibson&#39;s *Neuromancer*. It has been a w</title><updated>2022-07-03T18:22:07Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m rereading Gibson&#39;s *Neuromancer*. It has been a while, but Armitage still haunts my imagination every now and then. Gibson&#39;s obsession with the materials things are made of can make it an odd and slow read, but it is one of the best.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq4k4r/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iepzcui/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Bought a new evaporator fan motor for my fridge because the old one was noisy. F</title><updated>2022-07-03T17:44:25Z</updated><author><name>ShouldHaveVotedGore</name></author><content type="text">Bought a new evaporator fan motor for my fridge because the old one was noisy. Fixed the problem but I&#39;m slightly concerned that the old one had a third wire that connected to the metal housing, while the new one lacks this wire. Is this any sort of hazard?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iepzcui/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoyoma/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Looking for history book recommendations. I&#39;m trying to read more real books and</title><updated>2022-07-03T13:11:14Z</updated><author><name>dalinks</name></author><content type="text">Looking for history book recommendations. I&#39;m trying to read more real books and history is always fun. I&#39;m open to any really good books, but I&#39;d specifically like

* Rome (Been rewatching Rome on HBO Max)
* Indian history, esp Partition. Thats a big blank spot on my history knowledge
* Economic history is fun. I always enjoy hearing about the behind the scenes factors that led to our modern world.

I usually prefer larger scope to smaller, though there have been notable exceptions. Not usually into biographies but willing to give them a shot.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoyoma/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoufhi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Would you prefer to die after being completely bedridden for 20 years or being c</title><updated>2022-07-03T12:28:27Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><content type="text">Would you prefer to die after being completely bedridden for 20 years or being completely demented for 20 years? Assume no other options, including suicide, are possible. Does the answer change if the question is about your parents?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoufhi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and ma</title><updated>2022-07-03T12:03:27Z</updated><author><name>mustardEconomics</name></author><content type="text">TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and marry someone?

---

For most of my adult life, I wasn&#39;t really interested in romance, relationships, or women in general. This has recently changed. I&#39;ve grown increasingly interested about the idea of falling in love and marrying someone. There are a number of reasons for this. Lately, more and more frequently I&#39;ve been feeling unhappy about being alone and lacking connections, and I like the idea of someone genuinely feeling attracted to me. I sometimes feel like my current life is pointless overall; creating a family and fathering children feels like a good way of making myself feel that I&#39;ve amounted to something. And, to be honest, I want to actually share my sexuality with another living person. 

On the other hand... I&#39;m pretty introverted. Social interaction exhausts me quickly. There are days where, after having to endure others&#39; company for many hours, I just want to spend an entire evening without hearing another person&#39;s voice. Now, I&#39;m not *bad* at social interaction: When I need to, I&#39;m good at talking with people, acting smooth, suave, and confident. But it tires me out fast. And, to me, it always feels like I&#39;m putting on an act, pretending to be someone I&#39;m not. 

This makes me worry if marriage is really a good idea for me. Social interactions wears me out, but if I got married, I suppose I&#39;d need to socially interact with my wife (and later children) all the time. Getting to be alone would become the exception rather than a daily occurrence. It might make me miserable rather than happy. 
Also, while I&#39;m confident that I can get a woman interested in me by charming and intelligent conversation, I&#39;m scared of accidentally deceiving her. She might get the false idea that I&#39;m *always* a smooth-talking charmer, and will be disappointed to find out I&#39;m an introvert who doesn&#39;t really like talking much. 

So my question is, are these desires compatible? Should I aim for marriage if I find social interaction to be tiresome work? Perhaps some of you have experience with being married (or otherwise in a permanent relationship) while introverted?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieo612g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Took a flight yesterday.  I feel like you have to be almost 40 now to remember t</title><updated>2022-07-03T06:54:57Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><content type="text">Took a flight yesterday.  I feel like you have to be almost 40 now to remember this; but remember inflight meals?

Serving meals on flights makes absolutely no sense, but at the same time I kind of miss it.  It had to be expensive to serve meals on flights because it’s literally added weight and taking up expensive space.  No one on the ground would pay the price I think it costs.  My guess is $20-30 a meal.  They are sort of like MRE for the military.  Very specific portion sizes.  Supposedly the portion size that a person is suppose to eat; which is smaller than what eat but then you had more courses than I eat.

From nostalgia perspective the food was different than what you would buy on the ground.  It was optimized to taste ok in the air.

The economics of why we got rid of that are obvious.  No one is willing to pay $30 for an in flight meal that’s terrible compared to ground food.

And yes I know you can still fly first and get that, but it use to be any 3 hr flight.  And now we have an entire generation that has never experienced bad but interesting in flight meals.

And how I know it’s bad economics for in flight meals - would anyone pay $35 a person if I opened a restaurant with airline food?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieo612g/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>