<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T00:10:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqd24j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Possibly the Last? Ban Report**

As ZorbaTHut [has posted](https://www.reddit.</title><updated>2022-09-02T00:10:30Z</updated><author><name>Amadanb</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Possibly the Last? Ban Report**

As ZorbaTHut [has posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilj878k/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3), D-Day approaches. The move is a matter of when, not if. I don&#39;t think the exact date for pulling the switch has been set, but it&#39;s possible this will be the last ban report here. (Whether I&#39;ll continue doing these on the new site... eh. We&#39;ll see. Depends on how the mod tools work, how much modding there is to do, how active I am after the changeover, etc.)

Incidentally, there have been 3 AEO actions since the last report. One was someone talking about the dreaded triple parentheses and the admins failing to comprehend the use-mention distinction. One was someone using the newly-verboten g-word. And one was someone making a pretty bad comment about trans women which had already been modded before the admins came by and nuked it.

**The Bans**

/u/DreadnoughtOverdrive - [1 day](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtpaql/comment/ilsnek6/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/dragonslion - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilskynx/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/bgaesop - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilkpsob/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/naraburns

/u/SlightlyLessHairyApe - [3 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/comment/il95nmf/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3link) - /u/ZorbaTHut

/u/darwin2500 - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/comment/iezy5fl/) - /u/naraburns

/u/Kerguidou - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ik2flgc/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/dblackdrake - [5 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijrgzyr/) - /u/Amadanb

/u/jermleeds - [14 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijmwq2y/) - /u/naraburns

/u/JeanStealers - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijh5u1t/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/Wangushenpo - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/comment/ij27d4d/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/_Roark - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vauj5h/comment/iiwmn1u/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/RichardRogers - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/comment/iikma5q/) - /u/Amadanb

/u/erkelep - [30 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/comment/ihupq7l/) - /u/naraburns</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqd24j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an </title><updated>2022-09-01T21:19:24Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an economist from Harvard, that studies race, policing, and education.

He shares a lot of statistics that contradict popular narratives about the issues, but probably won’t surprise many frequenters of this sub.

For example,

He finds that when that POC (people of color, I think is the term he uses) are not killed by police more.

That black kids are doing worse in school and advocates closing bad schools. 

The pay gap isn’t really 33% or whatever, but it is closer to 9%, and there are concrete things that he can point to that cause the pay gap that aren’t discrimination (in one example it is a difference in overtime worked due to when shifts were scheduled). 

Basically, he is using data to analyze a lot of culture war adjacent topics and looking for actual reasons for discrepancies in outcomes rather than just pointing to discrimination because he really wants to improve the lives of people.

Sorry for the short initial post, but I like to watch.  I’m a free riding, lurker because posting takes so much energy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular</title><updated>2022-09-01T19:38:41Z</updated><author><name>lookingforthrowaway1</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular treatment course? 

A family member is currently experiencing an uncommon health issue on which there is limited research in the literature. I’ve found a few papers indicating that a certain treatment, although aggressive and not usually considered necessary, is 100% effective in preventing a fatal outcome. These are all peer-reviewed papers in respected academic journals written by well-credentialed researchers at reputable university medical schools. 

How can I bring this research up to my family member’s doctor without offending their ego or something? Can I bring a printout with these papers as a reference and summarizing their key points?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imp4pty/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Metaphors are useful illustrations for understanding. They are harmful for argum</title><updated>2022-09-01T19:11:30Z</updated><author><name>EngageInFisticuffs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Metaphors are useful illustrations for understanding. They are harmful for arguments.

I recently read a post that was about one subject, mentioned something else as a point of comparison, and resulted in a conversation that was dominated by the metaphorical comparison rather than the subject level issue.

The entire point of metaphors is comparison of two very different things that have certain similarities. In the case of contention, what those similarities are is also likely to come under contention. Many of the metaphors on here turn into argument over the technicalities of the metaphor rather than the object-level issue. 

That has a lot to do with the type of audience you get here, but it still illustrates that metaphors themselves can conceal as much as they reveal. Or even just emphasize and deemphasize certain aspects of the subject. While this is great for rhetoric, it does no favors for clarity of argument.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imp4pty/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/imow4dm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What&#39;s a fun/pithy way to describe the sort of behavior that I can only call &#34;Re</title><updated>2022-09-01T18:16:18Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What&#39;s a fun/pithy way to describe the sort of behavior that I can only call &#34;Reverse Monkey&#39;s Paw?&#34;

&#34;Asshole Genie&#34; or &#34;Monkey&#39;s Paw&#34; is where the wish-granting entity always tries to find a way to technically fulfill the request but leave the wisher worse-off somehow.  Like wishing for a million dollars just teleports a million dollars from the nearest bank vault.  A really, really asshole genie would also teleport all the radio trackers and ink packs. 

Reverse Monkey&#39;s Paw is where the requester&#39;s requests are so poorly-thought-out they really can&#39;t be fulfilled.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/imow4dm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imo2yki/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] /u/Ilforte any thoughts on Ravil Maganov‘s death? Seems... dubious... to me, but</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:09:54Z</updated><author><name>Lurking_Chronicler_2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">/u/Ilforte any thoughts on Ravil Maganov‘s death? Seems... dubious... to me, but I’ll admit I know little about Russian internal politics, and I was wondering if you might be more informed on the matter.

(Sorry if this isn’t the right place, but I don’t see any small-scale threads up at the moment).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imo2yki/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:08:17Z</updated><author><name>crowstep</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing.

My live-in girlfriend of one year recently told me that while she loves me, she isn&#39;t &#39;in love&#39; with me. Apparently these things are quite different for her.

Essentially, while she has loved all of her previous boyfriends, there was only one that she was &#39;in love&#39; with, who was from several years ago and not the one before me.

She told me it might take time for her to feel &#39;in love&#39;, but that if she doesn&#39;t feel it, she&#39;ll break up with me. Her parents had a nasty divorce so she&#39;s paranoid about settling down with someone who isn&#39;t her &#39;soulmate&#39;. (Not her exact words, but that was the gist of it).

Overall I feel pretty hurt by this. Saying we loved eachother seemed like a big deal to me, but apparently for her it didn&#39;t really count to the same degree. Now it feels like there&#39;s a timer on our relationship and if I don&#39;t meet some ineffable standard in her head by a certain point, it&#39;s over. I was also pretty stung by the idea that I (and apparently, all her other exes) don&#39;t measure up to the one that got away.

We spoke about it at the time of course, but the more I think about this, the more it bothers me. I&#39;m unsure whether to bring it up or just entrust my fate to the fickleness of female affection and hope that I eventually provoke more feelings in her than I am now. I can hardly guilt her into changing get feelings, so I&#39;m reluctant to bring it up at all. And if I&#39;m honest, I worry that even letting her know it bothered me would make her less attracted to me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the </title><updated>2022-09-01T06:00:20Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the difference between a woman/man born the wrong gender and an actual person born of that gender would you support it?

I think it would change my mind. I personally don&#39;t have a problem with the idea of people being transgender. My biggest problem with it is I think we don&#39;t have the technology to actually do what is being promised and the surgery/transitioning is cruel to vulnerable people. All you have to do is go on /b or /pol to see the results to see that this is not a settled scientific process. I know it sounds gross, but seeing the results of these surgeries just makes me sick to my stomach. And then you have the child side where kids who aren&#39;t even fully developed emotionally/physically getting life changing surgery that can&#39;t be reversed. This is what bothers me the most.

I truly think we will look back on this time the same as we do with lobotomies. It feels like we are doing experimental surgery on vulnerable people who would be better off staying their assigned gender. That&#39;s my argument against this current (what I consider) madness.

I feel that most people agree with me here. However, if transitioning was actually possible, would you change your mind? To me, it makes the debate over. If you can safely and effectively transition people, what is the downside?

Edit: On the 4chan part, I was being glib there. The point I was trying to make is that we only see bad results. With how aggressive the trans lobby is, if they were actually the same in how they looked, people would be saying look it&#39;s indistinguishable. That fact that we don&#39;t see this shows they know it looks unnatural and would be off-putting to most people if they actually saw the results. I’ve never seen a trans person pass irl. If they can’t make a person pass, there’s no way they can make a passing sex organ. The only people I&#39;ve seen pass (and only online) are people who didn&#39;t go through puberty as the opposite sex. But that would basically mean we&#39;d have to transition children, which I am pretty skeptical of.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart con</title><updated>2022-08-31T22:57:55Z</updated><author><name>ebrso</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart condition, but this was totally unexpected.  He was in his early 30s.  I had spoken to him on Sunday.  I only found out a few hours ago.  My parents are devastated.  I&#39;m not sure why I&#39;m posting this.  How do people go on after this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a m</title><updated>2022-08-31T21:21:25Z</updated><author><name>Vorpa-Glavo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a metaphysical naturalist understanding of modern biology, the answer has to be no. &#34;For&#34; implies a purpose, and purpose belongs to agents.

An airplane&#39;s wings are for flying - the intentions of engineers ensure that. But birds had no creator, no agent involved in their existence. We might be able to metaphorically talk about a bird being &#34;designed&#34; or &#34;built&#34; for flight, but it is only that: a metaphor.

If we want to limit our description to what can be described based on an physico-empirical view of reality, then a bird&#39;s wing&#39;s **make flight possible** or **allow them to fly**, but we can&#39;t speak about a bird&#39;s wings being &#34;for&#34; anything at all.

So too with the word &#34;need.&#34;

Does a seed &#34;need&#34; water and sunlight and nutrient rich soil? A metaphysical naturalist would say no. &#34;Need&#34; implies that there&#39;s some sort of goal, or right way for a seed to be, but the universe doesn&#39;t care if a seed dies or grows into a giant tree over many eons.

Humans trying to grow seeds might &#34;need&#34; water, and fertilizer and a location with the right amount of sun in order to fulfill that goal, but regarding the seed itself we can only make predictions about the outcomes of different conditions on the seed.

If the seed experiences Scenario A (X units of water delivered at intervals Y, Z units of soil of composition W, V hours of average daily sun exposure, etc.) then it will grow into a big tree, but if the seed experiences Scenario B (no water, no sun, no soil) it will stay a seed and die, with a thousand possible predictions branching off from these two.

So what do we make of &#34;sex&#34; from this standpoint?

I think the radical thing that this line of thinking implies is to stop thinking about &#34;man&#34; and &#34;woman&#34; as some sort of natural pairing.

Just as there are seeds, and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on the seed, so too there are animals and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on those animals.

If the gamete of animal A finds its way to the gamete of animal B, we might get a zygote, or we might get nothing at all depending on the particular animals involved and the particular gametes.

Things start to come down to categoricity and disciplined pattern formation.

Is a penis &#34;for&#34; a vagina? Is an ovum &#34;for&#34; a sperm? Do men and women have some sort of complimentary relationship?

It is almost certain that humans come pre-installed with social hardware that predisposes them to think of human males and human females as belonging to one type or category in some sense - the human. But if we pull back the curtains, we can see an equally valid way of slicing up reality: men and women are different but &#34;related&#34; things.

Men and women rely on each other to reproduce their own kind. Men can&#39;t make more of themselves without women, and women can&#39;t make more of themselves without men. But why think of them as part of one &#34;species&#34; or &#34;type&#34;? Sure, they share a lot of similarities, and can be contrasted against things like &#34;rabbits&#34; as a whole, even as one can draw parallels between &#34;human males&#34; and &#34;rabbit males.&#34;

I believe it was Bret Weinstein who said that if alien biologists came down to Earth, they would rediscover the concept of sex every day. I don&#39;t exactly take issue with this claim, but I do wonder if the aliens would have the encyclopedia entry &#34;Humans&#34;, or if there would be two encyclopedia entries &#34;[Human-Male]&#34; and &#34;[Human-Female].&#34;

There&#39;s one layer deeper to go here, though. Would the alien biologists even stop there? How would they deal with intersex individuals?

I think a certain form of so-called &#34;binary&#34; thinking is to talk about there being men and women, with intersex individuals being deviations from the norm that can still be forced into one of those two boxes, or filed away into a &#34;freak of nature&#34; box (though we would never call it that with modern social mores.)

But I think this &#34;binary&#34; thinking has exactly the same problem that &#34;needs&#34;- or &#34;for&#34;-based thinking produces: it engages in teleological thinking.

We could imagine that instead of having abstractions at the level of &#34;man&#34; and woman&#34; that the alien biologists have a unique compound word for everything that basically contains every bit of information about that thing known to the aliens.

At this level, maybe the alien biologists could notice patterns between two things, which for us would become categories, but for them remain unabstracted, ungeneralized observations about the entirety of existing things. Maybe these aliens don&#39;t even have the concept of &#34;distinct things&#34; but instead build up observations from correlations of raw sensory data that doesn&#39;t get processed by modules in their brain into &#34;objects&#34; and &#34;animals&#34; and &#34;things&#34;, but instead is dealt with as a Unity with sub-patterns within patterns that can be interacted with and about which predictions can be made.

I think our brain modules do a lot of work in making certain &#34;categories&#34; seem more plausible than others, that is the source of the shadow of teleology projected back out into the world. However, once we see past the shadow, it might genuinely become impossible to pick a point to stop cutting reality at the joints.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imknlnp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Cloudflare has put out a blog post in response to mounting pressure for them to </title><updated>2022-08-31T21:00:07Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Cloudflare has put out a blog post in response to mounting pressure for them to drop Kiwi Farms. Cloudflare had previously terminated services to The Daily Stormer and 8chan, but this time the company says it will take no action, and even suggest the previous deplatformings were a mistake.

Selected quotes:

&amp;gt;Some argue that we should terminate these services to content we find reprehensible so that others can launch attacks to knock it offline. That is the equivalent argument in the physical world that the fire department shouldn&#39;t respond to fires in the homes of people who do not possess sufficient moral character. Both in the physical world and online, that is a dangerous precedent, and one that is over the long term most likely to disproportionately harm vulnerable and marginalized communities.

&amp;gt;[...]

&amp;gt;Just as the telephone company doesn&#39;t terminate your line if you say awful, racist, bigoted things, we have concluded in consultation with politicians, policy makers, and experts that turning off security services because we think what you publish is despicable is the wrong policy. To be clear, just because we did it in a limited set of cases before doesn’t mean we were right when we did. Or that we will ever do it again.

&amp;gt;[...]

&amp;gt;We do, however, believe that in cases where our values are diametrically opposed to a paying customer that we should take further steps to not only not profit from the customer, but to use any proceeds to further our companies’ values and oppose theirs.

&amp;gt;For instance, when a site that opposed LGBTQ+ rights signed up for a paid version of DDoS mitigation service we worked with our Proudflare employee resource group to identify an organization that supported LGBTQ+ rights and donate 100 percent of the fees for our services to them. We don&#39;t and won&#39;t talk about these efforts publicly because we don&#39;t do them for marketing purposes; we do them because they are aligned with what we believe is morally correct.



https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflares-abuse-policies-and-approach/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imknlnp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-31T20:08:51Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis</title><updated>2022-08-31T19:05:00Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis in your hoods?

Finland is getting hit less than Central Europe, but getting hit nevertheless. We haven&#39;t been \*quite\* as dependent on Russian power than many other countries - Russian gas was only 5 % of the energy supply, Russians cut the flow already back in May, and in general Russian electricity imports have formed 10 % of the Finnish electricity use. However, prices are still expected to rise very high in the winter, naturally the season when the society most needs electricity and has to import it.

The crisis is particularly - as everywhere else - hitting those living in detached housing. Even though district heating and, lately, geothermal are increasingly popular for heating, and an increasing amoung of air-source heat pumps have been installed there&#39;s still a lot of them relying on direct electric heating, which on current terms translates to &#34;pay up the nose&#34;. Such houses might well see electricity bills hitting well over a thousand a month, unless nothing is done.

Among various issues:

\- Nordic electricity generation is reliant on water power, and though the Nordic countries haven&#39;t seen droughts on the Central European level, these are still affecting water power generation. Finland has imported electricity from Norway, and now the Norwegians are mulling restricting [electricity exports](https://www.helsinkitimes.fi/finland/finland-news/domestic/22095-lintilae-norway-restricting-electricity-exports-would-play-into-putin-s-hands.html).

\- There would still be a chance to avoid the worst of it - if the Olkiluoto 3 nuclear generator goes fully online before the schedule, or at least is not delayed any more. Olkiluoto 3 has been the white whale of nuclear projects for years now, incredibly delayed and costly project that is now in test use, with those tests also frequently facing unplanned downtimes. The current estimate for Olkiluoto 3 finally starting commercial use is December 2022, but we&#39;ll see. In particular having OL3 being online and without issues would lead to stability - less need to worry about whether winter&#39;s particularly cold and how windy/sunny it is for renewables.

\- While browsing Twitter, I&#39;ve seen a fair amount of what can only be described as &#39;schadenfreude&#39; by pro-Russian right-wingers in various countries mocking Europeans with high energy bills and Ukraine flags in the profile photo. There&#39;s next to none of that here, as the entire Finnish society continues to be broadly pro-Ukrainian. I haven&#39;t seen any major political actors suggesting trying to make nice with Russia as a solution, of course it would be hard to do that by our lonesome anyway as long as we&#39;re a part of the EU, and Russians might tell us to pound sand anyway.

\- The environmental aspect is, of course, a big local culture war, especially in a country where much (most?) of the culture war has been environmentalism-related for a long time. It&#39;s not an easy question, non-/anti-environmentalists say that of course when you do things to drive up the costs of polluting the prices of electricity (which cannot really be produced in any way without \*some\* pollution) environmentalists claim that without the environmental measures the situation would be worse, comparing us to Britain where the junking of &#34;green crap&#34; led to end to insulation efforts or to countries that are more dependent on fossil fuels than us.

\- There&#39;s a back-up power reserve including, among others, Finland&#39;s last electricity-generation-oriented coal plant (other coal plants mainly generate heat). It&#39;s pretty certain that if it comes to firing up the power reserve or rolling blackouts, the power reserve is going to be fired up - that&#39;s what reserves are for, after all - but there are calls to do this already at this point with the electric bills going up, and apparently there are difficulties related to this, such as the fact that the said coal plant would need some heavy maintenance to bring back up.

\- much of the price rise is caused by market issues, Finland being a part of the European electric grid and thus being affected by the comparatively larger issues of the other countries, the sheer uncertainty of the situation hiking up the futures, and so on. Of course, if nations like Norway restrict exports, there&#39;s just going to be a domino effect with it being easier and easier for other nations to do the same when necessity calls. It&#39;s hard to see these sorts of crises as anything less than further evidence in the breakdown of globalization, unless it alternatively finally becomes the crisis the European elites can use to enact the European federation.

The government is planning measures to alleviate the crisis. Currently, the news are reporting that they&#39;re considering a measure for a tax rebate on bills over 500€ / month and a cut on the electricity VAT, as well as some less defined measure to help the poorest families and some throw-ins like doubled child benefits etc.

To me, this seems counterproductive - like tailormade to help the most energy-consumptive housing and the least-well off, but leaving large urban middle classes living in flats or in less-consumptive detached housing with only the VAT benefit. If we want to actually avoid rolling blackouts, and unless there&#39;s some measures that will lead to a lot of new electricity fast, it would seem we&#39;d need to find some ways to reduce electricity use while ensuring that this won&#39;t break family budgets. That might mean models like guaranteeing a certain fixed price for electricity use under some ceiling and leaving market prices in force above that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk3g7h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] After failing to uncover evidence of what has been alleged as the greatest elect</title><updated>2022-08-31T18:54:29Z</updated><author><name>ymeskhout</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">After failing to uncover evidence of what has been alleged as the greatest electoral fraud in the history of the world, the back-up plan for some in that camp is to display a &#34;tough on election fraud&#34; approach. But in effect, it looks like they&#39;re taking out their frustrations on random nobodies. One of those guys was Hervis Rogers, who went viral during the 2020 election for waiting in line at a polling place for six hours and being the last person to vote. He eagerly spoke to and gave his name to a TV news crew that was on site, presumably proud to showcase to the public how committed he was to voting.

But, it turns out, [Rogers was a convicted felon](https://spectrumlocalnews.com/tx/south-texas-el-paso/politics/2021/07/14/the-arrest-of-hervis-rogers-brings-bail-reform-into-focus). Now 62 years old, he had been convicted of a burglary almost 3 decades prior, spent 9 years in prison, and was eventually released in 2004. But he remained on parole until June 2020, and Texas law makes it a felony for anyone to &#34;knowingly&#34; vote while still serving a parole sentence. The publicity of being broadcast as the face of the voting franchise is likely what prompted an investigation into his voting record. Although his voting rights were restored in time for the 2020 election, Rogers had somehow cast ballots on two separate occasions (in March 2020 and November 2018) while he was still on parole.

Texas&#39; Attorney General, Ken Paxton, [brought the hammer down on Rogers](https://www.texastribune.org/2021/07/11/texas-voter-arrested-parole/). Paxton had been one of the most enthusiastic boosters of Trump&#39;s stolen election theories, and he was responsible for filing the doomed [SCOTUS case](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texas_v._Pennsylvania) in this realm. Paxton [publicized Rogers&#39; case](https://twitter.com/kenpaxtontx/status/1413642254598688774?lang=en) as a way to flex how seriously he takes allegations of election fraud (Note: Paxton has [ongoing criminal legal issues](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Paxton#Legal_issues). He was indicted for securities fraud in 2015, and in 2020 several of his deputies had resigned in protest and accused him of bribery and corruption. It&#39;s likely that Paxton&#39;s enthusiasm in this area was leveraged for the purpose of seeking a presidential pardon). Rogers was arrested and held in jail on $100,000 bail. 

Pretrial bail is [nominally intended to encourage good behavior](https://ymeskhout.substack.com/p/the-poverty-trap-of-monetary-bail) from the accused while they wait for their trial. And with that in mind, it&#39;s impossible for me to appreciate how someone accused of illegally voting is somehow such a dramatic danger to the community to warrant $100k bail (especially since by the time he was arrested, Rogers&#39; voting rights had been restored for more than a year). Sky-high bail in this case appears to have been used as a way to impose punishment *now*, regardless of the presumption of innocence, and regardless of what ends up happening to his charges down the road.

Because the facts of Rogers&#39; situation meant that pretrial detention was very likely the only thing they ever would&#39;ve gotten out of his case. It&#39;s difficult to see how the prosecution could prove beyond a reasonable doubt that Rogers &#34;knew&#34; he was legally barred from voting. After all, he was able to cast ballots on two separate occasions with no issues, and he showed no hesitation about speaking to a camera crew.

The same thing is again playing out, but this time in Florida. Gov. Ron DeSantis has similarly jumped on the &#34;tough-on-fraud&#34; bandwagon and has endorsed several proposals, including advocating for a ballot signature match system [which likely would have disqualified his own voter registration](https://www.tampabay.com/news/florida-politics/2021/04/13/desantis-wants-voters-signatures-to-match-would-his-pass-the-test/). DeSantis recently held a press conference to announce that 20 people with felony convictions who voted in the 2020 election will be arrested and charged. This was showcased as the &#34;opening salvo&#34; for the newly minted &#34;Office of Election Crimes and Security&#34; that was created by DeSantis.

Before 2018, Florida had permanent felony disenfranchisement laws (one of only four states). The only way for a felon to regain their voting rights then was to petition the State Board of Executive Clemency. Gov. Charlie Crist had instituted a system of automatic restoration and approved 155,000 applications during his tenure. Gov. Rick Scott ended this system, and the number of approved applications plummeted to 3,000. Florida voters ended up overwhelmingly approving [Amendment 4 in 2018](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Florida_Amendment_4), which instituted automatic voting right restoration for felons &#34;after they complete all terms of their sentence&#34;. That specific clause became the subject of intense litigation, and the Legislature codified that &#34;all terms&#34; included paying all outstanding fines.

A persistent problem with this implementation is that nobody seems to have a good idea of when exactly &#34;complete all terms&#34; actually happens. State officials have [repeatedly admitted in court they have no good centralized system in place to make this determination](https://www.wlrn.org/news/2019-10-04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-floridas-amendment-4-lawsuit). Court records (many of which several decades old) are all over the place and poorly catalogued, with each local clerk&#39;s office using a different format. Sometimes fines are collected by multiple different government agencies, and there is no easy system in place to double-check the ledgers.

The 20 people whose arrests DeSantis touted so far appear to have been in the same situation: They were *[specifically told by election authorities that they could vote](https://www.politico.com/news/2022/08/26/desantis-voter-fraud-defendants-florida-00053788)*.

Given how messy Amendment 4&#39;s implementation has been, it&#39;s unclear how any normal person is expected to navigate to an answer on their own. Getting an assurance from the local election authority seems to be the best that anyone can expect. So if anyone should get into trouble, perhaps it&#39;s the local officials who messed up? That&#39;s the tack [some on the DeSantis camp](https://twitter.com/tarynfenske/status/1563261005303787521) are staking. Except... the director of the &#34;Office of Election Crimes and Security&#34;, who was appointed by DeSantis, [explicitly told local officials they were not at fault](https://www.politico.com/news/2022/08/29/despite-public-blame-desantis-election-investigation-chief-told-local-officials-they-face-no-fault-for-felon-voting-00054089). Local officials do not have access to all the relevant state-wide data, and [they instead rely on the state](https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2022/08/florida-voter-fraud-election-police-desantis-entrapment.html) via Division of Elections for this information.

To summarize, state officials in charge of tabulating incomplete felony sentences messed up and gave faulty information to local election officials. Those local officials approved the voting registration of people with felony convictions who by any measure appear to believe they were eligible to vote. Those people voted. Almost two years later, they get publicly arrested and dragged to jail for being dumb enough to believe someone from the government. Anyone want to defend this move?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk3g7h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar</title><updated>2022-08-31T17:35:44Z</updated><author><name>PM_ME_UR_OBSIDIAN</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar and task list. As of today I am using Google Calendar combined with Todoist.

Todoist caveats:

- No tracking of start date, only due date. Any task with a date configured is assumed to be a discrete amount of work to be done on the day that it is due, or shortly before.
- There is no concept of prioritization within a time window. I can&#39;t ask &#34;what is the most urgent task that I need to get done within two weeks?&#34; 
- If I have a daily recurring task and I mark it as done for yesterday, then the next occurence is tomorrow. There is no concept of catching up on overdue engagements.

The app is swell though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imjh3kz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I am kinda surprised that we haven&#39;t done the Duke/BYU volleyball yet.

A few da</title><updated>2022-08-31T16:31:29Z</updated><author><name>puntifex</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I am kinda surprised that we haven&#39;t done the Duke/BYU volleyball yet.

A few days ago, the Duke volleyball played a game at BYU.  The game was overshadowed by allegations of ugly racism when Duke&#39;s black starter, Rachel Richardson (I think there are several black women on the team, but only she is a starter) said that she heard someone racially abuse her throughout the match.  The player&#39;s ~~grandmother~~ godmother also took to twitter to say that the player was called the n-word &#34;every time she served&#34;.

This story hit the national papers with the predictable headlines - strong denunciation against racism, praise for Rachel as a strong person standing up to adversity, denunciation of coaches and officials, athleticndepartments, the crowd at the game, and all Mormons.

BYU&#39;s AD apologized profusely, and the school indefinitely banned a fan identified by Duke as the racist abuser. Rachel herself appeared on several national news stories, with the expected taking points and responses. 

A few days later, though, people stated asking questions.  Several students who were at the game came forward on the record to say that the racial slurs nevered happened.  Officials reviewed video of the crowd from the game, including when people claimed slurs were used - and AFAIK they&#39;ve found... nothing. 

There are other questions.  People started wondering why her teammates - whom one assumes both at least kinda like her (she certainly hasn&#39;t denounced any of her teammates as evil racists) , and, being 20 year old female athletes at an elite US institution are probably among the wokest people on the whole planet - haven&#39;t said anything,  as far as I&#39;ve seen?

Disclaimer - it&#39;s not like I&#39;ve done extensive research.  But I&#39;ve deen no articles writing anyone other than her or her family.   The Duke captain has an instagram that was updated two weeks ago - nothing.  All the quotes are from Richardson or her immediate family. 

And by the way - that ~~grandmother~~ godmother?  She happens to be a politician running for some office. 

I guess it would be hard for this story to be more unbelievable than the Duke lacrosse case (where the prosecutor was literally explicitly trying to frame some innocent kids of the right demographic, and was later disbarred),  and that was ~10 years ago, so I guess I shouldn&#39;t be surprised.

Edit - someone asked for links.  Disclaimer - I have a day job.  I am not claiming to be an expert or to have done extensive research as honestly, is not worth it.  But I am being honest in saying what I haven&#39;t seen.  If someone can post links that credibly contradict what I said (for examples, her teammates reacting strongly on the night of the event), I will gladly reconsider.  It&#39;s also hard to prove a negative,  and I&#39;m certainly not going to trawl through 30 college students&#39; instagrams.  All my links were from google or twitter, so nothing hard to find.

Duke volleyball captains instagrams are easily google-able, so I&#39;m not linking them.

The original face-value sucks are also very easy to find (abc, espn, usatoday, etc etc etc)

Here are some links calling the account into question

https://www.sltrib.com/sports/2022/08/30/fan-who-was-banned-by-byu-does/

I&#39;d *really* rather not link turtleboy sports given their culrure war angle but if nobody else is gonna cover it (and tweets are now deleted), whatcha gonna do?

https://tbdailynews.com/video-shows-that-duke-volleyball-player-and-her-politician-godmother-are-lying-about-being-called-n-word-during-byu-game/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imjh3kz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imj4q5z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] For those not following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine closely, Ukraine has been p</title><updated>2022-08-31T15:11:58Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">For those not following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine closely, Ukraine has been projecting a counter offensive in the Kherson region for two months, and they initiated it two days ago.

It is still very early and the Fog of War is thick, but I think we are about a week until we will have a good idea of how the counter offensive is (or was) going and that will tell us a lot about the future of the conflict.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imj4q5z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started list</title><updated>2022-08-31T14:25:19Z</updated><author><name>GeorgeMacDonald</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started listening to it and it is a great podcast! I don’t know too much about the science of health besides the very basics so this is pretty cool. 

What episodes do you all recommend? I listened to the skin care episode (forgot which one that was). The upshot was use sunscreen daily, vitamin A cream and interestingly enough vitamin C cream on your face. I have episodes 134 and 206 downloaded which are about preventing heart disease (I have some bad family history there) and exercise respectively. 

Specifically, I am interested in the exercise ones. I do crossfit type high intensity workouts three times per week which is 3 hours of exercise. I have a feeling that some more time with lower intensity exercise would be beneficial to me in addition to what I do but that’s just my intuition not a science based thing. 

Nutrition is also an interest of mine so episodes on that would be nice too. My basic knowledge is to eat less red meat, eat more vegetables inching one’s way into a vegetable based diet (which would be tough for me as I love carbs and meat and when I only eat veggies I get super hungry shortly thereafter). 

The Revolutions podcast by Mike Duncan was also recommended and is very good.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] What is the best French to English translation software?</title><updated>2022-08-31T10:27:23Z</updated><author><name>6tjk</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">What is the best French to English translation software?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imhhqa5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The DoJ has filed [their response](https://int.nyt.com/data/documenttools/doj-re</title><updated>2022-08-31T05:07:43Z</updated><author><name>huadpe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The DoJ has filed [their response](https://int.nyt.com/data/documenttools/doj-response-to-trump-request-for-special-master/1b30feb331082a68/full.pdf) to Trump&#39;s request to appoint a special master.  It is quite long, has a number of attachments, and gives us a lot more insight into the investigation so far.

My highlights:

1.  The filing includes a partially redacted photo of some of the documents seized during the search. *(Attachment F, last page of the pdf)*

 This photo will be the front page of basically every paper tomorrow, and was certainly a conscious choice to include as it looks extremely damning.  There are a bunch of documents with really blatant cover sheets and TOP SECRET // SCI printed in 36 point red font multiple times.

2.  The filing also gives us a copy of the subpoena that was issued on May 11 of this year, and the response provided on June 3. *(attachments C and E)*

 The subpoena demanded:

 &amp;gt;Any and all documents or writings in the custody or control of Donald J. Trump and/or the Office of
Donald J. Trump bearing classification markings, including but not limited to the following: Top Secret,
Secret , Confidential, Top Secret/ SI- G/NOFORN/ ORCON , Top Secret/ SI-G/NOFORN, Top Secret/HCS
O /NOFORN/ ORCON, Top Secret/ HCS- /NOFORN, Top Secret/HCS- P/NOFORN/ ORCON,
Secret/ HCS- P/NOFORN, Top Secret/ TK/ NOFORN/ ORCON, Top Secret/ TK/ NOFORN,
Secret NOFORN, Confidential/ NOFORN, TS , TS / SAP , TS / SI-G/NF/OC , TS / SI- G/ NF, TS/ HCS
O/ NF/ OC, TS/ HCS- O/NF, TS/ HCS- P/NF/ OC , TS / HCS-P/ NF, TS/ HCS- P/ SI- G, TS / HCS- P/ SI/ TK ,
TS/ TK/NF/ OC , TS/ TK/NF, S/ NF, S / FRD , S /NATO, S / SI, C , and C /NF

 The response said:

 &amp;gt;Based upon the information that has been provided to me ,I am authorized to certify , on
behalf of the Office of Donald J. Trump , the following :

 &amp;gt;a. A diligent search was conducted of the boxes that were moved from the White
House to Florida;

 &amp;gt;b. This search was conducted after receipt of the subpoena, in order to locate any
and all documents that are responsive to the subpoena;

 &amp;gt;c. Any and all responsive documents accompany this certification; and

 &amp;gt; d. No copy, written notation, or reproduction of any kind was retained as to any
responsive document.

 &amp;gt;I swear or affirm that the above statements are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

 The response to the subpoena was to produce a single envelope, double wrapped in tape, which contained 38 documents with different classification markings.

3.  DoJ says they found classified documents in Trump&#39;s office desk in the drawer which contained his passports, *(p. 12)* which was the reason his passports were seized.  The warrant told them to seize all contents of any containers that have classified information.

4. DoJ says multiple times *(p. 4 and 8)* that at no point prior to the execution of the search warrant execution did Trump claim he had declassified any of these documents despite numerous opportunities to do so.

5. DoJ hints at some specific evidence about documents being moved around Mar-A-Lago beyond what&#39;s known so far.  In particular they say *(p. 10)*:

 &amp;gt;Through further investigation, the FBI uncovered multiple sources of evidence
indicating that the response to the May 11 grand jury subpoena was incomplete and that
classified documents remained at the Premises, notwithstanding the sworn certification made
to the government on June 3. In particular, the government developed evidence that a search
limited to the Storage Room would not have uncovered all the classified documents at the
Premises. The government also developed evidence that government records were likely
concealed and removed from the Storage Room and that efforts were likely taken to obstruct
the government’s investigation. ... This included evidence indicating that boxes formerly in the Storage Room
were not returned prior to counsel’s review.

6. DoJ says they have finished their privilege review for attorney/client privilege already, and do not think executive privilege can possibly apply, and did not filter for it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imhhqa5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgofrm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Is &#34;Paperclipping&#34; a fringe idea?**

Lately, u/ilforte  has been banging the d</title><updated>2022-08-31T00:57:07Z</updated><author><name>gardenofjew</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Is &#34;Paperclipping&#34; a fringe idea?**

Lately, u/ilforte  has been banging the drum of [paraphrasing] &#34;worrying about alignment too much at the expense of a high-freedom future is terrible, Yud is deeply paranoid which colors everything else he writes about, etc.&#34; &#34;Here is some suggestive evidence that Ilforte is mistaken on AGI Doom being a fringe/LW-only/Yud!/etc. idea:

1. DeepMind&#39;s alignment team [engaging](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/qJgz2YapqpFEDTLKn/deepmind-alignment-team-opinions-on-agi-ruin-arguments) with Yud&#39;s List of Lethalities post. I don&#39;t detect much sneering, mostly specific disagreements with specific things.  

2. Sam Altman (OpenAI) re-tweeting that list of lethalities post (would link but short on time rn, easily found if you scroll back far enough)

3. Stability AI (of Stable Diffusion fame) is related to EleutherAI in some capacity. There&#39;s definitely a lot of personnel overlap. Emad (head of Stability AI, someone Ilforte has spoken very fondly of) has retweeted various LW posts ([1)](https://twitter.com/EMostaque/status/1563715319566409729) and has [retweeted this job ad](https://twitter.com/EMostaque/status/1512405527350943746) from Conjecture, the Alignment focused spin-off of EleutherAI, founded by Connor Leahy, seems to have alignment takes that are not far from Yud&#39;s, as you can tell if you either watch his interview on a [recent podcast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz4G9zrlAGs&amp;amp;ab_channel=TheInsideView) or simply read his feed. 

note: These are three differnet organizations, all with relatively diverse views on AI, especially Stability AI vs the others. 


**What is the point of this post?**

Ilforte is an extremely eloquent writer. He is probably the most talented (certainly the most compelling! though IMO his prose is often far from lucid...) prose writer currently active on /themotte. And yet he seems to have a completely evidence-free view on the possible danger of AGI, has a deeply suspicious view of Yud, who, for all of his many flaws, is so bad at hiding his own views that he spends all of his weirdness points debating PR-toxic topics like baby qualia-- (you can accuse Yud of a few things, but a talented dissassembler for the sake of other goals he definitely is not...)

Ilforte seems to have decided to direct all of his immense verbal talent to deriding pessimistic takes on AGI, and I think this bad. I think a redteaming of paranoid takes on AI is great, but Ilforte has often made his arguments mostly through suspicion of AI-suspicious people.

I think its time someone pointed at this argument directly and engaged with it. I&#39;m not that person, unfortunately, because I&#39;m drowning in work rn, but I&#39;m planting a flag here and hoping Ilforte and others can debate productively about ways that [suspicious of AGI] and [suspicious of those who are suspicious of AGI] can productively disagree and understand the world better.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgofrm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imgeml1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Reposting my question from the last thread to see if it just needed more visibil</title><updated>2022-08-30T23:43:29Z</updated><author><name>DrManhattan16</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Reposting my question from the last thread to see if it just needed more visibility.

So, I&#39;ve got a burning question about the whole &#34;Money corrupts politics?&#34; debate. It seems like whenever someone says it does, the response is to point to studies looking at whether it can change who the person in power. These studies point to the answer being no.

My question, then, is whether anyone has looked at this from the perspective of a politician?

1. Politicians want to have more votes and more money to run their campaigns. Having someone drop out of supporting you is something they should be sensitive to. Politicians may weigh their incentives and goals if two or more contradict, but I don&#39;t think any politician declares a level of support beyond which they will not allow any donations/support to change their policy goals.

2. Politicians may believe that campaign spending does affect the outcome of an election, so they act as if it does and strive to not lose large donators.

Now, these are just hypothesis, so I&#39;m looking to see if there are any studies testing them for validity.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imgeml1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgejsp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **There&#39;s Still a TJ Test, Actually**

The [Thomas Jefferson High School for Sci</title><updated>2022-08-30T23:42:55Z</updated><author><name>DinoInNameOnly</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**There&#39;s Still a TJ Test, Actually**

The [Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Jefferson_High_School_for_Science_and_Technology) is a magnet STEM-focused high school in Northern Virginia established in 1985. The school has special facilities meant to provide opportunities for students who show achievement and passion for STEM and who will eventually pursue careers in science, engineering, or medicine. It has courses in things like artificial intelligence, quantum mechanics, DNA science, and machine learning. It also has several labs where students can do research projects. It was [ranked](https://www.usnews.com/education/best-high-schools/virginia/districts/fairfax-county-public-schools/thomas-jefferson-high-school-for-science-and-technology-20461) as the best school in the country in 2022. 

Until recently, TJ admitted students through a competitive process similar to the college admissions process in which prior academic achievement, teacher recommendations, and an exam similar to the SAT played a major role. The school had a low proportion of black and Hispanic students who were admitted, and this was long a complaint of left-wing activists who advocate reforms to the admissions process so that more non-Asian minorities would be admitted. In particular, they blamed the admissions exam for eliminating most such students from consideration.

In 2020, those activists got their way. The school board voted to eliminate the admissions test in [October 2020](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/education/thomas-jefferson-high-admissions-change/2020/10/07/0a1f8faa-08a7-11eb-9be6-cf25fb429f1a_story.html) and later that year made other reforms to the admissions process, including setting minimum quotas for admission at the middle school level and adding &#34;experience factors&#34; to the process. The [class of students](https://www.fcps.edu/news/tjhsst-offers-admission-550-students-broadens-access-students-who-have-aptitude-stem) admitted the next year went from being 4.52% black and Hispanic to 18.36%. 

An advocacy group opposed to the 2020 changes [sued](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coalition_for_TJ_v._Fairfax_County_School_Board), alleging the changes discriminated against Asian Americans, whose share of admitted students decreased from 73.05% to 54.36%. The case is currently pending before the appeals court.

One thing I realized while I was researching this is that there actually still is a test that influences your probability of admission to TJ. One of the &#34;experience factors&#34; that increases a student&#39;s odds of being admitted in the [new admissions process](https://www.fcps.edu/registration/thomas-jefferson-high-school-science-and-technology-admissions/tjhsst-freshman) is whether they are an English Language Learner (ELL). An [ELL is a student](https://wida.wisc.edu/sites/default/files/resource/explaining-ell-status-english.pdf) who has extra support learning English in school. How do schools identify which students need extra support learning English?

Well, there&#39;s a test. Schools administer an English skills test and students who perform poorly on it are identified as ELL and offered extra instruction in special classes for ELLs. 

What this means for TJ is that a student&#39;s chance of being admitted to an elite school for the academically excellent is *increased* if they perform *poorly* enough on evaluations of their language skills.

The reason the school board added this consideration is obvious: The [large majority (78%)](https://www2.ed.gov/datastory/el-characteristics/index.html#four) of ELLs are Hispanic, so preferring ELLs in the admissions process is a way to increase the proportion of Hispanics admitted without needing to add race to the admissions process explicitly (which would be more easily challenged legally). Asians make up 11% of ELLs too, but it&#39;s notable that Hispanics outnumber Asians among ELLs by 7:1 but only by about 3:1 in the general population ([6.1% vs. 18.9%](https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/fact/table/US/PST045221)). A lot of Asian kids speak two languages but their parents made sure they were good enough with English that they don&#39;t need any special instruction.

This is just... so backwards. I don&#39;t think it would be fair to prefer students who speak more than one language in admission to TJ. But I could see an argument for it: Students who successfully learned a second language and succeeded enough to be equally or almost equally academically impressive as students who speak English natively have done something really impressive, now that they&#39;ve mastered the lingua franca, they&#39;ll probably shine even brighter. In fact, this describes a large proportion of the students admitted to TJ under the old process. But that&#39;s not what they&#39;re doing with this new process. They&#39;re specifically preferring the students who were *least* successful at learning the new language, the ones who struggled the *most* with it. 

On top of that, immigrant families who were responsible and ~~paid off their student loans~~ taught their kids English fluency and saved the taxpayer-funded school system the extra burden of dealing with kids who don&#39;t know English are punished, while the ones who depended on the government for that are rewarded.

Well, expect an increase in enrollment in ELL programs in Fairfax County of kids who seem to be speak pretty good English most of the time.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgejsp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imfp7ja/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Is data truth?**

Since I owed a reply to /u/Im_not_JB here: https://www.reddi</title><updated>2022-08-30T20:47:19Z</updated><author><name>Evinceo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Is data truth?**

Since I owed a reply to /u/Im_not_JB here: https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilvutba/

I&#39;m gonna try and figure out where we are with WikiLeaks.

Wikileaks has come from the perspective that information wants to be free, that leaks hold people accountable, and that releasing all available data is the best way to do so.

I think that this came from the same place of Aaron Schwartz, Jimbo Whales techno-utopian anti-state idealism that was in the air around the mid to late aughts. Compare the [Declaration Of Independence Of Cyberspace](https://www.eff.org/cyberspace-independence).

We now live in that world, where it&#39;s easy to disseminate vast dumps of data. It&#39;s available to anyone. But now that we have it, I wonder if it&#39;s really the best approach. Because what we end up getting is just data. It doesn&#39;t come with the tools to analyze it, and in the absence of analysts by competent folks, we get The Internet doing its own sleuthing. From misidentifying the Boston Bomber to pizzagate, I can think of examples of information overload harming rather than helping.

And that makes me lean back towards the journalistic approach of combining data with analysis and responsibility. I can think of plenty of hard hitting stories like the Panama papers that _did_ work out.

I think the profession of journalism won. I don&#39;t think it can or should be replaced by blindly dumping any data you can get your hands on and calling it journalism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imfp7ja/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/ime67pd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What problems do you think are AGI-complete?</title><updated>2022-08-30T14:54:05Z</updated><author><name>Primaprimaprima</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What problems do you think are AGI-complete?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/ime67pd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime3y6y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] News from an old corner of the culture war: Oberlin is [denied an appeal](https:</title><updated>2022-08-30T14:38:58Z</updated><author><name>roolb</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">News from an old corner of the culture war: Oberlin is [denied an appeal](https://legalinsurrection.com/2022/08/gibsons-bakery-wins-ohio-supreme-court-refuses-to-hear-oberlin-college-appeal/) to the Ohio Supreme Court in its loss to Gibson&#39;s Bakery. This is the end of the appellate road in the state, but I don&#39;t know if federal court is an option.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime3y6y/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime085j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **More on Student Loan Relief**

This week, the New York Times published [Why St</title><updated>2022-08-30T14:13:23Z</updated><author><name>deadpantroglodytes</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**More on Student Loan Relief**

This week, the New York Times published [Why Student Debt Relief Isn’t Elitist](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/29/opinion/student-debt-relief.html) by Paul Krugman and [Why I Changed My Mind on Student Debt Forgiveness](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/30/opinion/student-loan-debt-relief-biden.html) (by Susan Dynarski, a Harvard economist). Krugman&#39;s mostly calling out Republican hypocrisy in one form or another (fine as far as it goes), but the substantive part follows:

&amp;gt;The Biden administration says that its plan will provide relief to as many as 43 million Americans. That’s a lot of people, not a small, cosseted elite.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;even if you subscribe to the Trump diner theory of politics — according to which the only voters who matter are blue-collar guys wearing baseball caps — you should be aware that some of those guys probably took out loans to attend trade schools or community colleges, all too often getting nothing but debt in return. Even among those who didn’t take out student loans, many probably have children, siblings, cousins or friends who did. So the Biden plan will touch many people.

Dynarski&#39;s article focuses on the borrowers hardest hit.

&amp;gt;Defaults and financial distress are concentrated among the millions of students who drop out without a degree. The financial prospects for college dropouts are poor; they earn little more than do workers with no college education ...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;And dropout is not at all rare. A bit less than half of college students don’t earn a bachelor’s degree. Some people earn a shorter, two-year associate degree. But more than a quarter of those who start college hoping to earn a degree drop out with no credential.

If we take those articles at face value \[0\], we&#39;re talking about a program that provides relief to about 13 million Americans that fit a very sympathetic profile and badly need it - and a bonanza for another 30 million people, most of whom do not need that relief. \[1\]

**Would Anyone Support Country Club Loan Relief?**

Let&#39;s pretend for a moment that a Republican administration instituted a program subsidizing country club membership. After all, a lot of businesses are built and supported by the informal networks around country clubs, plus people that belong to country clubs tend to be successful.

So picture that: 60-70% of the borrowers do pretty well for themselves. Their businesses improve and they get richer. However, a substantial minority of the loan recipients don&#39;t have access to high-quality country clubs with their impressive facilities and wealthy cohorts. 30-40% take out loans to join municipal clubs or some strange off-brand variation called into being by the amount of money pumped into the system. The people do not flourish, their businesses do not succeed.

I don&#39;t think many people would stand for a country club relief program for both groups, and I don&#39;t think the New York Times would publish multiple defenses of the program in the space of a week.

This comparison might not sound fair, especially if you went to community college or commuter school (to say nothing of a for-profit college), but I promise it is directionally accurate.\[2\]

At liberal arts colleges, most private universities, and flagship state schools (at least), you get unbelievable amenities for your money. It&#39;s not just the oft-ridiculed climbing walls and lazy rivers - I&#39;m talking about the basics, the features of college that predate the crazy expansion of the last thirty (?) years: access to first-rate facilities, people paid to serve you, people paid to do your dishes, and on top of all that, excellent event programming so that, if your studies ever bore you, you&#39;ll still be stimulated.

Ultimately, I&#39;m shocked that so many early reactions to this involve a shrug, or (worse) approval of the policy, seemingly based on the sympathetic profile of a minority of beneficiaries, though maybe that&#39;s my naivete. Another writer here (responding to Trace&#39;s post, I think) wrote convincingly that people probably just conceive of this as &#34;free college&#34; rather than debt. That&#39;s an idea that&#39;s probably more popular than &#34;free country clubs&#34; (and definitely more popular than &#34;free country clubs for the rich&#34;), but I&#39;m not sure it deserves the support.

\[0\] People that have some college but no degree already do moderately better than people with a high-school diploma, [per the US Bureau of Labor Statistics](https://www.bls.gov/emp/chart-unemployment-earnings-education.htm), or [this Northeastern University study](https://www.northeastern.edu/bachelors-completion/news/average-salary-by-education-level), or any of the dozens of links that pop up when you start to research education and income.

\[1\] &#34;More than a quarter&#34; = 30% \* Krugman&#39;s &#34;43 million Americans&#34;, then round it up.

\[2\] Apart from, of course, the educational experience. But I must say, this is easy to overstate, especially if you&#39;ve been [Fred-pilled](https://substack.com/profile/12666725-freddie-deboer).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime085j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imdah89/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does anyone have a good theory about why antivaxxers are anti**vaxxers**, specif</title><updated>2022-08-30T10:22:40Z</updated><author><name>zfinder</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does anyone have a good theory about why antivaxxers are anti**vaxxers**, specifically?


People are ready to build statistical models, recheck scientific PDFs, run monothematic blogs with long texts filled with apocalyptic vocabulary, quarrel with friends. I don&#39;t see similar emotions regarding other medicines, including rather dubious ones, other medical manipulations, salt iodization, antibiotics in animal husbandry, contaminants in water (impurifying our precious bodily fluids) and in the atmosphere, inefficiencies in the healthcare system, unnecessary wars, all sorts of other aspects of corruption.


Is this a random feature of my information bubble, or is there really something visceral in vaccinations that affects some depths of consciousness?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imdah89/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imcpyav/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I came across a [fascinating blog post about dating and sexual preferences](http</title><updated>2022-08-30T05:37:55Z</updated><author><name>sonyaellenmann</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I came across a [fascinating blog post about dating and sexual preferences](https://blaqueinthecity.com/2022/05/21/dating-preferences-and-the-painful-burden-of-being-less-preferred-but-always-desired-2/) written by a black trans woman, drawing on her personal experiences in the dating market. She&#39;s clearly coming from a woke perspective — &#34;I only date people on the left; I guess that makes me &#39;rightphobic&#39;, but I&#39;m okay with that,&#34; lol. But she&#39;s also far more nuanced than your typical Twitter SJW (is there a less-dated noun for That Type? anyway)

Some notable excerpts, emphasis added by me:

&amp;gt; **A society that rejects transgender people’s bodies as valid is also one that deeply fetishizes them.** As a trans woman, most of the men I’d describe as “chasers” are men who get off on the social taboo of sleeping with transgender women and the fact that no one knows what they’re doing. Partially because they’re ashamed, but also because the secret excites them. Their secrecy also maintains their chances with cis women, who tend to be their preference. These men know that a lot of cis women would be repulsed if they knew they were attracted to transgender women, and this is the excuse they give for treating trans women how they do. Unfortunately, most chasers are in the position they’re in because they saw a trans woman who challenged their understanding of self, and they slowly but surely developed the habit of secretly consuming transgender pornography and contacting transgender women. They were curious, but then they learned they can prey on a group of people who are so used to not being preferred that they are often willing to go the extra mile to satisfy those who have privilege over them. **In fact, because transgender women know that they are rarely preferred over cis women, the attention of cis men is very validating to transgender women who are in an insecure phase of life. It’s not uncommon for transgender women to feel flattered by the affection of a man who identifies as heterosexual because, to them the expression of attraction is also a validation of them as women.** So, you have a group of heterosexual men who might otherwise be unimpressive whose inherent quality is now seen as impressive long before anything else is established. Some men become intoxicated by the idea that all they have to do is say they’re straight and gorgeous transgender women, who haven’t quite found their worth, will overlook all of their flaws, all of the reasons other women have rejected them all to feel more proximity to their privilege. This often leads to some very toxic and abusive dynamics that are very stressful for transgender women. **These men are actively attracted to them and choose to mistreat them because they are transgender. For me, that will always feel more transphobic than someone simply saying no to me.**

---

&amp;gt; Who men tend to prefer becomes very obvious when you are polyamorous. **I’ve dated men of various racial backgrounds who all denied they had a preference but were often primary partnered to cis white women. If they weren’t when I met them, almost all of them left or paused their relationships with me because of a new, cis white partner.** Removing monogamy from the conversation, allows for these things to be seen more clearly because a monogamous person could easily argue that it’s a coincidence that they just so happened to fall in love with someone who fits the idealized beauty standard. When you live in a very diverse city and all of your partners are that idealized beauty standard, it’s obvious you have a preference; but these people will deny it. **If you went to a Polyamory social and lined up every woman who was primary partnered, most of them will be cis and white; that’s not a coincidence. You’ll notice the “secondary” partners tend to be a bit darker skinned, often more queer, sometimes less cis than their primary. Often times, men primary their “preference” and keep their curiosities or the less socially acceptable partners as secondaries. To this day, I have never met a cis man primary partnered to a transgender woman with a cis woman as a secondary, but I have been the transgender secondary partner for many polyamorous men in LA.** If you were to ask these men if they had a preference, they would absolutely say no, but you see their preferences clear as day and you notice how when new women of color come to the event, they don’t get swarmed with attention the same way a white girl would. None of these socially aware, left leaning people want to say that they have a preference, but they do. But being a bit graceful, another aspect of “preference” that isn’t often discussed is that sometimes their “preference” really isn’t even their own. 

There are a couple poly people here, right? Hoping you can comment on whether her perception matches yours as well. Not because I don&#39;t believe her — sounds very plausible — but because scene dynamics can vary, regionally and otherwise, so I&#39;m curious.

Overall, the territory she treads in this essay is familiar — it&#39;s the madonna-whore dichotomy, the difference between a good-time girl and the one you take home to mama. I can imagine it&#39;s very frustrating to be sorted into the &#34;whore&#34; category sheerly because of your demographic. Last excerpt:

&amp;gt; Maybe it’s because I date men, but my experience with being less preferred has often been that I’m placed in a position where my intimate partners mistreat me and expect me to stay because they know I’m less preferred. It took me a while to understand that white men like my ex who very performatively trash white women to uplift women of color are doing so out of bitterness and a history of rejection. A lot of times when these men have low self-esteem, they’ll pursue someone they know they have more privilege than to prey on theirs instead. **Through our relationship, I knew he had insecurities, but I didn’t make the connection that those insecurities meant that he was intimidated by the white women he preferred and that he saw me as easier to connect with because I existed outside of most people’s preferences.** When he spoke about white women, it was always about how they were too prissy or high maintenance. He’d complain about women who had standards and were willing to say no and not settle for less. In retrospect, I can see that he knew he’d get away with relying on me financially because perhaps subconsciously, I did buy into the idea that a relationship with him was flattering, and I didn’t want to walk away from it. Chasers will often trash cis women in a similar way. They’ll talk about how much more feminine trans women are and how bitchy and stuck up cis women are. It’s all constructed to prey on the insecurities they know society promotes within you. These are often relationships where I’m expected to do a lot and to put up with more shit than the women they prefer. I cannot even believe that I spent all of this money in my last relationship providing for a man who is far more privileged than I’ll ever be, but that’s often the position you end up in. **These men often expect you to do more labor for them because you do not have the same bargaining power as their preference. I’ve seen men who were broke for me, be rich for their preference.** These relationships always left me feeling depleted and the only reason I speak so much about them is that they’ve left me with lasting trauma that has very viciously affected me and made me so fearful of men and their true desires. For that reason, it’s hard for me to hear conversations that attribute bigotry to someone rejecting someone they do not prefer. **I struggle to buy into the idea that because a man is attracted to me, he’s less bigoted than the men who reject me on the basis of who I am and leave me alone. I wish so many of my former intimate partners simply left me alone and pursued their preferences until one stuck. I wish they’d stop using me as a stop gap between relationships with the kind of women they prefer.** I wish I could stop being in relationships where I’m expected to settle for less, because of who I am. I cannot remember every man who’s rejected me for being a trans woman, but to this day, I feel the pain of being so intimate with men who mistreated me because I’m a transgender woman.

I definitely sympathize with the issue of having your low self-esteem used as manipulation leverage within an intimate relationship, by someone who is doing that shit because they too have low self-esteem (whether the self-assessment, by either party, is warranted or not).

Another theme of the essay, not emphasized as much in the longer passages that I quoted, is the degree to which desire is culturally mediated. She writes, &#34;What I dislike about this discourse is that on one hand it acknowledges that the type of people we&#39;re attracted to is linked to our socialization, but it downplays the depth of that socialization.&#34;

As for myself, I don&#39;t really have a point here. I thought her perspective — her inside view of dating as a black trans woman — was very interesting. I def encourage you to read the [whole post](https://blaqueinthecity.com/2022/05/21/dating-preferences-and-the-painful-burden-of-being-less-preferred-but-always-desired-2/).

Thoughts? I know you&#39;ll have &#39;em ;P</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imcpyav/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imbozoj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m not sure this question is small-scale...well, the question is, since I&#39;m not</title><updated>2022-08-30T00:18:30Z</updated><author><name>QuinoaHawkDude</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not sure this question is small-scale...well, the question is, since I&#39;m not willing to put a lot of effort into asking the question.  The scale of the answer(s) might be pretty expansive.

Why does the Left hate Ronald Reagan so damn much?

Or, more specifically, what did Reagan do, exactly, to earn so much opprobrium from progressives?

I see it all the time online, people who are on the left/progressive side of politics casually dropping a &#34;Reagan started the destruction of the American middle class&#34; into a conversation with no explanation or context.

I was was born in the late 70&#39;s so I don&#39;t have any memory of what times were like before the Reagan Era.  I&#39;d ask my parents, but their perspectives are probably skewed by the fact that they were only just growing up and starting their adult lives before 1980, plus they came from pretty poor backgrounds and bootstrapped their way into the upper-middle-class by way of being smart (smart enough to work in computer programming in my dad&#39;s case, and smart enough to marry a computer programmer and get the hell away from her white trash family in my mom&#39;s case).  My grandparents are dead so I can&#39;t ask them.

That caveat aside, an admittedly naive reading of American history from the end of WW2 through today seems like: 1950s, we&#39;re doing great, mostly because we&#39;re the only major power that didn&#39;t get bombed to smithereens during the war; 1960s still okay but slowing down, Vietnam is a real drag and blow to our egos; 1970&#39;s things start looking genuinely crappy, the oil crisis, inflation, urban decay, crime waves, etc.  Lots of people around the world genuinely thinking that the USSR might be the better place to live.  Then Reagan comes along in the 1980s and America gets its groove back, and within ten years the Berlin wall is falling and the Soviet Union is collapsing and living standards are getting way better.

I&#39;m not naive enough to think that everything good that happened between 1980 and 1988 was because of Reagan, but this general story is more or less accepted among cultural conservatives of what I guess I&#39;ll call the &#34;Tom Clancy set&#34;.

The main knocks on Reagan (in terms of actual economic policy, ignoring things like D.A.R.E and his handling of the AIDS crisis and the Iran-Contra affair) I&#39;m vaguely aware of are:  


1. Tax cuts on the top margin, the so-called &#34;trickle-down economics&#34;.
2. Certain anti-union actions, e.g. the air traffic controllers

That&#39;s it.  So, the economic left&#39;s sacred cows are high taxes on the rich and unions?  I guess it wasn&#39;t that hard to answer my own question.  But is there more to it than that?  How has this &#34;destroyed the American middle class&#34;?  My mom&#39;s aforementioned relatives are all solidly middle class (none of them went to college and they work retail or manual labor jobs) and they all, in 2022, live in decent houses with newish cars and wear name-brand clothing and get to go out to dinner multiple times a year.  They wouldn&#39;t have been doing that in the 1970s!  Not working the same kinds of jobs they do now.  What am I missing?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imbozoj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imau220/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why is it so hard to invent a good sugar substitute?

All the economic incentive</title><updated>2022-08-29T20:25:12Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why is it so hard to invent a good sugar substitute?

All the economic incentives are  in place, you got many companies that stand to make probably  hundreds of billions of dollars. Yet a century later, despite collective billions of R&amp;amp;D and some of the smartest chemists,   nothing even comes close. We&#39;re talking imitating sugar, not trying to cure cancer. The policy implications of this are huge: helping to fix global obesity, for example. Yet why can&#39;t it be done?

Trying to lose weight and this would be a godsend.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imau220/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imalmyd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **&#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34;** 

Did it? What does this actually </title><updated>2022-08-29T19:25:46Z</updated><author><name>Lorelei_On_The_Rocks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**&#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34;** 

Did it? What does this actually mean? It is a sentiment I encounter often. Including on this subreddit in the course of a discussion a few days/weeks ago (most articulately elucidated by /u/FCfromSSC). 

It usually comes up in arguments between Christian and non-Christian right-wingers. e.g:

&#34;Christianity is a cringe cuck Asiatic soy religion&#34; 

&#34;Actually Christianity is heckin based and redpilled and built western civilization.&#34; 

I disagree with the proposition, or at least, I am pretty sure I do. 

I think &#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34; can be interpreted a number of ways. 

First, and least charitably, it could be taken to mean that Christianity has had a very great influence on western civilization over the course of the past, say, fifteen centuries. This is undeniable. There would be no Gothic cathedrals, no *Divine Comedy* without Christianity. Sure. But I don&#39;t think this is what is meant by &#34;Christianity built western civilization.&#34; Because this is a very tautological and uninteresting interpretation of the proposition. If not for Christianity, European civilization would not bear a Christian stamp. Sure. So what?

There is a stronger interpretation, which is that Christianity added something (or some*things*) to European civilization which, while not explicitly Christian, it would not have had without Christianity. For example, it sometimes said that the scientific method is rooted in a Christian worldview (I happen to think this is absurd). However, I could still probably agree with this. European civilization would certainly have been very different without Christianity. Fun as counterfactuals are, we will never know precisely *how* it would have been different, but it certainly would have been, and many of these differences would probably have been subtle and not immediately tied to the absence of Christianity. 

The strongest interpretation of the proposition, and the one I believe its defenders are adhering to, is something like, &#34;European civilization is/was *great* and its *greatness* is entirely or largely owed to Christianity.&#34; This is the interpretation I strongly *disagree* with. 

It depends on what you think is (or was) *great* about European civilization. If you are a Christian, and you say, &#34;Christianity is true, and therefore a civilization that exemplifies Christian morals and virtue is great,&#34; then we have a very deep disagreement, because I *don&#39;t* think Christianity is true. The argument will have to be suspended while we dig down to a deeper level and argue about the truth of Christianity. 

But most defenders of the proposition don&#39;t tend to argue so bluntly. In my experience, they attempt to find common ground with the non-Christian RWer by which they can persuade them that the greatness of European civilization, agreed upon by both parties, can be credited to Christianity. 

So what made European civilization great? In my view it is obvious. 

First and foremost, strength and power. Various nations of Europe subjected a greater portion of the world than any before them. All of the Americas, all of Africa (save a few stubborn states), great swathes of Asia. It was a feat unequalled in world history, and &#34;great&#34; by any reasonable measure. 

Secondly, artistic and cultural achievement. It is obvious that Europe has been the world center for great art for the past several centuries. I confess I am no connoisseur, but *The Ecstasy of Saint Teresa* has left me in awe since high school. To say nothing of architecture, literature, etc. 

Thirdly, scientific achievement. Again, it is quite indisputable that Europe has been the center of scientific and technological excellence for the past several centuries. Northwestern Europe, in particular. No industrial revolution without England. 

So the question is, to what extent was Christianity responsible for any of these three?

I believe the answer is &#34;barely,&#34; or &#34;not at all,&#34; since Europe was leading in all three even before Christianization. If anything there was something of a backslide on all three metrics in the early middle ages. I&#39;m not trying to resurrect &#34;hole left by the Christian dark ages,&#34; but if Christianity had a stimulating effect on European greatness you would not expect its proliferation to coincide with the political, cultural, economic, and artistic decay that characterized late antiquity and the early medieval period. 

This argument is usually capped off with something along the lines of, &#34;well, you&#39;re just a LARPer, western civilization has been Christian for centuries so trying to resurrect pagan Greece or Rome is just dumb and pointless.&#34; Which may be true, but is also a huge self-own considering how many online Christian RWers are trad monarchist LARPer types. One might as easily say, &#34;well, the west has been liberal democratic for two centuries, now. Trying to resurrect catholic monarchy is just dumb and pointless.&#34; Or bring it even further down to date. &#34;Trying to resurrect the 1950s is dumb and pointless, that was more than half a century ago. Move on, stop LARPing.&#34; You get the point. 

I am aware that today, the great majority of western conservatives are Christian or at least Christian adjacent. In real life, I don&#39;t call Christian conservatives cringe and tell them they should be worshipping the Olympians. That would, indeed, be silly and pointless. I am happy to make common cause with Christian RWers IRL. But this is an argument I get into regularly in niche internet spaces, and I happen to think I have the better part of it. I am curious what the users of this subreddit think, since this is after all one of the niche internet spaces in which I have had this and related arguments. 

SIDENOTE: the also-common argument that &#34;Christianity united Europe&#34; is not addressed above because it is almost too stupid for words. After the dissolution of pagan Rome, Europe was never so united again until the 20th century. Christian Europeans spent centuries warring with their fellow Christian Europeans. And of course during the Based Crusades™ another set of Based Crusaders was up north slaughtering Baltic pagans. Not that any of this matters because pan-European nationalism is dumb in most contexts anyways.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imalmyd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imadzpj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why do almost all videos on the internet have subtitles all of a sudden?</title><updated>2022-08-29T18:32:51Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why do almost all videos on the internet have subtitles all of a sudden?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imadzpj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9xi04/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How many people here can hold an emotion for 10 minutes?

Sam Harris had a quote</title><updated>2022-08-29T16:44:15Z</updated><author><name>MihowZa</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How many people here can hold an emotion for 10 minutes?

Sam Harris had a quote recently where he said &#39; 10 minutes of anger can really fuck up your life &#39; and I understood it to be obviously true. But how many people can actually hold an emotion that long? I&#39;ve held sadness twice for a longer period of time: once when a long term gf and I broke up, and once when my best friend killed themselves. I also get angry in spurts - browsing Reddit sometimes does it or hearing peoples various political opinions I disagree with or know that are incorrect - but it&#39;s just a spur of the moment issue. Another example is sports. I love sports but I really never get too up or too down about my teams performance; there&#39;s always next year + being a Marlins and Dolphins fan that would just be an outlet to constant anger. Otherwise, pretty much every other emotion is just done after what seems like several seconds. 

This leads me to question if otherwise I am emotionally comatose the majority of my life? 

Now Sam was talking about it in relation (I believe) of criminality and, as always, of free will and I&#39;m talking about it more on a personal level, and that&#39;s what I&#39;d like to hear feedback on: how long do you hold onto emotions? And how does this impact your life daily and in general?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9xi04/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9smmz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ~~[Voters are split in support of Biden&#39;s $500 billion student loan handout, Bid</title><updated>2022-08-29T16:12:12Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">~~[Voters are split in support of Biden&#39;s $500 billion student loan handout, Biden approval up in new poll](https://www.foxnews.com/politics/voters-split-support-bidens-500b-student-loan-handout-biden-approval-poll)~~

&amp;gt;Registered voters are nearly tied in support of President Joe Biden&#39;s recent $500 billion student loan handout initiative, as the economy remains the most important issue to registered voters, according to new poll.

&amp;gt;A new Emerson College Polling national survey suggests that Americans are almost evenly split in favor and opposition to President Joe Biden&#39;s recent student loan handout, with 36% believing the loan handout is too much and 35% thinking it is just the right amount of action. Thirty percent think it is not enough action.

&amp;gt;The majority of registered voters, 51%, believe the executive action will result in colleges raising tuition, whereas 49% think that it will allow students to have more access to education.

538 shows Biden at 42% approval, a little higher than a week ago

https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/

This is the sort of partisan split we would expect for something as polarizing or politicized as his student forgiveness plan. There does not seem to be any evidence yet that Biden is seeing a net-loss of support. 

It&#39;s still possible that SCOTUS will try to block it. RBG not retiring was the ultimate gift for the right that keeps giving, whether it&#39;s Roe v. Wade or this....it shows how important the courts are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9smmz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9lflo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Lost in the shuffle last week was an interview between [Trump’s AG Bill Barr]( h</title><updated>2022-08-29T15:23:57Z</updated><author><name>ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Lost in the shuffle last week was an interview between [Trump’s AG Bill Barr]( https://www.commonsense.news/p/bill-barr-calls-bullsht) and Bari Weiss. I don’t normally enjoy writing about this kind of piece because of how heated people can get, but I found this interesting enough that I’ll give it a go.

Tl;dr: Likes:  
-	Trump, the president 
-	The right’s interpretation of Russiagate  
-	Republicans  
-	Joe Manchin and Stephen Breyer  
Dislikes:  
-	Trump, the person  
-	Progressives (unclear to me how wide a net this casts)  
-	Political tribalism  

Barr tells a few stories that echo what has come out about the Trump administration in a number of books and other sources. Stories like this one:

&amp;gt;AG BARR: It was on June 1 when the president was bellowing at a number of his cabinet secretaries, especially the military guys—the secretary and chairman of the joint chiefs. He was calling all of us “fucking losers” at the top of his lungs. 
Or this one, where he tried to resign over the allegations Trump was making of election fraud:
&amp;gt;AG BARR: He was in a little dining room that adjoins the Oval Office. He was as furious as I’d ever seen him. He confronted me and said, “Did you say this to the AP?” And I said, “I did. Because it was the truth.” I went over some of the allegations. He said there was plenty of evidence of fraud. I explained in some detail why the allegations didn’t fly. I told him that there were only five or six weeks to challenge a presidential election because the Constitution requires the Electoral College to meet at a certain date and he didn’t have much time. He’d already wasted five of your six weeks with this crazy stuff about the Dominion machines. He’d wheeled out this clown show of lawyers that no reputable lawyer is willing to work with.  
&amp;gt;I said, “Look, I know you’re unhappy with me. I’m going to tender my resignation.” And he slammed the table. Everyone jumped. And he said, “Accepted.” So I said OK and left. I was getting into my car right outside the White House and all of a sudden, people started pounding on the windows. It was late at night and raining, so it was sort of this eerie thing. The president sent Cipollone, another White House lawyer, out there, to retrieve me and tell me “Nevermind, he’s not going to fire you, and would you come back in?” And I said, “I don&#39;t think there&#39;s any use to going back in tonight. I’m going to go home. But we can talk about it in the morning.” 

I suppose it depends how much credence you lend to his version of events over Trump’s. Barr genuinely seems to like what Trump did while in office, though, if that moves your needle towards believing him. I won’t link those quotes due to space concerns. He also doesn’t lend any credence to the election fraud theories:

&amp;gt;AG BARR: I was somewhat demoralized that he was leaving office this way. The left says, “Oh, you said all these nice things about him in your resignation.” But I felt that what he should do was focus on all his achievements and leave with dignity. Whether he thought there was fraud or not, he had his day in court and he lost.  
&amp;gt;So I was demoralized that he was going out the way he was. I thought it was very unfair to all the people, especially the younger people, who had worked in the administration. It hurt them getting jobs and it also hurt the Republican Party, which I thought up until then, could take the high ground as the party of law and order.  
&amp;gt;I would say it [the January 6th riot] was an effort to intimidate Congress and the vice president. I haven’t heard words from the president that I would consider incitement under the law. That’s a very high bar because of our First Amendment, and it should be a high bar. But I did feel that he was morally responsible for it because he led these people to believe that something could happen on Capitol Hill that would reverse the election. That there’s something they could do involving pressuring the vice president and Congress that would overturn the election. 

Barr also says a number of things about politics that make me think that compromise and a rapprochement are possible. Perhaps I’m projecting, but he seems to argue against reactionary politics and towards something more constructive:

&amp;gt;Something I’m pretty tired of from the right is the constant pandering to outrage. The picking and picking at the scab without trying to channel those feelings in a constructive direction. In my opinion, Ronald Reagan was a great populist not because he followed the frustrated instincts and the outrage of the people, but because he channeled it and was constructive with it…We have these institutions that need reform. The first step is to win an election with a decisive majority that allows you to put a program into effect and fix some of these problems going forward. That is not done by just throwing fuel on the fire of outrage on one side of the equation while the other side does the same thing on their side…I think we should basically try to persuade people. People like Youngkin, the Governor of Virginia, have shown that the Republican Party is a potential majority party.  
&amp;gt;The problem with Trump is that it’s all about running a base election. Whip up your base, get them all upset and outraged, and turn them out at the polls. Both sides do that. That is a prescription for continued hostility and demoralization of the country. The first side to break out of that will do so by restoring politics to what it should be, which is the politics of trying to capture a majority of the people through persuasion and with a decisive enough majority to change things…I say to the people that want to make America great again, “What will it take to do that?” You don’t do it just by making your base madder and madder.  

And yet, at the same time, the way he talks about liberals is depressing:

&amp;gt;although we’ve been sort of harping on the warts of Trumpism, I think the greatest threat to the country is the radical progressive movement and what it’s degenerated into. In 2016, had there been another Democratic administration, I was concerned that we’d have dug an even deeper hole that would be much harder to get out of. I think Trump did serve a historic purpose: He was sort of the wrecking ball and against progressive excess. People were mad about it, and they wanted a no-nonsense person who would be a wrecking ball, and he did that. What I’m saying now is that we need something different moving forward. I give him credit for identifying people’s frustrations and being willing to call out some of the progressive excess that other people were cowering about then.  

&amp;gt;If we’ve left it behind, I don&#39;t think this ends well for the country. I don&#39;t see that this leads to any future for the country. I think we have to return to that if we’re going to have a future. I put this on the doorstep of the radical progressives as their responsibility. They’re the ones who have sharply shifted. The political model before this was the liberal democratic spectrum where you have right and left, but we’re all within the liberal, democratic, Anglo-American political tradition.  

&amp;gt;What we’ve moved to is a bipolar system that’s more typical of revolutionary countries, where you have a party like the Marxists or some other totalitarian party trying to take power. It’s all or nothing and anything goes. It’s war by other means. That’s where we are, and it doesn’t end well.  

&amp;gt;Those of us who are traditional conservatives, Reagan conservatives––I grew up on Bill Buckley and so forth––believe in the Anglo-American system of politics. We have a First Amendment that allows citizens to debate and come to some consensus for the public good. One of the things that bothers me is that people talk about democracy and the threat to democracy. Well, what did the framers think was the threat to democracy? In Federalist 10, Madison says it’s when the majority uses democracy to oppress the minority. When someone takes a transient 51% majority and tries to ram things down the throat of the other 49%, and now we’re finding ourselves sort of oscillating between those two worlds. Get 51 votes, good: Obamacare. You have 51 votes and you shove it down people’s throats. Whereas the institutions that we’ve had before this were meant to require some form of consensus and incremental change. They allowed people to build up some consensus for an approach, and things moved slowly. That’s not good enough for revolutionaries, who want to tear things down or change things instantaneously. I think that’s the basic challenge we face right now.

automod_multipart_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9lflo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im9jjgo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Related to the moving topic in the Friday thread on moving, we&#39;re moving soon. K</title><updated>2022-08-29T15:11:04Z</updated><author><name>Im_not_JB</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Related to the moving topic in the Friday thread on moving, we&#39;re moving soon. Kicker: don&#39;t know what state we&#39;re going to yet. We&#39;re currently trying to juggle a couple job offers. How do people manage moving to a different state when you already have a significant amount of stuff? (Prior moves have either been small amounts of stuff or to a place where we already had a domicile.)

I think the traditional thing is to go and scope out a place, get it arranged to rent or whatever, maybe live out of a hotel and work there some while your family stays back where you used to live, and so on. We&#39;re renting, and while we have some flexibility, we want to just leave this place pretty quickly. We&#39;re considering doing PODS, just packing up basically everything, having them store them in a facility somewhere, then live out of suitcases in an AirBNB in the new area for a few weeks or a month or whatever until we decide on and negotiate a new place to live.

Has anyone done this? Even if not, any thoughts?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im9jjgo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im90px1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Let&#39;s say I&#39;m a US citizen with no love for either major political party. Let&#39;s </title><updated>2022-08-29T12:52:12Z</updated><author><name>eight_unread_emails</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Let&#39;s say I&#39;m a US citizen with no love for either major political party. Let&#39;s also say that I&#39;m worried about anti-democratic tendencies that I feel like I observe from former president Trump and his faction of the Republican party. Does it make sense for me to become a republican and support the not-Trump/&#34;normal&#34; republicans in internal elections? The party seems to be at a tipping point on the &#34;Trump good/bad&#34; issue, and a small number of votes could have an outsized impact, as far as I can see. Are there any personal costs incurred by doing this (beyond risking getting more involved in mind-killing politics)? Are there safeguards in place keeping people like me from joining the party?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im90px1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im8j6bl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Manosphere is not what it used to be. It&#39;s been mostly ran off mainstream sites </title><updated>2022-08-29T09:41:26Z</updated><author><name>Schismatic6</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Manosphere is not what it used to be. It&#39;s been mostly ran off mainstream sites and most classic blogs are since defunct or moved on to other grift. Still there has been an idea I have been developing for a while.

It was always easy to dismiss as toxic masculinity, motivated by misogyny and sexism. This may be to some extent true but I propose a different framing that unites all the disparate factions even though I don&#39;t think they realize so themselves. It&#39;s about the male gender role. It&#39;s no secret that the traditional male gender role is not what it used to be. Between the state and women in the workforce the provider is largely obsolete and the feminism friendly attempts to construct a new one are just unappealing and don&#39;t really address mens desires at all. How the factions differ is their reaction to that.

Redpill sometimes gets accused of being patriarchal and while some are certainly sympathetic to it (though I think part of that faction has split off into the newer tradlarpers) they instead decide feel that women don&#39;t live up to their standards and *enjoy the decline* becoming philanderers instead. The archetype of philanderer did exist but it was never considered something commendable or worth emulating under traditional conventions. The MGTOW are pretty similar, but they decide to quit altogether. MRA try to renegotiate their place using more conventional activist tactics to get the legal recognition framing it in the terms of *rights* in parallel to women. I think what both are really getting at is that women don&#39;t want to hold up their end of the bargain, but still expect men to do theirs and that&#39;s fundamentally unfair. Traditional gender roles might have given men some power that could be abused but it also came with responsibilities that remain unrecognized, even as women got *liberated* from theirs. 

I think this is a discussion we should have, but unfortunately men constructing a new narrative is hostile to modern feminism. When you&#39;re accustomed to privilege equality feels like oppression, as they say.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im8j6bl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im7wnuv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So what should I be cooking with? Ghee?</title><updated>2022-08-29T04:41:59Z</updated><author><name>TJ11240</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So what should I be cooking with? Ghee?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im7wnuv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im6axzq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Catching up on a range of things at the moment, so apologies for being so late t</title><updated>2022-08-28T20:56:57Z</updated><author><name>TaiaoToitu</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Catching up on a range of things at the moment, so apologies for being so late to the party on this one: Regarding the discussion around [&#39;What we owe the future&#39;](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/book-review-what-we-owe-the-future), was there any discussion of discounting future humans I&#39;m the same way we discount future cash flows (though obviously at a different rate)?

The argument about the glass shard strikes me as very odd. Of course it makes a difference if the child comes 5 days hence or a millennia. Within a few years we can probably expect the shard to be buried and rendered harmless. Within a century we can assign a reasonably high probability that the forest track has changed route due to natural subsidences etc. Within a millennia, who knows if any humans will be around at all? So valuing a clear and present threat equally with some theoretical future one seems utterly absurd to me.

Just as the impact of any action we might take is affected by compounding uncertainties, human life is also. Is it not clear that the life of somebody actually alive today is worth more than somebody who&#39;s parents are yet to be born? As one looks further forward, there is less certainty that the hypothetical people your action seeks to aid actually exist! Or even if they do, maybe they are genocidal maniacs that killed your descendants, or otherwise so alien in their values that you wouldn&#39;t Uncertainty in both regards compounds over time.

People obviously care deeply about their grand kids, and thinking of the US Revolution for example, have been willing to make great sacrifices to secure a future for many generations of strangers to come. The discount rate need not be extreme, and probably properly even varies depending on the circumstance (discounting one&#39;s own descendants less steeply than those of your extended family/community/nation/culture/species for example). Of course, one need not do this formally or numerically at all, but if you&#39;re going to build a numerical case for a particular idea, then it seems disingenuous not to at least consider including it as a term.

This sort of thinking is intuitive to me, and I think lines up well as a formalisation of actual human values and behaviour, but I&#39;m curious that I&#39;m not seeing anything like this discussed in the likes of Scott&#39;s OP or follow up &#39;highlights&#39; post for example. Perhaps I&#39;m off base?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im6axzq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im5ub2m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Pinker&#39;s *Rationality*. I attempted a </title><updated>2022-08-28T19:01:15Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Pinker&#39;s *Rationality*. I attempted a while back to get through his Harvard lectures, but couldn&#39;t maintain interest. Perhaps I&#39;ll do better in text. Seems to have a fair amount of overlap with LessWrong-style thinking. I confess that I read these kinds of texts more like a medieval logic treatise that needs interpretation to get some use out of in one&#39;s life, than actually trying to learn how to think. Still, perhaps I&#39;ll learn something.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im5ub2m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im4v7tx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does anyone know of a good politically minded critique of the double entry accou</title><updated>2022-08-28T15:01:57Z</updated><author><name>RGbudvit</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does anyone know of a good politically minded critique of the double entry accounting system?

It&#39;s a little odd to me that one of the main mechanisms of business and one of the key ways states control industry seems to have so little focus.

Edit - there doesn&#39;t seem to be such a critique and I am not doing the best job of explaining my issue. Thanks folks I&#39;ll come back to this later if I can martial my thoughts more coherently.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im4v7tx/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im4fqz4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Has the Catholic Church ever admitted fault as an institution, or admitted as an</title><updated>2022-08-28T13:01:13Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Has the Catholic Church ever admitted fault as an institution, or admitted as an institution having been wrong about something?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im4fqz4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im3q30m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what&#39;s up with [excess mortality across Europe](https://www.euromomo.eu/grap</title><updated>2022-08-28T07:37:42Z</updated><author><name>D1m1tr1Rascalov</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what&#39;s up with [excess mortality across Europe](https://www.euromomo.eu/graphs-and-maps#excess-mortality)? This dataset received an update last week and has since created a lot of buzz in the vaccine-skeptic/anti-vaxx circles on reddit, Substack and Twitter, while receiving comparatively little airtime on more mainstream publications in relation to the (perceived) importance of the phenomenon. The basic finding is that elevated mortality has continued into 2022 and is currently on track to surpass both 2020 and 2021. This is particularly surprising given that we&#39;d expect a decrease in mortality now that a whole lot of vulnerable people have died already. Also note the sharp increase of mortality for people below the age of 44 and especially below the age of 14.

So far, the possible explanations I&#39;ve seen are:

* it&#39;s the heat wave,
* it&#39;s COVID itself or its long-term effects,
* it&#39;s the consequences from lockdowns, including staff shortages, treatment delays, economical and mental health fallout etc.
* and, most controversially of course, it&#39;s the vaccines

None of these seem particularly convincing to me. Why would e.g. heat waves and treatment delays be causing unusual levels of excess mortality for people below the age of 18? If it were the vaccines or lockdowns, the timing seems off. Europe is back open, mass vaccination happened last year at roughly the same scale and time in every European country, so why is Portugal&#39;s mortality going trough the roof right now while Denmark is mostly staying where it&#39;s at? COVID-infections might be contributing, but confirmed deaths are way down in basically every country and it&#39;s also not a known killer of young people. That widespread infections sort of shifted the general population health Bell Curve towards worse outcomes seems plausible, but studies on the side effects that don&#39;t look at vulnerable or severely ill subpopulations tend to come up with pretty unconvincing results IMO and again it wouldn&#39;t make sense for this to affect specifically young people.

Does anyone have a good idea for what&#39;s going on right now? Is it a combination of some of the mentioned possibilities? Or something else entirely? Or is it overblown, we should just wait a few months/a year or two and mortality will normalize?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im3q30m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He</title><updated>2022-08-28T01:19:00Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He may have used one of my requested questions, but I can’t tell as they were vague. Magnus is the most interesting case study of performance psychology because he’s so beyond his competition, in what amounts to the most competitive cognitive game in the world. 

Some interesting bits from the interview:

* Magnus does not like practicing with puzzles. Neither does he consider himself good at stand-alone puzzles. 

* Magnus hates strict, organized practice. He refused to do this as a child and instead enjoyed exploring interesting parts from books he takes a liking to. When he was younger he “fired” Kasparov as a coach (one of the best players of all time) because Kasparov wanted Magnus to analyze his past mistakes, which he found annoying.

* The above two bits are shocking as it flies in the face of our understanding of deliberate practice. But actually, maybe not! While it’s true that puzzles can be construed as very specific deliberate practice, you come across the scenarios in games anyway, in their “natural habitat” surrounded by other information; so playing difficult games is probably better than specialized puzzles. 

* While focusing on past major mistakes could be seen as optimal deliberate practice, it’s also highly demotivating. Magnus’ practice is odd in that he appears to choose the most motivating path. He reads from books guided by pleasure, and he ignores strict puzzle-based practices. He favors playing games, and if you notice, he very often plays these games with variable strategy in mind. Instead of focusing on one opening, when he plays online he frequently changes openings, tests out things he doesn’t know will work, etc. This is excellent deliberate, variable practice while maintaining motivation.

* While Magnus was the poster child of athletic chess players, in recent years he has fallen out of shape. I find it interesting that he favors sports games over weightlifting or cardio. This has a motivational component, because when he’s playing tennis for an hour or two he’s in a state of competition. I think this extra “competitiveness practice” aids him in chess. 

So I find it interesting that Magnus’ approach to chess prioritizes competition and motivation. I also find it interesting to think that if Magnus were placed in chess school with dry exercises and exams, he probably wouldn’t even make it in the top 200 students. He has a strong aversion to boring practice and is chiefly motivated by real competitive wins, and he’s not good at chess “practice puzzles”. This says a lot about modern schooling: what other talents are we missing out on because we focus on dry, boring practice problems that do not directly translate to real life? Have we missed out on Henry Fords and Da Vinci’s?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im0xsgc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] For the Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality fans here on The Motte, here</title><updated>2022-08-27T17:25:46Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">For the Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality fans here on The Motte, here&#39;s [Daniel Radcliffe singing an appropriately scientific song](https://youtu.be/rSAaiYKF0cs?t=32).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im0xsgc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more fema</title><updated>2022-08-27T11:00:56Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more female attention than those who have a gym body. Think Timothee Chalamet or Ezra Miller, versus buff Chris Pratt. I think this is because such natural thin disposition signals good metabolic health. This sign of effortless good health trumps the gym body because it conveys greater reproductive fitness and gene desirability.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilyae70/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] A poem from Yours Truly on the Occasion of u/Tracingwoodgrains wedding  


[http</title><updated>2022-08-27T02:15:46Z</updated><author><name>KulakRevolt</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">A poem from Yours Truly on the Occasion of u/Tracingwoodgrains wedding  


[https://anarchonomicon.substack.com/p/the-fox-and-the-hen?sd=pf](https://anarchonomicon.substack.com/p/the-fox-and-the-hen?sd=pf)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilyae70/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxhahm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] It seems like no amount of technological progress makes moving less terrible. I </title><updated>2022-08-26T22:28:29Z</updated><author><name>rolabond</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">It seems like no amount of technological progress makes moving less terrible. I hate it. Listening to emo music because it fits the mood as I pack. Thank you MCR.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxhahm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommend</title><updated>2022-08-26T22:23:35Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommended reading. https://archive.org/details/The_Sims/page/n43/mode/2up

Reproduced in full: 

&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED READING
&amp;gt; Here are some titles that might enhance your understanding of some of the background and sociai issues entertained in The Sims.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Warning: all are filled with provocative ideas; Maxis disavows any responsibility for encouraging deep thought.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Home: A Short History of an Idea by Witoid Rybczynski (Juiy 1 987), Penguin USA; ISBN: 0140102310
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Notes on the Synthesis of Form by Christopher W. Alexander (June 1970), Harvard University Press; ISBN: 0674627512
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - A Pattern Language : Towns, Buildings, Construction by Christopher Alexander, Sara Ishikawa, Murray Silverstein (1977), Oxford University Press (Trade); iSBN: 0195019199
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Architecture : Form, Space, &amp;amp; Order by Frank D. K. Ching, Francis D. Ching (February 1996), John Wiiey &amp;amp; Sons; ISBN: 0471286168
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Housing by Lifestyle : The Component Method of Residential Design by James W. Wentling (November 1994) McGraw-Hill; ISBN: 0070692939
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Time for Life : The Surprising Ways Americans Use Their Time by John P Robinson, Geoffrey Godbey (Contributor), Robert Putnam (June 1997)Pennsylvania State University Press (Trade); ISBN: 0271016523
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Maps of the Mind by C. Hampden-Turner (March 1982), MacMillan Publishing Company; ISBN: 0025477404
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Hidden Order: The Economics of Everyday Life by David D. Friedman (September 1997), HarperCollins; ISBN: 0887308856
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Making the Most of Your Llama by Linda C. Beattie (Editor), Araneen Witmer (Illustrator), Kathyrn Doll (Editor), Dr. Linda Beattie (September 1998), Kopacetic Ink; ISBN: 0961963417 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Finding Your Perfect Love by Arthur Clark, Cassandra Skouras (January 1998), Rosebud Press; ISBN: 0965276902
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - The User Illusion : Cutting Consciousness Down to Size by Tor Norretranders, Jonathan Sydenham (Translator) (April 1998), Viking Press; ISBN: 0670875791

----

In other news, Will Macaskill worked as a stripper? 

https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/08/15/the-reluctant-prophet-of-effective-altruism

&amp;gt; In graduate school, “I started giving three per cent, and then five per cent, of my income,” he said. This wasn’t much—he was then living on a university stipend. “I think it’s O.K. to tell you this: I supplemented my income with nude modelling for life-drawing classes.” The postures left him free to philosophize. Later, he moved on to bachelorette parties, where he could make twice the money “for way easier poses.”

----

And finally, after playing with Stable Diffusion, I am blown away. A wholly original work of art created inside a minute. Yes, it is hit or miss, but it is amazing that it can hit at all. 

You are probably already saturated with AI art, but [here are a few of my favourites](https://imgur.com/a/lti20Ia). Perhaps you can tell something about a person from the kind of art they generate. Feel free to share your creations.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror </title><updated>2022-08-26T20:32:28Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror scenario with humor elements, before circling the entire thing around to be a jab at a certain politician in another country with whom I have no beef. Anyway, via the game [Space Funeral](https://thecatamites.itch.io/space-funeral), which is a free and excellent two to three hour experience that feels like you&#39;re traversing a slightly humorous nightmare, I&#39;ve become more interested in older experimental music as a means of communicating an atmosphere of horror so that I can bundle it up with my already growing pile of copyright infringement. This has led me down the rabbit hole of early synthesizer music, starting with [Delia Derbyshire](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XVsqxNy8kkg) with the BBC Radiophonic Workshop. Most recently, I&#39;ve been delving into Japanese Synthesizer stuff, which is frequently very pretty...

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q)

And then, there&#39;s 70s-80s French experimental music, which is good at stoking a sense of terror and sometimes downright miserable to listen to (as also is Derbyshire)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0)

Not all the music I&#39;ve posted is good. A lot of it is discordant. But Space Funeral is pretty fun and if you know any other cool early synthesizer stuff that&#39;s good at creating an ambience, please shoot it over. Anyways, I am complete newb to this stuff and am not sure of how much interest it would be to anyone else. At very least, it you need to terrorize trick or treaters or your significant other during Halloween, some of these tracks will do a good job.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvmmbv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So I&#39;m still greatly enjoying Xenoblade Chronicles 3, but I had to take a week o</title><updated>2022-08-26T15:05:01Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So I&#39;m still greatly enjoying Xenoblade Chronicles 3, but I had to take a week off to travel.

The job system hasn&#39;t really opened up as much as I&#39;d hoped.  I&#39;m like, 40 hours into the game, and all my jobs are still capped at level 10.  I can clearly see they go up to level 20, I just have no idea when/how I uncap them.  Will it be story related, or a sidequest?  I guess I&#39;ll find out.  But that obnoxious cap turns the job system from something fun, to a chore where I&#39;m constantly rejiggering my party&#39;s jobs because someone hit their cap, and I don&#39;t want XP to goto waste.  I can&#39;t fucking wait for the cap to go away.

The story is **very** Xenoblade.  If you&#39;ve played one, you know what I mean.

The geography and world design at first seemed very bog standard.  It&#39;s gotten much more creative and alien as I&#39;ve gone along.  It&#39;s funny though, because Xenoblade 1 and 2 both started off with monologs about &#34;This game takes place on the back of a giant titan(s)&#34;.  Xenoblade 3 just throws you in, with no explanation about the construction or orientation of the world.  I think it&#39;s still taking place on a titan?  Maybe the corpses of the titans from the first two games?  I don&#39;t know.  It&#39;ll be interesting if they just never fucking tell you, but I think I&#39;d like at least a few more hints.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvmmbv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt</title><updated>2022-08-26T14:51:58Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt;!The arrow was fucking *bouncing* in the original.!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/iluqofd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Is there such a thing as a family with higher/lower genetic variance?

I was at </title><updated>2022-08-26T10:50:02Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Is there such a thing as a family with higher/lower genetic variance?

I was at a funeral, big Irish family, and all the men in the family seemed to be at extremes. Either 6&#39;3&#34; or taller and muscular, owned businesses or served in the marines; or on disability with some variety of genetic defect that prevented them from ever holding a job. It was a striking pattern, I meet one son who has had nine heart surgeries, the other son is on a scholarship and looks like the guy she tells you not to worry about. One daughter has muscular dystrophy, her sister is a judge.

I&#39;m thinking of other examples in my life. Twins on my little league team, one batted third and one batted ninth. Law school classmates in the top-5 of our class, who had siblings in nursing homes.

Is there any logic to this or am I just seeing random statistical noise? Any studies or theories?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/iluqofd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilu3sxx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Why does conciousness matter anyway? It seems terribly inefficient for something</title><updated>2022-08-26T05:49:15Z</updated><author><name>LeftNebula1226</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Why does conciousness matter anyway? It seems terribly inefficient for something that we have so much trouble understanding, without any real benefits. Couldn&#39;t we reason and all that good stuff without this crummy &#34;what is it like to be a human?&#34; nonsense attached to it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilu3sxx/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>