<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-06T23:29:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/indq3gl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does Effective Altruism have a *current* opinion on how to most effectively ceas</title><updated>2022-09-06T23:29:36Z</updated><author><name>herzenslied</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does Effective Altruism have a *current* opinion on how to most effectively cease the suffering caused by Russia&#39;s invasion of the Ukraine?

Or more concretely, which program/intervention offers me the most effective &#39;counteract Russian terrorism&#39; per $1, taking into account short- and long-term effects?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/indq3gl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in9ktm4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Starting PhD program in neurosci in 1 week. General advice is wanted, but I have</title><updated>2022-09-06T02:40:58Z</updated><author><name>GibonFrog</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Starting PhD program in neurosci in 1 week. General advice is wanted, but I have one specific question: how do I build a close knit group of friends? I am a little scared bc i am 21 and 2 years younger than anyone in my cohort of 20 ppl. I still like to hang out with my undergrad friends (moving away 400 miles) and do undergrad things (getting very very wasted etc).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in9ktm4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x6itk7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_september_5/in6zb44/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [The Motte has moved offsite](https://www.themotte.org/). Join us in our new hom</title><updated>2022-09-05T15:23:41Z</updated><author><name>ZorbaTHut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[The Motte has moved offsite](https://www.themotte.org/). Join us in our new home! All future Culture War threads, and other content, will be posted there.

If you&#39;d like to talk about this, please use [the Meta thread](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5t3jh/meta_the_motte_is_dead_long_live_the_motte/).

Hope to see you soon.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x6itk7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_september_5/in6zb44/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in4d1jz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I have had this sitting for a week but it never seemed to fit in the small-scale</title><updated>2022-09-05T00:00:19Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I have had this sitting for a week but it never seemed to fit in the small-scale or friday fun or wednesday wellness.

So I guess the question is &#34;how evil can a product be?&#34;


https://twitter.com/RayRedacted/status/1562914396732801025?s=20&amp;amp;t=YTSBi61pjYTqsfkgBKOA3Q

Short version: A consumer can buy a 30 TB hard drive off of Alibaba or Walmart&#39;s website (which is a reseller using them as a storefront).

The capacity is fake. Someone wrote hacked firmware so that two flash drives have (each) 512MB of actual storage self-report as 15TB. When you go to use it, the hacked firmware pretends to write the files and creates the whole directory structure. The directory structure is the only permanent part. The file contents start getting overwritten once you put in too much data. Someone could buy this and take a while to realize that their data is dead.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in4d1jz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in38d61/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m starting Minsky&#39;s *Society of Mind*, a classic AI</title><updated>2022-09-04T18:59:47Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m starting Minsky&#39;s *Society of Mind*, a classic AI text about building minds from smaller, mindless components. The current zeitgeist seems to be moving away from classic AI, but eventually we&#39;ll need better understanding of where precisely our machine-learning models fit in the broader scheme of knowledge. &#34;Shut up and scale&#34; doesn&#39;t seem entirely satisfactory. Maybe going over some slightly dust-covered ideas might spark some useful thinking. The book itself seems like a mix of aesthetic quirks and precision, and I seem to be in the mood for that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in38d61/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in2y0fb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Recently [posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/x0wtdt/open_a</title><updated>2022-09-04T17:48:58Z</updated><author><name>sciuru_</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Recently [posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/x0wtdt/open_access_to_research_articles_recent_progress/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) my summary of the article [“Transformative agreements: Do they pave the way to open access?”](https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/leap.1347) (2020) about struggles between publishers and pubic research institutions. I read the article to contextualize US govt [statement](https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/08/25/ostp-issues-guidance-to-make-federally-funded-research-freely-available-without-delay/) from Aug 25, announcing that immediate open access to all taxpayer-funded research articles should be implemented by 2025, thus eliminating current 12 months embargo.

I wanted to ask here first, as my interest is in market power dynamics and bargaining, not consumer perspective. I’d love to know what you think about how it works.

And separately, I’d like to know what is so awful about the post, that no one responded? Is it too long, boring, cluttered, grammar is poor? Want to know how to improve engagement.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in2y0fb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in22r6p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] **European Probation/Early Release Scandals:**

After playing a game that made f</title><updated>2022-09-04T14:23:06Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">**European Probation/Early Release Scandals:**

After playing a game that made fun of him, I read that Josef Fritzl, [World&#39;s Least Popular Austrian (silver medalist)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fritzl_case) might be eligible for probation next year, after 15 years in prison for the whole multi-generational incest rape dungeon business.  
It made me curious: what&#39;s the media environment in european countries like when this happens? Does the press pay any attention to it? Do people ever talk seriously about maybe bus-full-of-nuns-murderers needing to spend more time in prison?  

In the UK it&#39;s usually only the Daily Mail that notices/comes out with headlines about bringing back hanging, while the US sometimes gets some hand-wringing in the serious-people papers if the stars and skin colours align (which is fairly rare due to the 7 million year sentences in such cases).  
Is it basically the same in Europe? The only big one I&#39;m aware of was Pim Fortuyn&#39;s unrepentant assassin being released after 12(!) years to apparently more media attention in the english-speaking press than the dutch.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in22r6p/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1n72i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anybody able to give general advice on hiring a personal attorney for matters re</title><updated>2022-09-04T12:14:17Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anybody able to give general advice on hiring a personal attorney for matters related to one&#39;s involvement in an LLC?

Like I need one but have no idea where to start looking for a good one. Is there something like Amazon reviews for lawyers?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1n72i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1mcoe/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What should we make of anti-white propaganda like [this](https://www.youtube.com</title><updated>2022-09-04T12:05:33Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What should we make of anti-white propaganda like [this](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvNNtBmA3SQ)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1mcoe/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1j9vg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] If the US were competent at nation building (meaning we could overthrow dictator</title><updated>2022-09-04T11:31:44Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">If the US were competent at nation building (meaning we could overthrow dictators and actually establish lasting liberal democracies), would we have a moral obligation to do it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1j9vg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in098y6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [Here&#39;s an awesome song I discovered recently. LoTR fans in particular are likel</title><updated>2022-09-04T02:30:07Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[Here&#39;s an awesome song I discovered recently. LoTR fans in particular are likely to enjoy this one.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uxfoa23skHg)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in098y6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in0149g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I finally noticed that MATE, a continuation of GNOME 2, exists. I don&#39;t know why</title><updated>2022-09-04T01:24:11Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I finally noticed that MATE, a continuation of GNOME 2, exists. I don&#39;t know why, but GNOME 2 always made me feel like my computer was a place where intelligent things should happen.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in0149g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imywh47/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I was reading about someone who was diagnosed with small intestine cancer , and </title><updated>2022-09-03T20:18:54Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I was reading about someone who was diagnosed with small intestine cancer , and one of his symptoms was he would get a lot of pain a few hours after eating, presumably due to have an obstruction, so in order to mitigate this he ate once every 24 hours . He also kept his daily calorie intake up by drinking   shakes, yet he still lost 3/lbs a week even though his calorie intake was presumably the same.  Some for people with esophagus cancer who go to a liquid diet; they lose so much weight despite consuming unlimited liquid calories. I wonder if liquid diets violate the age-old calorie-in-calorie out maxim.  Of course, some of this weight loss is due   to the cancer itself, but I wonder how much the liquid diet plays a role in this too.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imywh47/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imw006q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Men torture themselves doing pullups, because no one is nice enough to give them</title><updated>2022-09-03T04:19:42Z</updated><author><name>pmmecutepones</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Men torture themselves doing pullups, because no one is nice enough to give them the upsies they truly want.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imw006q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m se</title><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m searching for mellow upbeat music and anything with lyrics is about sex and crushes. It doesn’t *have* to be this way; I used to listen to post-rock and it was not very sexed. Hymns are rarely sexy. But I like the indie genre, I just get tired of music about girls.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10</title><updated>2022-09-03T00:33:43Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10MHz_832K_XTIDE_MultiIO_SVGA/p6083514_19777986.aspx).  It hasn&#39;t shipped yet.  But I like to be able to code on every piece of hardware I own.  So I began noodling around, trying to set up a cross coding environment today.

I started with Visual Studio Code since it&#39;s crazy flexible.  Then I set up a bunch of task to compile my ASM files using NASM, using the CPU 8086 directive and outputting as OBJ files which need to be linked.  I&#39;m under the impression 16-bit code is the default with this arrangement.  I found a free linker called ALINK which then links the OBJ files into an EXE.  Then I set up, in kind of a janky way, for the Run command to launch DOSBOX and execute it&#39;s debug command on my exe.

I still want to find a way to export my breakpoints from Visual Studio Code and import them into DOSBOX.  I see that this debug version of DOSBOX I have can import breakpoints, and NASM spits out dbg files which I **think** I can parse for the segment:offset&#39;s I&#39;ll need to breakpoint at labels in DOSBOX.  I just am not sure off the top of my head how to export the breakpoint lines from Visual Studio Code.  Oh well, some day.

Anyways, it was a fun day.  Threw together a pretty simple number guessing game program.  It&#39;s a good way to get a grip on the basics.  Reading the keyboard, processing input, converting an ascii number to binary, generating a random number, some basic math, printing to the screen.  Then cause why not, I started fucking around with linking multiple ASM files, with GLOBAL and EXTERN&#39;d functions.  Did some far calls across memory segments.  Wasn&#39;t as bad as I thought it would be.

Probably start fucking around with EGA graphics and ADLIB sound next.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated im</title><updated>2022-09-02T22:51:29Z</updated><author><name>prrk3</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated imagery? There are striking resemblances between commonly reported phenomena reported by lucid dreamers and people with above average dream recall and generated images.

The most interesting phenomenon to me is that counting and reading in dreams is impossible. Lucid dreamers use this by counting their fingers or looking at clock as their “reality check” to tell if they are dreaming or not. It seems odd to me that humans can just forget the number of fingers they have. AI generated images have a similar problem with not caring much about discrete units.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an </title><updated>2022-09-02T21:17:17Z</updated><author><name>stolen_brawnze</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an AI text-to-image generator to a state art competition and [taking home first prize.](https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/1/23332684/ai-generated-artwork-wins-state-fair-competition-colorado)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For </title><updated>2022-09-02T17:57:26Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For all our optimization/nootropics bros, what&#39;s the best way to adjust my early-bird sleep schedule to go out partying on one night or two and then go right back to my standard sleep schedule?

I&#39;m an early bird, I basically go to sleep by 10:30 at the latest and get up between 4:30 and 5:00 every day. Getting up early is important to me, I like it, I function well that way from years of farm work and crew practice growing up. But as I&#39;m getting into middle age, I find it is getting hard for me to deal with days when I&#39;m at a wedding or a party or a gala or whatever and I want to stay up later and find my body failing me. I&#39;m curious if there&#39;s any scientifically supported evidence for how to handle it beyond pounding a 5 hour energy a couple times in a night.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</title><updated>2022-09-02T15:58:31Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wi</title><updated>2022-09-02T14:14:20Z</updated><author><name>07mk</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terrence_Howard#Terryology), a form of &#34;math&#34; developed by Terrence Howard, the actor who played James Rhodes in the first *Iron Man* film before he was replaced by Don Cheadle in later films. It seems that he had an issue with the proposition that &#34;1 x 1 = 1&#34; and thus sought to disprove it; here&#39;s a quotation from an argument he claimed he had with a professor:

&amp;gt; How can it equal one? If one times one equals one that means that two is of no value because one times itself has no effect. One times one equals two because the square root of four is two, so what&#39;s the square root of two? Should be one, but we&#39;re told it&#39;s two, and that cannot be.

Apparently he had such a problem with the regular math being taught there that he dropped out of college. I don&#39;t know how much work into Terryology he&#39;s done, but he&#39;s talked about spending time constructing (physical plastic) models to prove his new &#34;math&#34; and once [Tweeted a &#34;proof&#34; of why one times one cannot equal one](https://twitter.com/terrencehoward/status/925754491881877507) in an apparent bid to appease his critics. It&#39;s only 4 pages long, but I&#39;ll admit I could only put in the effort to skim it because of how poor the quality of writing was. But to me it seems that he just lacks a fundamental ability to grasp what addition and multiplication are and ends up confusing the 2 with each other. I was reminded of a podcast I listened to many years ago wherein a physicist being interviewed mentioned how his office gets mail all the time from people claiming to have found some huge breakthrough that would revolutionize the field, and when he happened to read one of them, it showed that the writer had no understanding of momentum and velocity and kept confusing the 2.

Also, [apparently Terrence has discovered some new form of physics](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-44pljnxztg) involving hydrogen bonds that will enable a new way of flying. I don&#39;t know if this is directly related to Terryology or if it&#39;s a completely independent thing he came up with.

I don&#39;t know much about Terrence outside him being an actor, but clearly he&#39;s an extremely successful one. Say what you will about him losing out on the MCU gravy train, but being a major character in even 1 major Hollywood production like *Iron Man* is a level of success that the vast majority of actors can ever dream about. It&#39;s just fascinating to me that someone with this poor an understanding of math, to the extent that addition and multiplication are beyond his grasp, has been able to be not just this functional, but this successful in modern society. Then again, acting isn&#39;t a particularly math-heavy profession, and it&#39;s possible that he hires professionals to handle his finances. It&#39;s just, if he thinks what those professionals are doing is all false made-up bullshit, how does he trust them at all to do what&#39;s right for him?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/</title><updated>2022-09-02T13:47:43Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/cereal_boxes.html). One of my online acquaintances is good at wrangling AI art generators to get surreal stuff. Here&#39;s the rest of [his DALLE-2 gallery](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/index.html) in addition to [Midjourney](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/midjourney/index.html) and [DALLE-Mini](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e_mini/index.html) generated stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/s</title><updated>2022-09-02T12:15:55Z</updated><author><name>Indi008</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/spliced

and some short stories:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/58017/the-dumping-ground

AND some poetry:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57952/nothing-here-but-hot-air

Free to read, and somewhat unrelated to this sub, but hey it fits the fun theme, and I&#39;m somewhat trying to write rational fantasy if there is such a thing. Not sure I quite achieved that.

Anyone else here a &#34;writer&#34; who studied science or engineering with the intent of writing technically accurate fiction only to find it&#39;s much harder than you think? I never know quite enough, and when I do, no one thinks it&#39;s a real thing. I once wrote a story about a mechanic and an actual issue I faced with my car and people thought it wasn&#39;t realistic, but my complete fantasy stories are apparently completely believable.

Edit: got a joke for y&#39;all...

Why did the cat fall off the roof?



.
.
.
.



Because it lost it&#39;s mu</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Satur</title><updated>2022-09-02T08:45:10Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Saturday nights, when the next SQS sticky is just around the corner, so I never post them, saving them for the next FF sticky. Now it&#39;s Friday morning, and my head is devoid of ideas beyond going shopping for a pull-up bar and discount male fashion.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular</title><updated>2022-09-01T19:38:41Z</updated><author><name>lookingforthrowaway1</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular treatment course? 

A family member is currently experiencing an uncommon health issue on which there is limited research in the literature. I’ve found a few papers indicating that a certain treatment, although aggressive and not usually considered necessary, is 100% effective in preventing a fatal outcome. These are all peer-reviewed papers in respected academic journals written by well-credentialed researchers at reputable university medical schools. 

How can I bring this research up to my family member’s doctor without offending their ego or something? Can I bring a printout with these papers as a reference and summarizing their key points?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:08:17Z</updated><author><name>crowstep</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing.

My live-in girlfriend of one year recently told me that while she loves me, she isn&#39;t &#39;in love&#39; with me. Apparently these things are quite different for her.

Essentially, while she has loved all of her previous boyfriends, there was only one that she was &#39;in love&#39; with, who was from several years ago and not the one before me.

She told me it might take time for her to feel &#39;in love&#39;, but that if she doesn&#39;t feel it, she&#39;ll break up with me. Her parents had a nasty divorce so she&#39;s paranoid about settling down with someone who isn&#39;t her &#39;soulmate&#39;. (Not her exact words, but that was the gist of it).

Overall I feel pretty hurt by this. Saying we loved eachother seemed like a big deal to me, but apparently for her it didn&#39;t really count to the same degree. Now it feels like there&#39;s a timer on our relationship and if I don&#39;t meet some ineffable standard in her head by a certain point, it&#39;s over. I was also pretty stung by the idea that I (and apparently, all her other exes) don&#39;t measure up to the one that got away.

We spoke about it at the time of course, but the more I think about this, the more it bothers me. I&#39;m unsure whether to bring it up or just entrust my fate to the fickleness of female affection and hope that I eventually provoke more feelings in her than I am now. I can hardly guilt her into changing get feelings, so I&#39;m reluctant to bring it up at all. And if I&#39;m honest, I worry that even letting her know it bothered me would make her less attracted to me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart con</title><updated>2022-08-31T22:57:55Z</updated><author><name>ebrso</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart condition, but this was totally unexpected.  He was in his early 30s.  I had spoken to him on Sunday.  I only found out a few hours ago.  My parents are devastated.  I&#39;m not sure why I&#39;m posting this.  How do people go on after this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-31T20:08:51Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar</title><updated>2022-08-31T17:35:44Z</updated><author><name>PM_ME_UR_OBSIDIAN</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar and task list. As of today I am using Google Calendar combined with Todoist.

Todoist caveats:

- No tracking of start date, only due date. Any task with a date configured is assumed to be a discrete amount of work to be done on the day that it is due, or shortly before.
- There is no concept of prioritization within a time window. I can&#39;t ask &#34;what is the most urgent task that I need to get done within two weeks?&#34; 
- If I have a daily recurring task and I mark it as done for yesterday, then the next occurence is tomorrow. There is no concept of catching up on overdue engagements.

The app is swell though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started list</title><updated>2022-08-31T14:25:19Z</updated><author><name>GeorgeMacDonald</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started listening to it and it is a great podcast! I don’t know too much about the science of health besides the very basics so this is pretty cool. 

What episodes do you all recommend? I listened to the skin care episode (forgot which one that was). The upshot was use sunscreen daily, vitamin A cream and interestingly enough vitamin C cream on your face. I have episodes 134 and 206 downloaded which are about preventing heart disease (I have some bad family history there) and exercise respectively. 

Specifically, I am interested in the exercise ones. I do crossfit type high intensity workouts three times per week which is 3 hours of exercise. I have a feeling that some more time with lower intensity exercise would be beneficial to me in addition to what I do but that’s just my intuition not a science based thing. 

Nutrition is also an interest of mine so episodes on that would be nice too. My basic knowledge is to eat less red meat, eat more vegetables inching one’s way into a vegetable based diet (which would be tough for me as I love carbs and meat and when I only eat veggies I get super hungry shortly thereafter). 

The Revolutions podcast by Mike Duncan was also recommended and is very good.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] What is the best French to English translation software?</title><updated>2022-08-31T10:27:23Z</updated><author><name>6tjk</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">What is the best French to English translation software?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>