<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-24T00:24:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihdzr8t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [removed]</title><updated>2022-07-24T00:24:04Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[removed]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihdzr8t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihddgmx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ## Will you miss the critters?

I&#39;m making this post inspired by [this post](htt</title><updated>2022-07-23T21:33:37Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">## Will you miss the critters?

I&#39;m making this post inspired by [this post](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihatskw/) by u/ZorbaTHut. Where he posits that the sheer control we have over-the raw materials of the earth are an awe-inspiring thought and sight. I want to highlight what we sacrifice for that, to some extent. It&#39;s all speculative and shower thought laden, so I implore you to just enjoy the ride. 

I want to talk about &#34;the environment&#34;. And on discussions about the environment. I  know jackshit about any of the life sciences. But I will try to build up a discussion/argument trying to carefully bootstrap whatsoever intuition I have from other fields. 

My understanding of the word &#34;ecosystem&#34; is that it is quite literally like any other [complex system](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_system). They are highly chaotic, non linear and dynamic. There are agents, feedback loops, gains, etc. Much like the [economic system](https://www.econlib.org/archives/2017/06/yudkowsky_on_my.html), there is a [delicate](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lotka–Volterra_equations) [balance](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0006320716301185). And this not that insightful at all. Anyone who read learned about the food chain can figure this out, with a bit of thought. This might be the one topic where I diverge significantly from my fellow libertarians and right wingers. Given the the delicate balance, I am more sympathetic to laws that minimize externalities towards the natural world. 

There are plenty of object level arguments on why the environment/ecosystems should be preserved. I won&#39;t go into those because they are signal boosted plentifully. I want to have a discussion on the aesthetics of it.

#### The Asian Monsoon 

When I was a child, I used to live in a country that gets the [Asian monsoon](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1nstixjMS7A&amp;amp;ab_channel=Geodiode). For the uninitiated, it is rain of the likes you have (probably) never experienced before. I&#39;m talking more rain in a month than most European and North American cities get in a years. 

In the countryside you would be immersed in nature just leaving your house. You could barely go for a walk without stumbling into a large (4 foot long) monitor lizard, snakes, turtles, frogs and bugs, so many bugs. And I am not understating this, you could seriously just go and find any one of those animals any day. 

A significant part of my childhood consisted of just going out into the edges of the jungle and observing all the critters and sometimes trapping them in plastic jars.  Every day felt like an adventure because I wouldn&#39;t know what I would come across the next day. Everything felt for a lack of a better word &#39;alive&#39;.

Unfortunately it seems like kids a few decades down might not be able to experience that any more. The [Asian monsoon](https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20220517-the-uncertain-fate-of-asias-monsoons) is drying up. So many of these critters depended on the rain and the vegetation it brought. I would consider it a huge loss to all the kids who would have been like me, if that part of the world dries up. 

#### The Windshield phenomenon

The [Windshield phenomenon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windshield_phenomenon) is the observation that less bugs splatter into the windshields of cars than they used to. There are countless anecdotes from Europe and North America about this phenomenon happening over time. 

Yes anecdata has its shortcomings but it really does seem like the World is [losing its critters](https://e360.yale.edu/features/insect_numbers_declining_why_it_matters).  The world has lost 70% of its insect biomass in the last 50 years. I don&#39;t know why, but for some reason, finding out about this filled me with a sense of sadness that is very hard to describe. It&#39;s not that I have empathy towards insects, it&#39;s just that the world became a less vibrant place. Less insects means, less other types of plants and animals, because its all linked, obviously. Less natural beauty in the world. 

I have visited the forests of North America (North East US) in the summer recently. Ofcourse they are not the same type of forest as the ones I had in my country, but they felt very &#34;clean&#34;. The forests I grew up with had so many critters that you could hear them crawling around. The forests in North America were quite in comparison. If the windshield phenomenon explains anything, the forests in North America were probably much more lively than they are now, at some time in the near past. 

There are plenty of reasons to believe the causation is anthropogenic. 

#### North America

North America used to have [buffalo heards](http://www.ozarkbisons.com/aboutbison.php) as far as the eye could see. [Passenger pigeon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passenger_pigeon) flocks that used to cover the sky. They both don&#39;t exist anymore, the latter not at all, the former not at the level it used to. And this is  entirely because of what I would confidently assert as [unadulterated evil](https://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2016/05/the-buffalo-killers/482349/). 

Did North America in the abstract not lose something great? 

#### Europe

Europe lost 60% of its forest cover because of agriculture and development. Thankfully [its recovering](https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/AG.LND.FRST.ZS?locations=EU). 

It gives me an uneasy feeling ,a sort of &#34;are we playing with fire&#34; type of feeling, when we can just wipe out 60% of life in a continent to live ourselves. There&#39;s not much more to it, just a passing thought.


#### Concluding thoughts

I am well aware that some damage to the enviorment has to be done to progress technologically. We need to mine raw materials to make bridges, cars, and computers. Some of that will ruin some forests and some mountains. I am also well aware that not doing destroying some of nature means terrible living standards forever. I understand all that clear enough.

But I also think sometimes, what good would having tall buildings and planes means if there are no places to live or go with tall trees and bushes with bugs and lizards. Mountains with tall trees and bushes. And land with mountains. 

&#34;Save the Earth&#34; is a vacuous phrase. The Earth has been there for billions of years without us and can do fine. Yes, we need the Earth to literally live, but we also need it for other things that make life worth living right? What candle does the tallest building hold to Mt Everest if awe is to be inspired? What candle does a botanical garden hold to the Amazon rain-forest?  Is the NYC skyline more awe inspiring than the Niagara falls? Can any zoo in the world replace seeing lions hunt in the Serengeti? 

I don&#39;t have enough knowledge to assert if its all doom and gloom and the natural world is inevitibly soon to be gone forever. But I do know that we already lost a fair bit of it, and we are losing it fast.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihddgmx/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series. I&#39;m already getting half</title><updated>2022-07-23T17:52:35Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series. I&#39;m already getting half a billion dollars worth of [entertainment](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FYS5d_YUEAAPl2D?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=orig) from it, and I&#39;m not even gonna watch.

Also my deeply closeted white trash middle school boyfriend turning out to be Sauron is an acceptable twist, if a lazy and obvious one.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihcc72i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Orban says the quiet part out loud:

[Orbán: &#34;Hungarians are not a mixed race an</title><updated>2022-07-23T17:03:04Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Orban says the quiet part out loud:

[Orbán: &#34;Hungarians are not a mixed race and do not want to become one&#34;](https://dailynewshungary.com/orban-hungarians-are-not-a-mixed-race-and-does-not-want-to-become-one/)

&amp;gt; He slammed Western European countries and politicians for encouraging illegal migration and mixing their population. He said that Western-European cities were lost to the non-European population. Orbán argued that the West moved to Central Europe, suggesting that this region would be Europe’s future.

&amp;gt; He said it would be the task of “our children” to admit Western-European Christians.

&amp;gt; Migration has divided Europe, he said. “The West is split in two”, with one half comprising countries where European and non-European peoples live together. “Those countries are no longer nations,” he said.

&amp;gt;“In a spiritual sense, the West has moved to central Europe,” he said. The two halves of Europe are locked in a battle, he said. The West has rejected central Europe’s desire to allow each nation to live as they like, “and they continue to fight central Europe to change us to be like them,” he said.

The idea that you can be some kind of white nationalist state in the EU strikes me as nary but impossible. The EU accession treaty requires one to sign the dotted line where it lays out in significant detail stuff like human rights, non-discrimination and other various liberal precepts. 

I don&#39;t particularly care if Hungary wants to go off it alone, but it can&#39;t continue to take EU money and then pursue a policy antithetical to its founding principles. 

Idealism aside, it&#39;s those who hold the purse who hold the reins - and it ain&#39;t Hungary and their spiritual brethren in the West.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihcc72i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihcajra/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Leftists believe that you and I don’t really act, but are simply the puppets of </title><updated>2022-07-23T16:51:14Z</updated><author><name>CardiologistBetter39</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Leftists believe that you and I don’t really act, but are simply the puppets of invisible, bodiless actors like society, social relationships, movements, various collective forces that apparently come out of nothing but themselves, since if you try to bring them back to an actual source, you have to come back to individuals acting in their worlds and relating with each other. And that won’t do, because then you’d have to recognize not “the commune,” not “human community,” certainly not that mystical absurdity “species being,” but yourself here and now – a unique individual capable of desiring, deciding and acting – as the center and aim of your theory and practice. And a whole lot of the theorizing that communists carry out seems to be aimed precisely at avoiding this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihcajra/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihatskw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some random showerthoughts. Epistemic status: almost certainly wrong, but perhap</title><updated>2022-07-23T08:31:05Z</updated><author><name>ZorbaTHut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some random showerthoughts. Epistemic status: almost certainly wrong, but perhaps with some kernel of meaning somewhere.

I&#39;m watching an anime called Silver Spoon, which I have a lot of things to say about but this isn&#39;t really one of them. It takes place mostly at an agricultural college and, unsurprisingly, the rest of it is mostly farms. It&#39;s full of scenes like [this one](https://i.imgur.com/tGqcD7y.png).

For some reason, my thought here was that this is simultaneously very empty and very full. It&#39;s full of *things*, but not *people*. This is, from what I understand, just what farms look like; they are very equipment-heavy, and so you&#39;ll have massive enormous farms, filled with giant silos and buildings and massive machines, but with surprisingly few *people* working at any given moment.

I can&#39;t help but compare this to my mental image of, say, the 1800s. In the 1800s, you had a small room with a bed and a table, you had a set of clothes, you maybe had a few other knickknacks. But most people fundamentally didn&#39;t have much *stuff*. Even when you went to work, *per capita*, you didn&#39;t really have much *stuff*; there are plenty of photos like [this one](https://www.cmog.org/sites/default/files/images/bib_92651.jpg). Just in terms of kilograms-of-mass-of-tooling-per-person, these aren&#39;t even vaguely in the same ballpark.

In some ways, this feels like an example of what wealth *is*. Back then, iron and steel and concrete were expensive and so people didn&#39;t have much of them. Today they are, relatively speaking, cheap, and yes there&#39;s obviously rich and poor, but even *poor people* today have ownership and access to far more iron, steel, and concrete than they did in the 1800s.

A month back, an artist [posted a bunch of posters they&#39;d made inspired by brutalist imagery](https://www.reddit.com/r/architecture/comments/vbz5fe/tribute_to_italian_futurist_antonio_santelia_i/). I think these are absolutely gorgeous in a raw and lonely way. To me, *they get the same feeling across*; yes, there are tiny ant-like people next to huge monoliths of concrete and glass (and iron and steel). But those monoliths are built *for them*, they&#39;re built for what they do for those people and for other people. Look at how much concrete each person has harnessed to their own benefit! Look at how many *tons* of raw material that is! The Hoover Dam powers 1.3 million households and weighs 6.6 million tons; that&#39;s *five tons of material per household*, just for the material used to provide their personal electricity!

Somewhat more directly is [this image](https://i.imgur.com/mwQG4nB.jpg), same artist. The building&#39;s purpose is unknown and the image is ambiguous enough that many other people will see this and get different things out of it. But to me, this is an apartment building; the person lives in a towering edifice of metal and glass, and even if you assume a small part of it is hers, this is still *wealth*, this is the ability to spend resources on that scale, the ability to *have* things and *use* them to your own benefit.

I kinda like this metric because in some ways it is very objective. It does not require that you hire *people*, because the cost of a &#34;person&#34; shifts wildly over time; it does not require that you pin anything to a shifting basket of technology and consumer goods. If concrete becomes cheaper *then that is still wealth*.

Perhaps we should measure a human not by the size of their wallet, nor by the size of their brain or muscles, but by the mass of steel and concrete harnessed for their benefit. And by that metric we have become very wealthy indeed.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihatskw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih9i22f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There is a lot of discussion of the the Russian invasion of Ukraine in a top lev</title><updated>2022-07-23T00:43:51Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There is a lot of discussion of the the Russian invasion of Ukraine in a top level thread from a couple of days ago with lots of claims of who thought what and when with only one real objectively verifiable claim referenced (that Russia would control more territory after a certain one month period), so I would like to give everyone an opportunity to make some falsifiable predictions with a percentage of certainty and a date and means to determine if the prediction was accurate. 

For example, I believe that their is a 35% chance that Russia totally controls either Slovyansk or Bakhmut by September 21, 2022, as assessed by the Institute for the Study of War at understandingwar.org.

Anyone else?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih9i22f/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih8eh3z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] As you may have heard [Biden has the coof](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qrJpJ</title><updated>2022-07-22T20:03:04Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">As you may have heard [Biden has the coof](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qrJpJb5Bih4)

What&#39;s interesting is that the gas seems to have completely run out of covid as a scary monster.  The press team is trying to treat this as if it&#39;s a major story that they need to provide updates on - Karine gave a long explanation of his current condition, and earlier today Biden gave a [incredibly bizarre](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IhR0w2eFFSI) talk about gas prices that seems intended to sortof play up how sick he is.  Why in gods name does this look like he&#39;s reporting from a cave in Afghanistan?  They literally built him an entire game show set to do these sorts of things from in the white house.  My guess is that they&#39;re trying to build some sort of story of him overcoming a challenge.

But: 

* [cnn isn&#39;t even apparently carrying the story](http://cnn.com).  Instead they&#39;re talking about Bannon being found guilty of not participating in the show trial about January 6th.

* [MSNBC is the same](https://www.msnbc.com/).  Nothing about Biden and covid, main story is about Bannon.

* [Nytimes is the same](https://www.nytimes.com/)

I&#39;m sure I could keep going.

Is this the final nail in the covid coffin?  Are we really actually done with this stuff?  The president of the US, a decrepit, 80 year old man who appears to be in incredibly poor health, gets it and nobody seems to even care.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih8eh3z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih8dtll/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I frequently argue in this space that the West, and particularly America, are no</title><updated>2022-07-22T19:58:44Z</updated><author><name>ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I frequently argue in this space that the West, and particularly America, are not as divided as we seem. That the founding ideals of our civilization are not dead, that conflict theory is wrong, and that excessive amounts of time, effort and intellect are expended curating collections of the ugliest stories the internet can find to justify visiting more harm on our fellow country(wo)men. I *still* can&#39;t think of a way to push back against this cultural rot, this inverse of CCP-propaganda where everything is terrible instead of everything being peachy, beyond highlighting examples where this isn&#39;t the case. While my last attempt convinced [approximately nobody,](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/i6yuis/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_10_2020/g1npsjq/?context=999) I&#39;ve been urged by multiple people to be better lately. So hop on buckoes and buckettes, we&#39;re about to take another spin on the merry-go-round.

[Four days ago at a mall in Indiana](https://www.foxnews.com/us/indiana-police-say-good-samaritan-took-out-mall-shooter-15-seconds-landed-8-of-10-shots), 20 year old Jonathan Sapirman opened fire with a rifle, killing three and injuring two more. He was &#39;neutralized&#39; by bystander-with-a-gun Elisjsha Dicken within 15 seconds. Here&#39;s the [front page article](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/18/us/greenwood-indiana-mall-shooting.html) the NYT ran:

&amp;gt;By that time, the gunman, identified by the police as Jonathan Douglas Sapirman, 20, had already killed three people and injured two others. But the deadly spree on Sunday was cut short by a 22-year-old bystander carrying a handgun while shopping with his girlfriend.  

&amp;gt;Chief Jim Ison of the Greenwood Police Department called the bystander’s actions “nothing short of heroic,” identifying him as Elisjsha Dicken of Seymour, Ind.
&amp;gt;“He engaged the gunman from quite a distance with a handgun, was very proficient in that, very tactically sound, and, as he moved to close in on the suspect, he was also motioning for people to exit behind him,” Chief Ison said at a news conference where he described surveillance video footage of the shooting.
&amp;gt;“This young man, Greenwood’s good Samaritan, acted within seconds, stopping the shooter and saving countless lives,” Mayor Mark Myers said on Monday.

There&#39;s no reference in the article to gun control, nothing about the NRA/gun lobby, nothing about the fact that the shooter [posted an image of a nazi officer on 4chan](https://www.thedailybeast.com/greenwood-mall-shooter-jonathan-sapirman-appeared-to-post-chilling-message-on-4chan-with-nazi-imagery?ref=scroll) prior to the shooting. The &#39;White Nationalist nazi probably-Trump supporting incel shoots 3 hispanic people&#39; story practically writes itself here. There&#39;s a short paragraph about the victims that&#39;s almost an afterthought:

&amp;gt;The Johnson County coroner identified the victims, who were all from Indianapolis, as Victor Gomez, 30; and a husband and wife, Pedro Pineda, 56, and Rosa Mirian Rivera de Pineda, 37. Two additional people were injured: a 22-year-old woman hospitalized with a leg wound and a 12-year-old girl struck by a bullet fragment.

It&#39;s mostly just glowing praise for the good samaritan who shot the kid. There&#39;s no reference to statistics that most mass shootings aren&#39;t stopped by bystanders (although they did [run another article later that made that claim)](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/19/us/armed-bystander-indiana-mall-shooting.html). They also ran another [largely neutral story](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/17/us/greenwood-mall-shooting-indiana.html) along with a video of [police officers praising the bystander](https://www.nytimes.com/video/us/100000008449377/indiana-mall-shooting-suspect.html). 

Fox News ran a story with this headline: [&#39;Media downplays ‘good Samaritan’ narrative following Indiana shooting, firearms experts weigh in&#39;](https://www.foxnews.com/media/media-downplays-good-samaritan-narrative-following-indiana-shooting-firearms-experts-weigh-in), because I suppose the NYT coverage was too biased. 

The substance to their accusations of criticism:

&amp;gt;The New York Times also weighed on the debate in a piece written by Richard Fausset, Eliza Fawcett and Serge F. Kovaleski, acknowledging that although Dicken’s actions were &#34;heroic,&#34; they were also a &#34;statistical unicorn.&#34; Citing an expert on gun policy at UCLA, they wrote most states that require a permit to carry a firearm do not require active shooter response training, and that if good guys with guns was the answer, training would be required across the board. 

A point which does not seem to be rebutted in the article. This is the closest I can find to a refutation:

&amp;gt;Cam Edwards, the editor of Second Amendment news site Bearing Arms, claimed that media coverage is simply biased when it comes to concealed carry, and more specifically, the idea that armed citizens &#34;can and do save lives.&#34; He also stressed the importance of proper gun training.  
&amp;gt;&#34;Every situation is different, of course, but generally speaking if someone has the means and the training to engage an individual who&#39;s actively trying to murder as many innocent people as possible I don&#39;t see any reason why we wouldn&#39;t want them to act as quickly as possible,&#34; he told Fox News Digital.  
&amp;gt;Smith too encouraged proper gun training, and said that the idea of a &#34;good guy with a gun&#34; argument is definitely &#34;situation specific.&#34; Nevertheless, she urged gun owners who heard of the Indiana shooting to get the proper resources, and not to irresponsibly dive into an active shooter situation.   

I suspect I&#39;m going to get the same answers as last time, but...what more do you want from the legacy media? They run this (in my opinion) almost right-slanted story and still get smeared as being ideologically biased. Red tribe still hates the fake news NYT and will never read this anyways, which serves Trump and the Republican party well. (Un)Surprisingly, this incident and the media coverage hasn&#39;t been discussed around here, so you aren&#39;t rewarding them for it. Why not? Why is it so rare that this space highlights a good deed or a de-escalation as opposed to dancing around the twitter bonfire like [Jack&#39;s tribe](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lord_of_the_Flies) and feeding on accelerationism?

Maybe when you read the next hot take trashing this or that outlet (including Fox news!), consider the many stories like this one that fly under the radar.

Apologies in advance, but I&#39;ll be busy this weekend and likely won&#39;t participate much in the comments.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih8dtll/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih8alu4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] After not listening to it for several years, I&#39;ve recently revisited &#34;Vessels&#34; b</title><updated>2022-07-22T19:37:34Z</updated><author><name>nagilfarswake</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">After not listening to it for several years, I&#39;ve recently revisited &#34;Vessels&#34; by the Australian melodic death metal band Be&#39;lakor. It is a brilliant record; I think it&#39;s one of the crowning jewels of the genre both musically and in lyrical poetry.

It&#39;s a concept album, tracing the journey of the energy of a photon of light. Each song is its own self-contained story, starting with the entrance of this bit of energy into a life and ending with the extinguishing of that life&#39;s light and the energy&#39;s departure. It starts in the fusion forges of the sun, in [An Ember&#39;s Arc](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IyuDOVm8TG4):

&amp;gt; This cascade of embers,

&amp;gt; Fused into a star&#39;s ignition

&amp;gt; A crucible for their collapse,

&amp;gt; Seething crux of its ambition

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; The axiom of this expanse,

&amp;gt; Unrelenting pressure

&amp;gt; Every moment, in each place,

&amp;gt; Collisions beyond measure

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; An ordinary pair that met,

&amp;gt; Whilst merging into one,

&amp;gt; Heaved and spat a mote of light,

&amp;gt; Adrift within the Sun

and it ends in the funeral pyre of a man in [The Smoke of Many Fires](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ARI0XyTiips):

&amp;gt; Like billions before him regardless of form

&amp;gt; It ended as chance had decided

&amp;gt; So briefly contained an inferno&#39;s refrain

&amp;gt; Having powered and angered and guided

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; At the heart of the blaze awareness dissolved

&amp;gt; Light ascended devoid of desire

&amp;gt; From a trail intertwined life and death strewn behind

&amp;gt; To the stars it returned from the fire</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih8alu4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih7pji9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m taking a break from my ADHD meds.  I switched to 10mg XRs about a year ago, </title><updated>2022-07-22T17:20:47Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m taking a break from my ADHD meds.  I switched to 10mg XRs about a year ago, and after taking an accidental break from them for a weekend, found my depression lifting a surprising amount.  Time passes much faster, I find it easier to sleep.  I find it easier to think creatively.  My performance at work is suffering, but coffee+nicotine+weak weed seems to be getting me through this week compared to last week.  I feel less helpless anxiety when faced with tasks.  I feel better able to keep myself company.

I still hate my life, but the experience of living it is less irritating to me now.  

I&#39;m going to see a different, less-intrusive doctor and get switched back to regular release, maybe up the daily dosage to 20, but see if I can get by only taking 10 or 15.  I just know the XRs aren&#39;t for me.

Has anyone else had similar experiences with XRs vs regulars?  Did you find an alternative to Adderall?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih7pji9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih7phca/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What’s the simplest, most barebones game you can think of? I can’t think of anyt</title><updated>2022-07-22T17:20:24Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What’s the simplest, most barebones game you can think of? I can’t think of anything simpler than Snake.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih7phca/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Open question: Is there any way to figure out how much, if any, of the oil price</title><updated>2022-07-22T16:44:22Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Open question: Is there any way to figure out how much, if any, of the oil price increases we&#39;ve seen could be due to price gouging rather than inflation/supply shocks?

It’s notoriously tricky to figure out where the line between ordinary supply and demand ends and potential price gouging can begin, but I hear accusations flying everywhere so I’d like us to take a try.

While much of the economy looks like it&#39;s facing a downturn, oil companies are still recording record profits, enough so that Congress passed the [Consumer Fuel Price Gouging Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/7688/text) and [President Biden directly addressed a letter](https://www.cnbc.com/2022/06/15/biden-tells-oil-companies-in-letter-well-above-normal-refinery-profit-margins-are-not-acceptable.html) to the seven largest companies addressing their suspiciously high margins.

There are obviously supply shocks constraining the volume of petroleum products which would raise the price, but the President argues the increase is beyond what’s justifiable based on the historical record:

&amp;gt;“Since the beginning of the year, refiners’ margins for refining gasoline and diesel have tripled, and are currently at their highest levels ever recorded,” he said. Biden noted that the last time oil was trading at $120 per barrel the average price of gas at the pump was about $4.25 per gallon. Today, gas prices are 75 cents higher, and diesel prices are 90 cents higher.”

Oil companies respond in turn by saying that they’re already operating near or at max capacity, and increasing refinery capacity takes time.  You can’t just snap your fingers and make more oil during a supply shock. . . and I guess it’s not their fault if that also happens to make them a lot of extra money in the meantime? (As an aside, is there any way to actually verify whether refineries are at max capacity, or do we kind of have to take them at their word?)

[This article](https://www.courthousenews.com/evidence-of-gasoline-price-gouging-is-very-hard-to-find/) at least argues that the price gouging story doesn’t line up, because oil and gas companies have relatively little control over prices at the pump, and gas stations are actually doing poorly financially. This seems to be substantiated [by a chart here](https://realeconomy.rsmus.com/oil-prices-and-price-gouging-deconstructing-the-price-of-gas/) that shows the breakdown of profit margins across producers, refiners and gas stations. But doesn’t this leave open the possibility that oil and gas companies are charging inflated prices to intermediaries, while refineries and gas stations are forced to resell at the lowest feasible point to keep business, thus keeping their profit margins tight while the producers grow fat?

From the courthouse piece:

&amp;gt;Although the U.S. is the world’s largest oil producer, all U.S. companies together account for only 14.5% of global oil production and thus even if they all somehow worked together they would have a very limited ability to sway global markets. The 13 OPEC countries, by contrast, produce a combined 44% of the world’s oil. Russia accounts for 13.1%, and Canada produces 5.8%, according to the U.S. Energy Information Administration.

Of course, factor in that Russia, Iran and Venezuela are out of the picture for US markets and China (normally about equal to Russia at around 15%) is running at reduced capacity.  Maybe all this increases the ability of the American companies to influence price changes, but not by a gigantic amount – it still wouldn’t come close to OPEC’s market share even minus Iran, and we would still need evidence that American companies were behaving in a cartelized manner.

The second hand evidence that does exist seems to be, as noted by the President, that current pump prices are above what they historically have been for the current barrel price, as well as the fact that pump prices didn’t fall in response to the March dip in oil prices (though [this piece argues](https://www.courthousenews.com/evidence-of-gasoline-price-gouging-is-very-hard-to-find/) that oil prices generally rise quickly and fall more slowly).  Furthermore, the oil companies’ complaints that they’re operating at max capacity seem a little self serving given that they don’t actually seem to be investing in digging new wells; instead that money is going right to the fat cats on top:

&amp;gt;A more significant allegation is that U.S. oil drillers are taking advantage of the situation by limiting their production to keep prices high. Instead of plowing profits back into drilling, Exxon, Chevron, BP and Shell spent more than $44 billion on stock buybacks and dividends in 2021 and have pledged up to $30 billion or more in buybacks this year

Why is this?

&amp;gt;The real reason that oil companies aren’t madly drilling, the Dallas Fed says, is because shareholders don’t want them to. After years of aggressively expanding operations that produced boom-and-bust cycles — including enormous losses during the pandemic when oil prices briefly turned negative — shareholders are demanding that energy companies focus on highly profitable assets rather than speculative new ones. And even though prices have spiked recently, especially after the Ukraine invasion, new drilling is time-consuming, and it’s not clear how long the current cycle will last.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In addition, with trillions of dollars flowing into socially conscious ESG (environmental, social and governance) mutual funds, investors are signaling that they want companies to move away from fossil fuels.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;“So far — and I am on the front lines, I see this every day — there is no interest to go in this space,” said Jeffrey Currie, global head of commodities research at Goldman Sachs.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;On the regulatory front, although the Biden administration claims that it’s not holding producers back, environmental and other regulations have made it “nearly impossible to build a new refinery in the United States,” said Jay Hatfield, CEO of Infrastructure Capital Management.

There’s a lot to unpack here.  I am not a finance guy but I guess it seems a little hard to believe that there is “no interest to go in this space” during an extended and indefinite period to wrest control of a huge market share and make a ton of money, but maybe the future really is so uncertain that just makes sense.  As for the claim that regulations have made it impossible to build in the US, we [do still seem to be building them](https://www.eia.gov/tools/faqs/faq.php?id=29&amp;amp;t=6) , though I have no idea if this is considered a bad rate of construction and would like to hear more from others.

Lastly, as a side note, all of the above can be true and still basically align with (at least a watered down version of) what critics are saying: oil companies aren’t investing in boosting production capacity because they’re focused on doing what makes the most possible money for their shareholders rather than what could actually bring prices down at the pump for Americans.  Perhaps that’s just capitalism working as it’s supposed to, but many would say that’s the problem.

Anyone have light they can shed?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih704dz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The January 6th hearings are still occurring, and I want to talk about them.

Th</title><updated>2022-07-22T14:36:53Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The January 6th hearings are still occurring, and I want to talk about them.

This was the &#34;bombshell&#34; video from yesterday where, apparently during some outtakes, Trump refused to say that the election was over: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kih5hGkx5-M

Except...this sounds a lot more like he is just critiquing the phrasing of a speech than anything else. 

I&#39;m reminded of this classic Simpsons clip: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SqDP8SnPVA0

The other &#34;bombshell&#34; is Josh Hawley &#34;fleeing&#34;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9rDGnMHNs_Y

Except, again: no he isn&#39;t?  This looks like he&#39;s taking a few quick steps probably to catch up with somebody on the escalator, and then walking next to them to chat.

I guess what I&#39;m frustrated by is just *how blatant* they are now being about this.  There isn&#39;t even the veil of an attempt to honestly present anything that has happened here.

What I&#39;m concerned about here is: what happens when the republicans take back control of the government?  What happens if *Trump* wins the presidency in 2024?  They&#39;ve spent the last 6 year pumping out various conspiracy theories about Russian collusion, and now &#34;insurrection&#34;.  It feels like laying the groundwork for something.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih704dz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih6qjeu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I was laid off for the first time in my professional career this week. My (previ</title><updated>2022-07-22T13:30:11Z</updated><author><name>STLizen</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I was laid off for the first time in my professional career this week. My (previous) company dropped about 30% of its workforce.

All in all, it isn&#39;t so bad. They paid good severance and it looks like the labor market is still pretty strong in my area (software engineering). I will also likely get a significant pay bump in my next position.

And yet the entire process has just kinda left my feeling crummy. I (obviously) knew that this sort of thing can happen but the immediate impact of my career and (short term) livelihood being in the hands of someone I don&#39;t know -- where I am just basically a row on a spreadsheet that they&#39;re washing their hands of -- does not feel good. I also really liked the people I worked with (and this seems really hard to screen for ahead of time IMO, more of a crapshoot) and we worked remotely throughout the country, so will likely not really every see one another again. 

My life is pretty hectic at home with a young child at the moment but I definitely want to start thinking about diversifying my income stream outside of just one job.

Not sure the point of this post, just venting I guess.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih6qjeu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih6gzap/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some of the more [hilariously stupid things](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gje</title><updated>2022-07-22T12:12:45Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some of the more [hilariously stupid things](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gje39I7pzuc) to be said on the floor of congress regarding firearms (apologies for the clickbait title). 

In which we see the bad faith, bad education and bad legislating process on display. The short historical sequence goes like this: 

1: After the Las Vegas shooting (in which the gunman owned but did not use a weapon with a bump stock), Trump directed the ATF to reclassify bump stocks as &#34;machine guns&#34;, a legal move which erases the distinction between semi- and full-automatic firearms. No longer is the dividing line &#34;one shot per pull of the trigger&#34;. Now the official position of the ATF is that a machine gun is any gun that can be fired quickly (undefined). [Jerry&#39;s](https://youtu.be/0FbUMqoyjDw?t=48) gonna need a tax stamp!

2: With bump stocks banned, but the legal fight only beginning and nobody turning them in, they turn to pistol braces, another legal-loophole device for a different law. In essence, these allow people who live in states that ban or heavily restrict SBRs (short-barreled rifles) to have a similar gun that is classified legally as a pistol. Sold as a device for disabled people, this is rarely how they are used, it&#39;s just a stock by another name, but legally distinct to keep from violating the NFA. 

3: So the anti-gun position has been to try to get the pistol braces banned not for being an end-run around the NFA, but for being a machine gun! This, despite the fact that there is zero way for a pistol brace to increase the rate of fire over a regular stock, if anything the opposite. 

For non-gun-people, it&#39;s a bit like if we banned sports cars for being too fast, then reclassified ten-speed bikes as sports cars, then banned bicycle shorts for being a turbo-charger.  So, the next time someone says the words &#34;common sense gun control&#34;, do me a favor and remember this bit. This is &#34;common sense&#34;.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih6gzap/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih683n9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Seeing liberal sex educators cast in a bad light has me thinking about my own ex</title><updated>2022-07-22T10:40:56Z</updated><author><name>gemmaem</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Seeing liberal sex educators cast in a bad light has me thinking about my own experiences, growing up in a country where sex education in schools isn’t nearly as controversial, and with a mother who was always pretty frank about these things. In some ways I’m a native of a culture in which the changes wrought on society by widely available contraception are accepted and taken for granted. The details of how to adjust to such changes are still playing out, but the broad strokes were laid down before I was born. I grew up, not in the absence of a traditional structure around sex, but in the *presence* of a structure that replaces that older one.

The value system that shaped my childhood sex education was one that wanted me to know about my body and to live in it confidently and without feelings of shame about any part of it. I also understood that society, and my parents, wanted me to avoid sexual coercion and avoid coercing others; avoid having sex too young and avoid getting pregnant before I wanted to. I knew my parents didn’t really approve of casual sex and I also knew they’d be very worried if I were to get married to someone I hadn’t already had sex with.

I don’t think that worldview was perfect; I have criticisms of it from both directions. But I also know that there were places where it succeeded beautifully. There were, indeed, aspects of it that were of incalculable value. The fact that my mother went out of her way not to communicate discomfort when I wanted to know about my body, as a preschooler, really *did* give me a foundational happy confidence. It meant that I could absorb other norms around privacy and courtesy to others as an overlay on that base layer; the shame doesn’t go all the way down. That’s honestly a priceless thing to have.

Puberty classes when we were all eleven years old or so were also really good. It honestly hadn’t occurred to me that people in more conservative parts of the USA might not get these until I casually mentioned them to my husband. I hadn’t quite realised that people would classify them as sex education. Admittedly, there were aspects of them that were related to sex: we learned about erections as well as periods. But most of what we learned was structured around “your body is about to get weird, don’t freak out” and “your peers’ bodies are also going to be changing, it is going to be weird for them, be nice.” The latter message is why it was really helpful that they didn’t separate us by gender. “Adolescent boys get erections for all manner of reasons, you don’t have to read too much into it” is a message with two target audiences. (The part where erections are also theoretically relevant to sex was mentioned before *very* swiftly moving on. I absorbed this fact with interest. I do not think I was harmed by it.)

By contrast, the high school lessons that *were* referred to as “sex education” honestly felt a bit embarrassing and useless. Sure, I learned something from seeing a condom demonstrated, even if I, for one, was not going to need that lesson for a good long while. Aside from that, though, I think by then we all knew everything we were being told about the mechanics of sex. I also knew pretty much everything they told us about STDs and contraceptives, either by hearing it from my mother or by reading about it. I’m too old for consent to have been on the syllabus, though I know that is changing in a lot of places, but I can easily imagine it being taught just as uselessly, if the overall atmosphere of detached tension hasn’t changed.

Unlike “puberty class,” when we learned “sex education,” we knew that this was something controversial and politically contested, and it showed in the structure of the lesson. Puberty classes felt *human*. We talked about feelings. Mostly unpleasant feelings of adolescent discomfort, admittedly, but we talked about them. Sex education did not talk about feelings, not really. It made the lessons both less engaging and less useful. Yet I know that everything I might have liked them to include would have political valence of one kind or another.

If I could go back in time and construct the lesson myself, I would include the way that sex means different things to different people. The way you can control which meanings you give it, to some extent, but you can’t control the meanings given to it by other people — you can only do your best to take them into account. I’d discuss emotional intimacy. How it’s common (not compulsory, just common) for sex to work better when there is an underlying emotional rapport. How sex can sometimes *induce* emotional rapport. How sex can feel wrong when you don’t have the right kind of understanding of one another; how the exact type of necessary understanding/intimacy can vary from person to person and doesn’t have to follow a specific formula. How it’s good to pull back and re-think when something feels off; how to accept when your partner needs to pull back and re-think.

A lot of these statements apply across worldviews to some extent. Unfortunately, the details are likely to be contested on both sides by a conservative establishment that wants to say that sex *does* have one correct meaning and one correct set of circumstances, and by a liberal establishment that fears setting norms of any kind, and doesn’t necessarily trust the ability of open-ended structural guidance to empower people to understand themselves and others. So we get a sex education that eschews subjectivity on this most personal of topics.

The easiest way to allow that subjectivity back in is to narrow the audience to a group of people that does have a set of shared values — hence, for example, the [Our Whole Lives](https://www.uua.org/re/owl) (OWL) curriculum put together by the Unitarian Universalists. Another strategy is private classes for young people whose parents are ideologically aligned with the teacher. And, of course, there are books and websites which are free to write whatever they like. [Scarleteen](https://www.scarleteen.com) was quite well known in my circles, as a young adult.

It’s no surprise that small, private classes have come in for some of the worst criticism from the likes of Chris Rufo. Compared to a centralised curriculum like OWL, there is going to be greater underlying variance giving rise to more outliers. Compared to a book or a website, there is going to be greater ambiguity in the available materials, allowing more room for fearmongering.

Rufo’s exploitation of ambiguity is particularly effective because the clarifications that it forces from people are still controversial. A large proportion of his audience is unlikely to be pacified by assurances that liberal sexual norms are being adhered to. Not only do they disagree with those norms, they may not even have a clear sense of what such norms would consist of in the first place. Caught on the back foot, his targets can end up protesting about what they *don’t* do (e.g. touching children’s genitals) instead of explaining the positive good they are aiming for (e.g. reducing shame by not making a fuss if children want to touch their own genitals).

I think it’s a real shame when the positive case for liberal sexual norms gets lost in the outrage. An education based on those norms can provide comfort in your own skin, confidence in your understanding of your body, and consideration towards others. Adults promote liberal values because they care about the children and young people who will be guided by them.

There was really only ever one sex education experience that I had that was uncomfortable in a disturbing sort of way, rather than in an awkward sort of way. We had I separate curriculum, again when we were eleven or twelve or so, about sexual abuse. It mostly consisted of a series of stories; the last one was fairly intense. Not that it was overly explicit, but it managed to be remarkably clear about the social dynamics. I remember the ending: how the child’s mother was angry with her for going along with it, how the child protested that she hadn’t known any better and had been polite as she was taught, how the mother apologised and agreed that it wasn’t the child’s fault. I remember that the story as a whole gave me a small inkling into how abuse could happen. I remember thinking it was hard to hear, but understanding why it might be important.

That’s the one truly disturbing thing that they taught us, and I get why adults would want a lot of care to be taken with those sorts of lessons. But you know what it wasn’t? It wasn’t grooming. It was, in fact, very much the opposite.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih683n9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5toir/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] tl;dr: Germany notices its &#34;13/52&#34; situation, but it&#39;s far less clear than it se</title><updated>2022-07-22T07:33:05Z</updated><author><name>Southkraut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">tl;dr: Germany notices its &#34;13/52&#34; situation, but it&#39;s far less clear than it seems.

Disclaimer: I&#39;m getting all my numbers and data interpretation on this one from an article by Junge Freiheit, a notoriously partisan and poorly-regarded right-wing newspaper. It&#39;s the only article on the topic I found that&#39;s not paywalled, and I haven&#39;t the motivation to actually read [the 50-page report](https://www.bka.de/DE/AktuelleInformationen/StatistikenLagebilder/Lagebilder/KriminalitaetImKontextVonZuwanderung/KriminalitaetImKontextVonZuwanderung_node.html). I&#39;m going to assume that they don&#39;t outright misread the data, though there&#39;s probably much in the report that doesn&#39;t fit their narrative.

The German Federal Criminal Police Office recently published their 2021 Federal Crime Report In The Context Of Migration. Here are some CW-relevant numbers.

For violent and sexual crime, there were 40593 German victims of migrant perpetrators, and 11107 crimes with migrant victims and at least one German perpetrator. According to JF, this means that in violent crime between Germans and migrants, migrants were to blame for 78.5% all cases and Germans for 21.5%. Rape sees migrants as rapists in 95.4% of all cases. For murder, it&#39;s 85.7% versus 14.3%.

JF notes that for this report, anyone with a German passport was considered German, and that this includes three quarters of the famous arab crime families in Germany. Presumably this is meant to get the reader to imagine that the numbers might be even more outrageously in disfavor of migrants, but doesn&#39;t that work both ways? Wouldn&#39;t this also wrongly consider foreigners with German passports German victims of foreigner-on-German violence when it is in fact foreigner-on-foreigner?

At this point I&#39;m left wondering what this report is even good for. I briefly skimmed it and it seems that it purely concerns itself with &#34;migrants&#34; in the sense of asylum seekers, official refugees, registered illegal immigrants and the like. Ever since the German cathedral adopted &#34;migrant&#34; as a term describing, in effect, &#34;anyone who can and does excuse himself as not-German in any way&#34;, the term has been seen as somewhat broader than how this report applies it.

I don&#39;t really have a point here. It seems this particular newspaper was eager to construe this report as somewhat equivalent to the famous FBI crime statistics, but it seems to me to fall flat because the situation in Germany lacks any clear black/white distinction.

Sorry for the ramble. It seemed relevant, but I fail to make much of it.

I seems obvious to me at ground level that foreigners are very much more likely to be violent than Germans, and that no matter how much you muddy up the distinction this core truth is evident on observation, but I doubt we&#39;ll ever see useful statistics verifying or contradicting this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5toir/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih5t22k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So last week I jumped on a ferry and spent the day touring various sites around </title><updated>2022-07-22T07:25:12Z</updated><author><name>charizard_monster</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So last week I jumped on a ferry and spent the day touring various sites around the D Day landings. 

This was partly designed as a bonding experience with my dad and partly because it feels to me like the liberation of France is arguably Western democracy’s finest hour.

In short, I’d recommend the trip. A number of the sites are extremely high quality and clearly received considerable investment from the US government. I almost skipped it, but I’m glad I stopped at the [cemetery at Omaha beach ](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normandy_American_Cemetery_and_Memorial). The grounds are beautiful, and I found the experience of seeing the graves of so many young men surprisingly moving.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih5t22k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5eokf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I want to post something I have thinking about for a while. Just a few caveats, </title><updated>2022-07-22T04:44:56Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I want to post something I have thinking about for a while. Just a few caveats, this is not a ban evasion. I used to post at the SSC forum but got bored with the culture war and deleted my old account. I only created this account because I wanted to post stuff to the Black Company subreddit (shout out to u/mcjunker) on a reread and I&#39;m now sucked back into this shitty site.

That being said, I have a theory about what makes people successful in today&#39;s economy. And slight background on myself: I have a CS degree from a top 50 school but at this point in my career I&#39;m just a glorified sys admin. I&#39;d probably bomb a FAANG interview but I feel like I could get that job if I did leet code for a few months.

Now to my theory. People in my life that are non-technical always ask me how I know so much stuff. To them I&#39;m an expert in everything, especially at my work. I have my hands in pretty much everything at work that&#39;s important in IT so I interact with these people all the time. Plus I&#39;m not rude to non-technical people like most STEM lords are so people always go to me because I&#39;m not going to be rude to them for not knowing something.

I&#39;m not a brilliant person and nothing I do is impressive. BUT my one skill that I have is that I&#39;ll just go learn something if I don&#39;t know it. If for example security buys a new messaging gateway, I&#39;ll just look through their documentation and learn all the ways we can automate stuff. When we buy new software, I&#39;ll just go look at their documentation and play around with it until I get what I want. I recently had to learn C# for a new product we bought, and mostly what I did was just play around wit their API and ask people on SO if I ran into any issues. I was just as confused as they were, but I actually just followed through and just messed with it until I got it working.

To contrast this, my mom has a PhD and is briliant but she just gives up on anything technical after 5 minutes. I contrast this with a woman I work with who is a high level engineer. In the 90&#39;s she got annoyed that she couldn&#39;t get certain data as an accountant and taught herself programming just to solve issues then became a software engineer and is now a millionaire and a director of software engineering at our company. She just was persistent in learning things until she got what she wanted. 

Essentially, the &#34;skill&#34; is how long you&#39;ll persist if the issue is difficult. It&#39;s why people drop out of engineering programs because they have trouble with integrals. Another example I&#39;ll give is a woman I worked with who was having issue with SharePoint. She opened a ticket with us and insisted she be on any emails with Microsoft. She ended up becoming an expert in SharePoint for our company and got the certs and now doubled her salary working as a SharePoint admin for a credit card company. She used me as a reference.

So my point is that intelligence isn&#39;t necessarily that important for an IT or programming career. What you need is to be comfortable being uncomfortable not knowing things and just learning it. Looking at documentation and just playing around with it until you know it. That&#39;s the only reason people at my work think I&#39;m smart is because I&#39;ll just play around with stuff until I get it. I&#39;ll just make an appointment to meet the team that we are able to learn from with their company. That&#39;s it. I&#39;m not some super smart guy. I just have the persistence and ability to not know something and not be embarrassed for not knowing it.

Has anyone else noticed this and used it for their career? People think I&#39;m really smart and it&#39;s not the case. I just go out of my way to learn things. Maybe it&#39;s because I have a CS degree so I learned how to learn, but it feels like most people&#39;s problems with tech is that they just give up quickly. Everything is online if you want to learn it. And how to we instill this in people? It seems to just be a personality trait. As I mentioned before, my colleague became a SharePoint expert on her spare time when she was an accountant and became I high level admin from self taught stuff. This isn&#39;t rocket science, you just need to be persistent and just take the time to learn it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5eokf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4w2le/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] China&#39;s  SMIC has started shipping domestically produced [7nm microchips](https:</title><updated>2022-07-22T02:06:09Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">China&#39;s  SMIC has started shipping domestically produced [7nm microchips](https://semianalysis.substack.com/p/chinas-smic-is-shipping-7nm-foundry).

This means that they&#39;re the third most advanced chip manufacturer, behind only Samsung in Korea and TSMC in Taiwan. Taiwan and Samsung are both on 5nm and introducing 3nm. Global Foundries is the top Euro-American fab and straggles far behind at 12nm.

Apparently China&#39;s 7nm chips are qualitatively inferior to TSMC/Samsung 7nm since the US is still blocking technology transfers of the special ultraviolet etching technology you need for better production. This may constrain them somewhat in the future. 

However, the situation at present is Samsung &amp;gt; TSMC &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  SMIC &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; everyone else. Samsung got to 3nm first, which upset the usual order of TSMC being number 1. As far as I can tell, all the big players can design chips, it&#39;s only manufacturing that&#39;s seriously difficult. How long will the UV tech sanctions hold back China? They have no shortage of money or brainpower. Let&#39;s also consider that our active sabotage of Chinese semiconductors is somehow less damaging than whatever we did to our own industries. Why is it that China is still ahead of our own fabs?

Contra others in the previous thread who argued that China isn&#39;t a serious threat to US/Western hegemony, I maintain that China is an extremely strong challenger the likes of which we&#39;ve never seen. They have unparalleled industrial scale - they&#39;ve significantly outpaced US naval shipbuilding for years now. When it comes to steel, cars, chemicals, HSR, solar panels and ports they&#39;re well ahead of any Western country. This is what we should expect from a country with a larger population than all Western civilization combined. Efficiencies of scale are no joke.

If you combine industrial scale with high-tech expertise, what more do you need? The best technology and the largest numbers = ultimate power. I&#39;ve argued in the past that we should have put more effort into [suppressing China](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ln1sv9/maginot_syndrome_bullish_for_han_hegemony/) back when they were weak. We wasted nearly 30 years after Tienanmen square, after the point where it should have been clear that they weren&#39;t just going to capitulate like the Russians. Let&#39;s not forget the 1996 3rd Taiwan straits crisis. If that&#39;s not hostility, what is?

Up until the mid 2000s the US could have obliterated the Chinese nuclear arsenal in a disarming strike. See pages 295-6 of the [Rand report](https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR392.html): they show that Chinese ICBMs were immensely vulnerable. China&#39;s single abysmally noisy and crappy ballistic missile sub would surely get sunk before travelling halfway across the Pacific to retaliate against the US. The US could have dictated terms to China about Taiwan, they could have enforced a blockade with ease. This is no longer the case, the US doesn&#39;t have escalation dominance up to strategic nuclear war. China&#39;s conventional capabilities are immensely stronger than they were, just look at all the green bars going to yellow and orange on the RAND graph. That is what getting weaker looks like.

We are doing something seriously wrong. IBM and Intel used to lead in semiconductor development. [US hypersonics have stagnated](https://www.science.org/content/article/national-pride-stake-russia-china-united-states-race-build-hypersonic-weapons) and now fallen behind China and Russia. They&#39;ve deployed weapons, US tests don&#39;t even [work](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/06/30/politics/us-hypersonic-missile-test-fails/index.html). I believe there is some [malaise](https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/china-acquiring-new-weapons-five-times-faster-than-u-s-warns-top-official) in our cultures that leads us to just take things less seriously than China does:

&amp;gt;“In purchasing power parity, they spend about one dollar to our 20 dollars to get to the same capability,” he told his audience. “We are going to lose if we can’t figure out how to drop the cost and increase the speed in our defense supply chains,” Holt added.

The same sort of effect applies to civilian products - there is surely a reason US semiconductor production died, why California&#39;s HSR takes so long and costs so much. If we&#39;re outnumbered, we need to work harder or work smarter. It doesn&#39;t look like we&#39;re doing either, just coasting on old advantages.

While many say that China doesn&#39;t have global ambitions, they have cultivated border disputes with most of their neighbors. They have an ideological goal in establishing their system as the moral/normative peer of liberal democracy. They also have the world&#39;s biggest trading economy - they naturally have global interests in resources and securing markets. One Belt One Road was an attempt to realign the world economy to favor China. And they&#39;ll get drawn into various conflicts just because they&#39;re so big. Power is seductive and addictive, as the US has discovered. There&#39;s also a lot of nationalism swirling around, a substitute for traditional Maoism/Marxism which they don&#39;t even practice. There&#39;s immense popular resentment with the US over bombing their embassy in Serbia, various aerial incidents, rhetorical support for Hong Kong, military support for Taiwan...

I judge that China has more potential for global intervention than the once-isolationist US back at the start of the 20th century. They have a similarly large industrial base, more need for overseas resources, are closer to Eurasia, are more nationalistic and much more bitter. The story of the 20th century was the US leaving its corner and dominating the world. The story of the 21st may be China doing the same.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4w2le/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4l4i1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] TW: Navel gazing and red-tribe/blue-tribe palm reading 

Yarvin has a new piece </title><updated>2022-07-22T00:41:46Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">TW: Navel gazing and red-tribe/blue-tribe palm reading 

Yarvin has a new piece in typical Yarvin style (long on flourishes, short on substance) call [&#34;You Can Only Lose the Culture War.&#34;](https://graymirror.substack.com/p/you-can-only-lose-the-culture-war)  In it, he makes a (muddled) Tolkein analogy, casting the blue tribe as &#34;elves&#34; and the red tribe as &#34;hobbits&#34;:  
  
&amp;gt;We know who are the hobbits and who are the elves. We know who is on top and who is on the bottom. (Of dwarves and orcs, we shall not speak.) We know what the elves want: they want to live beautiful lives. We know what the hobbits want: they want to grill and raise kids.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Dear hobbits: you can only lose the culture war. Even when elves use political power to impose elf culture on you, you cannot use political power to impose hobbit culture on elves.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;I mean, sometimes (rarely) you can. It never works out well. I suppose that in theory you could massacre all the elves. You don’t seem up for that in practice. As an elf… I have to regard that as a good thing. But it leaves you, dear hobbits, in a real bind.  
  
And then he adds a third group, the &#34;dark elves&#34;:

&amp;gt;Moreover, when hobbits try to take revenge on elves at large, or even worse when they actually succeed, they are damaging a resource they do not even know they have. There may even be some elves—the dark elves—who are actually on the hobbits’ side.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Naturally, being traitors and all, these dark elves keep a low profile. But culturally, they are still totally elves and into, like, “art films” and stuff. Any attack on elves in general weakens and demoralizes this important fifth column. What are they useful for, these dark elves? See below.  
  
This sounds like shorthand for dissident blue tribers, maybe more specifically dissident blue tribe PMC members.  
  
At first, when I read this, I thought of myself as a hobbit.  The hobbits (peasants), according to Yarvin, are hopeless at political action and have to stake their hopes of living satisfying, hobbity lives on a hobbit-friendly group of elves taking power (aristocracy).  So much for having an impact on events.  Maybe I should just tend my garden.  
  
But I thought about it more, and realized that I&#39;m solidly in the blue tribe.  Despite holding reactionary, anti-enlightenment political views and being a practicing Catholic, I&#39;ve lived in blue cities and around blue tribers most of my adult life.  It&#39;s where the money is, the power is, the cultural ferment, the dynamism.  Even after having kids and moving to a red area, my social circle is blue/purple and the industry I work in is dark blue, and I have trouble connecting with my red tribe neighbors on a deep level.  
  
What to do when your fellow tribe members are ideological opponents and your ideological allies are culturally alien?  I want to move to a clandestine dark elven community deep in the red state of Mirkwood where I can join a reactionary book club, go to weekly Mass, go to a climbing gym, and enjoy craft beer.  I want the blue tribe, right-wing cultural and intellectual ferment diffused to near-insubstantiality across the online right to be concentrated into one place so that it can start to do things and develop ideas and put them into practice.  I know I&#39;m not the only one out there, and that hobbits would love to be ruled by this sort of dark elven elite (at least compared to the current elite), so this seems like a huge market failure.
  
Why is this?  There seems to be a lot of dissident right wing energy out there -- why are no centers of intellectual activity forming?  Leftist movements seemed quite good at condensing political energy, historically. Certain cities or regions became centers of union/socialist/communist activity, and from that power base these movements were able to exert political pressure and score victories.  Red tribe right-wingers, hobbits, just want to grill -- they&#39;re not about to get politically active unless their families are threatened.  But blue tribe right-wing dark elves have much in common with blue tribe leftists.  So why is there no organizing impulse amongst the dark elves?  Fear of retaliation from the elven elite?  Perhaps it&#39;s all just a LARP? Something else?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4l4i1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1tvj2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Black and Brown Americans**

This is a phrase that gets used a lot, but I rece</title><updated>2022-07-21T13:53:30Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Black and Brown Americans**

This is a phrase that gets used a lot, but I recently started to wonder how Hispanic Americans think about it?

With Black Americans, the term might not be everyone&#39;s preferred one, with some folks preferring African American, and some others (mostly younger) preferring Person of Color. But, the term Black seems to have a generally positive connotation and plenty of people are happy to use it.

You get slogans like &#34;Black and proud,&#34; &#34;Black is beautiful,&#34; and &#34;Strong Black man.&#34;

Meanwhile, I don&#39;t know that I&#39;ve ever heard a Hispanic person refer to themselves as &#34;Brown&#34; or a &#34;Brown American.&#34; I seem to only hear &#34;Brown&#34; used in the phrase &#34;Black and Brown.&#34; It&#39;ll be in things like &#34;Police violence against Black and Brown people&#34; but never &#34;The Brown vote is central to winning the Nevada primary.&#34; That&#39;d be the Hispanic vote.

In fact, I think if you called a Hispanic person &#34;Brown&#34; to their face, you&#39;d better brace yourself for a slap. There&#39;s no positive connotation to it, quite the opposite, and the word would seem to feed into negative stereotypes about Hispanic people (brown being associated with dirt and shit).

No real question here, just musing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1tvj2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recomme</title><updated>2022-07-21T13:25:21Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recommends eating less than a teaspoon of salt per day, while animals our size generally eat a quarter to a third of an oz per day.  
I don&#39;t eat any processed food, so the only salt I get is on meat and fried eggs. Have been developing salt cravings this summer to the point that livestock mineral salt looks really delicious, which is a pretty reliable sign I&#39;m missing _something_.   
Everything out there is just yelling at people not to eat salt, but maybe someone here has done some proper research?

Bonus question: other than a costco multivitamin, what&#39;s a good extra source of zinc and other useful minerals?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1o33s/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] From [Twitter](https://twitter.com/jordanschnyc/status/1549877928074387456?t=7FW</title><updated>2022-07-21T13:11:04Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">From [Twitter](https://twitter.com/jordanschnyc/status/1549877928074387456?t=7FWLggTzvQUFcn08KKF9HA&amp;amp;s=19), quoting the Book of the Courtier, written in 1528:

&amp;gt;if fathers were generally better than children, we should have long since reached that last grade of badness beyond which it is impossible to grow worse.

This is flawed reasoning. There is one respect in which we know with certainty that fathers are generally ~~worse~~ better than their children: the quality of their genes. The average person has more deleterious genetic variants than his parents. Natural selection prevents this effect from compounding each generation by causing people with better genes to have more children, so that the probability distribution of who a random person&#39;s parents are has better average genes than a random sampling of that generation.

Similarly with culture, there could be some kind of selection effect countering actual cultural decline that is happening on some level.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1o33s/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1lzfu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The new Labor government in Australia is showing that it wants to distance itsel</title><updated>2022-07-21T12:54:31Z</updated><author><name>AshLael</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The new Labor government in Australia is showing that it wants to distance itself from the more extravagant excesses of the left: [Government forms have been changed to replace the term &#34;birthing parent&#34; with &#34;mother&#34;.](https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/jul/21/bill-shorten-intervenes-to-remove-birthing-parent-from-medical-forms-amid-criticism-in-daily-telegraph)

It&#39;s not a big deal, just a few words on a form. But it&#39;s a clear indication - along with other moves, such as their point blank refusal to entertain lifting their emissions reduction targets - that Albanese&#39;s government, for now at least, wants to continue the moderate, centrist approach that won them power rather than giving their progressive supporters everything they want.

It&#39;s also a further indication that a left wing party that is serious about winning and holding power sees pro-trans language as a loser. There were attempts by the former government to invoke trans culture war issues to their advantage during the campaign - and while the media was successfully baited into an outrage campaign, Labor steadfastly did not bite.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1lzfu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1erlm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Another month, another post about relentless negative thoughts. Mostly surroundi</title><updated>2022-07-21T11:51:48Z</updated><author><name>Anouleth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Another month, another post about relentless negative thoughts. Mostly surrounding the gym, my lack of progress, and generally feeling weak, lazy, fat, etc. Weight gain has unfortunately mostly stalled, due to working a physically demanding job with few opportunities to eat... but difficult to escape the belief that any weight gained wouldn&#39;t just be fat anyway. Have started running again with a friend (who has serious problems controlling his weight). I tend to get awful soreness/tightness in my shins, but seems to be getting less bad. Another friend has returned to the gym with me too, which is nice, except that it&#39;s because he broke up with his girlfriend, so it feels a little bit wrong to take pleasure from a bad event like that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1erlm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1d1vb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Came across a novel (at least for me) use of AI text generation, via a youtube c</title><updated>2022-07-21T11:35:25Z</updated><author><name>Tophattingson</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Came across a novel (at least for me) use of AI text generation, via a youtube channel that usually isn&#39;t on that subject. [Creating fake, factually incorrect woke-themed customer complaints.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gp1O8flnRr8). And [another example.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XM7hAND9tP8)

This seems to combine the unique weaknesses of both publicly available AI text generation and &#39;cancel culture&#39;. For the former, the weakness is that, while you can generate text that sounds reasonable at a first glance from someone who knows nothing about the subject, the actual, factual details are all wrong. For the latter, the weakness is a lack of due diligence in assessing the validity of claims of discrimination. Cancel first, think later. (Edit to clarify: I mention all this to make a comparison. I think this method would be far less successful at faking other forms of customer complaints, like asking for refunds, because they would face scrutiny which would reveal incorrect information)

It&#39;s very easy to exploit a zero tolerance attitude towards racism with vexatious accusations, and the technology to carry it out automatically seemingly already exists, waiting for someone to glue the pieces together with a little bit of code and start pointing it at targets. Is this on the cusp of being weaponized? Or perhaps it already has?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih1d1vb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ih1cjyp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m not seeing a CWR thread for this week. Did I miss something? Are we taking s</title><updated>2022-07-21T11:30:29Z</updated><author><name>Southkraut</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not seeing a CWR thread for this week. Did I miss something? Are we taking some time off?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ih1cjyp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih0wtcs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] South China Morning Post [writes](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/articl</title><updated>2022-07-21T08:14:51Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">South China Morning Post [writes](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3185140/chinas-court-ai-reaches-every-corner-justice-system-advising) that PRC has made legal AI a mandatory part of the judicial process. &#34;As required by the supreme court, a judge must consult AI on every case. If the judge rejects the machine’s recommendation, the machine demands a written explanation for records and auditing.&#34;

As I understand, Chinese judicial system is more similar to the Russian system: weak cases are dropped by the prosecution before the trial and the trial is more about the sentencing severity than the determination of guilt: the defense submits every extenuating circumstance, the prosecution submits every aggravating circumstance, the judge finds the person guilty and comes up with an appropriate sentence. If this is the case, then pattern-matching the punishment to similar cases from across the country might actually not be a bad band-aid, it will prevent judges from passing sentences that are too lenient or too harsh due to some bias.

For example, an AI like this could ensure that no implicit racial bias affects the sentencing. But there&#39;s always the risk the knobs of the AI can be fiddled with. What if, in the name of equity, the AI will insist on more lenient sentences if the person is BIPoC? Even if a principled judge keeps writing written explanations of why he agreed with Billy Bob&#39;s and Libby Mae&#39;s sentences, but increased Tyrone&#39;s and Shaneequa&#39;s, she or he will sooner or later be crucified in the media as a &#34;racist judge&#34;.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih0wtcs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igzkw9e/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW]  A post from u/buttfaceszn put into words something I&#39;ve been processing for a l</title><updated>2022-07-21T00:36:52Z</updated><author><name>productiveaccount1</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text"> A post from u/buttfaceszn put into words something I&#39;ve been processing for a long time. This has nothing to do with incels, sexism, or anything else in comment made by u/buttfaceszn. It&#39;s about how the evolution of our language has played a huge role in our division as a society. I&#39;m only speaking to my experience as an American but I&#39;m sure this isn&#39;t unique to us. 

TL;DR: We need to stop using extremist language and start defining our terms.

From u/buttfaceszn:

&amp;gt;I’ve noticed that the term incel has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejorative for sexism of any kind (at least on the internet) which strikes me as odd. I don’t really like when people use the term incel as an insult to people who bring up redpill/PUA/manosphere-type things, since I suspect there’s a lot of non-incels who find these things interesting and I personally think some of it has value.

u/buttfaceszn is right: Using extreme, specific language to describe tamer things is annoying at best and destructive at worst. To illustrate, let&#39;s change the subject of this comment to reflect how each American party often characterizes each other&#39;s views:

&amp;gt;I’ve noticed that the term (Fascism/Wokeism) has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejorative for (Conservatism/Liberalism) of any kind (at least on the internet) which strikes me as odd. I don’t really like when people use the term (Fascism/Wokeism) as an insult to people who bring up (Right-wing/Left wing) things, since I suspect there’s a lot of non-(Fascists/Wokies) who find these things interesting and I personally think some of it has value.

You get the idea - you could throw pretty much any culture war issue into this statement and it would work pretty well. For some reason, we&#39;ve started to use the most extreme, niche, and damaging words to describe anything that could remotely fall under its umbrella. Trump is a white supremacist, AOC is a literal communist, Gwyneth Paltrow is a scamming, elitist narcissist (unless...). The reasons as to why this is bad are obvious and I think we all agree that we shouldn&#39;t do it. But even in this sub people fling out loaded political buzzwords as if they&#39;re nothing all the time. Is our divisive language simply a sign of the division in our minds? Or does language start to create that barrier in the first place? Is there any way to fix this, even on a smaller scale (like in this sub)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igzkw9e/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igz1v8u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Herman Miller chairs - expensive meme or ergonomic dream?</title><updated>2022-07-20T22:08:07Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Herman Miller chairs - expensive meme or ergonomic dream?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igz1v8u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igyyi6u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I quit drinking and vaping.

According to Fitbit my resting heart rate is alread</title><updated>2022-07-20T21:43:02Z</updated><author><name>Gorf__</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I quit drinking and vaping.

According to Fitbit my resting heart rate is already 10bpm lower, and my HRV is 20ms+ higher.

I’ve tried to quit numerous times but I think this is the actual time. I’m just tired of feeling like dog shit most of the time. I’m tired and haven’t been exercising like I used to.

Vaping was always dumb, I don’t even want that in my life. But I can’t resist it when I’m drunk, and I’m always around it, so I ended up just doing it by default.

Alcohol is mostly just nice because it’s weird to not drink, at least in my friend group. So it’s just avoiding that whole awkwardness. But, it does seem like it’s getting more common to encounter people who don’t drink. Maybe that’s just because I’m getting older. In any case, I’m starting to give less of a fuck about that. Just let me live my life, I don’t need to put garbage in my body just to make you feel better.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igyyi6u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igyr7zl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How about a post on some recent Congressional legislation?

---

The House of Re</title><updated>2022-07-20T20:50:15Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How about a post on some recent Congressional legislation?

---

The House of Representatives has now passed two bills aimed at protecting abortion rights. 

The first is the [Women&#39;s Health Protection Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/3755/text). This bill basically sets out a list of reasons why abortions may not be restricted and creates a test for what future reasons will be prohibited by the law. It targets pretty directly laws various Republican states passed when *Roe* was still in effect to limit abortion. It empowers both the US Attorney General and private parties (including those seeking abortions and those providing them) to sue to enforce the law.

The second of these is the [Ensuring Women’s Right to Reproductive Freedom Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/8297/text?r=1&amp;amp;s=1). This law creates liability (enforced by either the Attorney General or private citizens) for anyone acting under color of State law who tries to prevent someone from traveling interstate for the purpose of getting an abortion that would be legal in the state they are going to have it done in.

Both bills passed the House with all but one Democrat in favor and all Republicans against.

Both bills are most likely dead on arrival in the Senate.

---

On Tuesday the House of Representatives also passed the [Respect For Marriage Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/8404/text) which enshrines, not [*Obergefell v. Hodges*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obergefell_v._Hodges) but rather [*United States v. Windsor*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_v._Windsor) into federal law. The law does not require that states perform either same sex or interracial marriages but it does require they recognize those marriages if performed in other states where they are legal. It is also enforceable by either the Attorney General or a private right of action. The law also clarifies that the federal definition of marriage includes both interracial and same sex marriages.

Interestingly 47 Republicans (~one-fourth of the caucus) joined the Democrats in passing the bill. If a similar fraction of Senate Republicans support the bill that would be sufficient to invoke cloture and pass it.

---

Finally, introduced today by a bipartisan group of Senators (but not passed anywhere) is the [Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022](https://www.democracydocket.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/electoral_count_reform_and_presidential_transition_improvement_act_of_2022.pdf). Exploitation of some ambiguity in the 12th amendment and Electoral Count Act (USC 3) were key to John Eastman&#39;s plan for Trump to retain the presidency even after losing the 2020 election. This act is an attempt to remove that ambiguity. The Act does so first by clarifying that state electors are determined by the laws of the state *prior to election day*. This is to prevent state legislatures from changing who the electors are after the vote has happened (unless they delegated themselves that power in advance). The Act also raises the threshold necessary to trigger a vote on an objection from one Senator and one Representative to one-fifth of Senators and Representatives. It also clarifies the grounds on which electors may be objected to. Finally it clarifies that the role of the President of the Senate is ministerial only and sets up an expedited legal process (three judge panel, then SCOTUS) for hearing challenges to election certification.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igyr7zl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igym84d/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any advice for joint issues? I have some chronic ankle problems that my doctor b</title><updated>2022-07-20T20:15:20Z</updated><author><name>wmil</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any advice for joint issues? I have some chronic ankle problems that my doctor brushes aside. 

I&#39;m just curious what has worked for people.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igym84d/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy93di/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Merriam-Webster recently updated the definition of the word &#34;female&#34;: The first </title><updated>2022-07-20T18:44:18Z</updated><author><name>DinoInNameOnly</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Merriam-Webster recently updated the definition of the word &#34;female&#34;: The first one:

&amp;gt;of, relating to, or being the sex that typically has the capacity to bear young or produce eggs

The second one is different:

&amp;gt;having a gender identity that is the opposite of male

The definitions for male are similar. First:

&amp;gt;of, relating to, or being the sex that typically has the capacity to produce relatively small, usually motile gametes which fertilize the eggs of a female

Second:

&amp;gt;having a gender identity that is the opposite of female

There are more definitions provided, but all of them use the words &#34;woman,&#34; &#34;girl,&#34; or &#34;female&#34; (or are defining about the word in a different sense, like a female rhyme or a female connector) so they don&#39;t tell us anything about what it actually means to be female, since the definitions of &#34;woman&#34; and &#34;girl&#34; both use the word &#34;female.&#34;

The definition of gender identity is 

&amp;gt;a person&#39;s internal sense of being male, female, some combination of male and female, or neither male nor female

The first definitions are obviously hateful and transphobic, so let&#39;s throw those out. If someone who didn&#39;t know what male, female, and gender identity were wanted to use the definitions to figure out what female meant, they would learn that being female means &#34;having an internal sense of being that is the opposite of the opposite of female.&#34; 

That&#39;s basically a long way to say that &#34;female&#34; means female. We learn from these definitions that male and female are gender identities that are opposed to each other, but we learn nothing about what the difference between them actually is or even what gender identity really means other than that it&#39;s an &#34;internal sense&#34; of some kind. The concepts are connected to each other while floating in the ether, unconnected to physical reality or to any non-gender concepts. This is the form gender ideology always takes when you scratch it even a little bit, circular definitions with no connection to reality. Merriam-Webster avoided the simplest one (&#34;A woman is someone who identifies as someone who identifies...&#34;) by adding more steps but the result, ultimately, is the same.

The only way to give these any kind of meaning is if you sometimes use the second definition and sometimes the first. If you interpret female as meaning &#34;having a gender identity that is the sex that typically has the capacity to bear young or produce eggs&#34;, then you&#39;ve come to something sort of like the understanding of the meaning of the word that progressives actually use. But to get to this definition, female has to mean *both* the second definition *and* the first definition at the *same time*, in the context of the *same statement*, even though these definitions contradict each other (e.g. Lia Thomas is only female by the second definition). 

This contradiction takes other forms, like how trans activists simultaneously insist that having a penis has nothing at all to do with being male at the same time that they insist that surgeries to fabricate a fake penis for someone who doesn&#39;t have a real penis are absolutely vital for some males in order to truly live out their gender identity. Penises are simultaneously completely irrelevant and absolutely vital to male identity. 

To believe in gender identity you have to simultaneously believe two contradictory things (that penises make someone male and that they don&#39;t). It&#39;s trite, but I don&#39;t know what to compare this to other than Orwell&#39;s doublethink.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy93di/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy0k3k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Semi-regular Ban Report**

No AEO actions since the last report.

/u/GrandBurd</title><updated>2022-07-20T17:46:49Z</updated><author><name>Amadanb</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Semi-regular Ban Report**

No AEO actions since the last report.

/u/GrandBurdensomeCount - [180 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/igteigl/) - /u/naraburns

/u/sp8der - [60 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/igtg87h/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/naraburns

/u/jermleeds - [3 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/igqq0fm/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/naraburns

u/HlynkaCG - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/comment/igctwkk/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/JeanStealers - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/comment/iga251u/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/barggle - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vuvo1k/comment/ifrpk4k/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/Nantafiria - [2 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/comment/ifgmwio/) - /u/Amadanb

/u/The_Reason_Trump_Won - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/comment/if6pju0/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/darwin2500 - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/comment/iezy5fl/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/naraburns</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy0k3k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igx4h21/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Is the main point of a therapist to pay someone for the emotional labor of liste</title><updated>2022-07-20T14:20:12Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Is the main point of a therapist to pay someone for the emotional labor of listening to you rant about your problems, nod along, and then provide comforting but non-falsifiable advice? I’ve been skeptical of trying one because I have serious doubts they would help actually solve the problems I have, but lately the closest thing I have to friends have been getting fired of putting up with my needy self-pitying bullshit (frankly I can’t blame them).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igx4h21/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igwztcg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ## Why I still talk about covid restrictions. And will continue to do so. 


Rec</title><updated>2022-07-20T13:47:34Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">## Why I still talk about covid restrictions. And will continue to do so. 


Recently there was a [post](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifl02lf/) talking about how; now that covid restrictions are mostly done with; covid is not something most people really think or talk about. But, there are still two groups of people who continue to talk about covid. Those who were really scared and still are, and the &#34;skeptics&#34;. The post somewhat implied that both groups are extremist in some way or the other on the issue of covid. 

I will try to defend my case on why I think my position of being a skeptic should have been the default position. And the fact it wasn&#39;t requires some heavy investigation as to why.

_____________________________________________________________

As a &#34;covid skeptic&#34; much of the discourse around covid restrictions makes me feel like I am being &#39;gaslighted&#39; on a grand level. The jist of it being that I operated under one overton window, one epistemology my entire life and both those things get radically shifted and transformed in 2 years and everyone is suddenly on board, and I am the crazy one for asking &#34;wait what about everything we knew before?&#34;? 

To put it shortly there have been shifts on multiple overton windows in ways that are not conductive to a epistemologycally and politically healthy society and somebody has to acknowledge and speak about it. And continue speaking about it, because some of these shifts pave the way for tremendous injustices. 

Here are the reasons why I will keep talking about covid for the rest of my life. And I will not be convinced I am crazy or of a certain ideological group because I do so. I believe the ones who are not talking about these things have had the cloak successfully put over their eyes (even if they are otherwise skeptics), they forgave what was done to them after it wasn&#39;t being done anymore, they are complacent.

1. Being a &#34;covid skeptic&#34; is the default position of almost all societies before 2020. It was the medical consensus that;
 * Lockdowns are not worth it (QALY,$, &#34;human rights&#34; ) for the vast majority of diseases. The ones that pose an IFR high enough to justify them are not that scary because they also tend to be non contagious for various reasons. 
What was  essentially considered putting entire cities or countries of people under house arrest suddenly became the default mode of addressing the problem? 
 * Universal masking is ineffective for airborne diseases.
 * Vaccinating the entire population by threatening the loss of education/work is by the State is overstepping the bounds by any reasonable western State. 

 The first two points are correct. They were reached after decades of &#34;good science&#34;. The bullshit ideological science (along with all sorts of publication bias and a thousand other traps) peddled to make it seem that lockdowns are worth it and masks work are the work of pure propaganda. We can&#39;t just let that slide right? If &#34;mistakes&#34; were made, they need to be discussed and analyzed lest they not be repeated. 

 We can&#39;t just replace the field of public health which is fundamentally based on the idea of a cost benefit analysis with some idiotic throw EVERYTHING at the wall and hope it works at whatever costs method right? More importantly we can&#39;t have this &#34;philosophy&#34; wear the skin-suit of what it replaced and pretend to be something it is not, rational. Least of all this needs to be discussed. 

2.  The much obvious economic malign caused by covid policies are blamed on &#34;supply chain issues&#34;,&#34;Ukraine war&#34;, &#34;general economic turmoil&#34;, etc. Why is no one talking about the elephant in the room when it comes to economic downturn?

	Really? Lockdowns and travel bans and printing all that money had nothing to do with the inflation and economic struggles? Why is no one discussing the policies that literally consisted of shutting down economies not having an effect when economies are shutting down? Would Sri Lanka be where it is today if not for travel bans and lockdowns? 

	In a recent [video essay](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxdHm2dmvKE) by Jordan Peterson. He posits that perhaps the Russian invasion of Ukraine was in part caused by covid restrictions, as some far out there nth order effect. That world leaders being isolated from each other in person for nearing two years might have been a straw that broke the camels back. Even if this sounds like a far reaching judgement on the surface, is it not more far reaching to assert that two years of lockdowns, mandates, minimized travel, and all its social and economic malaise would not manifest at the margins?

      What about an easier to digest example? The mass shootings in the US? They must be at least slightly correlated with the declining social and economic environment right? Why is no one talking about how further isolating and economically straining those on the margins of shooting up a school going to make them do it? Hell I wanted to cause mayhem as I was locked up in my room (don&#39;t live in the US) for 2 months on end. 

3. The overton window has been shifted significantly towards authoritarianism. We expected the government to play God and deal with nature in 2020 and they let us have our cake, they gladly played as the Gods people wanted them to play so desperately. As a libertarian I don&#39;t think this is a good development.  

	 Did we really expect the governments to do everything they did in 2020 for diseases of the past. They were given the right to put people under house arrest for arbitrary levels of disease depending on time and place. This is a terrible precedent. Will this increased state power never be used for stamping out dissent in the future? 

____________________________________________________________________

To further add on. This whole covid debate left me with a tremendous hate towards &#34;normies&#34;. Many of them felt the same as me. They knew masking 24/7 was stupid. They knew 20 year olds being forced to be vaccinated was unjust. They knew lockdowns would destroy everything. They were still compliant. They had their fun time at home binging netflix and making sourdough bread (as they lost their jobs because of lockdowns). They wore the masks dutifully under their nose. They got vaccinated because &#34;its just less hassle&#34;, etc. Fuck them.

Maybe I have the temperament of a rabid dog who absolutely won&#39;t do something if he thinks its stupid or performative or doesn&#39;t want to do it. Perhaps. But if more people were like me, No one would have complied with lockdown orders, what would they have done? Arrest all of us?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igwztcg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igu416v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Ukraine war updates

This is a slow grinding war of Artillery trenches and drone</title><updated>2022-07-19T21:51:20Z</updated><author><name>ussgordoncaptain2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Ukraine war updates

This is a slow grinding war of Artillery trenches and drone scouting. Ever since Gennady took over Russia has been steadily and slowly taking ground on [june 19th](https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-june-19) Lysanchansk was the frontline and now on [July 18](https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-july-18) Lysanchansk is firmly in russian territory and the new frontline is Bakhmut. One major issue with reporting on this war is that it&#39;s pretty hard to report on a war where most of the conflict is 50000 artillery shells a day (no seriously) getting fired into a fairly small area followed by a small advance and more artillery. Perhaps the best way to find shelling information is [Thermal anomaly](https://firms.modaps.eosdis.nasa.gov/map/#t:adv;d:7days;l:noaa20-viirs,viirs,modis_a,modis_t,street;@37.8,48.1,7z) data because a large scale artillery campaign is visible from such data.

Perhaps the best breakdown I could find of the Ukraine war comes from the [Austrian Military academy](https://youtu.be/dEbLuAPobao) showing just how russian progress has been (slow methodical but definitely moving forward). The grinding down of the Ukrainian forces has been steady, with the UKR forces going from 81 Battallions to 60 while the russians have gone from 93 BTG&#39;s to 108 after new reinforcements. (though remember that it&#39;s hard to assess the strength of the BTGs) While Thermal anomaly data definitely showed that new NATO weapons had a temporary decrease in russian effectiveness the data appears to show that russian artillery shelling has come back after the operational pause for (what appears to be) logistical reasons.

New NATO weapons are probably going to make an impact, though given that the US has sent roughly $7 Billion worth of equipment to UKR it&#39;s hard to say how much each marginal unit enables. Remember this is also NATO $7 billion so while the weapons work they&#39;re not necessarily very good in the &#34;bang for the buck&#34; department. In the report by Mr.Resner it&#39;s pointed out that the M777 is really vulnerable to damage from Shrapnel, and needs constant repairs to maintain it&#39;s combat effectiveness. 
.
.I keep getting conflicting reports on air defenses, it appears that Ukrianian air defenses are good enough to prevent bombing but they have no defense against air to ground long range missiles., though it appears such ATG missiles aren&#39;t very cost effective. 

I know reporting on what has become World war 1 with drones is a little boring, but still I&#39;m surprised at how little discussion there is about the only political event to actually remain relevant 5 months after it started in 2022.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igu416v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtlhuq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] https://twitter.com/disclosetv/status/1549460928328077314

Seventeen members of </title><updated>2022-07-19T19:54:35Z</updated><author><name>okay-dot-com</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">https://twitter.com/disclosetv/status/1549460928328077314

Seventeen members of congress were arrested today for protesting the recent SCOTUS decision re: Roe.

There&#39;s a video in that thread of AOC seemingly pretending to be handcuffed, but she raises a triumphant fist at one point, so maybe she didn&#39;t realize what it looked like she was doing.

I don&#39;t really know how to come at this from a TheMotte perspective. I just find it so humiliating that this is our government. From top to bottom, the US Government is a total embarrassment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtlhuq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igrrykb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] [removed]</title><updated>2022-07-19T12:46:32Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">[removed]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igrrykb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq8pkg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What does Napoleon tell us about ideology? He was the culmination of a revolutio</title><updated>2022-07-19T02:45:50Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What does Napoleon tell us about ideology? He was the culmination of a revolution between a far right and a far left. He took control undemocratically, became Emperor, and both sides were just… okay with it. Widespread support, yet dictatorial; attempted to balance the Left and Right, but motivated by personal ambition.

There’s something illustrative in this whole thing, but I’m too lazy to read Thomas Carlyle. It’s almost like both sides simply wanted practical improvements and a good story, and Napoleon more than sufficed.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq8pkg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq05ea/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] This comment&#39;s just a notice to anyone who might be recreating my personality so</title><updated>2022-07-19T01:41:30Z</updated><author><name>TJ11240</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">This comment&#39;s just a notice to anyone who might be recreating my personality some time in the future through all these years&#39; worth of comments, I&#39;d like to remind you I&#39;m usually working on a buzz in the evenings so that probably should be accounted for.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq05ea/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igo3c52/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-07-18T17:45:28Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igo3c52/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ignl1wi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Not sure if it&#39;s the correct thread to post this.

I remembered [this comment](h</title><updated>2022-07-18T15:45:03Z</updated><author><name>Sinity</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Not sure if it&#39;s the correct thread to post this.

I remembered [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vlopk0/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_27_2022/idwelna/) by /u/ZorbaTHut about trying to generalize the problem of (supposedly existing) people who can&#39;t understand conditionals. And I wonder if there&#39;s any connection with inability to understand pointers and recursion by some people described [here](https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2006/10/25/the-guerrilla-guide-to-interviewing-version-30/). Indirection?

&amp;gt; I’ve come to realize that **understanding pointers in C is not a skill, it’s an aptitude**. In first year computer science classes, there are always about 200 kids at the beginning of the semester, all of whom wrote complex adventure games in BASIC for their PCs when they were 4 years old. They are having a good ol’ time learning C or Pascal in college, until one day the professor introduces pointers, and suddenly, they don’t get it.

&amp;gt; They just don’t understand anything any more. 90% of the class goes off and becomes Political Science majors, then they tell their friends that there weren’t enough good looking members of the appropriate sex in their CompSci classes, that’s why they switched. **For some reason most people seem to be born without the part of the brain that understands pointers. Pointers require a complex form of doubly-indirected thinking that some people just can’t do**, and it’s pretty crucial to good programming. A lot of the “script jocks” who started programming by copying JavaScript snippets into their web pages and went on to learn Perl never learned about pointers, and they can never quite produce code of the quality you need.

&amp;gt; That’s the source of all these famous interview questions you hear about, like “reversing a linked list” or “detect loops in a tree structure.”


Through now that I checked, recursion was already covered in that 4chan post Scott referenced

&amp;gt; Other interesting phenomenon around IQ involves recursion. For example: &#34;Write a story with two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue.&#34; Most literate people can manage this, especially once you give them an example. &#34;Write a story with two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue. In this story, one of the characters must be describing a story with at least two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue.&#34; If you have less than 90 IQ, this second exercise is basically completely impossible. Add a third level (&#39;frame&#39;) to the story, and even IQ 100&#39;s start to get mixed up with the names and who&#39;s talking. Turns out Scheherazade was an IQ test!
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Time is practically impossible to understand for sub 80s. They exist only in the present, can barely reflect on the past and can&#39;t plan for the future at all. Sub 90s struggle with anachronism too. For example, I remember the 80-85s stumbling on logic problems that involved common sense anachronism stuff. For instance: &#34;Why do you think that military strategists in WWII didn&#39;t use laptop computers to help develop their strategies?&#34; &#34;I guess they didn&#39;t want to get hacked by Nazis&#34;. Admittedly you could argue that this is a history knowledge question, not quite a logic sequencing question, but you get the idea. Sequencing is super hard for them to track, but most 100+ have no problem with it, although I imagine that a movie like Memento strains them a little. Recursion was definitely the killer though. Recursive thinking and recursive knowledge seems genuinely hard for people of even average intelligence.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ignl1wi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igmj9y6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m looking for a study that shows that teaching quality is more important for g</title><updated>2022-07-18T10:20:46Z</updated><author><name>Greenei</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m looking for a study that shows that teaching quality is more important for good students than bad students, i.e. the learning achievements of good students increase more quickly with teacher quality. Scott may have linked it once as well. Anyone know where to find it? IIRC it was an experimental study.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igmj9y6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing some</title><updated>2022-07-18T05:02:13Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing something to celebrate. 

Started air-layering a couple hundred laurel starts last summer, planted them in a composted trench along the most exposed section of my frontage this spring, and only just got [the last of the weed barrier and wood chips down](https://files.catbox.moe/9hohcv.jpg).  
Total cost was about $20 for some rooting hormone and a lot of grunt work, and while it feels really good to be finished, I can&#39;t think of anything to treat myself to.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglayom/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Weird question, but does anyone having dining room chairs they recommend?   I ha</title><updated>2022-07-18T01:53:17Z</updated><author><name>bored_at_work_guy</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Weird question, but does anyone having dining room chairs they recommend?   I hate mine, but I&#39;m afraid I&#39;d hate whatever replacements I got as well.

Factors: Comfort, appearance, durability, slides across floor nicely.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglayom/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igl6cyu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What is the best physical state to be in when studying? Alone, with someone else</title><updated>2022-07-18T01:15:30Z</updated><author><name>cant-feel_my-face</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What is the best physical state to be in when studying? Alone, with someone else, at home, outside?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igl6cyu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igkfte0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What are the odds the center-left and center-right adopt the traditional gay pri</title><updated>2022-07-17T21:46:31Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What are the odds the center-left and center-right adopt the traditional gay pride flag as a way to signal opposition to the far-left positions on gender and sexuality?

It could be flown to mean *Not* The Progress Flag, but at the same time, the left would have a really hard time throwing -phobic labels at someone flying the rainbow flag.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igkfte0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjsk8b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What are your vices?

For me personally, compulsive snooping. I can&#39;t not snoop.</title><updated>2022-07-17T18:59:44Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What are your vices?

For me personally, compulsive snooping. I can&#39;t not snoop. When I start a job, I tell people, look I&#39;m a snoop, don&#39;t leave files open a file on my computer and expect me not to read it, don&#39;t leave a confidential letter open on the conference table when we&#39;re meeting there, don&#39;t have a &#34;private&#34; conversation in the car with me, I will read/listen/etc. Can&#39;t help myself. My wife and I are the same way, and as a result we&#39;ve always kept phone passwords because we just can&#39;t help ourselves and it&#39;s too much information to share.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjsk8b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjglwo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Nystrom&#39;s *Project of a New System of Ari</title><updated>2022-07-17T17:34:20Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Nystrom&#39;s *Project of a New System of Arithmetic*, which makes the case for switching to a hexadecimal system for things like clocks (seems like a 16-hour day with 90 decimal minutes per hour?). Skimming it shows that he somehow applies hexadecimal to other things like music. Does not seem like anyone has ever taken it seriously, but it&#39;s short and maybe interesting.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjglwo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjflgq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I dislike earbuds with earplug-nipple-things. It seems like the brands that didn</title><updated>2022-07-17T17:26:59Z</updated><author><name>cae_jones</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I dislike earbuds with earplug-nipple-things. It seems like the brands that didn&#39;t use them might be moving in that direction, though. What&#39;s a reliable no-plug wireless earbud brand? Preferably cheap and unlikely to disappear in the next x years?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjflgq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1y51/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Theists of the Motte, what are your thoughts on the Problem of Evil?</title><updated>2022-07-17T15:46:47Z</updated><author><name>NondualGenie</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Theists of the Motte, what are your thoughts on the Problem of Evil?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1y51/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1bj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is eating organic good for anything besides draining your bank account?

Curious</title><updated>2022-07-17T15:42:09Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is eating organic good for anything besides draining your bank account?

Curious how much of a sucker I&#39;ve been for the past ~1 year</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1bj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

F</title><updated>2022-07-17T13:27:30Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

For instance, if I am a feminist, it’s important to factor in the fact that people can be reared to value *either* feminist values *or* traditional values. Humans are this malleable, that they can be raised to value particular things according to what they consume and how they model rewards. Men, for instance, can be raised to value the Spartan way of life, the Athenian way of life, or the Puritan way of life. By simply changing some variables we can have people value different things.

This is important, because it means we can just think dispassionately “what is best for the whole of society”, without much care for what people happen to value at this particular point, ourselves included. I have little doubt that if I were born a Spartan I would love war and that if I were born a Puritan I would love prayer. People did not historically deviate from their culture’s values except in times of strong propaganda against the values, eg counterculture 60’s with their strong and vivid media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igifq3r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] How many people here actually own a firearm, and if you don&#39;t mind saying, is it</title><updated>2022-07-17T12:43:00Z</updated><author><name>ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">How many people here actually own a firearm, and if you don&#39;t mind saying, is it a hunting rifle/handgun/AR style whatever?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igifq3r/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>