<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-23T00:03:08Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ile306e/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Stable Diffusion was released to [public beta](https://stability.ai/blog/stable-</title><updated>2022-08-23T00:03:08Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Stable Diffusion was released to [public beta](https://stability.ai/blog/stable-diffusion-public-release) today, complete with weights. In general, it seems comparable to DALLE2, Imagen, and Parti, beating them in some ways and losing to them in others; the most general comment I&#39;d offer is that it seems to do worse with semantic content and better with textures. This isn&#39;t too important: the next generation (which is to say, 6-12 months from now) will beat all of them in all their best aspects.

Aside from a lot of verbiage around using it ethically, the official and publicly hosted version includes a safety classifier that removes bad outputs. Yay? Of course, since it&#39;s open source, it&#39;s easy enough to modify the code, and the world got right to it. We already have the UnstableDiffusion and PornDiffusion subreddits, and there will be an proliferation of them and their content in the coming months without the need to dance around the OpenAI and Google ~~blacklists~~ blocklists. I mentioned this to a friend, and she said that at least we&#39;ll have a couples years before we could supply images of a person and have porn generated from them. I didn&#39;t have the heart to point her to [textual-inversion](https://textual-inversion.github.io/). Who&#39;d have thought porn actresses would be some of the first to fall to AI? If it&#39;s any consolation to them, many other occupations are going to be wiped out in the coming first wave.

It seems like society is not just unprepared for this but unaware of how far along we are in the automated generation of digital content. For awhile it seemed like the hope was that professional gatekeepers would protect us, but it was obvious that strategy just needed a single defector to fail. If it wasn&#39;t Stability, it&#39;d have been Yandex. If it wasn&#39;t Yandex, it would be a leak.

Regardless, now the cat is out of the bag. I don&#39;t think there was or is any way to prevent or stop this, or even that it&#39;s bad that it&#39;s happening. What does seem likely is that we&#39;re in for a rough ride as society reacts to something that&#39;s blindsided it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ile306e/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcwl5b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I took apart the drain for reasons. Now I cannot get it back together.

https://</title><updated>2022-08-22T19:04:36Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I took apart the drain for reasons. Now I cannot get it back together.

https://i.imgur.com/w0qYn9H.jpg

The tall white pipe goes to the grey pipe. The U-pipe connects the tall white pipe to the one leading into the wall.

The pieces do assemble in something resembling a pipe, and water gets through them, but the connection is way too loose and water leaks all over the place.

There is this rubber washer where the U-pipe means the straight white pipe and it does not feel like it is seated right.

Is there a trick or a correct order to do these things? I do not even have anything where it *looks* like it securely tightened in all places.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcwl5b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but</title><updated>2022-08-22T18:45:28Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but from my vantage point while opposition may have slowed its ascent, it hasn&#39;t managed to reverse the gains.

Case in point: https://www.aier.org/article/the-suicide-of-the-american-historical-association/

Basically, the AHA President dared to offer the mildest of critiques of the &#39;1619&#39; project and now his own members are baying for his blood in the form of a career defenestration. He has hardly any defenders within his organisation and he&#39;s the top guy, so what hope is there for someone with less status within the history profession?

DeSantis&#39; so-called &#34;anti-woke laws&#34; were all stopped by a federal judge. He hopes his voters don&#39;t pay attention and he gives no indications of trying to fight hard to overrule  any of these setbacks.

University of Tennessee - supposedly in a red state where the GOP has political control - has [massively ramped](https://twitter.com/JohnDSailer/status/1559605619857956864) up the DIE (Diversity, Inclusion, Equity) policies.

The GOP appears content in complaining but doing little to combat any of this by using state power. As long as this is the case, my prediction is that &#39;wokism&#39;, for a lack of a better term, is here to stay.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcqjvm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Long-time lurker, and appreciator, of the discussions had in this subreddit. One</title><updated>2022-08-22T18:24:50Z</updated><author><name>Valerion</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Long-time lurker, and appreciator, of the discussions had in this subreddit. One topic that has captured my attention recently is the structure of bureaucracies and mechanisms for accountability and efficiency leading to the question below:

**Are accountability and efficiency for a government organization mutually exclusive? Is there an agency/department (U.S. or non-U.S.) that is regarded as possessing both?**

It strikes me from work in the U.S. public sector that the old observation that the government moves slowly to be true. 

Anecdotally, it seems the slowness stems from countless procedures of reviews to ensure legal and policy compliance. Multiple offices all cover similar portfolios with numerous redundancies and these offices will collaborate to draft policy and regulations. Policy drafts will then undergo legal review by multiple lawyers (with the severity of the policy determining just how high up the bureaucratic lawyer-chain it must go). Further compounding the wait time is after the legal review, you typically have to add on the wait time for a government executive to review the policy, receive a briefing on it (if they desire), and then approve it.

Colleagues and managers claim all of this is to ensure the organizations involved did their due diligence in the name of public interest. To them, fewer layers of review may speed things along, but that arrangement would open said policy/regulation to greater risk, whether in the form of a legal challenge or unintended consequence. I however wonder if there is an example of a government organization with processes that disprove this assertion. Must a government organization move slow to be accountable?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcqjvm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7l68/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Got my first reddit cares notice. I&#39;m glad the TRA brigade is looking out for my</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:24:06Z</updated><author><name>TJ11240</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Got my first reddit cares notice. I&#39;m glad the TRA brigade is looking out for my wellbeing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7l68/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7b6h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] To what extent should we even care about workplace inefficiencies and waste? Isn</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:22:19Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">To what extent should we even care about workplace inefficiencies and waste? Isn’t consumerism and inequity better to focus on, as it wastes more resources more flagrantly? For instance, Jeff Bezos wasting resources on yachts and so on, while squeezing the lowest workers dry; financial sector employees wasting resources on fancy things, while taking over companies to fire the slightly inefficient employees. Our system seems hyperfocused on inefficiencies of the lower class, while almost completely ignoring the inefficiencies of the upper class re: resource utilization. Consider how the upper echelon of Walmart waste exorbitant resources on multiple mansions, needless cars, needless trips, etc. It makes me wonder whether unionization and labor bargaining wouldn’t ultimately be more resource-efficient, as a way to prevent Bezosian wastefulness. 

Like sure, we could fire warehouse Bob because we can force warehouse Joe to do his job, if we cut Joe’s breaks down to 15 minutes and prevent him from talking at the water cooler. And if this existence is unlivable we can replace him with Juan when he dies from a fentanyl overdose. Or Bob and Joe can band together and fire Office Edward, who takes home extra resources akin to 40 Bobs a year, and wastes them buying vodka with gold flakes in it. Which one is really immoral and deserving of efficiency-finding? I refuse to believe Office Edward is actually that valuable in terms of what he brings to the company, having known Office Edward, and MBA programs are a meme. Maybe it’s better for society for Bob and Joe to get some slack versus Edward getting 1000x the slack.

This question is kind of reinventing the wheel, but this is the angle I’m trying to look at.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7b6h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7269/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there actually any evidence that sexual activity before a certain age is harm</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:20:44Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there actually any evidence that sexual activity before a certain age is harmful and if so, is it actually less harmful if the other person is close in age? Also, at what age does sexual activity become harmless, if it ever does? Or at what age is it minimally harmful?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7269/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilc6r63/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Interesting discussion on SSC with regards to social mobility from this paper fr</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:18:48Z</updated><author><name>Just_Natural_9027</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Interesting discussion on SSC with regards to social mobility from this paper from Nature:

The share of high-SES friends among individuals with low SES is among the strongest predictors of upward income mobility identified to date.

[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04996-4](https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04996-4)

[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04997-3](https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04997-3)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilc6r63/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:31:11Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-the-heat-level-of-the-terf)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[TERFs/trans issues\]

Article is in three parts.

(1) is a wall of snapshots from the &#34;trending topics&#34; bar on Twitter for the past two weeks, with dates, as well as a snapshot of Google Trends showing that (a) the war between the Trans Exclusionary Radical Feminists (TERFs) and the gender ideology wokes is getting extremely hot, and the burn rate keeps it pretty much squarely on Twitter nonstop, above Ukraine and guns and abortion. The Google Trends graphs show TERF &amp;gt; Intersectionality in interest solidly the past two months and has intermittent peaks well above it, landing the TERF wars in a position where they seem to be overtaking even the heat level of Whiteness related topics during Floyd.

(2) is a recap of the history of the TERF war that most people here can probably skip

(3) is analysis, wherein we attempt to explain why it&#39;s getting so hot, and make predictions about what&#39;s going to happen with it going forward into next year based on an analysis of motivations of either side. Key to the analysis is the presumption that personality traits are probably fairly fixed over time due to genetic factors, which means as religiosity has fallen over time, more people with the &#34;moral certainty and self righteous indignation&#34; traits have had to find another outlet, many of which fell into the Woke bucket. With a fixed (or growing) rate of these in the woke camp, they won&#39;t bend on trans ideology even in the face of all the new entrants to the TERF war driven by school board awakenings and JK Rowling acting as a rally point.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four differen</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:27:37Z</updated><author><name>EngageInFisticuffs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four different kinds of writers on the culture war, or really any kind of commentary on conflict. 

1. Partisan propagandists. These are your Nathan J Robinsons. Their positions are predetermined, so their analyses are rarely anything but hackneyed. &#34;My side is good, the other side is bad,&#34; doesn&#39;t leave much room for nuance *or* actual insight. I used Robinson as an easy example, but there are plenty of weird Trumpists who somehow wanted to say that Russia were the good guys invading Ukraine. Although I&#39;ll totally admit that they&#39;re analyses weren&#39;t stale to start off with, they still quickly became predictable.

2. Cynics/insult analysts. I am struggling to come up with any examples right now, but there are a lot of these in respected editorial positions. These people sometimes have interesting analysis, but so often they resort to content-free insults in order to show their disdain and that they are above the conflict. Never do they ever have actually constructive things to say. They just tear stuff down.These types of analysts had their hey day in the 90s, but plenty of them are still going by inertia in respected legacy media even today. This is actually the group that annoys me the most and got me to write up this analysis because I always forget they exist, and I will be fooled into reading some article because it isn&#39;t just partisan drivel, only to realize that it is the equivalent of socio-political malingering and their delight in being unorthodox is an end-goal in itself.

3. (Un)orthodox ideologues. These are your Rod Drehers and Freddie DeBoers. Although they certainly have a side in the conflict, that side is just a means to an end, not a cause in itself. They have some greater vision that they are loyal to, and this allows them to see and critique &#34;their&#34; side in surprising and effective ways and see value in proposals from their &#34;opponents.&#34; These are the types of editorials that are really interesting to read.

4. Exhaustively fair analysts. These are the Scott Alexanders. This is the rarest type, at least in conflict commentary. Most of the people who do this are probably being paid plenty of money for private analysis. Or, if not private, at least largely wonky topics that most people don&#39;t care about. Still, these are the gold standard when it comes to commentary. Not just because if their analysis, they aren&#39;t necessarily any more insightful than the 3s, but because their attempts to engage with all opinions charitably makes them powerful when it comes to persuasion. 1s are also very powerful when it comes to persuasion with their audience, but only on whatever topics won&#39;t make them considered traitors to their cause/audience. Scott has no such limits, and as a result he has convinced people to change positions on all sorts of issues. He has made people more trans-sympathetic and turned leftists into free-market supporters.  But it is also the hardest to do. People have complained that Scott doesn&#39;t really dig in and engage with a lot of topics like he used to. This style of writing takes the most intellectual and emotional energy. It&#39;s much harder than when you already know everyone on the other side is bad and wrong and your side is good and right. Or everyone is just corrupt and stupid, no matter the side. Especially since it is hard to remain an insightful, charitable person once you have had the eye of sauron upon you. Just look at Jordan Peterson.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-a</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:22:47Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-and-hot-air-balloons)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[pollution visualization math\]

Not sure this is totally culture war, except for the fact that nuclear power itself has been such a wretched target of environmentalist culture warriors that we haven&#39;t bothered to build any nuke plants in the USA in decades.

The article does the math to figure out how much power is generated by uranium and coal, and calculates an equivalent amount of pollutant for honest comparisons. Really pretty simple. Conclusion is that two nuclear fuel assemblies of uranium, each of which are about a half a meter long and ten centimeters wide, produce the same amount of energy as enough coal to fill up (with CO2) every hot air balloon at the  Albuquerque International Balloon Fiesta (largest hot air balloon festival in the world) almost 24 times over.

Then has some visual comparisons, so people can understand the scales in question.

I also reduced the article into image meme form:

https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/22543e64-aa06-47d3-8761-2207d8ee3e09\_5360x4320.png</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums </title><updated>2022-08-22T13:57:32Z</updated><author><name>jspsfx</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums looking for interesting nuggets of information? It’s rather like panning for gold. There’s a steady stream of dirt but almost on a daily basis you will find the seed of a worthwhile idea or some information that’s being suppressed/ignored in mainstream circles.
     
I suspect this is something most curious people do, even “intelligent presenting” people who keep their rhetoric straight and opinions inoffensive. I wonder if it’s an unspoken secret, some habit we engage with after dark.
    
During covid this became a daily activity for me. I hated it though. I hated that information and idea exchange were as locked down as we were physically. I knew any given /r/lockdownskepticism post or idea could be just as valuable as a post made in any mainstream subreddit - I could sort through the bullshit. But I also knew any information outside the establishment view was going to be tainted and treated as false purely by association being stuck in the conspiracy bin.
   
Many dissenting views and/or information which contradicted the dogma of the day regarding covid were relegated to the corners of the internet which the establishment media and institutions label as crazy and dangerous.
  
Essentially, in tandem with the government, social media companies helped create a rhetorical landscape where the only information the public would consume and digest through free discourse was information they deemed acceptable.
  
You could talk about lab leak theory but it would have to be next to the tweaker claiming *they* are transmitting covid via 5G Wi-Fi signals. You could talk about potential or active side effects of the vaccine but it would have to be lumped in with people claiming everyone who got it would die within a year.
   
This seems like the playbook for how “misinformation” is going to be handled online and it’s rather concerning to me. With that in mind I’m actually drawn to check in on these forums even more. Covid information control made me wonder what else am I going to miss if I just stick to mainstream sources… And where else am I to find this information but the black market of ideas?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilb4fkt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone got recommendations for audiobooks? As you can guess by the demographics </title><updated>2022-08-22T11:33:39Z</updated><author><name>Renaultsauce</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone got recommendations for audiobooks? As you can guess by the demographics of this sub, preferably fantasy/scifi or nonfiction history.

If anyone else is looking for something, I&#39;ve really enjoyed the bobbiverse series (4th book is out, if anyone read/heard the first 3 and liked them), it&#39;s exactly at the perfect line of engaging enough to stay interesting but also not too complicated and not too action-laden so that I love to hear it in the evening/night to calm down. Basic premise is that the main character is an AI replicant of a human that existed at some point, trying to cope with his new existence as a von Neumann probe. He ultimately builds up an interstellar empire, the bobbiverse, entirely consisting of clones of himself. It&#39;s not super deep but handles many different topics, most of them reasonably well, without devolving into an author tract. For the most part refreshingly positive in attitude, which is unusual in scifi in my experience.

The First Law Trilogy, which I think was recommended here before, is okay. It&#39;s reasonably recent but is heavily reminiscent of 90s dark gritty fantasy, in both bad and good ways. A bit slow start though, and I saw the ending coming from a mile, both of which diminished my fun significantly. But the author does avoid all the most common pitfalls, like getting too overly grimdark , obvious self inserts/mary sue etc. .

&#34;The Murderbot Diaries&#34; is something I&#39;ve recently heard as well, but can&#39;t really recommend. Also with a sentient AI as the MC, it starts out as a decent if a bit repetitious contender in the &#34;dark gritty scifi comedy&#34;, but after some time the politics of the author become increasingly clear and it devolves into extremely simple black (corporations) vs white (nonbinary environmentally friendly slavery abolishing scientist communist utopia). If you like the premise, read/hear the first few stories, but don&#39;t expect it to hold up long.

All three however have decent speakers and are enjoyable to listen to.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilb4fkt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:21:11Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it not for the US**

Every so often, people bring up the fact that Taiwan&#39;s military spending is moribund, somewhere below 2% of GDP (China is at a similar level). The US is around 4%. They call for Taiwan to [get serious](https://international.thenewslens.com/article/123554) with its training and spend more on their own defence. It does not seem fair for the US to spend proportionately more for another countries security...

However, there is only so much that Taiwan can do when outnumbered 20:1 in GDP. Taiwan is totally dependent upon foreign fuel and foreign food. The island produces around 10% of their food, China around 65%. There is only one way Taiwan could hope to deter the vastly larger Chinese military: nuclear weapons. The US [shut down](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan_and_weapons_of_mass_destruction) the Taiwanese nuclear program twice. Now, the US has forward-based nuclear weapons to Taiwan in the past but it is unlikely to do so today, given that China now has the power to hit the US mainland. 

If Taiwan had nuclear weapons, there would be no potential crisis. China would not invade a country with a credible nuclear deterrent. The US enabled this looming disaster by suppressing Taiwan&#39;s nuclear ambitions and giving them vague, indefinite not-promises instead.

Since Pakistan and India acquired nuclear weapons, they had only one small skirmish when in the past they would wage full-scale wars. Naturally, the US [sanctioned and harassed](https://www.eetimes.com/u-s-lifts-sanctions-against-india-pakistan/) them for taking this step towards peace. 

There have been no full-scale great power conflicts since WW2, a 70-year historical anomaly. Nuclear weapons make it unprofitable to wage war, so states don&#39;t do it.

If my country, Australia, had nuclear weapons, we wouldn&#39;t need to fight in expensive, pointless US wars since we wouldn&#39;t need their nuclear umbrella or assistance. We would have genuine strategic independence, we could relax and enjoy mining rent.

Now, one counterargument to my nuclear panacea argument is the tail-risk of nuclear war. If the US weren&#39;t so irresponsible, there would have been a much lower chance of nuclear war during the Cold War. It was the US&#39;s decision to invent the Cuban Missile Crisis, violently objecting to internal defense decisions made by the Soviets and Cubans. There are obvious similarities with the current Ukraine war and there is the mitigating factor that Cuba was in the US sphere while Ukraine is/was/contested in the Russian sphere. I don&#39;t particularly want to get bogged down in the movement of spheres of influence though. The way the US handled the crisis was extraordinarily aggressive. The US imposed a &#39;quarantine&#39; of Cuba, an effective blockade. They flew [U-2 spy planes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuban_Missile_Crisis#Crisis_continues) over Cuban airspace and had the temerity to complain when one was shot down! They dropped dummy depth charges on Soviet submarines to force them to surface, pointlessly causing the drama that legendary Arkhipov had to resolve. The US took various steps to raise tensions, dispersing its bombers around civilian airports and keeping some constantly in the air. They made it look as though they were preparing for nuclear war.

The 1983 nuclear scare is also the US&#39;s fault. Why were they launching [psychological operations](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Able_Archer_83#Psychological_operations) and exercises right next to Kamchatka if not to spook the Soviets? Raising tensions in this way is deeply irresponsible, it erodes the commons of mutually assured destruction to eke out small-scale gains in analyzing Soviet military readiness, observing radar patterns etc... It&#39;s needlessly provocative to mock-punch somebody but pull your fist away at the last moment. SDI was similarly bad - if you don&#39;t want a nuclear war, don&#39;t invite a pre-emptive strike by creating a strategic defense system! Of course, the US is still doing it, they left the ABM treaty and have been building up a large missile defense apparatus via AEGIS and GMD.

While North Korean leadership is regularly labelled as insane, they have not invaded anybody since the 1950s. Iran hasn&#39;t invaded anyone either, though they do wage proxy war (an activity not unknown by the US). On what basis can we argue that they would be irresponsible nuclear powers? Occasional political rhetoric calling for the destruction of Israel should not come before the logic of MAD, which has a far stronger empirical and historical basis. The Israelis have their fare share of [religious terrorists](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_religious_terrorism), yet they have remained responsible with their arsenal. 

Obviously, it&#39;s advantageous for the US (and other nuclear powers to a lesser extent) to sanction and bully other states into refraining from nuclearizing. The more states that have nuclear weapons, the less powerful they become. If Iraq or Libya had nukes, the US couldn&#39;t have attacked them. The US of course has the strongest global power projection capacity and thus the most to lose from massive nuclearization. It isn&#39;t surprising that the US is the most eager to suppress nuclear weapons. 

But I think this is important to consider when we discuss the looming risk of war, of geopolitical conflict generally. The assumption of nuclear risk in my view is excessively high and confuses nuclear risks with US risks. If Ukraine had nuclear weapons, there would be no problem today. What is far more destabilizing are airy promises of unspecified support for countries far away from their nuclear patron. Taiwan is only the most obvious example.

If the non-proliferation treaty didn&#39;t exist, the world would be a much better place and there would be fewer wars.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](h</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:16:14Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/british-indians-racism-muslim-islamophobia-b2149026.html?utm_content=Echobox&amp;amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Main&amp;amp;utm_source=Twitter#Echobox=1660996247) that turned a lot of heads in Indian online space. Over the past decade, the political zeitgeist in India has been apparently captured indisputably by Hindu Nationalism in the national capacity, while still struggling in many states. Any strand of liberalism left isn&#39;t really a direction anymore, but pressure from above or outside. The term &#39;South Asia&#39; is not very well liked in India, which is seen by many nationalists as a reductionism of their civilisation to another geographic patch of landmass and above all, a tacit affirmation of the current nation states of India and Pakistan as equally legitimate in inheriting the cultural ethnos of the subcontinent.

But in more recent years, the term has produced another bone to pick. White liberals are largely seen as the new cultural imperialists out to atomise societies and rearrange social relations between the sexes, ethnic groups, etc. They&#39;re also seen as militantly anti-India on matters such as Kashmir, with &#39;South Asian&#39; think tanks being their academic arm to dissipate psyops against India. Finally, they&#39;re perceived to be tacitly pro-Pakistan. The last one is a litmus test for a lot of Indians as to whether its all about values or consumer demographics. Is Hindu Nationalism a genuine concern, or just another cudgel against Indians? If Indians are fair game to be criticised for their attitude towards Pakistanis, the reverse should be axiomatic, correct? Well, BBC and other media are seen as hypocritically smearing India over its domestic problems with communalism, caste, gender, etc., while violent crimes by Pakistani origin men in the UK are obscured, leave alone Pakistan&#39;s own social problems. Last year, NYT&#39;s [job listing](https://www.newslaundry.com/2021/07/08/did-nyts-job-posting-for-a-business-correspondent-in-india-deserve-the-outrage-it-got) for an India correspondent sparked a huge furore in Indian media. The part about India&#39;s South Asian neighbours especially raised eyebrows as to whether the implication was that India is the belligerent actor in the region, when every single one of the [Indo-Pak wars](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Pakistani_wars_and_conflicts) was initiated by Pakistan, one of which even involved a [huge genocide](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1971_Bangladesh_genocide) by the Pakistani Army. This event is not discussed in the media, and Indian syllabi consider every even after Independence as contemporary history, so its not discussed in history textbooks either. But ever since war ignited in Ukraine almost 6 months ago, and India&#39;s repeated refusal to condemn the invasion and continued purchase of Russian oil, 1971 has been resuscitated yet again, as was Soviet support to India at the time. Suddenly, many Hindu Nationalists who were previously indifferent to Russia, turned [Russophilic](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/03/29/india-russia-ukraine-media/). But I think this is largely out of hostility to liberals than anything else.

For now, it looks like Hindu Nationalism is not about to lose its political clout in India and this will continue to leave lots of annoyance with liberals. Even the BJP&#39;s political opponents have caved on key issues like the [Rohingya refugees](http://twocircles.net/2022aug22/446679.html) to pose any competition. In all, the Nehruvian era Congress elites simply did not connect to the subalterns in producing the cultural and economic prosperity that they had wanted, whether in their socialist shade during the Cold War or in their neoliberal shade since 2004. And the vacuum it left behind is no longer its own to fill.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilab9wd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, this is going to be a case of &#34;sheltered religious conservative doesn&#39;t unde</title><updated>2022-08-22T05:16:44Z</updated><author><name>urquan5200</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, this is going to be a case of &#34;sheltered religious conservative doesn&#39;t understand slang&#34; but... what is a fuckboy? The term was referenced in a YouTube video I watched and I looked it up, all I got were definitions like &#34;a guy who lies to women to get sex,&#34; &#34;a serial monogamist who convinces women he loves them but just wants sex&#34;... basically the key points were 1) wanting sex not a relationship and 2) willing to lie to women about their intentions.

Is that it? I dunno, I guess it just seems like that&#39;s a very imprecise definition for a word like that. Do the definitions I found exhaust the meaning of the word or am I missing something?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilab9wd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilaauv3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Would this have been a better place to post my [synth question](/r/TheMotte/comm</title><updated>2022-08-22T05:12:00Z</updated><author><name>kcu51</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Would this have been a better place to post my [synth question](/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/il1dgn9/)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilaauv3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il8f1zq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What makes someone autistic?  I went out with a hot girl and described myself as</title><updated>2022-08-21T20:06:18Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What makes someone autistic?  I went out with a hot girl and described myself as sort of autistic.  Assume a decent amount of people here are in that group.  And nowadays that’s databale.  Like I have text receipts where I got in an argument with someone and they made fun of me for being autistic.  Sort of work in HFT.  I went to math tournaments as a kid.  So I guess my question is what’s like an autistic versus I’m a normie who can do math.  I guess musks claimed it but is he really that or just smart?  Nowadays it’s beneficial to just let people put you in that group.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il8f1zq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il8e07e/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] A question about AI and copyright.

I&#39;ve written some books, nothing amazing and</title><updated>2022-08-21T19:59:00Z</updated><author><name>RGbudvit</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">A question about AI and copyright.

I&#39;ve written some books, nothing amazing and nothing I&#39;m going to tell you about here.

I had this thought though and a question follows from it - AI is writing an awful lot of stuff. 

My question is - 

What measures have the creators of AI made to make sure they either don&#39;t violate my copyright or where they do but under fair use they attribute correctly to myself/another author?

Similar questions related to artwork spring to mind - are the AI blocked from creating already existing and protected images?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il8e07e/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il85eue/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Kamachi&#39;s *A Certain Magical Index*, b</title><updated>2022-08-21T18:59:05Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Kamachi&#39;s *A Certain Magical Index*, book 1. The anime was...fascinating in strange ways. Every time the topic was science, it was incredibly compelling. On the other hand, every time the topic was magic, it was horribly dull. This had the unfortunate effect of making the show boring whenever Touma was on-screen, and the very fortunate effect of making the spin-off anime *A Certain Scientific Railgun* excellent. My theory is that the writer has a respectable IQ and excellent writing talent, so whenever there&#39;s some real-world basis (however distant) for his thoughts like the science parts, it&#39;s hard not to be sucked in. But whenever the topic is based on non-empirical things, all we get is a jumble of complex thoughts that can&#39;t be understood unless you&#39;re the author.

On reflection, Academy City is a very dark dream, a place where every citizen is an experiment, everyone is complicit, and criminality is institutionalized. Nevertheless the peace of the everyday lives of the characters is the true focus, together with a desire to hold on to gratitude at having met the people they call friends, despite the nature of the place that they met them in. Hopefully the book will bring out more of the compelling side of this author by giving more breathing room to his thoughts.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il85eue/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7repi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Where are all the East Asian CEOs? Inspired by [this list of Indian CEOs.](https</title><updated>2022-08-21T17:22:24Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Where are all the East Asian CEOs? Inspired by [this list of Indian CEOs.](https://nitter.net/nihalmehta/status/1509512345134972935)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7repi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7hb7o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] How do I learn better techniques and standard practices for coding, given a amat</title><updated>2022-08-21T16:14:06Z</updated><author><name>hh26</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">How do I learn better techniques and standard practices for coding, given a amateurish knowledge do-it-yourself background, without wasting my time on basic stuff I already know?


As background, I took an AP Comp Sci class in highschool, and then mostly didn&#39;t do programming in undergrad except occasionally messing around on my calculator as I majored in Math.  In grad school, I ended up drifting more in the direction of game theory, and started doing mathematical modeling, which gradually become more and more of my emphasis until now as a postdoc that&#39;s pretty much all that I do.  I create a mathematical model that models some scenario, program it, explore the results of the model and tweak stuff, and then write and publish results about it.

Also, I program almost exclusively in Java because that&#39;s what I learned in highschool, though I have dabbled in a couple other languages.

So I do a lot of programming, but it&#39;s all self-contained stuff meant for my own use, and mostly self-taught via googling things whenever I need to know how to do something.  I&#39;m pretty good at taking a thing I need to do and hacking together the right steps and loops in the right order to make it work, but I suspect a more well-studied programmer would look at my spaghetti code in horror.  In particular, I suspect that my main flaws are

1. Lack of comments.  I sometimes write them, but often don&#39;t because I know what I&#39;m doing in the moment and also keep changing things on the fly

2. Lack of optimization.  I&#39;m aware that this is a thing, and the general idea.  I can make sure I don&#39;t use like a O(n^3 ) structure if a O(n^2 ) will do or something, but I haven&#39;t learned like common techniques for recognizing shortcuts that save processing time, or like this function nobody ever uses because it&#39;s ten times less efficient than this equivalent function.

3. General project organization?  Like, I separate stuff into classes and methods, and try to keep them organized nicely, but often it ends up as spaghetti code and when I want to do multiple algorithms that are similar but with slightly different steps, I&#39;m never sure whether to copy/paste a new method and change stuff there, or try to make one method more robust with booleans to toggle different steps on and off.  And like, planning ahead to make stuff more robust ahead of time and save time in the future.


Stuff like that.  And just general practices.  As I&#39;m looking towards possibly moving out of academia and into industry, I&#39;m worried my code will look very amateur and be hard for other people to use if I end up collaborating with people and/or designing something used by someone other than myself.  I&#39;m hoping to find some sort of resource that I can use to learn techniques for code design/structure/planning/efficiency, without wasting my time on basics of how to code in the first place that I already know.

Any suggestions or comments are welcome.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7hb7o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il6qiwz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Are there any other places like here?

I&#39;m talking obscure but reasonable.

I fe</title><updated>2022-08-21T12:51:02Z</updated><author><name>Random45666</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Are there any other places like here?

I&#39;m talking obscure but reasonable.

I feel like everybody in Forums/subreddits like these, talks with an undercurrent of belonging to the shadow government looking down on society discussing how to rearrange it.

That may sound elitist and maybe even an insult but it is way better than being in a comment section where people are insulting each other over grammatical errors.

I&#39;m already aware of:
Slatestarcodex 
Theschism
Thelastpsychiatrist
Datasecretslox
Lesswrong</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il6qiwz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il67f5p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What is this place?</title><updated>2022-08-21T08:51:35Z</updated><author><name>scomosucks</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What is this place?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il67f5p/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il63zw8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Recently bought a ninja air fryer - one of the big buggers.

Need advice/recipe </title><updated>2022-08-21T08:03:07Z</updated><author><name>imtiredofsleeping</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Recently bought a ninja air fryer - one of the big buggers.

Need advice/recipe books to make the most of it. What&#39;s the best thing about owning an air fryer?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il63zw8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/il1dgn9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] How plausible is a scenario where a patient world-optimizing AGI develops the te</title><updated>2022-08-20T06:36:12Z</updated><author><name>kcu51</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">How plausible is a scenario where a patient world-optimizing AGI develops the technology and capacity to create an synthetic human representative; and from then on works as much as possible through synth proxies (or natural humans directed by the synths)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/il1dgn9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driv</title><updated>2022-08-20T04:28:31Z</updated><author><name>gearofnett</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driven by some goal that I would set for myself, but I&#39;ve managed to achieve everything I wanted in the past few years, and the new goals I try to set for myself are not motivating enough for me to change my behavior. My regular day consists of waking up at 12-3pm, browsing the internet/reading a book/watching youtube or movie + 1 hour of work (if needed) + cook food, then going to bed at 3-6am. It&#39;s not all bad, on the weekends I go out with friends, and I also travel 3-4 times a year, but I understand that my regular day schedule is extremely unhealthy. If I keep living like that I won&#39;t be well physically or mentally. Even though I understand the consequences, it&#39;s still not motivating enough to change my ways. I try to fix my sleep, but after 2-3 days I&#39;m back to that degen schedule because I literally don&#39;t have a reason to be awake early. I work for myself, so I don&#39;t need to be up early. All my friends and family work regular jobs, so I can&#39;t interact with them at that time either. I&#39;m physically fit (as much as one can be when not working out consistently) and don&#39;t eat junk food, so I don&#39;t have an urgent need or want to go to the gym. I used to work out in the past and I know how much of an impact it has on your mental, but again, for some reason me knowing all that is not enough to push me to change. 

I&#39;m very tempted to get a regular 9-5 job or join the military just for the sake of having responsibilities that would force me to have a normal human schedule and hope that the habits I learn during that time stick with me for the rest of my life.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikxlm5f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m attempting to smoke two huge pork shoulders that are a total of 16 lbs this </title><updated>2022-08-19T13:42:17Z</updated><author><name>yofuckreddit</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m attempting to smoke two huge pork shoulders that are a total of 16 lbs this weekend. The story of my smoking experiences with pork are ones of being off by multiple hours in terms of completion, so I&#39;m working a whole day ahead of time. If I get done early, which has never happened, I&#39;ll wrap the meat in aluminum trays and keep it warm. 

Since most of y&#39;all are on the west coast I assume the proclivity for cooking vast cuts of meat this way isn&#39;t as popular as it is around my neck of the woods. But right now I have a small electric Masterbilt smoker. It was unbelievably affordable in my estimation, it&#39;s relatively easy to clean, but I&#39;ve been electrocuted while it&#39;s sprinkling a couple times and I&#39;ve always wondered if I should be stepping up to a pellet grill at some point. Any comment from someone who&#39;s made the move would be welcome. I only smoke stuff 6-7 times a year, so perhaps it&#39;s a luxury I shouldn&#39;t be considering anyway.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikxlm5f/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikwl5po/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] It&#39;s Janmashtami today. Janmashtami is the day when Lord Krishna was born. He is</title><updated>2022-08-19T07:19:12Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">It&#39;s Janmashtami today. Janmashtami is the day when Lord Krishna was born. He is an incarnation of Lord Vishnu and is one of the most beloved deity.

He was the charioteer for the supreme warrior Arjun during the Mahabharat. Arjuna didn&#39;t want to fight the war and Lord Krishna had a long conversation with him about life which is known as the Gita, the supreme Scripture for many Hindus.

I shall fast today and spend time with my family, read some theology thanks to Gita Press Gorakhpur.

The very first thing this commentary on the Gita says  is that one must appreciate being born a human. We can experience, conceive and feel divinity, something no other being can do and no matter how bad things are, we will always be lucky as compared to most animals.

This isn&#39;t the same as me going out for talking to girls or consuming substances but I like this a lot. I find theology quite profound and enjoyable to read. I find it more than just fun and hence the motif to post about today here.

May Lord Krishna bless us all. Happy Janmashtami to everyone reading this.

Jai Shri Krishna.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikwl5po/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikuljbf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Three of my family members have gotten Lyme disease (edit: actually one case was</title><updated>2022-08-18T21:25:23Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Three of my family members have gotten Lyme disease (edit: actually one case was anaplasmosis) this summer. I&#39;d never heard of anyone I know getting it before. There seems to be an epidemic. Any advice on how to avoid it?

It seems like a horrible disease to get, much worse than Covid.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikuljbf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iku9dfu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Where can I buy a really good umbrella? I&#39;ve been annoyed or disappointed by mos</title><updated>2022-08-18T20:09:37Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Where can I buy a really good umbrella? I&#39;ve been annoyed or disappointed by most umbrellas I&#39;ve owned, so I&#39;ve never really used them much. somebody out there must make a good one right?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iku9dfu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iktdbsz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I can recommend [this episode of Andrew Huberman&#39;s podcast](https://www.youtube.</title><updated>2022-08-18T16:43:24Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I can recommend [this episode of Andrew Huberman&#39;s podcast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DTCmprPCDqc) to anybody interested in longevity, exercise, nutrition, testosterone/estrogen and similar health and science-related topics.  
Phenomenal episode, I learned a ton from it.  
 In fact, I kind of wish we had a monthly or yearly megathread for discussing self-improvenent in the context of high-quality scientific studies. I think this is a topic with surprisingly little discussion for how significant the potential benefits are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iktdbsz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikq6pg1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any tips on getting a good Job Without going to college? Like internship or Cert</title><updated>2022-08-17T23:41:56Z</updated><author><name>Nerd_199</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any tips on getting a good Job Without going to college? Like internship or Certifications , Etc. I am personal real worry about getting myself in debt.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikq6pg1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition</title><updated>2022-08-17T20:45:16Z</updated><author><name>Gorf__</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition for a long time, and for a while I&#39;ve been circling this as probably the best approach to food long-term for health and longevity. The ethics side of it is nice too, but I&#39;m not super interested in discussing that. This is mostly an experiment to see how I feel, and how my weight and blood markers look after a while. I&#39;m trying to take a 90/10 approach, eating as plant-based as possible for all of my staple meals at home, but allowing some meat and dairy in when necessary, mostly when eating out. I haven&#39;t eaten any red meat or poultry in a few weeks, but I&#39;ve had fish here and then when out at restaurants, as well as some dairy stuff - some cheese here and there and ranch dressing.

Generally I&#39;ve been a hardcore meat-eater, so up until about 3 weeks ago, every dish was very focused around meat, and any vegetables were there as condiments or just because I felt like I &#34;should&#34; make myself eat some broccoli. It seems to me that this is an extremely common approach to food in the US. Everyone I know eats this way. Most of us have this idea that if you take away meat and dairy then you&#39;re stuck just eating salads all the time, but that&#39;s not the case at all. I&#39;ve been eating oatmeal + fruit + some agave for breakfast; a smoothie and usually some sort of leftovers for lunch; and the formula for dinner is roughly: some a carb (whole grain pasta, brown rice, quinoa, etc) with a few vegetables mixed in and some kind of sauce for flavoring. The other night I made whole grain spaghetti with homemade tomato sauce (just cook down canned diced tomatoes and throw in some garlic and spices), sautéed mushrooms, roasted asparagus, and then topped with sautéed spinach, and then I ate that for lunch yesterday and today, and it was delicious.

So it&#39;s been a big change, but I&#39;m loving it. When you&#39;re eating a wide variety of fruits and vegetables, there&#39;s just a lot more variation in flavor and texture going around. I&#39;m finding out that meat itself is kind of boring: it&#39;s mostly texture, salt, and fat flavor. It&#39;s all of the stuff surrounding it that makes it good. Really, meat is already losing its allure to me altogether.

I also feel less full and bloated after a meal. I&#39;ll be full because of the bulk of all the vegetables I just ate, but that goes away pretty quickly; otherwise I feel much better than I would after pounding a burger and fries.

Why am I using the term &#34;plant-based&#34; and not vegan? To me, vegan has a connotation of doing it more for ethical concerns, and plant-based has a connotation of being based more on nutrition. But that&#39;s just my own perception. A whole food plant based diet is one where you focus on eating plants that came from the ground more or less directly, maybe heating, chopping, and/or seasoning them first, but not much alteration beyond that. Ie, avoiding as many processed foods as possible - so while it&#39;s probably ok to have an Impossible Burger every now and then, it shouldn&#39;t be a staple. Folks who eat vegan for ethical reasons are probably more likely to eat processed foods like tofurkey or whatever, which isn&#39;t really any healthier than just eating meat all the time.

So the inevitable question is: _so where are you getting all of your protein?_ First of all, the whole &#34;incomplete protein&#34; thing isn&#39;t true - all plants have all amino acids. Yes, the amounts of each vary, but if you&#39;re eating a variety of plants then it&#39;s nothing to worry about. Incomplete proteins were written about in this popular vegetarian book in the 70s, and the author later realized her mistake and backed off of it, but it was too late - the idea had already been solidified in public consciousness.

Second, the actual amount of protein we need is probably majorly inflated for most people. Sure, bodybuilders might need more, but even they are probably majorly overdoing it. There&#39;s some good discussion about this in the book _Proteinaholic_ by Garth Davis.

In any case, it&#39;s pretty easy to hit solid protein numbers from eating plants, especially if you&#39;re getting lots of legumes. And protein shakes are still a thing if you need even more.

The only issue I&#39;ve had so far is that I&#39;m farting a lot, and the farts are pretty bad. I think I went overboard in going from eating like 10-15g of fiber a day to like 50g. I&#39;m going to try dial that back and then ramp it back up more slowly. So maybe more white rice and pasta for a bit as I give my GI tract more time to adjust to the massive amounts of fiber.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpds17/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m near the end of pregnancy, and I&#39;ve got a few problems going on.

A month or</title><updated>2022-08-17T20:29:21Z</updated><author><name>sagion</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m near the end of pregnancy, and I&#39;ve got a few problems going on.

A month or so ago I was diagnosed with gestational diabetes. It&#39;s not fair. Of the [risk factors](https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/basics/risk-factors.html):

&amp;gt;You’re at risk for gestational diabetes (diabetes while pregnant) if you:

&amp;gt;   * Had gestational diabetes during a previous pregnancy.
&amp;gt;   * Have given birth to a baby who weighed over 9 pounds.
&amp;gt;   * Are overweight.
&amp;gt;   * Are more than 25 years old.
&amp;gt;   * Have a family history of type 2 diabetes.
&amp;gt;   * Have a hormone disorder called polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS).
&amp;gt;   * Are an African American, Hispanic or Latino, American Indian, Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander person.

I have one - over 25. Never been tested for PCOS, so I guess I can&#39;t completely rule that out, but there&#39;s a reason I&#39;ve never tested for it. As far as my doctor and I can tell, this was random chance. My pancreas isn&#39;t processing insulin right because of pregnancy hormones from the placenta. Now I have to track my diet for carb intake, limiting but not avoiding carbs, test my blood glucose, and maintain some daily exercise (been getting harder to do). The diet is the most frustrating part. Ok, no, the long term risks to both my baby and me are the most frustrating thing. There&#39;s not much risk of a large-baby-birth, which I&#39;ll come back to, but the birth issues are worrisome if unlikely, and then the higher chance of both of us getting type II diabetes is, again, unfair. I would like to know the weight of that risk when controlled for the other risk factors. When your gestational diabetes may have been random chance and not because of factors that also influence type II diabetes (weight, family history, activity level), how big is that risk increase? My doctor thinks in all likelihood everything will turn out fine as long as I stick with the plan.

As I mentioned, the low-carb diet is a bit frustrating. I&#39;ve adapted for the most part, but planning consistent meals is still tricky, particularly when my pizza-craving husband forgets my restrictions. We&#39;ve gone out of town a couple of times and had family come stay with us. Those worked out ok mostly. I had to find a couple of creative spots to test myself, and once while out I broke down in tears after spending 15 minutes looking over a couple of walkable cafes for a quick, low-carb lunch option only to find my choice opened at 11 but didn&#39;t start the kitchen until 11:30, when we had to be elsewhere. I had also skipped breakfast and passed up getting a latte, chai, or pastry, which would all be bad diet choices. In general, it takes a lot more time and thought to pick out a restaurant that won&#39;t wreck my numbers. So much bread, rice, potatoes, or noodles that I&#39;d rather not spend money on to not eat. And then there&#39;s looking up food nutrition, guessing what information gets close to what I&#39;m actually having. Not fun when calorie counting, even worse when my baby&#39;s health is on the line. Less bad when I&#39;m home and can go with home cooking, but still tedious.

On top of this, my baby keeps hovering in the 20th percentile of fetal weight. My doctor is a little concerned but otherwise chill about this, believing that he just may be a genetically small baby since I&#39;m small myself (5&#39;3&#34; and petite). My husband, however, is very worried about the negative effects of a low-weight birth and wants me to gain weight. That&#39;s not very compatible with what I&#39;m supposed to do to manage my gestational diabetes. Low carb cuts out a lot of high-calorie stuff, particularly *yummy* high-calorie foods. I may have dropped a pound in the first few days of the diagnosis, before I got the guidance, when all I came up with as &#34;safe to eat&#34; and easy was salad. Now I&#39;ve got more meat, dairy, and nuts in there. I&#39;ve agreed with my husband to try tracking my calories to make sure I am getting enough, and he&#39;s agreed to try to attend the next appointment to talk to my doctor about the baby&#39;s weight. It&#39;s stressful and bizarre to hear my husband say he wants me to get fat. I don&#39;t want my baby to be too small, but I also don&#39;t want to exacerbate the gestational diabetes by gaining excess weight. Throw in typical late pregnancy bad sleep, and it&#39;s all so stressful to balance. I&#39;d just like our little guy to get here healthy, safe, and sound.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpds17/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikp4cjy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I have a £500 &#34;learning&#34; budget from work, and no idea what to spend it on. I am</title><updated>2022-08-17T19:30:53Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I have a £500 &#34;learning&#34; budget from work, and no idea what to spend it on. I am a software tester looking for a programming job, but all the programming resources I use range from free to very cheap. I could buy physical textbooks, but prefer digital (which are free or piratable).

Budget can be spent on learning &#34;anything&#34;, e.g. pottery lessons, but I must be a boring person and don&#39;t have many hobbies or ideas.

Any suggestions? Good programming resources to spend money on? Novel ideas?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikp4cjy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikof5fq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How likely is it that various common minor health problems (e.g. tinnitus) are c</title><updated>2022-08-17T16:53:19Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How likely is it that various common minor health problems (e.g. tinnitus) are caused sexually transmitted infections? If they are, is there a way to undo the damage or get rid of the infection?

EDIT: This was not a question specifically about tinnitus. That was just an example.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikof5fq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikoevdl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Is Adrafiil available anywhere?  If not, any suggestions for a replacement?</title><updated>2022-08-17T16:51:35Z</updated><author><name>Iconochasm</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Is Adrafiil available anywhere?  If not, any suggestions for a replacement?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikoevdl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmw6jf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I need to find a new hobby that&#39;s worth my time and provides immediate rewards w</title><updated>2022-08-17T09:35:25Z</updated><author><name>societal</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I need to find a new hobby that&#39;s worth my time and provides immediate rewards when I&#39;m done with it and incentive to do it more?  Any advice?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmw6jf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmstw7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-17T08:49:39Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmstw7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/w</title><updated>2022-08-17T08:44:43Z</updated><author><name>whenhaveiever</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/wellness_wednesday_for_june_22_2022/id9zyuu/). Has it really been eight weeks?

The pregnancy has been coming along nicely. We&#39;ve had two sets of ultrasounds so far, and our kid is the size of a lemon now. I&#39;ve heard about pregnancy cravings, but I&#39;d never heard of pregnancy aversions. They&#39;re apparently a thing, and it hops from one food to the next, including long-time favorite foods, so finding something that she&#39;s willing to eat can be challenging. But morning sickness barely showed up, and nothing like in the movies, so we&#39;re thankful for that. We&#39;re starting to figure out how to rearrange the house and loosely thinking about names. Instead of paying some $700 for a DNA test now that would tell us the sex, we&#39;ll wait until the week 20 ultrasound to find out for free. In the meantime, I&#39;m more accustomed to using the singular *they* than my mom is, and accidentally had her thinking we were having twins since I kept saying *they*.

I visited my parents (on the other side of the country, so I&#39;m not there very often). I got there in time to help my dad come home from rehab, and help both my parents through a remodel of their ground floor to add a shower plus room for a wheelchair to negotiate through the bathroom. That way dad can have everything he needs without stairs. He eats very little, and when we try to encourage him, he says he &#34;just can&#39;t.&#34; Finding something that *he&#39;s* willing to eat can also be challenging. Because he&#39;s anemic, his doctor put him on prenatal vitamins as a cheap source of easy iron, and with a few things going on in his gut, he&#39;s gotten a few ultrasounds. It&#39;s odd how life rhymes sometimes. Since I&#39;ve been back on this side of the country, dad was in and out of the hospital another time. They suspected a fistula and he was going to get surgery, then they decided he doesn&#39;t have one and just gave him antibiotics. I&#39;ve lost count of how many times he&#39;s been in there in the last year and a half, and while each one is necessary at the time, each time he comes back weaker and has to spend weeks regaining his strength.

We also visited her parents (not as far away as mine, but far enough that it had been awhile). Since that trip, I&#39;ve found it hard to get back to the normal routine. It seems especially more difficult to get up in the morning, and I have to really push myself to get going. I hope it&#39;s just a slump. I think part of it is regretting that I moved away from my parents way back when, and that I&#39;ve spent so much time away from them. I think part of it is in some way realizing that I&#39;m going to be sleeping much less once the baby comes, and so I might as well enjoy it while I can. But I&#39;m also not enjoying it. It makes me feel like crap.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>