<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T23:18:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheM</title><updated>2022-07-13T23:18:46Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?context=3). I did indeed start swiping on other guys on Tinder. I somehow got four matches in a couple days, and two of them didn&#39;t even ghost me immediately! We switched to Snapchat texts and everything.

...which was *absolutely exhausting*. I don&#39;t understand how people chat over text with near-strangers they&#39;re trying to possibly date. The notification sound now produces not so much butterflies as the panic response.

One guy gave me kind of pushy/weird vibes after a bit, so I blocked him, solving one problem. The other guy seems pretty cool so far. I followed TracingWoodgrains&#39; advice of suggesting an in-person meeting soon, which seemed to go over well, but he&#39;s not going to be free until the weekend, dooming me to several days of awkward texting. We might do a call soon at least.

On one hand, I hope it goes well, but on the other, I wouldn&#39;t be too upset if this connection disintegrated. Perhaps I should hold out for meeting people in-person or as friends of friends. The board game group this week involved a guy who I&#39;m pretty sure is gay; he&#39;s well outside my age range, but there being any gay guys there is progress.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1ycv6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [The Case Against Judicial Review](https://prospect.org/justice/the-case-against</title><updated>2022-07-13T22:45:46Z</updated><author><name>SaxifragetheGreen</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[The Case Against Judicial Review](https://prospect.org/justice/the-case-against-judicial-review)

Judicial review, first implemented in Marbury v Madison, is the basis of the powers traditionally held by the Supreme Court. This article goes over the history of it, but I can&#39;t get over the slant. It reads like nothing more nor less than sour grapes. Judicial review is bad because it is leading to bad outcomes today, right now. Starting from the end of the article:

&amp;gt;Under any government, there is always a danger of its power being abused. Democratically elected legislatures are not immune from this problem. It must be admitted that, should Republicans take control of Congress and the White House without any constraint from the Court, there’s a strong chance they’d pass all manner of abusive stuff. The Florida legislature, for example, recently passed a bigoted “don’t say gay” bill that blatantly violates the civil rights of LGBT teachers.

&amp;gt;But the risk of theoretically unconstrained congressional majorities must be set against the current fact of the Court steadily stealing the powers of Congress, eroding the freedom of the people—and, of course, doing nothing to protect gay Florida teachers from a feral state legislature. It’s far from the first time American courts have ignored the Bill of Rights, and it won’t be the last.

Bad outcomes, therefore judicial review is bad now, and while it could be worse in the future, we have to do something now.

From earlier:

&amp;gt;A current or future president, in response to some particularly egregious Supreme Court diktat, would explain their problems with the ruling, and insist that they will not obey the decision. They would say that in their opinion, Marbury v. Madison was wrongly decided, that the Court does not get to claim sole power to interpret the Constitution, and that the Constitution has no stipulation about the U.S. being a judicial dictatorship. From now on, if Congress, for example, directs the president to regulate air pollution, then they will do as instructed, rather than obeying the Court’s wishes.

Of course, we have had prior Presidents who have done exactly this! And what does the article have to say about Old Hickory?

&amp;gt;While challenging the judiciary is commonly associated with Andrew Jackson, the two best presidents in history, Abraham Lincoln and Franklin Roosevelt, had no choice but to directly confront the Court in order to advance justice.

While commonly associated with (bad president) Jackson, it&#39;s also been used by (good presidents) Lincoln and Roosevelt!

Now, I&#39;m no fan of Marbury v Madison. I don&#39;t think judicial review should be as powerful as it is today. But this author barely grapples with the fact that it is a sword that cuts both ways. Without judicial review, you don&#39;t get Brown v Board, you don&#39;t get Roe v Wade, you don&#39;t get Chevron v NRDC, you don&#39;t get Wickard v Filburn. Without judicial review you certainly don&#39;t get the two biggest Left wins in the court in the last decade, Obergefell v Hodges and Bostock v Clayton County. The things being specifically being complained about, West Virginia v EPA and Dobbs v Jackson&#39;s WWH, are themselves reversals of previously enacted judicial review!

So I ask the motte, is judicial review good, or bad? Has it outlived its usefulness, or was it ever useful? And when and how should Marbury v Madison be contested, if at all? I had hoped for a more nuanced take on it, but the article I shared got me thinking.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1ycv6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1j84r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A bit of news that should surprise no one paying attention to social media and i</title><updated>2022-07-13T21:01:48Z</updated><author><name>_Cullis</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A bit of news that should surprise no one paying attention to social media and its role in modern society:   


A journalist from an outfit that is hellbanned on reddit finds that ex-CIA [people have been hired](https://archive.ph/Aykej) to manage Facebook content policies.   


There&#39;s a [nice video](https://twitter.com/AlanRMacLeod/status/1546969640546582529) , where a the guy is explaining his role in developing rules  for permissible content to a sympathetic suitably ethnic looking woman.    


Doesn&#39;t mention he worked 17 years for the CIA, left there as [a senior analytic manager at CIA](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FXfuD5HWYAkobwY?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=large), with a focus on &#34;impact of influence operations on social movements, security and democracy&#34;.      


&amp;gt;Aaron Berman has devoted his career to making online spaces safe and constructive for democracy and civic discussion. He has more than two decades of experience in tech policy and national security, with a focus in online trust and safety and content moderation, first at the CIA and now at Meta (formerly Facebook). He has a Masters in Public Policy from Georgetown and BA from Williams College in computer science and music.  


At least his linkedin is honest!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1j84r/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1aso9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So an interesting culture war microcosm of the past week or two has been around </title><updated>2022-07-13T20:06:55Z</updated><author><name>huadpe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So an interesting culture war microcosm of the past week or two has been around the case of a 10 year old being raped and needing an abortion in Ohio.

Initial reporting only came from an article [sourced to an Indiana doctor who&#39;d had a 10 year old child brought in for an abortion after one was not available in Ohio.](https://www.indystar.com/story/news/health/2022/07/01/indiana-abortion-law-roe-v-wade-overturned-travel/7779936001/)  The story naturally attracted a lot of attention from abortion-rights advocates up to and including [the President.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/07/08/biden-abortion-10-year-old-rape-victim/)  Given the story&#39;s visceral impact and the general inability of Republican politicians [to defend the policy,](https://www.politico.com/news/2022/07/03/kristi-noem-abortion-children-00043886) there was a lot of skepticism thrown at the initial reporting.

Most notably, the [attorney general of Ohio](https://www.fox19.com/2022/07/12/not-whisper-evidence-show-10-year-old-ohio-rape-victim-got-abortion-indiana-ag-yost-tells-fox-news/) went on Fox News and claimed the story had no evidence, and the [Wall Street Journal](https://www.wsj.com/articles/an-abortion-story-too-good-to-confirm-joe-biden-ten-year-old-girl-indiana-ohio-caitlin-bernard-11657648618) called it a &#34;fanciful tale.&#34;

Today we have confirmation that [a man was arrested and charged with a crime fitting that description in Columbus, OH.](https://www.dispatch.com/story/news/2022/07/13/columbus-man-charged-rape-10-year-old-led-abortion-in-indiana/10046625002/)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1aso9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0u4zm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Fresh off [the lithium debacle](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7iAABhWpcGeP5e6S</title><updated>2022-07-13T18:19:26Z</updated><author><name>89237849237498237427</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Fresh off [the lithium debacle](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7iAABhWpcGeP5e6SB/it-s-probably-not-lithium), Slime Mold Time Mold (SMTM) has a new blogpost on *one weird trick* that causes weight loss: [eating potatoes, and only potatoes.](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2022/07/12/lose-10-6-pounds-in-four-weeks-with-this-one-weird-trick-discovered-by-local-slime-hive-mind-doctors-grudgingly-respect-them-hope-to-become-friends/). The idea is that eating a diet consistent solely of potatoes will lead to considerable weight loss, and the results are plain to see. [No one gained weight](https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ahPd4EygAeEXd2we3MAb5EuX_Wm0sCGBPQ4qYjg6u8iIJF9ppFKh9rO9SQxEzAfTgn-Ts460M6jmjHvf4LOhUuOaEJFXZMD76TUswGpTU8E9K0XmaDEu3ev7O1xU8EX99KkosyQYy9RWuCNVRgU), [mean weight loss was pretty large](https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/SvOOLFA04BaBzC53ckpT2ZvNuAsnUpDzHltfEGBHUJK-LNvlNErRuTsWiTQS0mxhtHOFqmZHwg3QbOeMhlF6Fz1MXDavpQnlQ18k0iyUUUWGUu_dK7A9hlrNqJEsvSu9Nddehv8lr-Sd1hgk1fw), and [results were reasonably consistent by BMI before the experiment](https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/owVbw0OZIQdIiRwq6lRoNtJ0ONOTdFQa5rqEBI41qw68BUqnSvNjKhDnGfe_YtZAaQbyoKDip9eCE_rT-Wm0-dlAkxLcs6BZDtPMXjL_u-ztB1jbubCOorXx-qmD2aOZtW_nq46sgGCEjt5xIKc). SMTM&#39;s post sounds deservedly ecstatic, but it also sounds undeservedly like they think they&#39;ve made a discovery.  
  
Throughout the article, they pepper in comments like &#34;If you predicted (or could have predicted) that the potato diet would cause this kind of weight loss, or if medical / nutritional science could have predicted that this diet was going to be so effective in the short term, and so easy for so many people — then why haven’t doctors and nutritionists been recommending the potato diet to people alongside diet and exercise?&#34; and &#34;We understand if you don’t really get this. We didn’t get it either, despite reading about all the previous success stories, until one of us tried the potato diet for ourselves. Hunger vanishes in a really weird way that is hard to describe to anyone who hasn’t felt it directly. So listen to all our participants who are like “no it’s not calories, it’s not willpower”. Or try it for yourself, you might be surprised!&#34; At a first glance, it&#39;s difficult to imagine someone wrote this with anything like serious intent, and these sorts of quotes are commonplace throughout the blogpost. They stand as solid evidence of virtually complete ignorance of this area of research. I&#39;ll explain by tackling these quotes.  
  
The first one should stand out to SlateStarCodex readers who remember [this review](https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/04/25/book-review-the-hungry-brain/) of Stephan Guyenet&#39;s *The Hungry Brain*. At the beginning of Section III, Scott described a very relevant study: &#34;In 1965, some scientists locked people in a room where they could only eat nutrient sludge dispensed from a machine. Even though the volunteers had no idea how many calories the nutrient sludge was, they ate exactly enough to maintain their normal weight, proving the existence of a “sixth sense” for food caloric content. Next, they locked morbidly obese people in the same room. They ended up eating only tiny amounts of the nutrient sludge, one or two hundred calories a day, without feeling any hunger. This proved that their bodies “wanted” to lose the excess weight and preferred to simply live off stored fat once removed from the overly-rewarding food environment. After six months on the sludge, a man who weighed 400 lbs at the start of the experiment was down to 200, without consciously trying to reduce his weight.&#34;   
  
The study in question is amply described in the book and can be read in full [here](https://nyaspubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1965.tb34828.x) (or [via sci-hub](https://sci-hub.se/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1965.tb34828.x)). It&#39;s really something, but it&#39;s also not the only study of its type. There have been plenty of studies on single-food diets, both with animals and humans. The general tenor of their results is that restriction to a singular type of food leads to weight loss. People who read *The Hungry Brain* will be unsurprised that sort of work is cited. The authors over at SMTM evidently read Guyenet (he is cited twice in the linked post), but never read his book or they could not have written that first quote. But, we know from their series *A Chemical Hunger* (e.g., [here](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/07/a-chemical-hunger-part-i-mysteries/), [here](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/11/a-chemical-hunger-part-ii-current-theories-of-obesity-are-inadequate/)), that they at least cite *The Hungry Brain*, and even had [a blogpost on this exact study](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/23/a-chemical-hunger-interlude-b-the-nutrient-sludge-diet/). The blogpost is an unimpressive handwaving exercise by way of ignoring the post-1980 research on this topic and dismissing the pre-1980 research with the reason being that results from before the obesity epidemic really kicked off won&#39;t generalize. But this criticism is too broad. In their own potato diet post, they say that they expect their results will generalize, but for some reason, other monotonous diets will not? Perhaps their criticism only applies to this specific 1965 study, although I have doubts since they focus so heavily on potatoes, to the exclusion of general dietary monotony.  
  
Regardless, if you read just a few pages more in *The Hungry Brain*, you will discover (p. 65) where Guyenet predicts the result of a dietary content restriction: &#34;The fact that sensory-specific satiety drives us to overeat suggests a simple solution to the problem: Limit yourself to a few foods.&#34; What is the potato diet but limiting yourself to a few foods? The quantity of research supporting this point is enormous, so their arguing that it wasn&#39;t predicted - when they have evidently read and even written about material predicting it - should be galling for them. The snide remark they make asking why doctors haven&#39;t recommended eating potatoes only serves to obfuscate the reality that it is not potatoes that made the difference here, but induced dietary monotony. (Which is different from cross-sectional dietary monotony, both in terms of causes and effects.) To answer their subsequent quote
  
&amp;gt; If you knew the potato diet would work, why did you not run this study many years ago? Why are there no clinical trials? Did you think people would not be excited to see this result? 

It&#39;s clear that all that needs to be said is &#34;The studies were done, the trials were run, the results were in, you just ignored them.&#34;  
  
The &#34;We understand if you don&#39;t really get this&#34; quote refers to a reduction in hunger with the diet. My best guess about why they &#34;don&#39;t really get this&#34; is that they misunderstand hunger. Firstly, Guyenet explained their result very well, and his perspective is by no means unique. Secondly, hunger [follows a Circadian-like rhythm](https://eje.bioscientifica.com/view/journals/eje/152/6/1520845.xml) and is reduced to a pittance when you completely restrict caloric intake. Consistent with this, [ghrelin levels fall when you fast](https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/90/2/741/2836628). That is part of the standard explanation why, after a few days of fasting, you suddenly stop feeling any hunger. Even the subreddit /r/fasting [has a FAQ section mentioning this](https://www.reddit.com/r/fasting/wiki/fasting_in_a_nutshell#wiki_5.2._tips_and_tricks). Hunger is similarly reduced by dietary austerity, and more austere diets yield bigger weight losses and less rebounding, but I don&#39;t wish to ramble.  
  
As with the rest of their posts on weight and weight loss, SMTM&#39;s latest comes up short. It ignores things they&#39;ve read, ignores obvious implications, mechanisms, and prior work that should be cited, whilst being replete with generalizability concerns despite failing to acknowledge predictions generalize to cover theories like their own.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0u4zm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0g9km/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A small update on the Ukraine war front - it appears that the sanctions Lithuani</title><updated>2022-07-13T16:50:11Z</updated><author><name>tricksandcandlewicks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A small update on the Ukraine war front - it appears that the sanctions Lithuania put on Kalingrad are [now facing pressure from an EU commission](https://statefirstnews.com/2022/07/13/update-today-breakingthe-european-commission-today-backed-down-to-russian-threats-and-issued-new-guidelines-saying-sanctions-dont-apply-to-rail-transit-via-lithuania-to-kaliningrad-th/). The EU wants Lithuania to back down. It would seem that predictions that Russia saw this move as a serious threat to its sovereignty over Kalingrad were correct. I was more surprised that the EU decided to fold that quickly. When they&#39;re already getting Russia to shut down Nord Stream 2 and other pipelines, it makes me wonder what cards are left to play.

While I do find the Ukranian case for war sympathetic, I really don&#39;t get the case for Lithuania poking the bear here. This isn&#39;t even a case of Lithuania building up a military capable of enforcing the regulations it was trying to pass, just taking an opportunity to swipe at the much bigger country next door for unclear reasons. Who benefits?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0g9km/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig03xrr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Disclaimer: Not from the US.

Pretty bummed out about not getting a specific job</title><updated>2022-07-13T15:30:59Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Disclaimer: Not from the US.

Pretty bummed out about not getting a specific job. I applied for a a job that was exactly what I was looking for. I had the exact tech stack they were looking for as well. Pay was good too (60k no tax, without bonus, not the US so this is a good pay). 

However, as a part of the interview process, I got handed an &#34;aptitude test&#34;, which was a blatant IQ test. I have never done a real IQ test, but my scores are mensa.no (130), mensa.dk (135). Now I don&#39;t put in too much weight into those numbers but I don&#39;t think I am stupid. My IQ is probably around 120 if we go by proxies of IQ. 

I failed their IQ test hard. They didn&#39;t give me a percentile, but I got 61/100. Mind you this test was a lot harder than standard IQ tests. All the questions were 3-d instead of the normal 2-d patterns. My score was below their minimal threshold. Now are they looking for the next Einstein for a junior role, idk. But I am still quite salty about it. I know IQ has real predictive power over interviews and other proxies, so I got told straight to my face that I am not smart enough, which isn&#39;t pleasant even if you know about it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig03xrr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig02yql/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Jordan Peterson - remember him? - has a [big talk](https://www.youtube.com/watch</title><updated>2022-07-13T15:24:36Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Jordan Peterson - remember him? - has a [big talk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxdHm2dmvKE) out on Russia/Ukraine war. 

It&#39;s over 50 mins long, so I will jump right into the most controversial CW part. Basically he raises the hypothetical question whether A) the West is degenerate and B) if it is, does that potentially justify or at least *explain* why Putin may have acted in Ukraine to forestall its assimiliation to [GAE](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3oVkne9WgpY)? 

An outraged left-wing activist has [cut out](https://mobile.twitter.com/thebadstats/status/1546327272780472321) the most relevant part. Peterson first answers the question regarding whether or not the West is degenerate. His answer is clearly yes. 

He then moves to the second part, and speculates that in his view, Putin could indeed have calculated that if did not invade then Ukraine would have become assimilated to GAE and thus lost forever.

Naturally, Peterson is being slammed online as a &#39;Putin shill&#39; and a Russian stooge etc, but the questions he raises are valid. Perhaps we are seeing an element of the culture war actually &#34;going hot&#34;. 

It&#39;s said that the 20th century was a fight between liberalism, fascism and communism. Perhaps wars in the 21st will be fought over transgenderism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig02yql/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] 
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble match</title><updated>2022-07-13T13:52:37Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble matches message me in the last week, despite typically getting less than one a month. I’ve been incelposting a bit more than usual lately, so maybe writing this up will provide some context for my point of view as well as allowing  others to offer perspective and point out errors in places where I may be blind.

Match number 1 was a thin blonde who opened with “How are you doing handsome?” Yellow flag. That is not something that women say to me, especially not as an opening. I’m not grotesque or repulsive(I don’t think), but I’m certainly not “handsome”, otherwise I wouldn’t be a mid 20s kv. As we continue chatting it immediately becomes clear that this person is both horny and forward with said horniness to an extent that I find very suspicious. This isn’t how I’ve known girls to act, but she doesn’t talk like a scammer or bot and her pictures seem real. It’s a work day so I try to stall until the weekend with some playful flirting. At some point she drops “I’m male but very feminine”. Mystery solved. I don’t see a “report as wrong sex” button on the app, so I just unmatch and move on. 

Match number 2 was more what I would consider “my type”. She’s a good bit overweight but has a cute face. She’s from the exurbs not the suburbs, has no visible tattoos or piercings, and overall seems to have a more conservative view of gender roles than the median woman on these apps. She sends me a “heyy” and I say hey back. No response. A few days later, after the debacle with match number 1 has played out, I admit I get desperate. I ask me friends if she’s out of my league, just to check if I’m being delusional. I get a “definitely not, go for it”. She has her Snapchat name on her Bumble profile, so I add her. We start texting on Snap. She replies very slowly, sometimes not at all, but there are a few moments where it feels like things are going well and there might be something there. 

I’ve had dating apps since my first year of college, but for most of that time I never really used them. This is the furthest I’ve ever gotten with a woman from these apps, and the furthest I’ve gotten with a woman since my not-really-a-gf gf in 8th grade that never got past holding hands. In the long breaks waiting for her replies, I notice my mental state deteriorating. It’s all I can really think about. I’ve never met her in person, but for the first time since early college I have a plausible path towards getting a girlfriend (or at least some kind of intimacy). I haven’t gotten the same butterflies when someone texts me since high school. I start checking my phone obsessively even though I have notifications on. When she leaves me on read I start to panic. I keep texting her. She never says stop, but I’m not a complete moron. I know what the most likely outcome is. At this point I almost want it just to have my sanity back. Finally she blocks me. I hate myself, but I’m free. No more obsession. It’s over. 

After writing this all out I am reminded of Scott Aaronson wanting to chemically castrate himself over fears he might harm a woman if he did not. I am not and have never considered going that far, but I do have to ask the question: Is it ethical for me to continue looking for a partner? Every woman who has ever swiped right on me either wishes she hadn’t or is indifferent. 

I’m 6’3 and make 70k a year if that’s relevant. Something is wrong with me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzla0z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anyone have advice on how to improve my text game? I do pretty well with women i</title><updated>2022-07-13T13:21:35Z</updated><author><name>disposablehead001</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anyone have advice on how to improve my text game? I do pretty well with women irl but getting them to the first date is a struggle. I also don’t have enough matches to feel like I can I get in decent practice. I was ghosted by a cool match (into Feynman and nuclear energy, be still my heart) and I’m pretty sure I made two or three errors that killed that convo. When I get my next exciting match in 3-9 months, I don’t want to fuck it up again, but I expect I will because I don’t have a way to stay in form.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzla0z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifzejpk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In what could become a regular sort of analysis given the CJ policy trends curre</title><updated>2022-07-13T12:26:50Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In what could become a regular sort of analysis given the CJ policy trends currently, let us turn our attention to the policy shitshow exemplified by [this story](https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2022/jul/8/new-york-bodega-clerk-jose-alba-makes-bail-after-s/). A quick synopsis of the facts as we know them currently (subject to additional information and corrections, of course). 

1: Female subject with small daughter in tow attempts to purchase a number of items at a bodega, but her EBT card is declined. The clerk (M/61)runs the card a couple times, then declines the sale. When he gathers the items, the woman begins shouting that he assaulted her daughter, that he &#34;snatched&#34; a bag of chips from her etc. Unclear from video angle. 

2: Female subject threatens bodega clerk that she will go get her &#34;N\*\*ger&#34; and &#34;fuck you \[him\] up&#34;. 

3: Female subject retrieves her boyfriend, a 35-yo ex con with north of 25 arrests, including multiple arrests for assault and reportedly on parole from an assaulting-a-cop beef.

4: Female and male subjects return to the bodega and initiate first a verbal confrontation, followed by the boyfriend coming behind the counter and assaulting the clerk. The clerk stabs the boyfriend several times, and the girlfriend follows them behind the counter and stabs the clerk three times (exact timeline unclear). Boyfriend dies, clerk&#39;s wounds are superficial. 

5: NY prosecutors charge the clerk with second degree murder, do not charge the woman at all. They ask for $500,000 bond, the judge gives them a quarter mil bond. Later, under public pressure, the bond is reduced to $50k and enough money is raised to get the wounded clerk out of Rikers. 

6: Current status is the clerk has become a local [cause celebre](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/07/11/us/new-york-bodega-stabbing-murder-charges/index.html), but is still facing a second-degree murder rap. The woman who initiated every stage of the conflict and stabbed the clerk remains free of arrest and charges entirely. 

As I&#39;ve said many times before, I&#39;ve lived through this news cycle before. The swing in criminal justice public policy exemplified by BLM and the sort of reforms pushed by the rationalist community (among many others) very quickly started resulting in these sorts of issues. It&#39;s a sort of microcosm of systemic failure of the justice system. It combines outrageous social behavior, aggressive violence, the intentional policy of keeping violent criminals free, and swift punishment for the victims of violent crime who dare to defend themselves. 

This is, in my view, the inevitable result of the reheated 1970&#39;s policies we are currently implementing in many major cities. When criminals are considered the victims, it is citizens who are the &#34;perpetrators&#34;. Basic anarcho-tyranny. This is the criminal justice system currently being adopted, and if allowed to fully mature, we will probably see the same sort of crime wave we did in the &#39;70s and &#39;80s, complete with the economic hollowing-out of major cities, a civilian population that will get scared and start arming itself, and a criminal population that will explode when they fully realize that the only people doing time are the ones resisting them.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifzejpk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a b</title><updated>2022-07-13T11:52:31Z</updated><author><name>JosephinesOtherMan</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a baby?  Almost all of our friends moved away from our city during or after COVID.  

My wife and I traveled for a friend&#39;s engagement party (one of those friends who moved away)--it was fine.  The day after, we met up with an old friend of mine and an old college friend of hers who live there, and we had a much better time with them than we&#39;ve had with any of our friends at home in a really long time.  

... I&#39;m finding myself feeling a little sad after that for two reasons:

1. Most of our friends at home have moved away, and while it&#39;s not too hard to make little acquaintances or Jane Jacobs-esq &#34;public friendships&#34; around (especially with a baby), it seems very hard to find or develop close friendships at this point in our lives.
2. Meeting up with those old friends made me realize how distanced a lot of my friendships at home were--we were a large crew of folks who met up to have fun together, but ultimately we weren&#39;t very close (the contrast between the friends at the engagement party and the old friends the day after felt fairly extreme)

I have a handful of close friends who mean a lot to me, but almost all of them are distributed around, and we keep in touch when we can, though a lot of formerly close friendships have gotten a little less close over COVID for whatever reason too.  I vaguely worry that the only person who I can rely on is my wife (my family isn&#39;t reliable), and it scares me a little.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/com</title><updated>2022-07-13T10:32:20Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vlopk0/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_27_2022/ie5imbr/?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) thread on vaccines and birth rates collapsing in many countries, since it just struck me (after reading some other discussions about it, admittedly) that it&#39;s quite odd neither me or the other posters considered one very obvious explanation: it&#39;s the vaccinations!

...and by that I mean not the vaccines themselves, but the vaccination process; at least in Finland, the local authorities [explicitly recommended](https://yle-fi.translate.goog/uutiset/3-11750453?_x_tr_sl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;amp;_x_tr_hl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp) that women avoid pregnancy for two months (note: for some reason Google Translate translates it as a &#34;couple of months&#34;, but Finnish text talks about two months) after vaccination. I&#39;m not sure whether other countries had similar recommendations, but I&#39;d imagine at least some did.

Of course, the &#34;birth gaps&#34; noted are longer than two months, but similar recommendations might generally make people get antsy about the prospect of pregnancy, and so might the fact that even people who get vaccinated might well encounter a lot of antivaxx posts about the dangers of vaccination and pregnancy and thus be less willing to get pregnant. Who knows, something like that might ironically create a permanent effect \*even if\* it turns out the vaccine itself does not create major pregnancy risks.

Is there any info about various countries and their official vaccination/pregnancy recommendations, or any other way to test this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifz2ezj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anything to watch out for besides oxybenzone (potential endocrine disruptor) in </title><updated>2022-07-13T10:19:49Z</updated><author><name>70rd</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anything to watch out for besides oxybenzone (potential endocrine disruptor) in  sunscreens? Titanium dioxide was ruled [unsafe](https://www.efsa.europa.eu/en/news/titanium-dioxide-e171-no-longer-considered-safe-when-used-food-additive) as a food colorant, doesn&#39;t say anything about topical use however (this [study](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3423755/) suggests it should not be too bad.

I&#39;ve found [EWG](https://www.ewg.org/sunscreen/report/the-trouble-with-sunscreen-chemicals/)&#39;s post but am unsure how reliable of a source they are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifz2ezj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifyt7j4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Small culture war snippet:


Kemi Badenoch began her race as leader of the Conse</title><updated>2022-07-13T08:13:50Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Small culture war snippet:


Kemi Badenoch began her race as leader of the Conservatives, and the news is that, during her first public event, her staff put &#34;males&#34; and &#34;girls&#34; on the gender neutral bathroom of the event&#39;s building. 
Hence, polemics

I am always surprised by the rhetoric used in these cases, because the main defence from the progressives left is &#34;why we should care about this when we have the economy to care about?&#34;

Mind you, this tactic of &#34;but the economy?&#34; is probably the most used ever by every political side in history, but my point is another:
Is difficult to conserve your face if, suddenly, gender affirmation and the cultural war on it become a very trivial and stupid debate to do if the right do it, while at the same time is a topic that save literally lives if it is not done


How it is possible? The cultural war about gender is one of the main engines of the left today, but suddenly is trivial if the enemy does the same and debate on it? We are supposed to believe that, at the same time, is a stupid issue to die on but it literally save thousands of lives?
Nobody saw the contradiction?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifyt7j4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifxa7hd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does anyone recall a post on the idea that &#34;midwits are the lieutenants of socie</title><updated>2022-07-12T23:39:12Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does anyone recall a post on the idea that &#34;midwits are the lieutenants of society&#34; or something like that?  The thrust was that midwits get a bad rap because they serve an important, load-bearing function in society by being smart enough to do useful work but not so smart that they question the narrative and destabilize things.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifxa7hd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifwjyxh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does anybody have experience with, and/or can recommend, apps for forming online</title><updated>2022-07-12T20:37:25Z</updated><author><name>herzenslied</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does anybody have experience with, and/or can recommend, apps for forming online friendships with people nearby-ish?

I&#39;ve had some decent amount of success with language learning apps like HelloTalk and Tandem, but seeing as these are gained primarily towards language *learning*, I don&#39;t really meet people in *my own* country/region via them - only foreigners. This kinda bums me out as every single one of my friends is too far away to visit comfortably, and I don&#39;t currently see the need to increase that number further.

This is something I&#39;d like to change, but I can&#39;t really think of any apps that suit the bill. Unfortunately, the app market is of the &#34;95% shit, 5% decent&#34; variety, so any tips that could speed up my process of going through the seemingly inexhaustible list of garbage-quality &#34;friend finding apps&#34; on the play store would be greatly appreciated.

Specifically, I&#39;m looking for something that *isn&#39;t* just another dating app clone Tinder-wannabe (like the top search results for &#34;friends&#34; on the play store all seem to be). But something more like the apps I mentioned above, where you can actually send messages to people, reach out, and form friendships based on common interests.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifwjyxh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifvndpf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I have a quick question about birth order effects that I think people here might</title><updated>2022-07-12T17:02:38Z</updated><author><name>PokerPirate</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I have a quick question about birth order effects that I think people here might be able to answer.  Specifically, how can I reconcile the following two observations:

1. first borns tend to have higher achievement (as measured by wealth/education/etc) as adults

1. the 2nd/3rd/etc child will tend to walk/talk earlier than the first because they are trying &#34;to keep up&#34; with their big brother/sister

Why is it the case that having an older sibling is helpful for young infant development, but not in the latter years?  Or am I misinterpreting these results and that&#39;s not actually the case?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifvndpf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifvc3ol/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] # Why do so many people dislike capitalism?

And I&#39;m not saying in this post tha</title><updated>2022-07-12T15:49:52Z</updated><author><name>Chad_Nauseam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text"># Why do so many people dislike capitalism?

And I&#39;m not saying in this post that there are no good arguments about capitalism, I&#39;m only trying to understand the *modal* argument against capitalism.

I think people inherently don&#39;t like being told what to do. When someone compels you to do something, chances are it benefits them more than it benefits you, so we have an automatic reflex to assume that we&#39;re being shortchanged.

The weird thing is, when you look around at modern society, there&#39;s no one entity that really tells you what to do. If you don&#39;t like your job, you can quit at any time and no one will make you keep working. But then, if you don&#39;t have any job, you&#39;ll probably have to live on the street and that&#39;s not pleasant, so if you want to live a normal life you&#39;ll have to find *someone* who has money and convince them to give it to you.

The system that coordinates this is capitalism, so indirectly, the market forces of capitalism are telling everyone what to do. That inherently makes people dislike it, I think. You can ask yourself &#34;why am I doing something I hate every day?&#34; and trace the causal chain back and eventually you&#39;ll get to &#34;because capitalism&#34;. That&#39;s probably not going to endear someone to capitalism!

People won&#39;t say it explicitly, and it feels like of strawmannish to say out loud, but I genuinely think maybe 50% people who say things like &#34;fuck capitalism&#34; are imagining in their heads &#34;Capitalism makes everyone have to do stuff they hate all day and most people don&#39;t even get paid that much money for it. Wouldn&#39;t it be great if there were a system where nobody had to work and we still had our modern living standards?&#34;

Through this lens, a lot of arguments that seemed weird to me started to make sense.

1. The subreddit /r/antiwork. Enough said I think. Some people say that their real goal is just &#34;workplace reform&#34; or something like that, but I think that&#39;s just the motte. 
2. [Leftie youtube PhilTube made a video about &#34;bullshit jobs&#34;](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_X-812q_Jc). If you&#39;re not familiar, [bullshit jobs](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs) says that half of all work people do in the developed world is pointless. If you look at his examples, like &#34;programmers repairing bloated code&#34;, I think you&#39;ll find this assertion a bit questionable. But you can understand why it&#39;s a very tempting idea: if half of jobs are completely pointless, that means everyone could work 20 hours a week instead of 40 with no loss in productivity! 
3. There&#39;s of course the preference for small businesses over megacorps. When a mom and pop shop hires you to work the register, that&#39;s not capitalism making you do it, that&#39;s just mom and pop asking you to do something for them and paying you for your time. They&#39;re probably giving you a good deal, right? But when Amazon hires you to work in the warehouse, even if they pay better than mom and pop and offer better benefits, suddenly is some weird foreign global system that&#39;s getting you to work for them. They&#39;re probably ripping you off!

Again, to be clear, I&#39;m not saying there are no good arguments against capitalism or anything like that. I think it&#39;s okay to look at bad arguments for position X, as long as you don&#39;t come away from that process thinking that those are representative of the best arguments for position X.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifvc3ol/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifu5vwr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In the UK the Tories are having a new leadership election. For one reason or ano</title><updated>2022-07-12T09:45:29Z</updated><author><name>TheColourOfHeartache</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In the UK the Tories are having a new leadership election. For one reason or another a lot of minority candidates are in the race and people are talking about it. Much of it is presented as a reply to lawyer, full time virtue signalling tweeter, and [fox killer](https://barristerblogger.com/2019/12/26/should-jolyon-maugham-be-prosecuted-for-bludgeoning-a-fox-to-death/) Jolyon Maugham.

[This article](https://www.thenational.scot/news/20267870.jolyon-maugham-sparks-racism-debate-deleted-tweet-sunak/) covers the origin. 

[Of course the Conservative Party could choose an ethnic minority leader](https://capx.co/of-course-the-conservative-party-could-choose-an-ethnic-minority-leader/) says Sunder Katwala

&amp;gt; That ethnic minorities can reach the top of the political ladder matters – but it would certainly not make either Britain or the Conservative party a post-racial nirvana. While it will take more to shift the Conservatives’ share of the ethnic minority vote, the leadership contest sends a powerful symbolic message about the race to the top. The next challenge will be to develop the substantive agenda to deliver on that promise.

[In a more humourous article about poorly air conditioned leadership speeches](https://archive.ph/8pIpT#selection-1559.0-1559.144) Tim Stanley remarks 

&amp;gt; Actually, I think historians will write that the two notable things about this race were, one, it was incredibly diverse and, two, nobody cared.

Rakib Eshan says [The left’s problem with diversity](https://www.spiked-online.com/2022/07/11/the-lefts-problem-with-diversity/)

&amp;gt; The left’s unhealthy obsession with racial identity and ethnic heritage can only do more harm than good. Treating ethnic-minority people not as individuals but as representatives of ethnic groups will only undermine our multi-ethnic democracy.

&amp;gt; Beyond the identitarian game-playing, Britain is grappling with myriad social and economic problems. From the cost-of-living crisis to the endless backlogs in the NHS, the Tories have left numerous open goals for the opposition. The classic conservative message, that family stability and hard work can insulate people from harsh economic conditions, sounds tin-eared at best amid the current crises. These are the bread-and-butter domestic issues that Tory leadership candidates should be challenged on. But instead, the Conservatives’ opponents have been reduced to race-baiting playground behaviour.

Tomiwa Owolade writes for the New Statesman [It’s absurd to say the Conservative Party isn’t ready for a non-white leader](https://www.newstatesman.com/quickfire/2022/07/its-absurd-to-say-the-conservative-party-isnt-ready-for-a-non-white-leader)

&amp;gt; But the third and most pressing point is this: why shouldn’t an ethnic minority person be a Conservative? If we accept that not all ethnic minority people are the same – which should be the first plank of anti-racism – then we have to accept that they do not all share the same political perspective. And nor should they. Political pluralism should be staunchly defended: it is as important an element of diversity as any other.

--------------------

I&#39;d sum up the whole debate like this:

* The left know the Tories are doing better than Labour on diversity at the top so they&#39;re keeping quiet.
* The right don&#39;t care that much, and are mostly talking about taxes and cost of living. (Except Kemi Badenoch whose mostly talking about free speech and culture) But are willing to take a bit of a victory lap to indulge themselves. 
* While everyone writing about this topic is by definition engaging in culture wars. I think you can say that people who mention the fox are more tribal than people who don&#39;t.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifu5vwr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iftth4n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What does it mean for someone to &#34;find themselves&#34;? I see this phrase used all t</title><updated>2022-07-12T06:51:55Z</updated><author><name>retireaus</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What does it mean for someone to &#34;find themselves&#34;? I see this phrase used all the time in contexts that seem almost oppposite.

Joe is a 27 year old dentist, highly successful, but got into dentistry because his parents wanted him to. He decides to take a 6 month holiday in south america to &#34;find himself&#34;, hiking, partying and travelling, and comes back refreshed and ready to grind dentistry for another 5 years.

Sam is a 25 year old loser stereotype. Lives with his parents playing world of warcraft while working 30 hours a week as assistant manager at the local burger king. Started a degree in computer science but never finished it. Sam decides to &#34;find himself&#34;, a process which involves joining a gym, taking steroids, and getting into bodybuilder culture. He later competes as an amateur bodybuilder and starts an instagram, and appears to have higher self esteem, though the excessive focus on bodybuilding and steroids seems slightly unsavoury. His newfound lifestyle at least allows him to start dating, though he still lives with his mum and has racked up a problematic credit card debt.

Anne is a practicing surgeon and has a high pressure full time job. Anne decides to take on higher paying contract work for 12 months, which is similarly high pressured, which she describes as &#34;finding herself&#34;.

So finding yourself sort of seems like reevaluating your priorities in life, possibly changing them, possibly keeping them the same but with a firmer grasp on the underlying reasons, possibly changing your behaviours slightly but leaving your personality largely unchanged with slightly more money or sex partners, possibly focusing on short term financial goals to defer more profound goals until later.

I sort of see threads of commonality, but it also feels functionally like a just-so story for any set of behaviours whatsoever. Self improvement? Find yourself. 6 month holiday? Find yourself. Divorce and start dating fresh? Find yourself. Take on higher paying contract role? Find yourself.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iftth4n/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/iftd8wr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Noah Smith on how Shinzo Abe is not the man the West paints him to be.](https:/</title><updated>2022-07-12T03:56:00Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Noah Smith on how Shinzo Abe is not the man the West paints him to be.](https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/abe-shinzo-a-retrospective) Some excerpts:

**Economic Policy**

&amp;gt;But most important of all was the shift in the economic role of women. Before Abe, Japan had persistently lagged in terms of women’s labor force participation, especially among mothers. The country’s sexism was legendary and entrenched. When Abe came to power at the end of 2012, I definitely did not expect him to change this — during his brief, abortive first tenure as PM, his health minister caused a national scandal by referring to women as “birth-giving machines”. Abe’s reputation as a staunch cultural conservative seemed to presage more business-as-usual.  
But it was not business-as-usual. As soon as he got into office for the second time, Abe began to talk up the importance of women in the workforce, and to implement some real policies toward this end as well. By 2014, it was clear to me that the national dialogue around the issue had shifted.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The key number we were all keeping an eye on here was women’s labor force participation, which surpassed the number for the United States for the first time in 2017.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;So on macroeconomic policy and structural reform, Abe really delivered in a way that I didn’t expect him to. And the results were clear — falling unemployment despite a flood of new workers into the labor force, record profits for small and medium sized businesses, and modestly rising incomes despite rapid aging and a growth in the old-age dependency ratio.

**Surprisingly Liberal**

&amp;gt;But by the second time Abe took power, his approach had changed. Abe visited Yasukuni Shrine — where the ashes of several Japanese war criminals are kept — once at the beginning of his term in office, but did not do so afterwards. This was in contrast to his mentor Koizumi Junichiro, who had made annual visits when he was Prime Minister in the 2000s. That was the first hint that Abe was behaving in a less overtly nationalist manner in his second term.  
In 2015, Abe reversed his previous denialist stance on the issue of Korean “comfort women” (WW2-era sex slaves), issuing a formal apology and explicitly laying the blame on the Japanese military for the first time.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;But Abe’s most liberal actions came in an area that’s not (yet) a hot-button issue in Japan — immigration. Under Abe, Japan opened itself up to immigration in a way that it never has before, with a “guest worker” program that offered a path to permanent residence, and a fast-track permanent residency program for skilled workers. The number of foreigners living and working and settling down in Japan soared.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The anti-racist wave that beat back the racists online was present in the real world too — anti-racist counter-protesters showed up to shout down the hateful Zaitokukai, usually outnumbering them by a huge margin. Of course, Abe doesn’t get credit for that activism, but unlike Donald Trump — who spent a lot of time attacking “antifa” and ran cover for racist demonstrators — Abe and his administration focused on cracking down on the racists. That kind of leadership makes a difference.  
On almost every issue of race and nationhood, therefore, Abe — in his second term — behaved as the polar opposite of Donald Trump. He opened up his country to immigration, tourism, and trade, apologized for past misdeeds, made overtures to old enemies, and cracked down on racism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/iftd8wr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ift23ku/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m rewatching Kizumonogatari.

[This scene is so good](https://youtu.be/Un1h_py</title><updated>2022-07-12T02:24:07Z</updated><author><name>Sinity</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m rewatching Kizumonogatari.

[This scene is so good](https://youtu.be/Un1h_pyGogc?t=7)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ift23ku/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifs4qa3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-07-11T22:18:40Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifs4qa3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifrq463/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In Poland, government decided to create a new school subject for high schools, &#34;</title><updated>2022-07-11T20:42:52Z</updated><author><name>Sinity</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In Poland, government decided to create a new school subject for high schools, &#34;History and Present [time]&#34;. It is kinda CW-related.

[Core curriculum](https://pastebin.com/56ftUTbw)
===

(I&#39;ve translated it and dumped onto pastebin); some excerpts below:

Objectives

&amp;gt; 1. In the aspect of attitude to the truth: the acquisition of reliable knowledge of the most important cultural, political, social and economic changes in Poland and the world after 1945 up to the present - and in this context obtaining an understanding of the main issues of social life, politics and law, as well as knowledge of the immediate origins and nature of the great problems of the modern world.
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt; 2. in the aspect of attitude towards the good: to prepare the student for an independent and fair assessment of the said changes taking place in Poland and in the world since the end of World War II in terms of continuity and change (or rupture) in relation to the foundations from which our Homeland grows, understood as a community shaped according to specific cultural norms and visions of man, family and society dating back to the classical Greco-Roman civilization and Christianity.
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt; 3. in the aspect of attitude to life: acquiring an inquisitive interest in collective life, readiness to personally undertake social tasks and civic involvement in the spirit of patriotism as a wise love of the homeland formed in the tradition of the Republic, through the practice of individual and social virtues, as well as through the discovery of the harmony of rights and duties, freedom and responsibility, human happiness and the development of human communities, and the importance of just laws and prudent policies.

Some specific requirements

&amp;gt; I.	Knowledge of the fundamentals of social life. The student:
==
&amp;gt; 2) explains how the concept of &#34;social contract&#34; developed in modernity differs from the traditional understanding of the naturalness of social ties;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 6) can explain the process of nation-building and the variety of contexts of meaning of this concept; explains what patriotism is and how it differs from chauvinism and cosmopolitanism;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 10) can list and characterize the basic attributes of the state and explains what the raison d&#39;etre of the state is;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 11) can explain the various models of the relationship of churches and religious associations with the state, especially those present in the tradition of the First and Second Commonwealths;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 15) explains the basis and content of &#34;human rights&#34; and their relationship to the heritage of Western civilization (inspiration coming from Christianity and from the science of natural law dating back to Greco-Roman times);

(This last one is _interesting_ given beliefs of our current Minister of Education. See section &#34;Czarnek&#34; below.)


&amp;gt; II.	The world and Poland in 1945-1956. Student:
==
&amp;gt; 4) can explain where the term &#34;Cold War&#34; and &#34;Iron Curtain&#34; came from and in what sense it was used, and presents the main areas of Cold War confrontation;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 5) explains the significance of the establishment of NATO and the Warsaw Pact;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 8) can apply his knowledge of the relationship of states and the kinship of nations to characterize the beginnings of European integration in the economic and political fields (until 1957), indicating its ideological reasons (the Christian worldview of the &#34;Founding Fathers&#34;), cultural reasons (the proximity of European nations) and political reasons (fear of Soviet expansion, preparing to receive American aid under the so-called Marshall Plan, solving the &#34;German problem&#34; by integrating the German economy with other Western economies);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 10) characterizes the significance of the seizure of power in China by the Communists in 1949 and Mao Zedong&#39;s rule (the greatest genocide after 1945 during the &#34;Great Leap Forward&#34;, persecution of religion);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 11) explains the significance of the creation of the state of Israel for the situation in the Middle East and for international politics;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 12) **characterizes the origins and principles of Zionism and Islamism;**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 21) characterizes the 1952 constitution of the People&#39;s Republic of Poland, its definition of the sovereign (&#34;working people&#34;), as well as its propaganda nature and façade in relation to the real rule of the PZPR.


&amp;gt; III. The world and Poland from 1956 to 1970. Student:
==
&amp;gt; 8) characterizes the principles of the social market economy and the &#34;welfare state&#34;, presents examples of them in relation to the world of the early 1960s;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **9) characterizes the social and moral transformations known as the &#34;1968 revolution&#34; (including the &#34;sexual revolution&#34;) and their intellectual inspirations (neo-Marxism, &#34;new left&#34;);**

&amp;gt; 10) characterizes pacifist ideas and movements; **can identify the difference between ecology and ecologism;**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 15) explains the concept of &#34;cultural revolution&#34;, pointing to its different contexts of meaning (what is the difference between the Chinese &#34;cultural revolution&#34; and that in the West);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 17) characterizes the ways of struggle of the regime of the Polish People&#39;s Republic against the Church in the 60s and 70s (including the relegation of religious people to the status of second-class citizens);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 18) is able to apply his knowledge of various models of relations between religious associations and the state to explain **the communist policy of &#34;separation of church and state&#34;; explains the terms: secularism, secularism, indifferentism;**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; IV.	The world and Poland in 1970-1980 The student:
==
&amp;gt; 1) characterizes the reasons for the weakening of the position of the United States of America in the world in the early 1970s and the growth of the influence of the global communist camp (defeat in Vietnam, the Watergate affair, the energy crisis);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 7) characterizes the way in which Germany settles its accounts with the legacy of Nazi rule (positive and negative examples: the activities of the Center for the Prosecution of Nazi Crimes in Ludwigsburg, the career of Heinz Reinefarth, the issue of reparations and restitution of the works of art seized in Poland);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 9) characterizes the rule of Edward Gierek (prosperity on credit, submission to the USSR, changes in the Constitution of the People&#39;s Republic of Poland in 1976);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 10) characterizes the main manifestations of the opposition in Poland in the 1970s: The Catholic Church and the birth of the so-called democratic opposition after the 1976 workers&#39; protests;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 11) explains the significance for Poland and the world of the election of Cardinal Karol Wojtyla as Pope.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; V. The world and Poland in 1980-1991 The student:
==
&amp;gt; 1) characterizes the changes in the programs of Western left and right-wing parties evident in the 1970s and 1980s, and the rise in popularity of free-market and conservative-liberal programs (&#34;new right,&#34; neoliberalism);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 2) explains the significance of the victory of Margaret Thatcher in Great Britain (1979) and Ronald Reagan in the United States of America (1980) for East-West relations;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 3) characterizes the main causes of the erosion of the communist system in the 1980s (internal flaws in the system, the &#34;revolution of the spirit&#34; behind the &#34;Iron Curtain&#34;, the tough attitude of the West);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 4) characterizes the changes taking place in China after the death of Mao Zedong (the rule of Deng Xiaoping and the beginning of &#34;state capitalism&#34;);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 6) presents the circumstances and consequences of the introduction of martial law by the authorities on December 13, 1981, the forms of struggle of the regime of the People&#39;s Republic of Poland against the freedom aspirations of the Poles (censorship, &#34;unknown perpetrators&#34;, &#34;Wujek&#34; Coal Mine, Lubin 1982, the murder of Grzegorz Przemyk) and the forms of resistance of Poles against the martial law regime;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 7) characterizes the role of the Catholic Church in Poland in the period after the introduction of martial law (help for all the persecuted, culture without censorship, masses in support of the homeland, the person of Blessed Fr. Jerzy Popiełuszko, the pilgrimage of St. John Paul II to Poland in 1983 and 1987);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 8) characterizes the manifestations of the crisis of the communist system in Poland in the 1980s (economic inefficiency) and its consequences combined with the repressive policy of &#34;martial law&#34; (emigration of many educated and socially engaged Poles);
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 10) explains the concept of &#34;enfranchisement of the nomenklatura&#34; using the policy of Mieczyslaw Rakowski&#39;s government (1988-1989) as an example;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 16) indicates what the &#34;transformation&#34; implemented in Poland after 1989 consisted of, using the example of the assumptions and implementation of the Sachs-Balcerowicz plan;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; VI. The world and Poland in 1991-2001 The student:
==
&amp;gt; **1) characterizes the concept of the &#34;new world order&#34; (&#34;New World Order&#34;) and gives examples of its functioning (the First Gulf War in 1990);**

&amp;gt; **4) explains the concept and various contexts of globalization;**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 8) characterizes the main provisions of the Constitution of the Republic of Poland of April 2, 1997 (the preamble, the relationship between the most important organs of power, **the independence of the courts and the tri-division of power,** the rights and duties of a citizen of the Republic of Poland, **the Constitution concerning marriage and the family**);

(that&#39;s pretty rich coming from the current government; [link](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_constitutional_crisis))

automod_multipart_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifrq463/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifqh42h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] #My body, my choice

The left and the right have both recently used this slogan,</title><updated>2022-07-11T15:49:14Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">#My body, my choice

The left and the right have both recently used this slogan, and interestingly enough, have argued their points in almost exactly the same way down four levels of argument.

**Abortion**

- Left: When it comes to abortion, my body my choice. The government must respect my bodily autonomy and my right to make choices about my own body.
- Right: But it’s not just about your body. There is a child developing inside of you who also has rights, and the government must respect their bodily autonomy too.
- Left: It&#39;s not a real child, it doesn’t substantially have the ability to experience or think. Even ignoring my right to privacy, I have the right to avoid a life-changing nine month pregnancy which could see me dead or disabled because of it, and I would also be consenting to the onerous duty of having to raise and support the child for at least eighteen years, and in the case of an otherwise healthy child with Down Syndrome, in perpetuity.
- Right: Well, how about adoption instead?

**Vaccine**

- Right: When it comes to the vaccine, my body my choice. The government must respect my bodily autonomy and my right to make choices about my own body.
- Left: But it’s not just about your body. There is a community of people breathing around you who also have rights, and the government must respect their bodily autonomy too.
- Right: It&#39;s not a real vaccine, it doesn’t substantially prevent transmission. Even ignoring my right to privacy, I have the right to avoid a life-changing shot which could see me dead or disabled because of it, and I would be consenting to the onerous duty of having to show the government and private companies my vaccine cards with all required boosters in perpetuity.
- Left: Well, how about lockdowns instead?

EDIT: Well, it looks like I found a nigh-perfect [scissor statement](https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/10/30/sort-by-controversial/). Although I have opinions on both topics, I was inspired to post this simply by how closely the arguments are mirrored.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifqh42h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifqfwcp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I would appreciate if someone could provide feedback on this line of thinking. I</title><updated>2022-07-11T15:41:05Z</updated><author><name>escherofescher</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I would appreciate if someone could provide feedback on this line of thinking. It&#39;s something that occurred to me during a long evening walk and I can&#39;t decide whether this is a somewhat accurate map of the territory or a complete fabrication of some baser part of my mind.

Collectivism as a different mode of being. I had always assumed that people who lean toward it do so through a conscious choice, that they think through some sort of mini social contract, judge the benefits, and accept/reject it on merit before joining a group. Also, they&#39;re conscious and watchful while part of some group so that if the group breaks the contract, they would leave it.

But what if it&#39;s not a conscious choice? What if, whoever dips their head under the collectivist waterline, surrenders their &#34;self&#34; and their brain becomes a substrate for running the collective&#39;s distributed OS?

Perhaps it will help if I describe what lead me to this train of thought. I imagined a person deeply enmeshed in some collective identity. If you&#39;re in the US, imagine a woman with short blue hair, her face full of piercings, a t-shirt that says &#34;long live Che&#34;, a pair of Doc Marten&#39;s, and NPR blaring on her headphones. Or, to balance things out, imagine an obese man driving a leased pickup truck with one American and one Gadsden flag, listening to a radio version of One America Network&#39;s report about election fraud.

What these two stereotype images have in common is that it seems both of these people have surrendered their minds to a collective. In other words, they outsource their opinion-formation and worldview out to a group of people. Do they still reason? Are they critical of new information? Do they introspect? Or do they merely think what their chosen collective tells them to think?

I&#39;ve met many people that fall somewhere farther or closer to these stereotypes. And one characteristic that always strikes me is that they communicate in the same way: repeating slogans or headlines from their preferred media source (or social media milieu), ie. they&#39;re outputting canned rhetoric someone cooked up for them. Because of that, they can&#39;t actually engage in a discussion because they can&#39;t respond to arguments. They can only shoot back these prepackaged messages.

Going down this slippery slope, talking with people like this doesn&#39;t mean engaging with a reasoning individual, but with a tentacle of a much larger organism. Basically, an alien.

Eh, I know that to some this must sound like an edgy 16 yo&#39;s, &#34;2deep4you&#34; line of thinking. I think I bring it up because it&#39;s dawning on me just how differently different people think and it&#39;s freaking me out. I think one of my core beliefs was that people reason more or less in the same way, but observing people is shaking things up in my mind.

So, is there any merit to this? Any threads in the form of reading I could pull to understand this side of humanity better? Any gross mistakes in this view?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifqfwcp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifpphsh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] We talked quite a bit about the quality of information in the media ecosystem an</title><updated>2022-07-11T12:20:02Z</updated><author><name>Walterodim79</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">We talked quite a bit about the quality of information in the media ecosystem and how that has intersected with science of questionable quality in the Covid universe, but today I want to highlight an example that&#39;s generally a bit further from the culture war. Over the weekend, my NYT digest pinged me with the now one year old wellness article *[Do We Really Need to Take 10,000 Steps a Day for Our Health?](https://archive.ph/Xq0Fv#selection-319.0-322.0)*. As someone that&#39;s immediately triggered by people looking for excuses to justify their sedentary lifestyles, I naturally clicked through for a quick rage-read (put aside for a moment how unhealthy *that* behavior is). So, what&#39;s the origin of the claim that fewer steps is actually fine?

&amp;gt;A 2019 study by Dr. Lee and her colleagues found that women in their 70s who managed as few as 4,400 steps a day reduced their risk of premature death by about 40 percent, compared to women completing 2,700 or fewer steps a day. The risks for early death continued to drop among the women walking more than 5,000 steps a day, but benefits plateaued at about 7,500 daily steps. In other words, older women who completed fewer than half of the mythic 10,000 daily steps tended to live substantially longer than those who covered even less ground.

Wait, *what*? How does this causal inference chain work? If you showed me [that study](https://archive.ph/3Xcuo), I&#39;d think it&#39;s fine as far as it goes, but that the only thing that it really tells us is that elderly women that have dropped to as few as 2,700 steps are often pretty well on death&#39;s door, which is what I would have already expected. There&#39;s pretty much nothing I can draw from that regarding the value of moving more for young and middle-aged people. There definitely isn&#39;t anything strong enough to move me off the prior that moving more is almost always a good thing. I suppose I agree that there&#39;s no magic number and if there was, it&#39;d be a hell of a coincidence that it happened to line up with a shiny, round number, but that&#39;s never really been the point anyway. Oh well though, she&#39;s not done citing evidence:

&amp;gt;Another, more expansive study last year of almost 5,000 middle-aged men and women of various ethnicities likewise found that 10,000 steps a day are not a requirement for longevity. In that study, people who walked for about 8,000 steps a day were half as likely to die prematurely from heart disease or any other cause as those who accumulated 4,000 steps a day. The statistical benefits of additional steps were slight, meaning it did not hurt people to amass more daily steps, up to and beyond the 10,000-steps mark. But the extra steps did not provide much additional protection against dying young, either.

Well, that&#39;s a bit more encouraging, so [what does that study say](https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/article-abstract/2763292)? 

&amp;gt;A total of 4840 participants (mean age, 56.8 years; 2435 [54%] women; 1732 [36%] individuals with obesity) wore accelerometers for a mean of 5.7 days for a mean of 14.4 hours per day. The mean number of steps per day was 9124. There were 1165 deaths over a mean 10.1 years of follow-up, including 406 CVD and 283 cancer deaths. The unadjusted incidence density for all-cause mortality was 76.7 per 1000 person-years (419 deaths) for the 655 individuals who took less than 4000 steps per day; 21.4 per 1000 person-years (488 deaths) for the 1727 individuals who took 4000 to 7999 steps per day; 6.9 per 1000 person-years (176 deaths) for the 1539 individuals who took 8000 to 11 999 steps per day; and 4.8 per 1000 person-years (82 deaths) for the 919 individuals who took at least 12 000 steps per day. Compared with taking 4000 steps per day, taking 8000 steps per day was associated with significantly lower all-cause mortality (HR, 0.49 [95% CI, 0.44-0.55]), as was taking 12 000 steps per day (HR, 0.35 [95% CI, 0.28-0.45]). Unadjusted incidence density for all-cause mortality by peak 30 cadence was 32.9 per 1000 person-years (406 deaths) for the 1080 individuals who took 18.5 to 56.0 steps per minute; 12.6 per 1000 person-years (207 deaths) for the 1153 individuals who took 56.1 to 69.2 steps per minute; 6.8 per 1000 person-years (124 deaths) for the 1074 individuals who took 69.3 to 82.8 steps per minute; and 5.3 per 1000 person-years (108 deaths) for the 1037 individuals who took 82.9 to 149.5 steps per minute. Greater step intensity was not significantly associated with lower mortality after adjustment for total steps per day (eg, highest vs lowest quartile of peak 30 cadence: HR, 0.90 [95% CI, 0.65-1.27]; P value for trend = .34).

OK, this is actually pretty good. It&#39;s still more in the direction of predictive data than advice (IMO), but those differences are *really* large. We should be looking at that and describing dropping to 4,000 steps per day in middle age as an emergency, a strong predictor of impending doom. This doesn&#39;t necessarily provide advice for the young, but we can probably start drawing some inferences about just how bad it is to not move around much. Of note, the 12,000 step group actually did a decent bit better than the 8,000 step group; they have overlapping confidence intervals, so that&#39;s a weak conclusion, but I&#39;d personally be inclined to take it as a suggestion that we don&#39;t really have any cap on the &#34;more is better&#34; line of thinking. What&#39;s the conclusion from our intrepid NYT reporter?

&amp;gt;The good news is that upping our current step counts by even a few thousand additional strides most days could be a reasonable, sufficient — and achievable — goal, Dr. Lee said. The formal physical activity guidelines issued by the United States and other governments use time, not steps, as a recommendation, and suggest we exercise for at least 150 minutes a week, or a half-hour most days, in addition to any moving around we do as part of our normal, daily lives. Translated into step counts, Dr. Lee said, that total would work out to a little more than 16,000 steps a week of exercise for most people, or about 2,000 to 3,000 steps most days. (Two thousand steps equal approximately a mile.) If, like many people, we currently take about 5,000 steps a day during the course of everyday activities like shopping and housework, adding the extra 2,000 to 3,000 steps would take us to a total of between 7,000 and 8,000 steps most days, which, Dr. Lee said, seems to be the step-count sweet spot.

Wait, *what*? How is that the &#34;sweet spot&#34;? Is this based on the idea that it&#39;s some unbearable suffering to go for a long walk? I&#39;m just absolutely blown away that anyone would treat 10,000 steps as (implied above) unreasonable and unachievable. Just how low of a bar are we setting and why is that the tone that a NYT blogger wants to set for people?

On one level, I know I&#39;m being petty, but I actually do think misunderstanding causality and failing to actually look at the data in a couple pretty simple papers highlights just how bad science and medical journalism is. It&#39;s not just politically charged topics like Covid and environmentalism, it&#39;s something as simple as, &#34;should people be advised to take more than 8,000 steps?&#34;. When the writing is this bad on something that I wouldn&#39;t expect bias to creep in, I find that I&#39;m unsurprised that it goes completely off the rails on topics where there&#39;s a tribal affiliation with morally good conclusions.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifpphsh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifp0lwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] According to [this graph ](https://nitter.net/QuarantinedCoof/status/15461851456</title><updated>2022-07-11T07:01:36Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">According to [this graph ](https://nitter.net/QuarantinedCoof/status/1546185145698353154#m), Biden&#39;s approval rating took a big dip after the Afghanistan pullout. Why? I thought people generally wanted the US to pull out.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifp0lwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnth1f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What happens to thinking people who are clearly wrong but [whose heads haven&#39;t e</title><updated>2022-07-11T00:16:45Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What happens to thinking people who are clearly wrong but [whose heads haven&#39;t exploded](https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_dennett_the_illusion_of_consciousness?language=en)? 

The (imo) stupid adage that science advances one funeral at a time is so old that I think it has finally [overstayed its welcome](https://rootsofprogress.org/how-curing-aging-could-help-progress) and, with any luck, we&#39;ll bid it final goodbyes soon enough. 

Yes sometimes, often even, it is right on the money. There are walking scholarly zombies all around: people who&#39;ve bet it all on a hypothesis, have been publicly and convincingly proven wrong (or had the ground move under them to the point their entire map became obsolete) and have not recanted. Indeed, some double down or just begin to ignore all criticism. 

What do we know about such cases and such people? Are they just cognitively rigid and emotionally invested? Bound like slaves to a cottage factory that has been built around their assumptions, perhaps? Does the stress of debunking alter their reasoning somehow, degrade it maybe? How does it feel from the inside? I&#39;ve seen some curious patterns, but don&#39;t want to bias you. 

The easy recent example: Hofstadter and GPT-3, see [Scott&#39;s 53rd point](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/links-for-june-1e7) and [my comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vp23id/quality_contributions_report_for_june_2022/iej8xel/).  

What are your examples? And if you know any more systematic sources: I&#39;d be much obliged. Sounds like something Lesswrong ought to have done a lot of work on.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnth1f/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnimbw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-07-10T22:50:45Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnimbw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifmdv53/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone know what happened to [A New Radical Centrism](https://web.archive.org/we</title><updated>2022-07-10T17:55:15Z</updated><author><name>jacksonjules</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone know what happened to [A New Radical Centrism](https://web.archive.org/web/20220420073405/https://twitter.com/a_centrism)? (Posted an old archive link for clarity about who they are).

I assume they got banned for breaking Twitter&#39;s content rules on race and trans stuff. Do they have a new landing site?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifmdv53/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifm9qxr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Schwab&#39;s *The Fourth Industrial Revolutio</title><updated>2022-07-10T17:25:48Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Schwab&#39;s *The Fourth Industrial Revolution*. I&#39;ve only heard of him filtered through anti-lockdown perspectives, but I admit that I find it hard to hate someone who dresses, as they say, like a Bond villain.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifm9qxr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifm3k67/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] When one is a useless, defective parasite upon the body public, who provides not</title><updated>2022-07-10T16:41:54Z</updated><author><name>Capital_Room</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When one is a useless, defective parasite upon the body public, who provides nothing, contributes nothing, does nothing meaningful, and who (socially speaking) already practically doesn&#39;t exist, why should one bother suffering through 30+ years of increasing misery and futility, rather than just skipping to the inevitable conclusion now?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifm3k67/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflhxov/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] It appears I&#39;m going to acquire a decent sum of money soon. Nothing too crazy bu</title><updated>2022-07-10T14:04:11Z</updated><author><name>ShouldHaveVotedGore</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">It appears I&#39;m going to acquire a decent sum of money soon. Nothing too crazy but more than I&#39;d be comfortable with just sitting around in a checking account. How would you suggest &#34;storing&#34; it? Mutual funds? Multiple approaches to &#34;diversify&#34; against single point of failure?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflhxov/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflcie0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What podcasts are you into these days?  CW stuff is good, but I&#39;m open to anythi</title><updated>2022-07-10T13:18:50Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What podcasts are you into these days?  CW stuff is good, but I&#39;m open to anything that goes deep.
  
Only thing I can&#39;t tolerate is excessive bantering and bullshit, I don&#39;t like feeling like a stranger listening in on a bunch of bros cracking inside jokes.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflcie0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflb2gs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Did Christianity produce a “domesticating” effect in Europeans?

I was reading a</title><updated>2022-07-10T13:05:50Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Did Christianity produce a “domesticating” effect in Europeans?

I was reading about that [Russian fox experiment](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domesticated_silver_fox). Domesticated traits started to occur only after the second generation. After six generations you had a few hyper-domesticated foxes and by the 20th generation 30% of foxes constituted this hyper-domesticated status. 

The Christian social system appears especially conducive to domestication.  Only those with especially prosocial tendencies will get the most out of services; those with especially “domesticated” qualities will be graded best by peers according to the Christian rubric of grading another’s behavior; greater voluntary activity within the church would draw in the especially prosocial, creating prosocial pairings similar to in the Fox experiment. Those who best internalized the behavioral proscriptions of the Church had the highest status, and this obedience is a kind of domestication. Traits like intelligence, humor, and athleticism have no real value in the historically Christian social system, although a minimum amount of intelligence was probably necessary to secure a mate.

Compare to what (little) we know about Paganism. Paganism had no such fixation on domesticated qualities.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflb2gs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifkwy7m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Are some smart people just naturally gullible? My boyfriend is extremely gullibl</title><updated>2022-07-10T10:21:29Z</updated><author><name>2cimarafa</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Are some smart people just naturally gullible? My boyfriend is extremely gullible. Sometimes he&#39;ll send me instagram posts of literal fake news (not really partisan, more like tabloid-esque &#39;the Queen has cancer and 30 days to live&#39; headlines, or &#39;PROOF Rishi Sunak responsible for taking Partygate photos&#39;, ie., things that are plausible but also functionally made-up by the post); he sometimes struggles to tell whether some mockumentaries are fictional until 10-15 minutes in. Objectively he&#39;s very intelligent according to widely held IQ proxies, test scores, grades, his job and so on. But I&#39;m sometimes stunned at his lack of scepticism, I&#39;m actually very worried that one day someone could trick him into a stupid investment or into being mugged by leading him into an alleyway under false pretences or something. 

Do you know people like this (maybe you&#39;re together with one)? Is there a solution or do I just have to live with this concern?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifkwy7m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifjq0i7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does the opposite of the Gambler&#39;s Fallacy have merit?

The tldr on the Gambler&#39;</title><updated>2022-07-10T02:07:29Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does the opposite of the Gambler&#39;s Fallacy have merit?

The tldr on the Gambler&#39;s Fallacy is this &#34;We&#39;re flipping a coin. It hit heads the last 4 times, so we&#39;re due a tails this next time.&#34; But, the law of independent variables tells us that&#39;s BS. Each flip is independent, and so the odds of hitting tails doesn&#39;t go up each time you hit heads.

But, does the odds of a heads *increase* for each heads previously flipped?

I want to argue yes, and yeah, I&#39;m aware of the Hot Hand Fallacy. But here&#39;s my idea...

After some improbable number of consecutive heads flipping (and this is important) *the same coin*, the odds that the coin isn&#39;t fair increases. Cheating starts to become a better explanation than just chance.

And this becomes apparent at the extreme. Imagine a coin has been flipped 1 million times, heads all 1 million of them. Then we flip a million and oneth time. What are the odds of heads? It&#39;s not 50/50, because the 1 million previous flips are basically proof positive that the coin is rigged.

If that last million-flip example makes sense, I&#39;d wonder where is the number of flips where we start to think there&#39;s a meaningful deviation from the 50/50 prediction.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifjq0i7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifj0415/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] to those who have done deep dives into metaphysics/ontology/epistemology: is it </title><updated>2022-07-09T22:33:40Z</updated><author><name>SebJenSeb</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">to those who have done deep dives into metaphysics/ontology/epistemology: is it worth it? to me most of these arguments are a great example of philosophical masturbation about things that dont mean anything in the real word.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifj0415/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifiszzt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So a Nazi walks into a bar.

Fuck, damnit. I always screw this one up. Let me st</title><updated>2022-07-09T21:38:40Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So a Nazi walks into a bar.

Fuck, damnit. I always screw this one up. Let me start again...

So a Nazi walks into a Browning Automatic Rifle.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifiszzt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/iffvcby/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [She works in cryonics now](https://www.smbc-comics.com/comic/ageless).

*SMBC i</title><updated>2022-07-09T05:18:44Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[She works in cryonics now](https://www.smbc-comics.com/comic/ageless).

*SMBC is the rude little brother of XKCD: just as clever, but he&#39;ll kick you in the shins if you don&#39;t laugh.*</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/iffvcby/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifefcnn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Just killing a bit of time before D&amp;amp;D.</title><updated>2022-07-08T22:01:38Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Just killing a bit of time before D&amp;amp;D.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifefcnn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ife1wvw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m re-reading the Hyperion books at the moment.  It&#39;s a  perhaps overly literat</title><updated>2022-07-08T20:28:26Z</updated><author><name>_Cullis</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m re-reading the Hyperion books at the moment.  It&#39;s a  perhaps overly literate space opera series from early 1990s, and while some of it has aged gracefully (e.g. in the future, everyone has a smartphone and/or comm implants and people get withdrawals if they&#39;re deprived) .. there are some parts that really didn&#39;t.

(set cca 2600 or so)

&amp;gt;I was thinking about how free of mobs recent centuries had been: **to create a mob there must be public meetings,** and public meetings in our time consisted of individuals communing via the All Thing or other datasphere channels; it is hard to create mob passion when people are separated by kilometers and light-years, connected only by comm lines and fatline threads.

Indeed, it seems  that networking supercharges mobs, and the networked ones are even worse than the physical  ones.  They don&#39;t dississipate when they get hungry and tired, and they keep egging each other on.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ife1wvw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifdq2if/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Some old books (e.g. *The Arctic Home in the Vedas*) argue the original Indo-Ary</title><updated>2022-07-08T19:08:12Z</updated><author><name>6tjk</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Some old books (e.g. *The Arctic Home in the Vedas*) argue the original Indo-Aryan homeland was located above the Arctic Circle based on readings of the Vedas and Zoroastrian texts that are argued to only make sense based on them being set in the far north, such as descriptions of year-long days or descriptions of stars that imply they were observed from near the North Pole. Have any modern scholars addressed this argument and either supported or refuted it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifdq2if/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I re</title><updated>2022-07-08T13:38:22Z</updated><author><name>Nightmode444444</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I recently ran across an external forum that is totally fascinating. It’s a fairly large and active community of Christian polygamists. They’re not associated with a denomination (definitely not Mormon) and seems to be legitimate biblical scholars. They have reasoned their way into polygamy with carful reading of scripture. If you liked watching Big Love and want to really see how modern polygamists live. Here’s your shot. 

Some observations:

* They seems to be quite persecuted within mainstream Christiandom. As you would expect.
* They also seem to be quite intelligent and know the Bible inside and out. They can support their position quite well and it seems difficult find a flaw in their logic. As a Catholic, I can’t say that I’m an expert on scripture and the only argument I have against their logic is that The Church has taken a very diffierent view on sex and marriage. Without having The Church as an authority, I don’t know how evangelicals who stick to the Bible as ultimate authority can pin these people down. 
* There does seem to be some motivated reasoning going on here. Some posters are clearly looking to justify their lust and build a harem, but most seem to be quite sincere. 
* The community is surprisingly healthy with lots of activity and very collegial users. Reminds me of themotte in some ways. 

I find the whole thing fascinating. Besides the whole intellectual discussion of polygamy and the Bible there are quite of few gems in here. Ever want to see a bunch of Christian men painstakingly discuss whether or not lesbiansism between sister wives is a sin (spoiler: it’s not)? Ever want to see full throated defense and encorgament of patriarchy? I’ve always loved to observe these types of communities that I would otherwise not know about. Reminds me of early internet days. 

I won’t link to the the forum, but you can google christian polygamy forum and find it quite easily. 

Enjoy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcbz0w/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recommend some gems on Xbox Gamepass I can try.  Small-scale stuff is fine.  I&#39;m</title><updated>2022-07-08T13:36:53Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recommend some gems on Xbox Gamepass I can try.  Small-scale stuff is fine.  I&#39;m getting an Xbox S so I can spend more time with my brother.  So, come to think of it, good co-op campaigns are particularly welcome.

I&#39;ve played most of the classics; I think the only big single-player shooter franchise I&#39;ve never touched is Gears of War.  I&#39;ve been strictly PC Master Race or Playstation before now.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcbz0w/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc776u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Of course this is subjective but;

I think East Asian cuisine (Korean, Chinese, </title><updated>2022-07-08T12:59:27Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Of course this is subjective but;

I think East Asian cuisine (Korean, Chinese, Thai, NOT JAPAN) is a tier above all other regional cuisines. Everytime I catch myself voraciously craving something savory or reflecting on a meal I had long after it&#39;s over, its usually from those cuisines.

I had a Korean meal (rice, kimchi jigae, banchan, spicy fried chicken) yesterday and I can&#39;t get it out of my mind. It ticked all the boxes of sweet, umami, spicy, tangy, fatty, varied textures.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc776u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc4ovs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anyone feel like big social media and social media adjacent companies are s</title><updated>2022-07-08T12:38:15Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anyone feel like big social media and social media adjacent companies are sitting on a goldmine of social science research? 

The recent conversations on Tinder/dating got me thinking that I would really like to see a plot of &#39;average x/10 rating&#39; vs &#39;match rate&#39;. My gut instinct tells me it would be a sigmoid function with the range [0,30].</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc4ovs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc3y7g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Anyone here ever listened to the podcast Decoding the Gurus?
[They have a new ep</title><updated>2022-07-08T12:31:50Z</updated><author><name>genieanus</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Anyone here ever listened to the podcast Decoding the Gurus?
[They have a new episode on Lex Friedman and Jonathan Heidt.](https://decoding-the-gurus.captivate.fm/episode/lex-fridman-jonathan-haidt-the-techno-monk-the-social-scientist)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc3y7g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifbt2f0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I recall a study done by someone who followed up with people who give obviously </title><updated>2022-07-08T10:39:16Z</updated><author><name>Mantergeistmann</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I recall a study done by someone who followed up with people who give obviously wrong answers on studies (&#34;I work 30 hours a day&#34; or &#34;everyone I know is an extraterrestrial&#34;) and took down the justifications people gave a about their answers. My Google-fu is failing me here, though. Is anyone else familiar with it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifbt2f0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>