<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T01:42:15Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizy0yn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I caught [this campaign ad tonight](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RHxQFqbdFUk)</title><updated>2022-08-05T01:42:15Z</updated><author><name>Iconochasm</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I caught [this campaign ad tonight](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RHxQFqbdFUk).  Watch that.  It&#39;s only a minute. 

What party do you think John is in?  There is actually a reference, but it&#39;s quick.  I missed it when I saw it live.

I feel like there&#39;s a lot to unpack here.  Fetterman is going to fight Washington?  Where his party has the White House, the House and the Senate???  Because people feel forgotten, like their best time was a generation ago?  A decade of left-leaning media has taught me that that&#39;s a blatant racist dog-whistle, appealing to aggrieved white entitlement.  Maybe it&#39;s just smart, faux-flag campaigning in a red wave year with a very unpopular president.

Here is Fetterman&#39;s [spot on gun violence](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Krqv8O4ENQ).  This one&#39;s 2.5 minutes; that&#39;s how I getcha.  So, a couple of things to note.  First, in the story he tells in that bit, the person he went after was, in fact, not any kind of a shooter.  It was, according to [The Root](https://www.theroot.com/john-fetterman-has-had-eight-years-to-apologize-for-pul-1846249115) literally some unarmed black jogger that Fetterman pulled a shotgun on.  Second, the town of Braddock has a population of [1,721](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Braddock,_Pennsylvania).  Managing to go *a whole five years* without a *fatal* shooting seems like the kind of low bar you describe as damning with faint praise.  But maybe Fetterman was the magic ingredient - they had another murder in [2018](https://www.city-data.com/crime/crime-Braddock-Pennsylvania.html), in [2020](https://www.wpxi.com/news/top-stories/he-was-one-most-loyal-people-loved-ones-remember-man-shot-killed-north-braddock/3KVFBCDYPZG3FEISI5DCJK2Y5Q/), and another just a [few weeks ago.](https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/man-dead-after-overnight-shooting-braddock/C6JVNFDK3NDXXPJMGO5HLN3PO4/)

Fetterman is, belying appearances, a Harvard School of Government grad who has been called a [&#34;carpetbagger&#34;](https://whyy.org/articles/braddock-made-john-fetterman-a-politician-its-also-home-to-some-of-his-biggest-critics/).  This is kind of funny because the opponent he is leading by [11 points](https://www.forbes.com/sites/nicholasreimann/2022/07/28/fetterman-takes-double-digit-lead-over-oz-in-new-pennsylvania-poll/?sh=5fe0b07d6227) is absurd TV clown doctor/carpetbagger, [Dr. Mehmet Oz](https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2022/jul/18/john-fetterman-knocks-mehmet-oz-carpetbagger-attac/), who was last seen getting rolled by [Joe Rogan](https://twitter.com/joerogan/status/546471534768828417?lang=en).  Fetterman has been blasting out attack ads while he recovers from his stroke - yes, that&#39;s right, he had a minor stroke a few months ago, because he was diagnosed with a heart condition, and then didn&#39;t go to a doctor for 5 years.

You know, single-payer stuff aside, I think he&#39;s my new favorite Democrat.

All of which is to say that I hate campaign season, I hate seeing these ads, and whatever the outcome is, yes, actually, but more stupider.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizy0yn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizll0b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Why was Brittney Griner getting paid millions to play basketball in Russia?

It&#39;</title><updated>2022-08-05T00:09:45Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Why was Brittney Griner getting paid millions to play basketball in Russia?

It&#39;s been well-reported how WNBA players are paid: Griner, one of the better players in the league, made something like $220k/year, a relative pittance compared to players in the NBA who typically make millions. Why the pay gap? Perhaps it&#39;s because of systemic sexism. Perhaps it&#39;s because no one watches WNBA games and the NBA subsidizes it to the tune of $10M/year. But I&#39;m less interested in understanding that than why WNBA players can move to Russia in the off season to make millions.

To state the obvious: Russia is not richer than the US; it&#39;s not more populous than the US; Russians are not more into basketball than Americans; and Russians are not big on feminist signaling compared to the US.

So what&#39;s the story with the seven figure payouts? The obvious answer is that Russian women&#39;s basketball is just money laundering, but it&#39;s not clear how women&#39;s basketball would offer a good vehicle for that. Is it oligarchs bringing over accomplished female athletes for salacious reasons? Maybe, but it&#39;s not like Russia is lacking in ballerinas and figure skaters who are genuinely world class in their spheres (and Griner in particular is not the type to be interested in men). And I can&#39;t buy that it&#39;s genuine interest in the sport.

The best answer I&#39;ve been able to come up with is that it&#39;s just a way for Russian oligarchs to show off and compete with each other, but even if so, why settle on women&#39;s basketball of all things?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizll0b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiz0ik0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] This was intended to be a reply to a comment by u/Ilforte but it took on a life </title><updated>2022-08-04T21:40:50Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">This was intended to be a reply to a comment by u/Ilforte but it took on a life of it&#39;s own. It&#39;s a theory I&#39;ve had for a while and it was stoked by the comments below about DeSantis and the 2024 election: Biden isn&#39;t running in 2024. Even if his approval rating recovers I don&#39;t think he has it in him, and that&#39;s the kind of decision that has to be made before he&#39;d know if his approval rating would recover, and he&#39;d be taking a risk that it would tank and hand the election to the Republicans. That being said, he can&#39;t exactly come out and say that he won&#39;t be seeking reelection. He&#39;d immediately become a lame duck and serve the last 2 1/2 years of his presidency in irrelevance. He could be the greatest president in history for that last 2 1/2 years and it wouldn&#39;t matter because everyone would be focused on the massive primary field that would develop. And he can&#39;t just name Kamala Harris as his successor, because nobody likes Kamala Harris, and this dislike would be intensified since she&#39;s already vice-president and we&#39;d see newspaper headlines about what a horrible &#34;dry-run&#34; she&#39;s having. 

So the best chance for the Democrats is for Biden to hold off as long as possible in announcing anything. There will be a lot of media speculation but Biden will just say that it isn&#39;t important. Any serious candidates for the nomination will be forced to hold off lest they find themselves running against an incumbent. Then, at the last possible moment, he announces he&#39;s not running but really wants you to consider voting for Amy Klobuchar (or someone else who&#39;s not Kamala Harris) in the primary. Since no one other than Amy Klobuchar has gotten word that the president isn&#39;t running, no one else is ready to stage a primary campaign, and we end up with a repeat of 2016 except without Bernie Sanders. 

And the Republican side isn&#39;t as locked-in as people seem to think it is. First, if Trump runs again, he&#39;s probably going to lose. Biden&#39;s baggage may rub off onto the other Democratic candidates, but Trump has plenty of his own baggage that&#39;s far worse. He already lost the 2020 election, and his behavior afterwards was appalling to anyone who didn&#39;t vote for him. True believers may brush off the MASSIVE FRAUD conspiracies and Jan. 6, but very few Biden voters will, and he needs to convert a lot of Biden voters. 

DeSantis has his own dilemma in that his nomination becomes more difficult if Trump decides to run. Everyone says that he&#39;s young enough to wait—he&#39;ll only be 50 in 2028—so there&#39;s no rush. The problem is that it&#39;s not so simple. He&#39;s the current star Republican, and his star can fade. Who&#39;s to say whether someone else might steal the spotlight by then? Furthermore, he&#39;s able to stay in the spotlight because he takes bold high-risk, high-reward actions in the culture war. He&#39;s been successful so far, but it may only be a matter of time before he oversteps. Already, the Reedy Creek mess may come back to bite him in the ass if the choice is between abandoning his position or the state assuming $1 billion in Disney&#39;s debt. (Honestly, losing the inevitable lawsuit may be the best thing for him politically.) He&#39;s had decent instincts so far, but if the pressure to stay in the national spotlight ramps up then he might take increasingly unjustifiable risks.

With that being said, he may have to take a shot at the nomination in 2024, Trump or no Trump. The choice is 2024 as the heir-apparent against a bunch of also-rans, 2024 as the rising star against Trump and (probably) Trump alone, or 2028 as former Florida Governor Ron DeSantis in a field of thousands. (Or, less likely, in 2032 in a field of thousands after some nobody took on Trump and surprisingly ended up as president.) On the one hand, running against Trump seems like a bad bet; despite claims of waning influence in the party, the candidates he&#39;s endorsed have done exceedingly well in the primaries. On the other hand, all these candidates could lose. Dr. Oz is down by double digits in a purple state against a committed leftist. J.D. Vance is down in the polls and it&#39;s questionable whether he&#39;s actually running a campaign. Herschel Walker is, well Herschel Walker. If the Republicans underperform in the midterms I&#39;d say it&#39;s pretty much over for Trumpism as a national force. Thus, DeSantis is in the ironic position of hoping his own party underperforms in the midterms because it gives him a clear path to the nomination regardless of whether Trump runs. If he loses to Trump and Trump loses the election then he&#39;s still alive in 2028 because he can credibly say that Trumpism is a losing proposition and the country needs to move on. Of course, I&#39;m probably wrong and we&#39;ll see Trump v. Biden in 2024.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiz0ik0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiymawn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [removed]</title><updated>2022-08-04T20:07:24Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[removed]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiymawn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiyg6o3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW]  Finland’s NATO quest, still probably globally the most important development th</title><updated>2022-08-04T19:28:52Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text"> Finland’s NATO quest, still probably globally the most important development this country is a part of, is advancing. The [US Senate just voted to confirm](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/03/us/politics/sweden-finland-nato-senate-vote.html) Finland and Sweden as NATO members. Of course, the vote was a bit of a formality with a predestined result and a 95-1 vote, with Josh Hawley the only senator opposing. It should be noted that [Hawley’s perspective](https://www.hawley.senate.gov/hawley-op-ed-why-i-wont-vote-add-sweden-and-finland-nato) is by no means an isolationist one, let alone pacifist, but rather the argument is that the European countries are not pulling their weight on defence and that US should focus on the China threat anyhow.

Now, Hawley is, of course, entitled to his opinion, and it’s hardly my task from Finland to dictate that US has some sort of a duty to be allied to Finland if they don&#39;t wish so (of course, the votes of the other senators and Congress in general indicate otherwise). NATO membership might currently be popular in Finland, but it’s hardly without issues, as recounted [here](https://jacobin.com/2022/04/finland-nato-russia-ukraine-invasion-putin-sweden) – and out of the raised fears, Turkey has certainly proved that it can get [troublesome](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jun/30/erdogan-warns-turkey-could-still-block-finland-and-swedens-accession-to-nato). 

Certainly I&#39;ve seen some pro-NATO voices say that they are less positive on the organization than before Erdogan started issuing his demands and that they don&#39;t consider the organization worth it if it means having to junk longstanding human rights policies, like extraditing people without due process simply because another country demands it.

However, slam-dunk as the US approval was, Hawley’s given reasoning still seem like they need commenting. It’s not a new idea that many in the US think will focus on the Pacific sector and away from Europe is not a new one. However, one would think that such a development would precisely, at least within conventional geopolitical logic, be predicated by Europe becoming militarily more independent from the United States. It’s hard to imagine how adding the Finnish army to the mix would increase this dependence.

While many European countries indeed have not had their defence budgets at 2 % of the GDP, as Hawley himself noted, Finland has just recently [increased this budget considerably](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-05/finland-adds-2-2-billion-defense-spending-in-shadow-of-war) to match this limit. This was during the most left-wing and thus most anti-militarist government constellation that is currently realistically possible in Finland, and the more right-wing and conservative parties in the opposition would, if anything, support even larger military budgets. 

Since much of the new budget spending consists of material procurement with long-term orders, it’s going to be sticky for at least the coming decade. There’s an issue in comparing the military budgets of different countries, as NATO counts several things in military budgets that Finland currently does not count, such as military pensions, as mentioned [here](https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/04/14/what-finland-can-offer-nato/), for example.

Finland has specifically traditionally based its defense mainly on land forces and solutions that are not \*that\* expensive, ie. do not require high-tech weapons platforms. In particular, the FDF has concentrated on building up its artillery, with the [strongest artillery in Western Europe](https://www.hitc.com/en-gb/2022/05/13/finland-has-53rd-strongest-military-but-artillery-capability-sets-them-apart/). Precisely this war in Ukraine has shown that the era for such traditional armies is not in the past, and indeed the current phase of the war, by all accounts, seems to be one where artillery continues to be the king, with Russians blasting away at Ukrainians and Ukraine seeking to even the score using HIMARS. As many have noted, this war is basically exactly the one FDF has always trained for.

Of course, one might reasonably ask still whether FDF would still need copious naval and air support from other countries, chiefly the US. The Finnish Navy is… well, not really the mainstay of the Finnish defence, and the air force, even with F35s, has generally not been expected to hold its own independently against Russia. 

That score is considerably evened by the fact that the pacakge deal also includes Sweden, a country with weak land forces but a stronger navy and particularly air force. The Finnish and Swedish armed forces just fit together quite well, which has been one of the reasons why one of the main alternatives conceived to NATO in Finnish debates has just been a formal defence alliance with Sweden.

All told, while a real case might be made, within American context, for opposing the expansion of NATO, Hawleys’ arguments don’t really give an impression of such a stance - mainly that there’s political credit to be had in portraying yourself as an anti-hawk on Russia in a situation where there is room on the American right for that niche.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiyg6o3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iixrh4y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Today, Florida Governor Ron Desantis [suspended a State Attorney](https://www.ta</title><updated>2022-08-04T16:54:31Z</updated><author><name>Hacef_</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Today, Florida Governor Ron Desantis [suspended a State Attorney](https://www.tampabay.com/news/florida-politics/2022/08/04/desantis-suspends-hillsborough-county-state-attorney-andrew-warren/) for signing a pledge indicating that he would refuse to prosecute cases brought under the state&#39;s new laws restricting/criminalizing abortion after 15 weeks. Likewise, said State Attorney signed a pledge against enforcing laws that would restrict/criminalize gender-transition treatments for minors, although no such law currently exists on the books in Florida. 

Andrew Warren, the State Attorney in question, was the only Florida Attorney who had signed such a pledge, but he joined a number of other state attorneys from around the country.

Official order explaining and enacting the suspension [here.](https://www.flgov.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Executive-Order-22-176.pdf) (PDF warning)

Hillsborough County is one of the more populous and economically important areas of the state, although usually overshadowed by Miami and Orlando, and also leans more Democrat than the rest of the state (not counting Broward and Palm Beach). 

A few initial points:

* It is clear that the [Florida Constitution grants the Governor the authority](https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/ExecutiveSuspensions/2023) to do this, although the Senate is in charge of either fully removing or reinstating the suspended official.

* Noteworthy, however, is that State Attorney is an *elected* position and the position is a regional one rather than statewide, in this case it applies only to the counties in a particular legal district. You can thus argue that the people who voted Warren in largely agree with his stance.

* It doesn&#39;t appear that there have been any *actual* cases where the State declined prosecution, so this appears to be a pre-emptive move by DeSantis. Although they allege that there is a non-prosecution policy for crimes where the initial encounter with police was due to non-criminal violations.

* Prosecutorial discretion is indeed a recognized legal concept which is usually given broad deference. I know of no mechanism by which anyone can *force* a State Attorney to bring charges against a given suspect/Defendant. This is a powerful tool because of double jeopardy protections, which means if given charges are officially dropped by the State Attorney, they can never be brought again, even if a *different* State Attorney argues that they were dropped for &#39;improper&#39; reasons. The whole point is that the prosecutor doesn&#39;t have to explain themselves.

* With that in mind, I actually wonder if Mr. Warren hadn&#39;t signed the public pledge, and instead had just quietly ordered his prosecutors to decline to prosecute any abortion cases that weren&#39;t, shall we say, &#39;egregious,&#39; he might not have been noticed and the case for removing him might be much weaker.

* There is a yet-untested argument that [Florida&#39;s Constitution actually *does* protect abortion](https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2022/06/florida-15-week-abortion-ban-state-constitution-privacy-rights.html) because Florida&#39;s &#39;right to privacy&#39; amendment was added after *Roe* was decided and thus could, even after the recent SCOTUS decision, be determined to have intended to codify abortion as part of the right to privacy.


My own thoughts: 

Desantis continues to show willingness to flex his authority as Governor in very targeted ways. This action is probably less objectionable than his moves targeting Disney since the subject is a government official who is directly employed by the State.

At a basic level, I have to agree with the action. Whatever your thoughts on the validity or morality of a given law, it is the very *definition* of dereliction of duty for a state attorney to decline to enforce laws that the legislature has passed and the governor has signed and thus nominally represent the will of the state&#39;s electorate. Their whole job, prosecutorial discretion or no, is to enact the will of the people of the state as expressed in its laws by prosecuting violations of said laws. It would be outrageous if a state attorney were to refuse to prosecute a given law in exchange for monetary gain, it is only somewhat less outrageous to refuse to prosecute for purely political reasons. 

So even if people take this as yet *another* sign of DeSantis&#39; fascistic ambitions to rule Florida, and later the Country, with an iron fist, this is still an utterly justifiable exercise of executive authority, and is well *within* the limits of the authority delegated to the Governor, so you cannot truly argue that this is a troubling expansion of executive authority by a power-mad wannabe Despot. 

Leaving aside the extant problems of enforcing abortion restrictions when it is simple to travel to a different state to get one, having a &#39;sanctuary city&#39; for abortions *within* the state would render the entire law almost moot since  Hillsborough County is at most a 4 hour drive from anywhere in the state except the deepest part of the panhandle.

And end of the day, it is a savvy move by Desantis as it will of course garner support from his base, it should also cause many possible opponents to keep their heads down, and the ones who will be emboldened to fight back pretty much already despise him, so net result is he has simply shored up his already strong position with minimal effort or political capital expended.

I see a few likely effects intended by this action. 

The First order effect is removing a rebellious official who might have grown into a bigger problem down the line. Whatever other steps Warren takes from here, he won&#39;t be able to use his position as a government official to legitimize his actions.

Second order is a warning to other state government officials, and not just state attorneys, that if they publicly assume a stance in defiance of the State Government, they will be summarily removed without prior warning and no waiting until they actually *do* something objectionable. This one action will probably force many other officials who quietly agreed with Warren to dutifully stay in line during Desantis&#39; tenure. 

Third-ish order is probably to prevent any sort of camel&#39;s nose from entering in the tent which could possibly lead to an avowed leftist like [Chesa Boudin](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chesa_Boudin) getting elected and declaring amnesty for other classes of crimes. 


It is also possible that this is aimed at being a direct response to [George Soros&#39;](https://www.wsj.com/articles/why-i-support-reform-prosecutors-law-enforces-jail-prison-crime-rate-justice-police-funding-11659277441) recent piece declaring his intent to continue to support/fund &#39;reform-minded prosecutors.&#39; This action would basically close that off as an avenue for social agitation in Florida.

The primary way this backfires is if Warren runs for office again and is elected again and thus a clear message is sent to Desantis that the constituents are rejecting Desantis&#39; influence and defying the laws he has championed. I&#39;m not sure how it shakes out, ultimately, if a given district &#39;goes rogue&#39; in electing someone *because* he promises to defy the state&#39;s authority. Desantis and the GOP-controlled legislature could absolutely escalate by taking actions that target the city/county/people more directly, but that would probably draw more ire than its worth.

Maybe he&#39;ll find some use for that [newly reformed state guard](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Florida_State_Guard) after all.

It&#39;s probably similar to how many [County Sheriffs will state their refusal to enforce gun control laws](https://www.npr.org/2019/02/21/696400737/when-sheriffs-wont-enforce-the-law). Arguably as long as their jurisdiction doesn&#39;t turn into a zone of open rebellion/insurrection necessitating intervention by state-level authorities you just leave things be and govern &#39;around&#39; the problem.

**EDIT:** and just so I cannot be accused of strawmanning, [here](https://twitter.com/NikkiFried/status/1555197696608182272) is a Democratic hopeful for the Florida Governorship in this year&#39;s election calling Desantis a &#34;wannabe dictator&#34; and this action &#34;outrageous and dangerous&#34; without elaborating. [Here&#39;s](https://twitter.com/CharlieCrist/status/1555227810326880256) the other hopeful echoing the &#39;wannabe dictator&#39; language and calling it an &#39;attack on women&#39; (but making the reasonable point that the State Attorney was elected twice so maybe his constituents like him.)

So this is in fact what the mainstream Democrats are willing to say about a Governor exercising lawful authority to ensure the enforcement of a (presently) valid law of the state.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iixrh4y/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iix1zxm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anybody got a remedy for the daily diarrhea that lasts about a week after a nigh</title><updated>2022-08-04T14:09:38Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anybody got a remedy for the daily diarrhea that lasts about a week after a night of drinking when you&#39;re middle aged?

I mean I know the answer is don&#39;t drink, but suppose the deed is done.

Drank for the first time in months recently. Hangover was bearable, about what you&#39;d expect from one. But the real drag was for a while afterward every single day was diarrhea. Intestines are not a fan of the whole drinking thing. For that and other reasons I do not plan on doing this very often at all--but any helpful tips to keep in mind would be appreciated.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iix1zxm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iivy7kw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some things just seem to &#39;maximize&#39; and only grow in one direction. 

When I was</title><updated>2022-08-04T07:10:26Z</updated><author><name>I_Dream_of_Outremer</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some things just seem to &#39;maximize&#39; and only grow in one direction. 

When I was a kid the only commercials in baseball were on static billboards and in between innings, which was bad enough, to be sure. But they slowly started having &#39;sponsors&#39; for big events (the World Series brought to you by Ford), which morphed into &#39;sponsors&#39; for tiny events (the GameDay StatCast powered by Intel), which grew into &#39;sponsors&#39; for absolutely anything (if your team hits a homerun today you get a free burger tomorrow). Then moving, active billboards, all game long. Then sponsors on the mound, etc, and now they even have mini-ads in between pitches.

&#39;More of this is better&#39; seems to sometimes be the active principle, and (*here&#39;s my point*) I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s terminally so with &#39;liberalism.&#39; I used to like what it had to offer, but now I&#39;ve been pushed far enough that I want my baseball advertisement-free and don&#39;t particularly care how that comes about.

[Somewhere around 94% of abortion is elective](https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6874-13-29/tables/2) - maybe it&#39;s a good idea to not make people forcefully adopt cats and dogs - but if your &#39;pet shelters&#39; are killing ~94% of their &#39;patients&#39; for no morally defensible reason maybe you&#39;re more akin to the Aztecs then a healthcare provider.

More vs less abortion. More vs less immigration, especially illegal. More vs less income taxed away. More vs less kids being sexualized and taught about sex stuff. More vs less affirmative action. More vs less war in far off places. More vs less regulation. More vs less corporate consolidation. More vs less &#39;gun control.&#39; 

&amp;gt;The mother of excess is not joy but joylessness.

-Nietzsche</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iivy7kw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iivid1j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Call this a self-effacing journal entry.

My phone recently suffered some minor </title><updated>2022-08-04T04:15:48Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Call this a self-effacing journal entry.

My phone recently suffered some minor water damage, and I was easily able to get a replacement for $100.  Thank you insurance, you did your part, will be removing you now.  I&#39;d be kinda happy to have a new device with zero miles on it, except...

My previous phone was a Oneplus 7 Pro, the dumb orange one with the 5g.  I got it for half off on a desperation promo, I loved it to death, with it&#39;s pop-up camera and notification slider, and the fact that no one has heard of the thing.

The insurance guys sent me a Note 10 Plus.  Apparently they were out of that model.  Because there weren&#39;t that many.  Because no one had heard of it.

It says a lot about my character that I experience so much internal strife at the prospect of having to, however briefly, use a Normie Phone.  I could turn around and sell it for $300 tops, and use that money to buy...nothing that excites me, at the moment.  Some overpriced Sony midranger?  The Nothing Phone?  Eh.  Nokia hasn&#39;t made anything good, 

I used to sell phones.  I have strong opinions about them (I have legit sherlock-scanned people based on their phones).  It&#39;s a personal accessory, it doesn&#39;t say nothing about it&#39;s owner.  I made a lot of money matching up the Note series with the right people; I got so many grumpy boomers to upgrade to the things.  They&#39;re good devices, the pen is nice for the tactical games I play, I like scrolling around with it.  This thing will last me two more years easily.  I really do care less and less about phone crap; I hate the world they&#39;ve created, and feel somehow implicated.  Twitter is on phones man, and I knew that, and I was selling the things anyways.

And I&#39;m still pissy that someone might see the phone I have and mistake me for a Normie.

Urge to buy Xperia 10 IV, rising.  It&#39;s got a side-mounted fingerprint scanner, and a really long aspect ratio.  Visually striking, and people do recognize Sony, so Sony making phones will blow their mind.  There&#39;s a green one...

Yes, I choose the phone I use based on the opportunities it gives me to indicate to people that I am different, in whatever small, inconsequential way.  I once used the Razer phone, the monolith with the RGB shit on the back.  Before that, the Moto Z, the phone with magnetic modular doodads.  Before that, the Essential phone, a titanium brick from 2016 that looked exactly like the latest iphones somehow.

I have a disorder: &amp;gt;!I can&#39;t like popular things!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iivid1j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iivbqf8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Well, today I made the gigantic mistake of trying to play devil&#39;s advocate in an</title><updated>2022-08-04T03:17:25Z</updated><author><name>JhanicManifold</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Well, today I made the gigantic mistake of trying to play devil&#39;s advocate in an abortion debate with a smart left-leaning guy. The lack of norms surrounding steelmanning, the intellectual turing test and not holding your position too emotionally just made the whole thing unbelievably frustrating. The guy was pathologically unable to understand that his ideological opponents didn&#39;t have evil motives, but that they were normal, well-meaning people just like him. 

In finding the last few islands of good reasoning remaining on the internet, I might have forgotten how people (even smart ones) debate in the wild. I think no left-leaning person is ever really exposed to coherent right-wing arguments, and even when couched in a &#34;I&#39;m just playing devil&#39;s advocate&#34; frame, it still elicits frustration and anger in them. Lesson learned: don&#39;t ever debate anything political or religious unless you have reason to think that the person is one of the vanishingly few who can do that without frustration.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iivbqf8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitrgdq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Edit: Reprimand received from infallible /r/motte content deputy for posting the</title><updated>2022-08-03T20:13:33Z</updated><author><name>SunRaSquarePants</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Edit: Reprimand received from infallible /r/motte content deputy for posting the following, which mentions the culture war related actions of another subreddit, a city-themed sub that has clearly chosen a side and promotes a single unified ideological front. Added spoiler tags accordingly for those of you who don&#39;t want to see a silly yet &#34;banworthy&#34; meme, and for those of you tired of hearing about the internet. Just ignore it if you aren&#39;t interested. Have a nice day


I got permabanned from &amp;gt;!/r/austin!&amp;lt; for posting this: &amp;gt;!https://i.redd.it/7cgcotj3to091.png!&amp;lt;  

Reason given: &#34;spamming&#34;

What&#39;s the *real* &amp;gt;!austin!&amp;lt; subreddit?

edit: perhaps it&#39;s this one &amp;gt;!https://old.reddit.com/r/austincirclejerk/!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitrgdq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitjna5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **A Few Takeaways from the Kansas Abortion Referendum**

Kansas holds a place in</title><updated>2022-08-03T19:20:09Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**A Few Takeaways from the Kansas Abortion Referendum**

Kansas holds a place in American discourse as the prototypical &#34;Red State&#34;; it a Democratic presidential candidate hasn&#39;t won the state since 1964, and a Democratic Senator hasn&#39;t represented the state since 1939. They have had Democratic governors (including the incumbent, Laura Kelly) but hey, nobody&#39;s perfect. More importantly, the state was the subject of the book &#34;What&#39;s the Matter with Kansas?&#34;—which was later turned in to a documentary film—which tried to explain why relatively poor rural people tended to vote &#34;against their interest&#34; for conservative Republican politicians. (I use scare quotes because I think it&#39;s rather presumptuous that someone decide someone else&#39;s interests for them, especially if they don&#39;t actually know that person and are relying on broad demographic information.) 

Of course, the truth is more complicated than that. I&#39;m friends with a couple who lived in the state for several years after they both got postdocs at Kansas State University, and their initial trepidation of moving to the prairie after living in one of the hippest parts of Pittsburgh for a decade turned into an unexpected adoration. While the people there were definitely Trump-supporting conservatives, there was none of the bitterness that one would see in Appalachia. My friends reckoned that this was because there was no deindustrialization that left people longing for a glorified past America; these were simply people whose families ranched cattle for generations and always made a decent living from it and had six kids and always voted Republican because they always voted Republican. It probably also didn&#39;t hurt that practically any farmer would let the husband hunt deer on their property, in contrast to Pennsylvania, where people pay good money for private hunting leases and most people are stuck with overcrowded public game lands and state parks. And the Democratic governor? My friends said that she won simply because her campaign focused on solving the state&#39;s budget crisis while GOP opponent Kris Kobach focused his campaign on illegal immigration. In a state with few immigrants period, let alone illegal ones. Apparently, Kobach had become a punchline within a few weeks of nomination, even among people who ended up voting for him.

Against this backdrop, the citizens of Kansas voted yesterday on an Amendment to the state&#39;s constitution that would remove limits on the legislature&#39;s ability to regulate abortion. The average observer who bought into the &#34;What&#39;s the Matter with Kansas?&#34; rhetoric assumed the measure would pass handily. Professional journalists and others who were actually paying attention saw the issue as a tossup. So when the measure failed, the surprising thing wasn&#39;t that it failed, but that it failed by a 20 point margin. It&#39;s as of yet unclear what such an outcome means, whether for the midterms or abortion politics generally, so here are my initial thoughts:

**1. This won&#39;t help Democrats in the midterms**

To be fair, it won&#39;t *hurt* them either, but I wouldn&#39;t expect a ton of pro-choice Republicans to start voting Democrat. The referendum focused on a single issue, but actual candidates have to deal with as many issues as are necessary. Additionally, now that abortion is primarily a state issue, I would expect that most GOP voters would prefer to have it addressed in state houses rather than Congress. This may also have an effect on the Kansas gubernatorial election. The race is currently a tossup, but Republican challenger Derek Schmidt was on record as supporting the measure and argued the losing position on behalf of the state in 2019. He did, however, temper his position by claiming that termination of nonviable pregnancies did not meet the definition of abortion under Kansas law and would thus not be affected by a constitutional change, though his opponents pointed out that any abortion legislation could define terms however lawmakers wanted. This is a moot point now, but it remains to be seen how Schmidt handles the issue going forward (my guess is that he says the people have spoken and moves on to other things) and whether this tips the scales in favor of Laura Kelly. But I&#39;m no expert in Kansas politics so this is all speculation.

**2. This may have a huge effect on Republican abortion rhetoric**

In recent years, it&#39;s been rare for any Republican running for office to say anything that could remotely be conceived as pro-choice, and the Republicans that did were almost all in New England or the Mid-Atlantic. A quick perusal this morning of comments on the Fox News website and r/conservative shows that the attitude in these places seems to be &#34;This is what we wanted—leave it up to the states, and let the people decide. The people of Kansas have spoken.&#34; While I agree that this is a reasonable position to take and I don&#39;t doubt the sincerity of those taking it, this isn&#39;t exactly what was advertised when it came to overturning *Roe*. Pro-life advocates in states like California didn&#39;t want to see *Roe* overturned out of abstract support for Mississippians&#39; right of self-determination; they wanted it overturned because they wanted people in Mississippi to stop killing babies and hoped that one day California would pass such legislation as well. Certainly, some Republicans in Congress have been advocating for some sort of national ban, despite the knowledge that such a ban would likely be opposed by a majority of voters overall. And while I haven&#39;t looked into it that closely, it would appear that very few Republicans at the state level have voted against trigger laws and other restrictions in states that have enacted them.

If the vote proves anything, it&#39;s that Republican opinion on abortion isn&#39;t as uniform as Republican politicians seem to have assumed. I don&#39;t expect a wave of pro-choice Republicans getting elected on a platform of expanding abortion access in states that have restricted it. I do, however, expect a lot of Republican politicians to ditch the anti-abortion rhetoric that they assumed was getting them votes. Sure, some will know that their base is heavily Evangelical and will have no good reason to stop, but for others who rely on a broader base and need to expand their support they may realize that the issue alienates as many as it attracts and will stop hammering on it. At the Federal level in particular, it may be more politically expedient to defer the issue to the states and leave it at that. At the very least, I would expect the constant barrage of pro-life rhetoric coming from the Right to ebb at least somewhat and no longer be at the point where every Republican running for office has to trot out his pro-life credentials.

**3. Expect more ballot measures**

Some states allow for direct ballot measures and a number are already scheduled, as one would expect. What&#39;s been left out of the conversation thus far is what happens in states that don&#39;t allow for direct ballot measures; some states require voter approval for constitutional amendments, but these measures have to be proposed by the legislature before they go to the ballot. If the national GOP shifts its rhetoric from &#34;Abortion is wrong and should be banned&#34; to &#34;Abortion is an issue that should be decided by the states&#34;, then state legislatures are going to be under pressure to actually allow the people to decide. Pro-life state legislators might not be vulnerable on their votes for abortion restrictions directly, but they may be vulnerable if they steadfastly refuse to submit the question to the people. Some may argue that it&#39;s impractical to turn every matter of state law into a constitutional issue and that elected bodies are the best way of enacting the will of the public, but this argument isn&#39;t particularly effective when it involves what was clearly a national constitutional issue for fifty years and is one of the most controversial issues of the past two generations. If one looks at the referenda most of these states have put on the ballot in the past, the vast majority of it is stuff that most voters wouldn&#39;t find particularly interesting or controversial. In Pennsylvania in particular, the legislature has a tendency to submit items for constitutional amendment as a means of passing a sort of &#34;Super Law&#34; that&#39;s really hard to get rid of.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitjna5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iiti1r4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I have a seven hour flight tomorrow, can anyone recommend any iPhone/iPad games </title><updated>2022-08-03T19:09:12Z</updated><author><name>wear146</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I have a seven hour flight tomorrow, can anyone recommend any iPhone/iPad games or books (I like to read fairly light weight things when I travel, something like The Butchers Boy would be my Goto sort of novel)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iiti1r4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iitfiat/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any recommendations for bidets?</title><updated>2022-08-03T18:51:55Z</updated><author><name>disposablehead001</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any recommendations for bidets?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iitfiat/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iite1ng/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How do you keep an indoor cat stimulated/entertained?</title><updated>2022-08-03T18:42:05Z</updated><author><name>PM_ME_UR_OBSIDIAN</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How do you keep an indoor cat stimulated/entertained?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iite1ng/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iit4mxc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Sorry I do not have a better opening essay or a better link but Biden&#39;s White Ho</title><updated>2022-08-03T17:39:40Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Sorry I do not have a better opening essay or a better link but Biden&#39;s White House has been doing anti-trust against Penguin Random buying Simon &amp;amp; Schuster. https://edition.cnn.com/2022/08/01/media/book-publishing-merger-reliable-sources/index.html

And I am -- okay with this? I guess? I worry that consolidation is choking out minority viewpoints, and a lot of the conversation is about that. [Stephen King](https://ca.news.yahoo.com/stephen-king-testified-against-publishings-224159979.html) opposed it so the headlines about being too scary for King write themselves.

My personal hope is that it stops the industry from choking off anti-woke viewpoints. And it might do that. Or completely fail at that. I have been tragically wrong before.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iit4mxc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iit0kaw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m moving across the country next week to a small city in the middle of the mou</title><updated>2022-08-03T17:13:22Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m moving across the country next week to a small city in the middle of the mountain west. It has a college and is a (very) regional economic hub, but certainly ain&#39;t a social powerhouse.

Any advice for meeting people in their early-mid 20s? I know basically nobody there.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iit0kaw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iis7csl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I know that there currently are a number of topics that are more pressing for mo</title><updated>2022-08-03T14:03:57Z</updated><author><name>D1m1tr1Rascalov</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I know that there currently are a number of topics that are more pressing for most people here, but I had to follow up on my mini series of desperate rants about German COVID policy ([1](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/t8jl8a/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_march_07_2022/i058805/), [2](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/tvv1dl/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_april_04_2022/i3c817g/)) given the latest news: while the details are not fully fixed yet, our government coalition seemingly intends to pass a law that will continue to regulate Covid measures into the future. 

For context: the most restrictive measures ran out at the start of April and from then on federal states could reintroduce a number of the old measures via a vote in parliament. Two states, Hamburg and Mecklemburg-Vorpommern, did so to extend things for another month, a triumphant success for the wary majority of Twitter users, journalists, bureaucrats and of course government members, most of whom were in some way opposed to lifting Covid measures. Sadly for them these two federal states actually continually had higher case rates than the rest of the country throughout the entire period they kept up with mandatory masking and vaccine passes. 

In the time after up to today, the manic predictions of many of the people mentioned above did not come to pass, an insult compounded by the result of an investigation by a government commission staffed by experts in the field (many were proponents of stricter measures) which failed to find much or even any impact on health outcomes attributable to anything Germany did during the pandemic. Only mask mandates come out unscathed in the report, but not via a careful analysis of German data, but simply by citing the extant body of scientific literature on the topic.

So, why am I writing all of this? Shouldn&#39;t the (German) Covid hawks be defeated, their doomsday predictions falsified, their prestige trashed, their credibility destroyed, their control mania shown to be useless? Sadly no, it&#39;s Germany after all, we love our rules and [rules we shall have](https://twitter.com/Karl_Lauterbach/status/1554809274412548097/photo/1). The linked picture shows a list of powers that the federal states will have starting October 1, only a few of which are mandatory (masking in public transit and hospitals), but all of those on the left (including mask mandates in public spaces, testing requirements or proof of recent (past three months) vaccination/infection) can simply be put into effect if the local government desires it without a vote in parliament or a veto by anyone. Given the comments by leading figures at the federal state level, it&#39;s all but guaranteed that these things will be enforced right from the get-go.

This new law still has to pass a vote in federal parliament, but given that our health minister is already tweeting out the list from above it seems like it&#39;s a foregone conclusion that it will pass. At this point, I really don&#39;t know what to say anymore. We&#39;re at something like 99% antibody prevalence among the population, the most vulnerable are long dead or vaccinated, hospitals have shown no signs of difficulties, even despite our stringent measures up to March Omicron ran trough and gave half the population a confirmed infection (in reality probably close to everyone), basically every country around us is done with this stuff, and yet here we are, chugging along. Resistance is limited to boomers raging on Facebook and the online comment sections of newspapers and a few stragglers of the much maligned Querdenker (&#34;crossthinker&#34;) movement that had a populist-right and conspiracy theory vibe to it. It seems that basically everyone with an ounce of power or prestige in Germany is determined to keep this up as long as possible.

To make this rant a bit more interactive: what is the state of Covid discourse in your locality? What measures are there still, do people or politicians talk about it a lot, what are the plans, if there even are any, for winter? Also, to our neighboring countries: I am very sorry for everything Germany has done to you, but *please*, [~~Morgenthau~~ ](https://bigthink.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/origin-163.jpg?w=480&amp;amp;h=270&amp;amp;crop=1) us, I&#39;ll learn Polish, Danish, anything (EDIT: Morgenthau might be a bit extreme, see comments below, on googling something like a more extended [Bakker-Schut plan](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_annexation_of_German_territory_after_the_Second_World_War) might be more appropriate).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iis7csl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iirygg2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I caught a severe infection my toe which stopped me from working out. I had been</title><updated>2022-08-03T12:57:10Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I caught a severe infection my toe which stopped me from working out. I had been consistent for two weeks and on the last day pulled 60 kgs for 3 sets of 4 reps at a bodyweight of 68. That is some progress.

My life is still in shambles, time management issues, adhd, just the general inability to stick long term but I did have some progress, I did 10 hours (first 10 videos are longer on average for this 120 video playlist) of the [DSA Playlist for my job interviews](https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDzeHZWIZsTryvtXdMr6rPh4IDexB5NIA).

I took me a month to do it and that was all due to me simply not changing my ways, This is still much much better than 0 which is all I have done since beginning college and I do feel good in having made some progress. My aim is to do all 120 plus videos by the end of the month so that I can get a job I desire.

Action leads to more action......Excuses lead to more excuses.Both have their own momentum.- RSD Tyler

I cannot thank this place enough for being rude to me at times and pointing out that I was posting fluff and not actual progress. Here is a little bit of it, not a lot, not good but still a whole lot more than I likely would have done given my track record.

I aim to pull close to 100 kgs and finish the entire playlist by next month, hopefully have a job in hand too. I am in my final year of uni and my uni has firms visit us for jobs so am doing this just for that. Leetcode hard enough and you will get a job.

My low CGPA (6.79/10) is an issue so shall try to bump it up to 7 or above this year and get back to my NLP internship hopefully.

Also my stupid decisions did have their consequences and my brother is paying for it. My parents enrolled him into a third tier BCA(bachelors&#39; of computer applications, A bachelors degree in Computers that is laughed at by everyone for being a meme degree only taken by losers) at a local uni here in my hometown citing my own academic failures as they are extremely worried that if my brother performs like me, they can only get him to pass here and not outside at a better uni. I feel really bad. I am responsible for making the life of my entire family worse and likely permanently.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iirygg2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iirwh5v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In this moment, when I believe we&#39;ve seen peak-Woke, it may be interesting to lo</title><updated>2022-08-03T12:40:52Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In this moment, when I believe we&#39;ve seen peak-Woke, it may be interesting to log some pre-mortems.

In that vein, I ran across an [interesting article](https://mattgoodwin.substack.com/p/the-great-awokening-of-british-media) about the correlation of US and UK journalists in this process.

&amp;gt;it becomes clear that Britain’s media —once known for being much less moralistic and divisive than its American counterpart— is now undergoing the same Great Awokening.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In fact, if we compare America and Britain, as we do below, then we see that despite the two countries having entirely different histories of racism and discrimination, the trends now closely track one another. If anything, remarkably, British media now appears to devote more attention to these issues than their American counterparts.

This provides some support for the concept that the UK is a cultural colony of the US. Cultural hegemony is a hell of a drug.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;As concepts have become much looser, our national debate has become more divisive —ironically just as the country is becoming a much more tolerant, accepting, and welcoming place.

Guided by the beauty of our memetic superweapons....

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;The end result is a media that is simply socially constructing a very warped picture of the country we live in, which is playing an active role in driving the division.

This brings us back to my old hobbyhorse, which is that bigotry is essentially a conspiracy theory about the world that justifies (in the mind of the bigot) their insane hatreds and tactics. The parallels between things like anti-semitism and anti-white-supremacy pretty much write themselves. The construct that the world is rigged against \[decent people\] by the evil racist \[Other\] who is implacably hateful and infinitely destructive, and thus all extremism is \[self-defense\] is as old as group hatreds.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;This has also almost certainly been exacerbated by how media today has also become far more dependent on degree-holding journalists who have usually passed through elite private schools and universities (about 44% of Britain’s columnists went to one of only two universities —I will let you guess which)

This is directly another point of mine, which is that this whole woke thing has been primarily a revolt of the upper-class and the upwardly-mobile against the proles. The word games, the holier-than-thou moralizing, the vicious anger over the most minor of slights. This has been the attempt of the aspiring aristocracy to enact something very close to sumptuary laws. Instead of an appeal to their natural superiority or divine right, these neo-aristocrats claim immunity from criticism and a slate of special privileges based on their supposed disenfranchisement, poverty and victimization. Which is a bit rich coming from graduates of the most rarified schools in the world. Part of the ineradicable conflict of social justice was always that it was a top-down movement of and for the rich, connected and famous. A lot of other people jumped on the bandwagon, and even more just kept their heads down, but this is and has always been a movement driven intellectually by the upper classes.

&amp;gt;our new victimhood culture —which is especially strong in the elite institutions— instead incentivizes people to define themselves first and foremost as members of a victimised group, to derive their sense of social esteem, social status, and recognition from this status, and to punish, aggressively, perceived oppressors.

This is, for instance, why I think the obsession of the left over the last decade has been to ram the concept of &#34;self-identification&#34; through, and shut down any criticism. They need the concept because a pack of mostly-white, mostly-rich, mostly-straight and very well connected posh twats are running their mouths about &#34;social justice&#34;, and their identities don&#39;t give them enough protection in the progressive stack. Self-ID gives them an easy out! Anyone can be &#34;genderqueer&#34; or a &#34;nonpassing trans lesbian&#34;(also known as straight dudes). The profusion of sexual identities feeds a fundamental need for validation in the stack.

The movement was only viable so long as they could keep anyone from pointing out the Emperor&#39;s dick. That fundamental phenomenon may be coming to a close.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iirwh5v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiribg9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How many of you are non-[Positivists](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positivism)?</title><updated>2022-08-03T10:14:38Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How many of you are non-[Positivists](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positivism)?

I saw a [few](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihdw15n/) [posts](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihh363a/?context=3) getting stuck into /u/self_made_human&#39;s enthusiasm for posthuman life as an end in and of itself, rather than due to the risks involved. They seemed more popular than the post itself. I&#39;ll admit the way he expressed it was fairly enthusiastic and unambiguously attacked various holies like nature.

But is this disagreement substantive as opposed to aesthetic? It&#39;s reasonable to be sceptical of proposals promising massive political, economic, biological, neurological change. There are all kinds of problems with this, imbalances of power and so on. But I think there&#39;s also an aesthetic objection that comes before practical objections. See the fairly famous [comic](https://twitter.com/merryweatherey/status/1185636106257211392). 

It does appear fairly dystopian if everyone is just a lump of meat in a featureless, rusty pod. Dripped up like a drug addict, muscles wasting away, puddles of drool... The source of protein probably would be bugs or some synthetic cocktail. Connotations: pod, bugs, cattle, drug-addict, weakness, dependence, unreal.

If you reword self-made-human&#39;s proposal as calling for ultimate mastery over the universe so that everyone can do whatever they want, what&#39;s wrong with that? What about the will to power? What about moving ever forward as a technological civilization? What about the urge to climb mountains and conquer the stars?

Imagine instead that you&#39;re an ascended intelligence with a body that spans kilometres, absorbing the ferocious energies of the Sun for fuel, in a constant state of hyperawareness about the universe. You know more than our civilization, you think thoughts we can&#39;t even imagine. You&#39;re watching your neighbours if they try to infringe upon your million-trillionth of the Sun, armed and ready. You play, modify and return games with your friends. You&#39;re in discussion with all kinds of obscure communities, you&#39;re politically engaged in the debates about interstellar travel: who will get to take the next few stars? Connotations: immortal, celestial, inhuman but immensely powerful.

I bring up positivism because there is what I think is an aesthetically motivated backlash against positivism. I was talking with [/u/IG111](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiq0nl4/), who objected to 

&amp;gt;The real world is only a very complex technical environment with various parameters to optimize.

Isn&#39;t this the case? Don&#39;t we want to maximize fun (interpreted broadly as some combination of romantic love, good conversation, physical competition, intellectual activity)? Don&#39;t we want to maximize our power in the universe? Perhaps we don&#39;t know what parameters we want, perhaps our optimization ability is constrained and perverted by technical limitations. Perhaps we took one step forward and two steps back because of these limitations. But in principle, isn&#39;t optimizing the end-goal?

That seems to me to be the inevitable end goal of positivism. You use empirical experiments to acquire power and get what you want. There&#39;s been a reaction on the left away from positivism, that&#39;s where we got critical theory and the degrowth/anti-industrial wings of environmentalism. But there aren&#39;t many critical theorists on the motte. 

I think there&#39;s also been a movement on the right away from positivism, examples above. See:

&amp;gt;godless (metaphorically) science fiction version of paradise

&amp;gt;Nothing, they&#39;ll be stuck in a pod or chip doing nothing.

I think there&#39;s a bunch of right-coded concepts about the value of strength, personal sovereignty and hubris floating around that makes people object to certain cultural conceptions of the positivist vision (epitomized by the [comic](https://twitter.com/merryweatherey/status/1185636106257211392) above). Is this so? Or am I just bad at modelling?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiribg9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqr2lz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I see a lot of negativity directed online at Andrew Yang&#39;s new &#34;Forward Party&#34;, </title><updated>2022-08-03T04:38:44Z</updated><author><name>Unreasonable_Energy</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I see a lot of negativity directed online at Andrew Yang&#39;s new &#34;Forward Party&#34;, including some here on the The Motte, from the general perspective that &#34;obviously third parties can&#39;t work&#34;.  But it&#39;s easy to see that Yang, whatever else he may be, is not an *idiot* -- he must know the structural reasons why third parties can&#39;t gain traction in the American system.  So given that he&#39;s not an idiot, what is trying to achieve here?  What does he *say* he&#39;s trying to achieve, and how does he answer the obvious &#34;spoiler&#34; critique that everyone&#39;s making?

In this [interview with *The New Yorker*](https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/andrew-yangs-third-party-aspirations), Yang&#39;s asked:

&amp;gt; So the idea would be to get Democrats and Republicans to sign up for the Forward Party’s agenda, not to run candidates in the Forward Party to challenge Democrats and Republicans?

and replies

&amp;gt; Having someone run on the Forward Party line would be deeply impractical in the vast majority of districts around the country. We’re going to be supporting candidates who support these principles. I’m sure the vast majority of them are going to be running as Democrats or Republicans, because that’s much more realistic.

His response to the &#34;spoiler&#34; critique, then, is that his party is not, like a traditional political party, generally aiming to actually field potential-spoiler general-election candidates under the Forward Party banner.  It&#39;s more like an &#34;endorsement party&#34; -- a way to coordinate like-minded people around supporting major-party candidates who support certain principles.

But we already have organizations that exist to support major-party candidates without fielding their own -- interest groups create PACs and Super PACs.  Both are legally limited in influence -- PACs are limited in campaign expenditures, and Super PACs are limited by not being allowed to &#34;coordinate&#34; directly with campaigns.  

It sounds to me like Yang wants something like a Super PAC that&#39;s potentially able to coordinate with major-party campaigns, but he doesn&#39;t have a better legal structure than &#34;political party&#34; to operate under.  But what interest group wouldn&#39;t want to be able to start an organization like that?  If an interest group&#39;s forming a new party were a viable political strategy that somehow circumvented the limitations on PACs and Super PACs, why doesn&#39;t any given interest group start their own &#34;political party&#34;, that happens to not field candidates but only exists to direct support toward ideologically-aligned major-party candidates?  

I don&#39;t understand the relevant legal landscape here well enough to say, but it seems like Yang&#39;s project is suffering from people&#39;s assumptions about what a &#34;political party&#34; is supposed to do, when he&#39;s actually trying to create something else.  But if he&#39;s actually innovating some new variety of political organization, what&#39;s stopped other people from doing so in the past?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqr2lz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqqpw9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-03T04:35:20Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqqpw9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article2</title><updated>2022-08-03T03:21:34Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article263823143.html) (as of the time of this writing) of votes being counted it seems the attempt to amend Kansas&#39; constitution to clarify that it *does not* protect a fundamental right to abortion has **failed** 60-40. The amendment was a reaction to a [Kansas Supreme Court ruling](https://www.kscourts.org/KSCourts/media/KsCourts/Opinions/114153_2.pdf?ext=.pdf) from 2019 that found the Kansas constitution protected a fundamental right to abortion. This ruling required state regulations on abortion to overcome strict scrutiny to be constitutional. The [full text](https://sos.ks.gov/elections/22elec/2022-Primary-Election-Constitutional-Amendment-HCR-5003.pdf) of the amendment:

&amp;gt;Because Kansans value both women and children, the constitution of the state of Kansas does not require government funding of abortion and does not create or secure a right to abortion. To the extent permitted by the constitution of the United States, the people, through their elected state representatives and state senators, may pass laws regarding abortion, including, but not limited to, laws that account for circumstances of pregnancy resulting from rape or incest, or circumstances necessary to save the life of the mother.

As someone whose pro-choice I&#39;m encouraged by this result. The people of Kansas apparently prefer a constitutional right to abortion to having legislative control of it. I don&#39;t want to generalize this too far outside of this one race but it seems to indicate abortion may be a winning issue for Democrats.

ETA:

I didn&#39;t know about this when I wrote the above but something similar happened in Mississippi in [2011](https://ballotpedia.org/Mississippi_Initiative_26,_Definition_of_Person_Amendment_\(2011\)). Mississippi had a ballot initiative trying to amend their state constitution so that the definition of &#34;person&#34; would include &#34;every human being from the moment of fertilization.&#34; That amendment was defeated by a pretty similar margin (58-42).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiq9xjh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Late to the party: Best audiobooks you&#39;ve heard recently? I have some audible cr</title><updated>2022-08-03T02:14:45Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Late to the party: Best audiobooks you&#39;ve heard recently? I have some audible credits I need to burn so I can pause the subscription. I like classics, I like history, I&#39;d love something beach-read-y (listen-y?), I like long.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiq9xjh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiq99mq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] The new inflation bill says price controls are supposed to be handled by:

&amp;gt; </title><updated>2022-08-03T02:09:40Z</updated><author><name>netstack_</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">The new inflation bill says price controls are supposed to be handled by:

&amp;gt; ‘‘(6) The sharing with the Secretary of the
10 Treasury of such information as is necessary to determine the tax imposed by section 4192 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to enforcement of this part).

If that&#39;s referring to 26 USC § 4192, uh, [it was repealed in 1965](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/26/subtitle-D/chapter-32/subchapter-E).
I don&#39;t think this source is supposed to be a historical snapshot.
So where&#39;s the section?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiq99mq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iip8cht/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some thoughts on Artificial general intelligence.

[Econtalk recently had guest </title><updated>2022-08-02T21:46:39Z</updated><author><name>SomethingMusic</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some thoughts on Artificial general intelligence.

[Econtalk recently had guest Gerd Gigerenzer](https://www.econtalk.org/gerd-gigerenzer-on-how-to-stay-smart-in-a-smart-world/#read-comments) on how AGI is not nearly close to becoming a reality.  His blanket summary is that while computers can outperform humans in tasks, his example is Watson   winning Jeopardy, it failed miserably when being applied to other tasks such as diagnosing illnesses and creating treatments. AI thinking in probability and statistics while humans think in patterns and narratives.

&amp;gt;AlphaZero can beat every human in chess and Go, but it doesn&#39;t know that there is a game that&#39;s called chess or Go. A deep neural network, in order to learn, to distinguish pictures of, say school buses, from other objects on the street needs 10,000 pictures of school buses in order to learn that.

&amp;gt;If you have a four-year-old and point to a school bus, you may have to point another time, and then the kid has gotten it. It has a concept of a school bus.

&amp;gt;So, what I&#39;m saying: artificial intelligence, as in deep neural networks, has a very different kind of intelligence that does not resemble, much, human intelligence. Basically, to understand that deep neural networks are statistical machines that can do very powerful look for correlations. That&#39;s not the greatest ability of the human mind. We are strong in causal stories. We invent, we are looking for.

The biggest problem with AGI is not that it will think or imitate a human, but that a human believes that machines *are* thinking like humans.  Humanity is not just the external interaction between people, but also the internal thoughts, narratives, and emotions that go alongside these actions.

Despite this, we have significant needs for an AGI to be developed and deployed. There are more j[ob openings than there are employable people in the US](https://www.businessinsider.com/job-openings-june-jolts-labor-shortage-outlook-hiring-trends-quits-2022-8), and compounded with the decreased birth rate and a decreasing labor pool it will be harder and harder to fulfill these positions.  Likewise, an AGI could significantly [help secure food supply, as many parts of growing plants are still incredibly labor intensive](https://youtu.be/M2GIXU_WFC0?t=368).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iip8cht/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iip09be/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Sometime in the fall/winter of 2020-21, I made a ~~$200~~ $50 bet (to a charity </title><updated>2022-08-02T20:54:48Z</updated><author><name>iprayiam3</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Sometime in the fall/winter of 2020-21, I made a ~~$200~~ $50 bet (to a charity of choice) with someone here that there would still be Covid mask mandates 2 years later.


Unfortunately, this was made under iprayiam2, and as far as I can tell the original conversation is lost (at least my half of the conversation). Therefore, I can&#39;t and won&#39;t hold the original bet accountable, but I&#39;d love to know if the other party remembers our exchange.

The jist was something close to: 

*Between September 2022 and March 2023, there will be at least three different places within the US, which have a mask mandate policy at some point inside of that timeframe.*

I know it&#39;s a little early, but recent news about many schools renewing their mandates for the fall brought this to mind, and thus I am almost guaranteed I will win. (I even expect to win if you only include broader public mandates, but in either case, forcing public school children or folks on a college campus of public universities to comply surely counts anyway.)

Anyone remember making that bet with me?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iip09be/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiomw7g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What is the best resource/advice you have seen for how to negotiate a new job of</title><updated>2022-08-02T19:30:37Z</updated><author><name>Im_not_JB</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What is the best resource/advice you have seen for how to negotiate a new job offer?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiomw7g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinm4z4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So it looks like the PLA&#39;s [response](https://twitter.com/CGTNOfficial/status/15</title><updated>2022-08-02T15:41:54Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So it looks like the PLA&#39;s [response](https://twitter.com/CGTNOfficial/status/1554483299607023616) to Pelosi&#39;s Taiwan visit turned out to be [China&#39;s final warning](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China%27s_final_warning) after all. And Chinese social media is [not happy](https://twitter.com/003CarrierFan/status/1554479124726546432?cxt=HHwWgICwgeWhz5IrAAAA).

It seems that China currently lacks the amphibious capabilities to launch a full scale successful attack on Taiwan for the moment, but given the track record of the PLA&#39;s development, this capability *might* be achieved within 5 years. Xi cannot be seen as a toothless tiger however, I think he might attempt to capture an island in the Taiwan Strait to declare a moral victory. I&#39;m also wondering how this could impact Biden&#39;s approval at home if he&#39;s truly seen as standing up to China after humiliating failures in bringing the iron curtain down on Russia.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinm4z4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinlcsn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I wrote this blogpost explaining part of Curtis Yarvin&#39;s &#34;Cathedral&#34; critique in</title><updated>2022-08-02T15:36:58Z</updated><author><name>Kalcipher</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I wrote this blogpost explaining part of Curtis Yarvin&#39;s &#34;Cathedral&#34; critique in more-or-less rationalist terms.

[https://esotericmusings.substack.com/p/absolutist-primer-5](https://esotericmusings.substack.com/p/absolutist-primer-5)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinlcsn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iinihgc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Online banking security: how?

What are the actual, _realistic_ threats you have</title><updated>2022-08-02T15:18:52Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Online banking security: how?

What are the actual, _realistic_ threats you have to deal when banking through mobile apps? Is there real potential for half a mil to get transferred out of my brokerage account in five minutes because I was using a slightly too old version of android?

I&#39;m not worried about credit cards, because you have over a month to notice and take care of it. It&#39;s the idea of losing everything with no backsies that really spooks me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iinihgc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinbqkq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A minor (major?) culture war story from here in Australia.

---

Lidia Thorpe, a</title><updated>2022-08-02T14:34:47Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A minor (major?) culture war story from here in Australia.

---

Lidia Thorpe, an Australian Greens (Australia&#39;s progressive party) Senator representing Victoria in Federal Parliament, made [headlines during her swearing in ceremony by describing the Queen as a &#39;colonising Queen&#39; and raising a black power fist](https://www.smh.com.au/politics/federal/thorpe-s-coloniser-queen-oath-out-of-order-as-former-leaders-find-backbench-20220801-p5b6an.html) (apologies for the source, but basically no apolitical coverage exists). Eventually, she was told to retake the oath as written, which she did, but strongly protested. This incident became prominent in not just domestic Australian news, but made it into international news.

Lidia Thorpe is a Indigenous woman and activist, is no stranger to these kinds of controversy has been involved with various culture war issues in the past. She&#39;s a major provocateur, and a model progressive culture warrior.

---

Some debate has emerged over the truthfulness and validity of Thorpe&#39;s statement. Thorpe herself stated: &#34;It&#39;s a fact, it&#39;s truth. It&#39;s not something to get upset about... If people are hurt by truth, then we need to keep talking truth so we can get people on board and educate people.&#34;

On one hand, you can argue that her statement that the Queen is a coloniser isn&#39;t true because the Queen herself has personally done very little to actually colonise anyone. This is seems to be the form most mainstream pushback against Thorpe&#39;s statement is taking.

However, looking at Thorpe&#39;s statement in context of what else she said, she has a point. The Queen is the head of Australia, and Australia *is* a colonial state (or maybe post-colonial state), at least in the sense that Australia as a state is result of British settler colonialism, and it forms the foundational basis of our culture to this day.

I think the real issue is that Thorpe is breaking, probably intentionally, a unspoken agreement in Australian society, and Western liberal post-colonial society more broadly. I think the agreement goes something like this: don&#39;t call any of us individually, specifically colonists, racists, or other bad term, and we&#39;ll agree with you that those things are bad.

What Thorpe is doing is essentially putting her ideological opponents (which include mainstream politicians) in a double bind, and I believe she is very aware of what she is doing. Everyone has agreed that colonialism is a bad thing that we oppose. So when she accuses a prominent, respected and essential figure like the Queen of being a colonist, her opponents can either:

- Just deny any association between the Queen and colonialism. This is weak because it doesn&#39;t actually refute the arguments made by Thorpe and other progressives, which do have some legitimacy to them.

- Admit the Queen is a coloniser or otherwise concede to her point, which is basically agreeing the Queen (and Australia) is bad and illegitimate. Which no non-progressive politician actually wants to do, least of all because it delegitimises the very political system the politicians operate under.

What politicians *can&#39;t* do is say, &#39;yes we admit the Queen is a coloniser and Australia a colonial state, but *that&#39;s a good thing*&#39;. Well, outside of some far-right political pariahs like Pauline Hanson. But the more that Thorpe and other progressives pushes and prods and tries to break the unspoken post-colonial &#39;liberal agreement&#39; on topics like race and colonialism, the more I think people will eventually just say &#39;fuck it, you know what, I like Australia, colonialism is good, actually.&#39;

This story has a strong similarity to the issue of white identity and white racial consciousness in the US and the Western world. The unspoken liberal agreement for the last 50 or so years has been for whites to supress any white consciousness or identity, which has seemed to work reasonably successfully, as white rarely do think about themselves in racial terms compared to other ethnic groups. But this is changing as progressives are deliberately trying break the status quo and stoke white racial consciousness, albeit only in self-flagellating and guilt ridden form. But this runs the risk of white eventually saying &#39;enough, if you want me to be racially conscious, I will do it on my terms, I don&#39;t want feel guilty&#39; and becoming actual racists. I suppose the progressives would still see this as a win.

There was a similar story to this one a couple years ago in Canada where [NDP leader Jagmeet Singh called a Bloc Québécois MP racist in Canadian Parliament](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/ndp-jagmeet-singh-rota-racist-therrien-1.5616661). Singh was also breaking that unspoken agreement, I believe.

--- 

To conclude, one interesting thing I noticed about this news story is that there was no coverage of it by the ABC, our national public news broadcaster. At least, I can&#39;t find any articles about it on their website. The only national Australian public news [coverage I could find of it was from NITV](https://www.sbs.com.au/nitv/article/2022/08/02/senator-lidia-thorpe-makes-international-headlines-after-colonising-queen-oath), a publicly-funded Indigenous news and broadcaster, which was unsurprisingly strongly favourable to Thorpe. If you think the ABC&#39;s lack of coverage might be due them not wanting to report on &#39;culture war&#39; type topics, they were more than happy to [run a story a few days ago when Pauline Hanson, a far-right Federal Senator walked out during the acknowledgement of country](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-07-27/pauline-hanson-walkout-acknowledgement-of-country/101275080) (those statements which acknowledge land is stolen from Indigenous/First Nations/Native peoples).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinbqkq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iim3mt2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] America and Mexico have begun tø merge into one state. Austin is very white. I l</title><updated>2022-08-02T06:52:29Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">America and Mexico have begun tø merge into one state. Austin is very white. I live in Austin, and I spent a week in San Antonio. If you go there, it is Tejano culture 101. If you go there, it&#39;s 70% Mexicans or second gen Mexicans or rich white germans in the suburbs. Essentially everyone there is Mexican. I looked it up and it&#39;s 70% Hispanic, but if you go there it&#39;s 100% Tejano. The nicest hotels are French/Spanish/Mexican and incredibly beautiful. It is literally my favorite city outside of NYC and Chicago.

The great thing about San Antonio is it is essentially a foreign city in America. You will probably hear more Spanish than English there. It&#39;s basically a Mexican city in America.

It&#39;s probably the best argument against HBD because it is actually much cleaner than Austin and way better of a place to party.

But let us circle back. Everyone I know wants to move to Mexico. Mexico, Puerto Vallarta, etc. I know many people whop have moved there.

 When I was growing up, Mexico was considered a shit hole. I actually went to Mazatlan once and it was disgusting. It has now been gentrified and apparently Americans love living there.

Then we have Mexico City, which has become the new Brooklyn. Apparently it has an amazing art scene. Everyone I have talked to says Mexico city is the new Paris with tons of artists.

How will the world work when cities like Mexico City become full of rich Europeans and Americans? When Texas (which is absurdly wealthy) starts to blend with Mexico what is next? And if we are being honest, Mexicans are Catholic vs the Protestans in Texas?

What is next? It feels obvious. Mexico and America integrate further with Americans reversing the trend and moving to Mexico. And unlike Europe with Muslims, it&#39;s a bunch of people with similar culture.

It feels to me like Mexico will converge and be more like Canada in the future. In 50 years, Mexico will be like Canada and just another wealthy country on our border.

Am I crazy for thinking this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iim3mt2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iilcoqr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So last week Viktor Orban gave a controversial speech on &#34;race-mixing&#34; among oth</title><updated>2022-08-02T02:27:45Z</updated><author><name>EfficientSyllabus</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So last week Viktor Orban gave a controversial speech on &#34;race-mixing&#34; among other things. Here&#39;s the [complete official translation](https://miniszterelnok.hu/speech-by-prime-minister-viktor-orban-at-the-31st-balvanyos-summer-free-university-and-student-camp/), and [subtitled video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyNVFIo23Bg).

Summaries by [Hungarian portal 444](https://insighthungary.444.hu/2022/07/28/orban-causes-outrage-for-opposing-mixed-race-society-in-hungary), [the Guardian](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jul/24/viktor-orban-against-race-mixing-europe-hungary), [CNN](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/07/27/europe/viktor-orban-hungary-race-speech-intl/index.html).

&amp;gt; Migration has split Europe in two – or I could say that it has split the West in two. One half is a world where European and non-European peoples live together. These countries are no longer nations: they are nothing more than a conglomeration of peoples. I could also say that it is no longer the Western world, but the post-Western world. And around 2050, the laws of mathematics will lead to the final demographic shift: cities in this part of the continent – or that part – will see the proportion of residents of non-European origin rising to over 50 per cent of the total.

&amp;gt; In such a multi-ethnic context, there is an ideological feint here that is worth talking about and focusing on. The internationalist left employs a feint, an ideological ruse: the claim – their claim – that Europe by its very nature is populated by peoples of mixed race. This is a historical and semantic sleight of hand, because it conflates two different things. There is a world in which European peoples are mixed together with those arriving from outside Europe. Now that is a mixed-race world. And there is our world, where people from within Europe mix with one another, move around, work, and relocate. So, for example, in the Carpathian Basin we are not mixed-race: we are simply a mixture of peoples living in our own European homeland. And, given a favourable alignment of stars and a following wind, these peoples merge together in a kind of Hungaro-Pannonian sauce, creating their own new European culture. This is why we have always fought: we are willing to mix with one another, but we do not want to become peoples of mixed-race. [...] The time will come when we have to somehow accept Christians coming to us from there and integrate them into our lives. This has happened before; and those whom we do not want to let in will have to be stopped at our western borders – Schengen or no Schengen.

One long-term (20+ years) advisor of his, the sociologist Zsuzsa Hegedüs (who is Jewish herself) has stepped down after the speech and called it &#34;pure Nazi text worthy of Goebbels&#34;, due to such explicit references to &#34;race&#34; (&#34;faj&#34; in Hungarian).

Shortly after the speech people realized that it is almost verbatim from a 1973 book. In fact Orbán mentions the book just a bit before the above section:

&amp;gt; There is an outstanding 1973 book on this issue which was written in French, and recently published in Hungary. It is called “[The Camp of the Saints](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Camp_of_the_Saints)” [Le Camp des Saints], and I recommend it to anyone who wants to understand the spiritual developments underlying the West’s inability to defend itself.

The NYT wrote [an article](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/22/books/stephen-miller-camp-saints.html) on it in 2019: &#34;A Racist Book’s Malign and Lingering Influence - “The Camp of the Saints,” published in 1973, has been a must-read within white supremacist circles for decades. Stephen Miller, Marine Le Pen and Steve King have touted it in recent years.&#34;

Most of the above quoted speech section is from the intro of the book, including exact phrases like &#34;historical and semantic sleight of hand&#34;. Orbán(&#39;s speech writers) basically just swapped the &#34;Gallo-Roman sauce&#34; of the original French book with &#34;Hungaro-Pannonian sauce&#34;.

Common directions of criticism were 1) that Hungarians are also mixed, no population is racially pure, 2) Hungarians came from Asia, 3) it&#39;s biologically inaccurate to talk about &#34;faj&#34; (=&#34;race&#34;, &#34;species&#34;) regarding humans.

Interestingly, or not, back in 2012, Orbán also called Hungarians &#34;half-Asian&#34; ([HU source](https://24.hu/belfold/2012/07/26/orban-veszekedos-felazsiai-nep-a-magyar/)):

&amp;gt; &#34;My philosophy is that unity is a question of strength: if there is strength, there is unity,&#34; he said. There are other ways of forging unity - for example, in the Scandinavian countries - but he believes that the Hungarians are incapable of doing so. &#34;That&#39;s the only way it works with half-Asian derivatives like us. Here everyone is clever, everyone knows better, everyone has a better idea,&#34; he said.

[Turanism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turanism) and emphasizing cultural or other relations to Turkic peoples have been common over the last ~150 years on the conservative right wing in Hungary. So how does this add up? Not so well, because the text was essentially taken out of a French nationalist context, and it doesn&#39;t fit so well. The actual far-righters in Hungary, like the Our Homeland Movement have been talking about a &#34;Northern Civilization&#34; (&#34;from the Celts all the way to the Japanese&#34;) instead of Western for some time now, exactly for this reason, and I guess as a way to get closer to the Russian far-right vision of Dugin&#39;s Eurasianism.

So saying that Hungarians came from Asia misses the point (well, it&#39;s arguable anyway in a modern genetic sense, and even if so, the origin was near the Urals, the border of Europe). Orbán and the far right&#39;s problem is with Africans and Middle Eastern Muslims.

He has since stated that his speech may have been misunderstandable, and he actually just meant cultural differences, not biological. But the word &#34;race&#34; was unusually blunt even for Orbán. He usually talks in terms of religion (Christianity vs Islam) or cultures and civilizations, not races. In fact, the Hungarian word he used (&#34;faj&#34;) is now quite taboo in this sense, today it&#39;s only used in the meaning of &#34;species&#34; (of animals or plants). Another common criticism came from this angle: that humanity is one species, *Homo sapiens*. This is a very shallow criticism but apparently many felt that it&#39;s some kind of gotcha, that Orbán doesn&#39;t even know basic biology and doesn&#39;t understand the concept of &#34;species&#34;. Except that &#34;faj&#34; used to be a much broader term, for stuff like ethnicity, nationality, race, species etc.

Zooming out a bit, it&#39;s clear that Orbán loves the kind of attention that these speeches give him. It&#39;s like antifragility, he thrives on being demonized and gets stronger each time when he survives these. So, since there was a possibility of difficulties at home (due to economic problems, they can&#39;t keep to their election promises just a few months after their re-election), he decided to cause some controversy so he can again frame things in this way, that all conflict with the EU ultimately stems from the issues of migration, gender, Soros etc. That&#39;s his home turf, that&#39;s the lens he wants on everything.

On Thursday, Orbán [will speak at CPAC Texas in Dallas](https://www.newsweek.com/von-der-leyen-rips-orban-over-mixed-race-speech-cpac-still-welcoming-him-1729399), to the outrage of American media.

So, 1) Most of this wasn&#39;t even Orbán&#39;s own ideas but took it verbatim from a book, 2) The reaction to it was lazy criticism, the nth iteration of calling Orbán a fascist or feigning ignorance about meanings of words or performatively not understanding that by other races Orbán meant Africans and Middle Easterners, not Uralic Asians. 3) Orbán needed nothing other than exactly that, to be criticized for his stance on migration and gender instead of utility price hikes and tax raises.

So is he a racist? It doesn&#39;t matter because this is post-politics. People perform to get reactions, it&#39;s not about beliefs. A prominent journalist from Orbán&#39;s circles, Zsolt Bayer (shown [here](https://nepszava.hu/3162052_nemeth-szilard-bayer-zsolt-alsoors-rasszizmus-polo-fenykep) with a Secretary of State) wore a &#34;white lives matter&#34; T-shirt just a few weeks ago. It&#39;s hard to tell what one should interpret as sincere opinions (if that&#39;s even possible for a politician to have) versus pure posturing. But it&#39;s mostly just two sides symbiotically needing each other to justify themselves.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iilcoqr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought w</title><updated>2022-08-01T23:33:25Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought were pretty optimistic in Ukraine&#39;s favor; turns out I was too pessimistic. 

Russia is hauling out the museum piece 152&#39;s from the 1920&#39;s for second line units; the tempo of their advance and quantity/quality of artillery fire has dropped off way quicker (Like, an order of magnitude quicker) than I thought it would.

Apparently, the HIMARS shoot and scoot has been working. Ukraine can&#39;t push Russia where they are strong; but Russia can&#39;t advance along an entire front anymore without taking unsafe risks.

This on top of Ukrainian counteroffensives in Kherson; and (maybe? Questionably?) drama amongst the Russians staff running the war (apparently the two top guys hate each other, and refuse to allow one to be elevated over the other.  Water cooler shit though, so who knows.)

Basically: I predicted slow Russian advance for some time until their logistical problems caught up to them and they couldn&#39;t just atomize their problems with a zillion guns, then a frozen front until some political solution was reached or Russia got their economy in gear; which was wrong.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iikjjz1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] how do I tell radical leftists that their idea of centrism as a facist-allied pa</title><updated>2022-08-01T22:51:17Z</updated><author><name>SomewhatEmbarassed</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">how do I tell radical leftists that their idea of centrism as a facist-allied passivity is inherently intolerant of any views different from their own</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iikjjz1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijr0wh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I spoke with a researcher who will go by &#34;Alex Datepsych.&#34; out of Spain, on dati</title><updated>2022-08-01T19:43:45Z</updated><author><name>Pongalh</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I spoke with a researcher who will go by &#34;Alex Datepsych.&#34; out of Spain, on dating, inceldom and related topics for those who may be interested. [Part 1](https://youtu.be/frw7mi-reRA). [Part 2](https://youtu.be/JcDBxBaEPEQ).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Per the details on my YouTube page, in Part 1 we touch on the deracinated dating pov of the isolated, profilicity (ala philosopher Hans-Georg Moeller), AWALT (&#34;All Women Are Like That&#34;), MGTOW, the all-that-matters-are-looks blackpilled MRAs, and hilarious old school pickup artist &#34;Mystery.&#34;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

In Part 2 we discuss the racial composition of incels; &#34;Just Be White&#34;; the relationship between income, job type and infidelity; and the impact of remote work and pandemic on singles vs. marrieds.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[Here is Alex&#39;s website](https://datepsychology.com/).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijr0wh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The </title><updated>2022-08-01T17:57:40Z</updated><author><name>PutAHelmetOn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The comparison isn&#39;t motivated by &#34;haha look at how ridiculous these people are,&#34; it&#39;s specifically around reframing the following:

&amp;gt;Everyone has a gender identity, but most people are [cis by default](https://thingofthings.wordpress.com/2015/01/28/cis-by-default/)

To something more like:

&amp;gt;The genderqueer community is comprised of people who have gender identities, which may involve wearing clothing of their preferred gender... A small minority of them express a desire to become, or already see themselves as, their gender

Since I&#39;ve just committed analogy in the first degree, I expect the low-decouplers to be out in full force, so here are a few objections I foresee:

Possible counter: &#34;Well, most people don&#39;t have a fursona but most people do have a gender identity&#34;. Reply: I think both parts (before &amp;amp; after the &#39;but&#39;) are potentially wrong:

* Don&#39;t most people have a &#34;human by default&#34; fursona?
* Do most people *actually* have a gender identity?

To expand on (2): the language around gender identity is maximally confusing. 

As an example, I posed the question &#34;do you have a gender identity? what is it?&#34; to my dad and he said &#34;of course I&#39;m a male.&#34; despite not knowing what LGBTQ activists really think about gender identity. If two people say &#34;my gender identity is man&#34; that **does not mean they are really saying the same thing.** A less confusing language would be to call gender identity a &#34;fnord&#34; and then my dad would realize that he has no idea what a &#34;fnord&#34; is, just that it is something controversial.

Possible counter: &#34;this is not how people use the words &#39;fursona&#39; and &#39;gender identity&#39;&#34; to which I reply: this is missing the point. I am engaging in prescriptivism here, and I&#39;m claiming that speaking as if normal people have gender identity \[the way activists mean it\] is misleading. That activists enthusiastically say it&#39;s OK that gender identity means different things to different people makes me think this confusing language is intentional.

How should I react to a furry telling me my fursona was a human? I would probably tell him I&#39;m not a furry, sorry, not for me, but good for you. Should my reaction to activists asking me about my gender identity be any different? &#34;Sorry, not for me.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of com</title><updated>2022-08-01T16:08:28Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of compulsive browsing in my life has led me to see clearly how one&#39;s mind adapts to the things he interacts with. Social media seems to be the way things are because I use it, not because it is the way things are. Browsing seems like an effective means of getting information because it&#39;s the most present way that I&#39;m exposed to information, not because it is an effective means of getting information. And it&#39;s the most present way because something went wrong between the human-computer interaction.

I feel the need for something more compatible with this zen state of not hating everything. Even the things I actually care about are slipping away from my life unless I take the effort to hurt myself by reading garbage, so maybe I need something better.

Hopefully there are recognizable classics out there? Looking for anything: theories about interfaces, how to manage users, inside stories like that one about how they designed r/place...especially looking for ones that widely influenced the current industry, however annoyingly mainstream they are, and also any academic tomes that are well put together. The best I&#39;ve found is [this](https://www.researchgate.net/post/Any-good-books-about-designing-social-media) link, but everything else seems to be about marketing on social media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American R</title><updated>2022-08-01T13:20:01Z</updated><author><name>TheCoachSpo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American Right might be moving in. Tons of interviews, speeches, etc from prominent conservatives suggesting that it would be best for America to embrace Christian Nationalism. This raised some alarms; there is strong research connecting Evangelicals to conspiracies such as QAnon (among others) that could eventually lead to danger or even violence (ex: Jan 6th, the 26% of W. Evangelicals who &#34;agree that true American patriots might have to resort to violence in order to save our country.&#34; - PRRI).   
My question: How much of a threat does the Christian Right pose to American democracy and peace? A shrinking demographic who may believe they are losing their country, when paired with their renowned civic activism and news media that reinforces their increasingly conspiratorial beliefs, might just be the recipe for outbreaks of political violence. Needless to say, this trend of the Christian Right has me sincerely concerned.

I also want to quickly get out there that [Gordon Wood](https://moodle2.units.it/pluginfile.php/366505/mod_resource/content/1/Conspiracy%20and%20the%20Paranoid%20Style.pdf) and [Richard Hofstadter](https://harpers.org/archive/1964/11/the-paranoid-style-in-american-politics/) did some pretty well-known work on American/Colonial paranoia, suggesting that the colonists (many of whom had strong religious ties) viewed history as moments caused by individual actors rather than a stream of events. This allows them to attribute moral responsibility to bad actors and in doing so reveals how the good deed/bad deed doctrine of many Christian denominations might make believers more susceptible to conspiracy theories. After all, conspiracies are based on an idea that a small cabal of people are plotting something nefarious, like the Hellish plot of #PizzaGate.  
Woods suggested that this &#34;individual actor&#34; thinking still runs strong in American veins. If so, am I being overdramatic in [this short essay](https://coachspo.substack.com/p/an-american-conspiracy-movement-that) where I claim that Christian Right conspiracies pose a significant threat to American safety?  
A helpful recap of my essay: &#34;I believe there are warning signs around us. The size of the Religious Right is perpetually underrated in America and they are adopting conspiracy theories at a startling pace. What’s more, these theories are dangerous precisely because they promote the idea that White Christians are losing their status and identity. As Professor Walter proposed, when this happens the chance that a nation falls into violence or a Civil War only increases. Perhaps it was no coincidence that during the Insurrection the “Heavenly Father” was prayed to on the senate floor.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/154969215336</title><updated>2022-08-01T12:56:52Z</updated><author><name>Tophattingson</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/1549692153365991424), over the past four years, and particularly over the last two, opinions on trans issues have moved rightward (for lack of a better term) in the UK. The few positions that didn&#39;t move rightward relate to needing doctor&#39;s approval to legally change gender, or not requiring living as your new gender to legally change gender. However, these are two that were already very unpopular, and remain very unpopular, just slightly less, so it may represent changes only within the segment of the population that is very pro trans rights becoming even more pro.

I&#39;ve long suspected (or had as a concern) that existing legislation and institutional support for trans people, changes largely done out of the public eye, is only sustainable via obscurantism. That is to say, if the wider public knew how far the UK had already gone on this topic, that they&#39;d want to roll it back, and the only reason they&#39;re not rolling it back is because they don&#39;t know. Between high-profile trans people in sports, and the escalation of activism in general, they are now increasingly noticing and not liking it. The real nuclear button on this would be treating refusing to date trans people as transphobic, [because the overwhelming majority of people will refuse to date them.](https://www.researchgate.net/publication/325490626_Transgender_exclusion_from_the_world_of_dating_Patterns_of_acceptance_and_rejection_of_hypothetical_trans_dating_partners_as_a_function_of_sexual_and_gender_identity)

This survey result is certainly interesting. It also counters the idea that there&#39;s an ever-leftward drift on all social issues.

As a side not, I&#39;d be interested if anyone can approximate &#34;what percent of the UK&#39;s population would be banned from twitter / other social media if they were to clearly state their views on trans&#34; from the full survey results.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female</title><updated>2022-08-01T11:48:56Z</updated><author><name>Athanasius_19</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female representation among police officers to 30%](https://30x30initiative.org/about-30x30/)

&amp;gt; The 30×30 Initiative is based on the importance of achieving at least 30% representation to empower a group to influence an organization’s culture. This 30% threshold is where change begins to happen, but it is not our end goal. 30×30 is working with policing agencies to improve recruiting practices and establish community partnerships so that agencies become truly representative of the jurisdictions they serve. While 30×30 is focused on advancing women in policing, these principles are applicable to all demographic diversity, not just gender.

The website claims that women are better suited for police work, since &#34;women officers use less force and less excessive force; are named in fewer complaints and lawsuits; are perceived by communities as being more honest and compassionate; see better outcomes for crime victims, especially in sexual assault cases; and make fewer discretionary arrests.&#34;

They cite intersectionality as a cornerstone of the project, and several big police departments are listed as participating in this initiative. There are a few companies and activist groups backing it, including Microsoft. There&#39;s also a &#34;steering committee&#34; with a bunch of names I don&#39;t recognize, and would&#39;ve skipped over until I noticed that all of them are women.

Thoughts on how this would affect police relations and effectiveness? My prediction is that police work will slightly improve in safer communities, but that in more dangerous areas there will be a negative effect towards more crime, since crime rates aren&#39;t something the page mentions outright.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihhuxc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There is a group of specialists in Germany that work on designing signage/Symbol</title><updated>2022-08-01T08:48:11Z</updated><author><name>thatnoisy</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There is a group of specialists in Germany that work on designing signage/Symbols that can communicate to people 1 million years from now. The reason for that is the government&#39;s requirement that radioactive waste must be stored securely for 1 million years at least. This seems silly to me. 

Yes radioactive waste is no laughing matter but are we really so concerned about hypothetical people in the far future digging up some barrels of (by then) mildly radioactive debris? This is assuming that A Humans still exist and B They lost the ability to produce Geiger counters. Really what pushes this into hypocrisy territory to me is that we actively don&#39;t give a shit about real actual humans right now. We could feed and shelter homeless people with the money that we&#39;re using to pay these historians and linguists. I just don&#39;t get it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihhuxc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iigbkjf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there a sub with an ongoing discussion of the continuing takeover of /r/scien</title><updated>2022-08-01T01:13:45Z</updated><author><name>SunRaSquarePants</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there a sub with an ongoing discussion of the continuing takeover of /r/science with &#34;social science&#34; political agenda posts?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iigbkjf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iifwx1y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] The main CW thread seems to be roughly half as many comments as usual, any specu</title><updated>2022-07-31T23:14:38Z</updated><author><name>exiledouta</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">The main CW thread seems to be roughly half as many comments as usual, any speculation as to why?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iifwx1y/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat </title><updated>2022-07-31T18:49:40Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat hackers in the 90s. It&#39;s nice to read such a close account of something that I&#39;ve only vaguely heard of in news reports. So far Par&#39;s story has been gripping and sympathetic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iie1yph/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What’s the issue/position that you’ve most recently changed your mind on?

I&#39;ll </title><updated>2022-07-31T15:13:45Z</updated><author><name>Just_Natural_9027</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What’s the issue/position that you’ve most recently changed your mind on?

I&#39;ll start with saying each and everyday I am more convinced that ignorance is bliss particular with regards to political and culture war discourse.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iie1yph/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidzg8g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Not sure if it matches the typical Sunday question thread theme, but I&#39;ll be vis</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:55:36Z</updated><author><name>margotsaidso</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Not sure if it matches the typical Sunday question thread theme, but I&#39;ll be visiting San Diego for a few days. Anyone have recommendations for must-see things or something off the beaten path to check out?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidzg8g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especiall</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:26:54Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especially related to reinforcement, learning type stuff, more advanced than basic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidoauk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there anything stopping Elon Musk from just buying Twitter stock at the marke</title><updated>2022-07-31T13:29:22Z</updated><author><name>zataomm</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there anything stopping Elon Musk from just buying Twitter stock at the market price before he potentially loses his lawsuit?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidoauk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies </title><updated>2022-07-31T13:27:10Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies to society or morality, or at least that&#39;s the best way I can think to describe it. I realise I&#39;m treading philosophical old ground here but it is something I&#39;ve been thinking about recently.

In the Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma, and the Tragedy of the Commons etc, we have the general case of rational individual actions leading to negative outcomes for everyone.

What this really reminds me of egoist, classical realist, amoral (individualist, even) philosophy, perhaps best exemplified by Machiavelli&#39;s *The Prince*. That is generally a purely self interested individual with no concern for the common good. But there is a glaring issue with Machiavellian philosophy. No one would ever want to work under the Prince, over him or with him, because he would betray you in a heartbeat, and would be constantly looking for opportunities to undermine you for his own benefit. If everyone took Machiavelli&#39;s advice and acted like the perfect Prince, there could be no society. Everyone would just be continuously trying to screw each other over, there can be no true cooperation or common good.

This has kind of given me the idea of a kind of &#39;social parasitism&#39; (yes I am aware of the association of the term with Soviet political prisoners - I using it in an different sense. It&#39;s an apt label here). Machiavelli&#39;s Prince is basically a &#39;social parasite&#39;, in the sense benefiting himself while harming society and others generally. Just like an actual biological parasite, the social parasite needs the host (&#39;society&#39;) to thrive, yet if there are too many social parasite, it will leech too much off the host and kill society and itself (metaphorically), causing society to devolve into chaos and bloody anarchy. The Prince can only exist by exploiting the system he is ultimately undermining by his actions.

If I can think of any benefit that the Prince might provide to society, it might be if there is only one who gains supreme power and thus could theoretically rule competently (after all, this was the original intent for the Prince. But that requires there to only ever be one and only one Prince or would-be Prince. (Maybe you could use this as justification for some kind of elitism)

Sociopaths are essentially naturally this, amoral and a callous disregard for others, only concerned with their own benefit, abusing others trust. But too many sociopaths would cause everyone to become distrustful and thus collapsing the whole system that sociopaths love to exploit.

In some sense, I think this also applies to the constantly debated mistake vs conflict theory around here, with conflict theory obviously representing social parasitism. Conflict theorists can make easy gains by exploiting unassuming mistake theorists, but too much conflict results in dysfunction and collapse of social institutions which the conflict theorists are trying to overtake in the first place. The mistake theorists are the ones actually trying to solve issues, after all. I also wonder if there&#39;s a conflict theorist Schelling point, where the number of conflict theorists reaches critical mass, they create more problems than mistake theorists can solve, so mistake theorists are left with a choice, to either: become a conflict theorists and try to grab whatever resources are around before the collapse, or &#34;die&#34; a mistake theorist. (e.g. a previously principled scientist becoming politicized to secure his job even if it undermines the integrity and value of said job).

This is obviously not a new observation, but then moral systems (historically religions) primarily exist as enforcement mechanism, as a means to dissuade people from becoming social parasites. It&#39;s the Mafia don in the Prison&#39;s Dilemma who threatens the prisoners to keep their mouths shut.

I guess another question is, does social parasitism exist in mostly stable or unstable equilibrium? Does the system tend towards a sustainable number of social parasites, only forced out of balance by extreme external events? Or is there a natural, cyclical boom-bust pattern, where increasing social parasitism will ultimately destroy institutions, and mistake theorists will have to build new institutions from scratch before the cycle repeats.

Maybe I&#39;m looking at it backwards. Maybe the conflict theorists surge *after* the collapse of an institution, rushing to pick at the scraps like a vulture collecting carrion. Attempting to carve out a little niche for themselves, while stunting the ability for mistake theorists to rebuild. Maybe this is what we are seeing with the death of God, decaying social cohesion, and the attempt to establish some new common morality again.

Yeah I don&#39;t really know where I&#39;m going with this. I would like to hear everyone else&#39;s thoughts on this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiczkhv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] When looking at an url for a potentially sketchy website, which end should I be </title><updated>2022-07-31T08:35:29Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When looking at an url for a potentially sketchy website, which end should I be looking at- the front or the back?   
In other words, the     

&amp;gt;www.microsoft...    

or the     

&amp;gt;...microsoft.com/    

?    

I&#39;m assuming at least one end can show legitimacy at a glance. I saw [this gif](https://i.redd.it/sgp2jxdqmte91.gif) recently and got curious.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiczkhv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicun3i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] For our Russian posters:

How are things in Russia for the average person? How&#39;s</title><updated>2022-07-31T07:29:07Z</updated><author><name>S18656IFL</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">For our Russian posters:

How are things in Russia for the average person? How&#39;s the mood? How&#39;s the personal economy? 

There are a lot of numbers floating around but they often fail to communicate how things are on the ground.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicun3i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicqf8c/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there a term for deep happiness and fulfilment spiked with the bitter knowled</title><updated>2022-07-31T06:34:26Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there a term for deep happiness and fulfilment spiked with the bitter knowledge that this too shall pass, sic transit gloria mundi, memento mori, remember you are dust?
  
These days I feel like I&#39;ve achieved nearly all of my life goals, but I&#39;m pained with the knowledge that I can&#39;t stay in this particular stage of my life forever.  The summer of my life will one day end, and I&#39;ll pass into autumn and winter.  There&#39;s a bittersweet beauty to how transient life is and how fleeting moments of fulfillment are.  It&#39;s both pleasurable and painful, like just the right amount of DOMS after a good workout.  I wish I were more poetic or artistic so I could express the sensation better than this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicqf8c/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iicjaqt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Crazy story about a property developer in LA whose hubris led to bankruptcy and </title><updated>2022-07-31T05:11:28Z</updated><author><name>bulksalty</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Crazy story about a property developer in LA whose hubris led to bankruptcy and a swanky mansion.  

https://archive.ph/5pncd

Chalk up another tale that reminds me that property development seems like an absolutely insane business.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iicjaqt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iibil29/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anyone use decentralized apps?

I&#39;ve poked around again and the survivors o</title><updated>2022-07-30T23:54:27Z</updated><author><name>slothlikesamwise</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anyone use decentralized apps?

I&#39;ve poked around again and the survivors of the big boom a few years ago seems to be Dat protocol and IPFS. Any cool uses for them that aren&#39;t just filesharing?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iibil29/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iian6cu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Looking for gaming suggestions:

1. Has progression elements. Buying upgrades, g</title><updated>2022-07-30T19:53:52Z</updated><author><name>cjet79</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Looking for gaming suggestions:

1. Has progression elements. Buying upgrades, gaining experience, etc.
2. Has skill elements. Like an FPS, action rpg, or some other game that requires some skill.
3. You can become God like. By the end of it I want my cumulative game skill and upgrades to make the game stupidly easy. Slaughtering foes without a thought, and only the hardest of bosses presenting the slightest challenge.

I can find plenty of games with the first two elements. It&#39;s the third element that is difficult to find.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iian6cu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii6wb1t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Anybody got any genius miracle cures for &#34;brain fog&#34;?

I can&#39;t explain why but i</title><updated>2022-07-29T23:08:53Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Anybody got any genius miracle cures for &#34;brain fog&#34;?

I can&#39;t explain why but it feels like screen time might be the culprit so might try to limit that since it is the weekend</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii6wb1t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii63rde/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Yesterday, I switched to a new Internet provider and got decent speed. Not coinc</title><updated>2022-07-29T19:47:34Z</updated><author><name>netstack_</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Yesterday, I switched to a new Internet provider and got decent speed. Not coincidentally I also reinstalled *League of Legends* for a few rounds with my brother.

It’s popular enough that this kind of gets taken for granted, but the premise is really clever.
On one hand, there’s the distillation of an RPG into each game: do tasks, numbers go up, steer the character to a style you want. There’s a balance between fundamental gameplay loops to improve and broader game *knowledge* to accrue. On the other is the pure PvP aspect using humans as a seed to keep things fresh.

But what really gets me is the specialization. I like a game which gives a specific job, a part of the machine. You get to play to strengths and watch the whole thing come together. And *League* does this better than a lot of games.

Anyone care to share recommendations in this “specialist” genre?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii63rde/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii60d0o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anybody have a link to Yarvin&#39;s essay that covers why he thinks modern poet</title><updated>2022-07-29T19:24:51Z</updated><author><name>SeeeVeee</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anybody have a link to Yarvin&#39;s essay that covers why he thinks modern poetry sucks?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii60d0o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5ks9g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What are your go-to hotel chains, where you always feel like you get good servic</title><updated>2022-07-29T17:41:43Z</updated><author><name>eBenTrovato</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What are your go-to hotel chains, where you always feel like you get good service, a clean room, and your full money’s worth? i.e., what’s the Chick-Fil-A of hotels?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5ks9g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight F</title><updated>2022-07-29T17:24:38Z</updated><author><name>DWXXV</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight Further

In 1997 a little game came out called “Final Fantasy 7.” You may have heard of it. The game is wildly influential, often considered one of the best games of all time…and has aged like moderately fine vinegar. If you weren’t active in gaming at the time it’s hard to overstate the influence of the game. It was fantastic, for many people it changed what they thought games were capable of, and one of the spoilers was for decades afterwards (although less so now) was often uttered along with “Vader, father” as one of the top spoilers of all time.

A big part of the game was the music. Nobuo Uematsu and the rest of the sound team had been doing fantastic work with severe technical limitations for ten years at that point, and some of the music from this era transcends videogaming to become some of the best music period (I’d argue Chrono Trigger for this one). Uematsu loved progressive rock, and while he was excellent at classical compositions he loved to inject a flavor that was rare at the time into his music. Compare Dragon Quest with the average Final Fantasy battle theme. 

The music of FF 7 was fantastic. “One Winged Angel” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ce7gVYs7Em0) is still considered one of if not the best compositions in gaming. “Bombing Mission” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VCcSmvGrGx8) can be unironically (and has been) performed by a massive orchestra. 

Excellent battle tracks have always been a tradition in JRPGs, since you’ll be hearing a lot of them, and in the old days you had to stretch one track for almost all the fights in the game.

The battle track for FF 7 is “Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DotavimguEU). Limitations in fan translation resources and official releases resulted in this being generally translated (literally) as “Those Who Fight” if you wanted to pirate a MIDI and listen to it on a Walkman or something like that. Sometimes it would be translated as “Fighting” and later, official releases would land on “Let the Battles Begin!”

It’s fine. Not the best FF has done, but it wouldn’t get that stale for most people. Most encounters are short anyway.

Not so for boss battles. The boss battle theme needs to be a banger, especially in a game that mostly uses one theme for all the bosses.

AND IT FUCKING IS.  

“Sara ni Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z_GUWdkJQgw) is still excellent, if limited by the technology of the time. Translated literally as “Those Who Fight Further” and occasionally as “Still More Fighting” the song often appears in top FF battle music lists. Later official translations would label it “Fight On!” which I think is a shame since it loses the character of the initial battle/boss battle names. Listening to it now you can tell that something great is hidden in this track limited by technology.

And we’ll get there.

In the years since the initial release FF 7 has remained influential. The music has been remixed thousands of times, it’s been a fixture in orchestral video game concerts, and Nobuo even made a metal band that plays some of these songs (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NzFh9GuE0rA). Gamers have been clamoring for a remake of the game. In 2020 they got it.

The game is controversial for reasons we won’t get into, but the music is not. With a massive team including the original composer they made a truly next gen sound track for a next gen game. Fans had some trepidation, these songs had been remixed by the community, professional composers, and the man himself tons of times. What were they going to do?

Well the answer was use everything learned about these songs and game composition over the last 20+ years. The soundtrack is absurdly good. From modern takes like an atmospheric exploration theme that turns into a battle theme when a fight starts (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5S49M40hv4) , to taking a one note joke enemy and turning it into an absurd and energetic boss battle (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQgXZ2HDiCQ). The game has everything.

The original battle theme still lives all over the game (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lu-dHQxxv4w), with variations to fit the mood and location of interest. But they hold back on the boss battle music. Yeah it shows up at the end of the first chapter (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AdGOnPsE-Xs). And it’s good. But is this it? Is this the epic remix?

No.

At the end of chapter 7 you fight a boss that was pretty much a joke in the original game. The fight is epic. And this fucking plays (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cQDLBKpbXQU). It has everything. I challenge you to drive the speed limit with this on. They held back, made you think they pretty whiffed on the remix for the boss theme, but they fucking stuck the landing. 

The rest of the soundtrack has some damn good tracks, but nothing injected nostalgia directly into my veins like The Airbuster. 

Never forget how powerful music can be.

Thank you for coming to my Ted Talk.

DW out. 

Anyone who has anything they want to add or correct is welcome!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii4mf7k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] /u/2cimarafa Did you ever find that subreddit about obscure test taking? Seemed </title><updated>2022-07-29T13:58:25Z</updated><author><name>margotsaidso</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">/u/2cimarafa Did you ever find that subreddit about obscure test taking? Seemed like a great Friday Fun Thread topic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii4mf7k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3sijm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I am really enjoying the new army logistics series on aCoUP: https://acoup.blog/</title><updated>2022-07-29T09:03:26Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I am really enjoying the new army logistics series on aCoUP: https://acoup.blog/2022/07/29/collections-logistics-how-did-they-do-it-part-ii-foraging/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3sijm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3jab4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recently for the first time, I tried alcohol. The high was really pleasurable an</title><updated>2022-07-29T07:02:53Z</updated><author><name>DandyPandemonium</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recently for the first time, I tried alcohol. The high was really pleasurable and I felt extremely guilty about the hedonistic behaviour. It&#39;s only for this reason that I was hesitant about trying an inebriating substance, afraid that I might get addicted. But, any suggestions for fun activity/activities while being high, preferably something eye opening? I usually just listen to tool and other metal songs on shuffle and go into a peaceful zone.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3jab4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3exax/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [two Bay Area meetups in August](https://sonya.substack.com/p/august-2022-picnic</title><updated>2022-07-29T06:12:02Z</updated><author><name>sonyaellenmann</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[two Bay Area meetups in August](https://sonya.substack.com/p/august-2022-picnics) that are perhaps of interest to the rest of you dorks as well &amp;lt;3</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3exax/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>