<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-02T02:27:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iilcoqr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So last week Viktor Orban gave a controversial speech on &#34;race-mixing&#34; among oth</title><updated>2022-08-02T02:27:45Z</updated><author><name>EfficientSyllabus</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So last week Viktor Orban gave a controversial speech on &#34;race-mixing&#34; among other things. Here&#39;s the [complete official translation](https://miniszterelnok.hu/speech-by-prime-minister-viktor-orban-at-the-31st-balvanyos-summer-free-university-and-student-camp/), and [subtitled video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyNVFIo23Bg).

Summaries by [Hungarian portal 444](https://insighthungary.444.hu/2022/07/28/orban-causes-outrage-for-opposing-mixed-race-society-in-hungary), [the Guardian](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jul/24/viktor-orban-against-race-mixing-europe-hungary), [CNN](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/07/27/europe/viktor-orban-hungary-race-speech-intl/index.html).

&amp;gt; Migration has split Europe in two – or I could say that it has split the West in two. One half is a world where European and non-European peoples live together. These countries are no longer nations: they are nothing more than a conglomeration of peoples. I could also say that it is no longer the Western world, but the post-Western world. And around 2050, the laws of mathematics will lead to the final demographic shift: cities in this part of the continent – or that part – will see the proportion of residents of non-European origin rising to over 50 per cent of the total.

&amp;gt; In such a multi-ethnic context, there is an ideological feint here that is worth talking about and focusing on. The internationalist left employs a feint, an ideological ruse: the claim – their claim – that Europe by its very nature is populated by peoples of mixed race. This is a historical and semantic sleight of hand, because it conflates two different things. There is a world in which European peoples are mixed together with those arriving from outside Europe. Now that is a mixed-race world. And there is our world, where people from within Europe mix with one another, move around, work, and relocate. So, for example, in the Carpathian Basin we are not mixed-race: we are simply a mixture of peoples living in our own European homeland. And, given a favourable alignment of stars and a following wind, these peoples merge together in a kind of Hungaro-Pannonian sauce, creating their own new European culture. This is why we have always fought: we are willing to mix with one another, but we do not want to become peoples of mixed-race. [...] The time will come when we have to somehow accept Christians coming to us from there and integrate them into our lives. This has happened before; and those whom we do not want to let in will have to be stopped at our western borders – Schengen or no Schengen.

One advisor of his, the sociologist Zsuzsa Hegedüs (who is Jewish herself) has stepped down after the speech and called it &#34;pure Nazi text worthy of Goebbels&#34;, due to such explicit references to &#34;race&#34; (&#34;faj&#34; in Hungarian).

Shortly after the speech people realized that it is almost verbatim from a 1973 book. In fact Orbán mentions the book just a bit before the above section:

&amp;gt; There is an outstanding 1973 book on this issue which was written in French, and recently published in Hungary. It is called “[The Camp of the Saints](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Camp_of_the_Saints)” [Le Camp des Saints], and I recommend it to anyone who wants to understand the spiritual developments underlying the West’s inability to defend itself.

The NYT wrote [an article](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/22/books/stephen-miller-camp-saints.html) on it in 2019: &#34;A Racist Book’s Malign and Lingering Influence - “The Camp of the Saints,” published in 1973, has been a must-read within white supremacist circles for decades. Stephen Miller, Marine Le Pen and Steve King have touted it in recent years.&#34;

Most of the above quoted speech section is from the intro of the book, including exact phrases like &#34;historical and semantic sleight of hand&#34;. Orbán(&#39;s speech writers) basically just swapped the &#34;Gallo-Roman sauce&#34; of the original French book with &#34;Hungaro-Pannonian sauce&#34;.

Common directions of criticism were 1) that Hungarians are also mixed, no population is racially pure, 2) Hungarians came from Asia, 3) it&#39;s biologically inaccurate to talk about &#34;faj&#34; (=&#34;race&#34;, &#34;species&#34;) regarding humans.

Interestingly, or not, back in 2012, Orbán also called Hungarians &#34;half-Asian&#34; ([HU source](https://24.hu/belfold/2012/07/26/orban-veszekedos-felazsiai-nep-a-magyar/)):

&amp;gt; &#34;My philosophy is that unity is a question of strength: if there is strength, there is unity,&#34; he said. There are other ways of forging unity - for example, in the Scandinavian countries - but he believes that the Hungarians are incapable of doing so. &#34;That&#39;s the only way it works with half-Asian derivatives like us. Here everyone is clever, everyone knows better, everyone has a better idea,&#34; he said.

[Turanism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turanism) and emphasizing cultural or other relations to Turkic peoples have been common over the last ~150 years on the conservative right wing in Hungary. So how does this add up? Not so well, because the text was essentially taken out of a French nationalist context, and it doesn&#39;t fit so well. The actual far-righters in Hungary, like the Our Homeland Movement have been talking about a &#34;Northern Civilization&#34; (&#34;from the Celts all the way to the Japanese&#34;) instead of Western for some time now, exactly for this reason, and I guess as a way to get closer to the Russian far-right vision of Dugin&#39;s Eurasianism.

So saying that Hungarians came from Asia misses the point (well, it&#39;s arguable anyway in a modern genetic sense, and even if so, the origin was near the Urals, the border of Europe). Orbán and the far right&#39;s problem is with Africans and Middle Eastern Muslims.

He has since stated that his speech may have been misunderstandable, and he actually just meant cultural differences, not biological. But the word &#34;race&#34; was unusually blunt even for Orbán. He usually talks in terms of religion (Christianity vs Islam) or cultures and civilizations, not races. In fact, the Hungarian word he used (&#34;faj&#34;) is now quite taboo in this sense, today it&#39;s only used in the meaning of &#34;species&#34; (of animals or plants). Another common criticism came from this angle: that humanity is one species, *Homo sapiens*. This is a very shallow criticism but apparently many felt that it&#39;s some kind of gotcha, that Orbán doesn&#39;t even know basic biology and doesn&#39;t understand the concept of &#34;species&#34;. Except that &#34;faj&#34; used to be a much broader term, for stuff like ethnicity, nationality, race, species etc.

Zooming out a bit, it&#39;s clear that Orbán loves the kind of attention that these speeches give him. It&#39;s like antifragility, he thrives on being demonized and gets stronger each time when he survives these. So, since there was a possibility of difficulties at home (due to economic problems, they can&#39;t keep to their election promises just a few months after their re-election), he decided to cause some controversy so he can again frame things in this way, that all conflict with the EU ultimately stems from the issues of migration, gender, Soros etc. That&#39;s his home turf, that&#39;s the lens he wants on everything.

On Thursday, Orbán [will speak at CPAC Texas in Dallas](https://www.newsweek.com/von-der-leyen-rips-orban-over-mixed-race-speech-cpac-still-welcoming-him-1729399), to the outrage of American media.

So, 1) Most of this wasn&#39;t even Orbán&#39;s own ideas but took it verbatim from a book, 2) The reaction to it was lazy criticism, the nth iteration of calling Orbán a fascist or feigning ignorance about meanings of words or performatively not understanding that by other races Orbán meant Africans and Middle Easterners, not Uralic Asians. 3) Orbán needed nothing other than exactly that, to be criticized for his stance on migration and gender instead of utility price hikes and tax raises.

So is he a racist? It doesn&#39;t matter because this is post-politics. People perform to get reactions, it&#39;s not about beliefs. A prominent journalist from Orbán&#39;s circles, Zsolt Bayer (shown [here](https://nepszava.hu/3162052_nemeth-szilard-bayer-zsolt-alsoors-rasszizmus-polo-fenykep) with a Secretary of State) wore a &#34;white lives matter&#34; T-shirt just a few weeks ago. It&#39;s hard to tell what one should interpret as sincere opinions (if that&#39;s even possible for a politician to have) versus pure posturing. But it&#39;s mostly just two sides symbiotically needing each other to justify themselves.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iilcoqr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iil2u16/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I had a 3-month no-drinking promise (I&#39;m that guy (under a new account) who used</title><updated>2022-08-02T01:13:56Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I had a 3-month no-drinking promise (I&#39;m that guy (under a new account) who used to write about making promises to God to avoid vices for X amount of time). It lapsed today and I am drunk and so so happy. I have made another promise and am ok with this being something I experience only a few times a year (since chasing that dragon clearly leads only to horrible things).

Just wanna say hi to y&#39;all. Love to everybody.

I wish this were something sustainable. But it is what it is. God has made it so. Chemical happiness is temporary and poisonous and it has to be.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iil2u16/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought w</title><updated>2022-08-01T23:33:25Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought were pretty optimistic in Ukraine&#39;s favor; turns out I was too pessimistic. 

Russia is hauling out the museum piece 152&#39;s from the 1920&#39;s for second line units; the tempo of their advance and quantity/quality of artillery fire has dropped off way quicker (Like, an order of magnitude quicker) than I thought it would.

Apparently, the HIMARS shoot and scoot has been working. Ukraine can&#39;t push Russia where they are strong; but Russia can&#39;t advance along an entire front anymore without taking unsafe risks.

This on top of Ukrainian counteroffensives in Kherson; and (maybe? Questionably?) drama amongst the Russians staff running the war (apparently the two top guys hate each other, and refuse to allow one to be elevated over the other.  Water cooler shit though, so who knows.)

Basically: I predicted slow Russian advance for some time until their logistical problems caught up to them and they couldn&#39;t just atomize their problems with a zillion guns, then a frozen front until some political solution was reached or Russia got their economy in gear; which was wrong.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iikjjz1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] how do I tell radical leftists that their idea of centrism as a facist-allied pa</title><updated>2022-08-01T22:51:17Z</updated><author><name>SomewhatEmbarassed</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">how do I tell radical leftists that their idea of centrism as a facist-allied passivity is inherently intolerant of any views different from their own</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iikjjz1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijr0wh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I spoke with a researcher who will go by &#34;Alex Datepsych.&#34; out of Spain, on dati</title><updated>2022-08-01T19:43:45Z</updated><author><name>Pongalh</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I spoke with a researcher who will go by &#34;Alex Datepsych.&#34; out of Spain, on dating, inceldom and related topics for those who may be interested. [Part 1](https://youtu.be/frw7mi-reRA). [Part 2](https://youtu.be/JcDBxBaEPEQ).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Per the details on my YouTube page, in Part 1 we touch on the deracinated dating pov of the isolated, profilicity (ala philosopher Hans-Georg Moeller), AWALT (&#34;All Women Are Like That&#34;), MGTOW, the all-that-matters-are-looks blackpilled MRAs, and hilarious old school pickup artist &#34;Mystery.&#34;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

In Part 2 we discuss the racial composition of incels; &#34;Just Be White&#34;; the relationship between income, job type and infidelity; and the impact of remote work and pandemic on singles vs. marrieds.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[Here is Alex&#39;s website](https://datepsychology.com/).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijr0wh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The </title><updated>2022-08-01T17:57:40Z</updated><author><name>PutAHelmetOn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The comparison isn&#39;t motivated by &#34;haha look at how ridiculous these people are,&#34; it&#39;s specifically around reframing the following:

&amp;gt;Everyone has a gender identity, but most people are [cis by default](https://thingofthings.wordpress.com/2015/01/28/cis-by-default/)

To something more like:

&amp;gt;The genderqueer community is comprised of people who have gender identities, which may involve wearing clothing of their preferred gender... A small minority of them express a desire to become, or already see themselves as, their gender

Since I&#39;ve just committed analogy in the first degree, I expect the low-decouplers to be out in full force, so here are a few objections I foresee:

Possible counter: &#34;Well, most people don&#39;t have a fursona but most people do have a gender identity&#34;. Reply: I think both parts (before &amp;amp; after the &#39;but&#39;) are potentially wrong:

* Don&#39;t most people have a &#34;human by default&#34; fursona?
* Do most people *actually* have a gender identity?

To expand on (2): the language around gender identity is maximally confusing. 

As an example, I posed the question &#34;do you have a gender identity? what is it?&#34; to my dad and he said &#34;of course I&#39;m a male.&#34; despite not knowing what LGBTQ activists really think about gender identity. If two people say &#34;my gender identity is man&#34; that **does not mean they are really saying the same thing.** A less confusing language would be to call gender identity a &#34;fnord&#34; and then my dad would realize that he has no idea what a &#34;fnord&#34; is, just that it is something controversial.

Possible counter: &#34;this is not how people use the words &#39;fursona&#39; and &#39;gender identity&#39;&#34; to which I reply: this is missing the point. I am engaging in prescriptivism here, and I&#39;m claiming that speaking as if normal people have gender identity \[the way activists mean it\] is misleading. That activists enthusiastically say it&#39;s OK that gender identity means different things to different people makes me think this confusing language is intentional.

How should I react to a furry telling me my fursona was a human? I would probably tell him I&#39;m not a furry, sorry, not for me, but good for you. Should my reaction to activists asking me about my gender identity be any different? &#34;Sorry, not for me.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of com</title><updated>2022-08-01T16:08:28Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of compulsive browsing in my life has led me to see clearly how one&#39;s mind adapts to the things he interacts with. Social media seems to be the way things are because I use it, not because it is the way things are. Browsing seems like an effective means of getting information because it&#39;s the most present way that I&#39;m exposed to information, not because it is an effective means of getting information. And it&#39;s the most present way because something went wrong between the human-computer interaction.

I feel the need for something more compatible with this zen state of not hating everything. Even the things I actually care about are slipping away from my life unless I take the effort to hurt myself by reading garbage, so maybe I need something better.

Hopefully there are recognizable classics out there? Looking for anything: theories about interfaces, how to manage users, inside stories like that one about how they designed r/place...especially looking for ones that widely influenced the current industry, however annoyingly mainstream they are, and also any academic tomes that are well put together. The best I&#39;ve found is [this](https://www.researchgate.net/post/Any-good-books-about-designing-social-media) link, but everything else seems to be about marketing on social media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American R</title><updated>2022-08-01T13:20:01Z</updated><author><name>TheCoachSpo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American Right might be moving in. Tons of interviews, speeches, etc from prominent conservatives suggesting that it would be best for America to embrace Christian Nationalism. This raised some alarms; there is strong research connecting Evangelicals to conspiracies such as QAnon (among others) that could eventually lead to danger or even violence (ex: Jan 6th, the 26% of W. Evangelicals who &#34;agree that true American patriots might have to resort to violence in order to save our country.&#34; - PRRI).   
My question: How much of a threat does the Christian Right pose to American democracy and peace? A shrinking demographic who may believe they are losing their country, when paired with their renowned civic activism and news media that reinforces their increasingly conspiratorial beliefs, might just be the recipe for outbreaks of political violence. Needless to say, this trend of the Christian Right has me sincerely concerned.

I also want to quickly get out there that [Gordon Wood](https://moodle2.units.it/pluginfile.php/366505/mod_resource/content/1/Conspiracy%20and%20the%20Paranoid%20Style.pdf) and [Richard Hofstadter](https://harpers.org/archive/1964/11/the-paranoid-style-in-american-politics/) did some pretty well-known work on American/Colonial paranoia, suggesting that the colonists (many of whom had strong religious ties) viewed history as moments caused by individual actors rather than a stream of events. This allows them to attribute moral responsibility to bad actors and in doing so reveals how the good deed/bad deed doctrine of many Christian denominations might make believers more susceptible to conspiracy theories. After all, conspiracies are based on an idea that a small cabal of people are plotting something nefarious, like the Hellish plot of #PizzaGate.  
Woods suggested that this &#34;individual actor&#34; thinking still runs strong in American veins. If so, am I being overdramatic in [this short essay](https://coachspo.substack.com/p/an-american-conspiracy-movement-that) where I claim that Christian Right conspiracies pose a significant threat to American safety?  
A helpful recap of my essay: &#34;I believe there are warning signs around us. The size of the Religious Right is perpetually underrated in America and they are adopting conspiracy theories at a startling pace. What’s more, these theories are dangerous precisely because they promote the idea that White Christians are losing their status and identity. As Professor Walter proposed, when this happens the chance that a nation falls into violence or a Civil War only increases. Perhaps it was no coincidence that during the Insurrection the “Heavenly Father” was prayed to on the senate floor.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/154969215336</title><updated>2022-08-01T12:56:52Z</updated><author><name>Tophattingson</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/1549692153365991424), over the past four years, and particularly over the last two, opinions on trans issues have moved rightward (for lack of a better term) in the UK. The few positions that didn&#39;t move rightward relate to needing doctor&#39;s approval to legally change gender, or not requiring living as your new gender to legally change gender. However, these are two that were already very unpopular, and remain very unpopular, just slightly less, so it may represent changes only within the segment of the population that is very pro trans rights becoming even more pro.

I&#39;ve long suspected (or had as a concern) that existing legislation and institutional support for trans people, changes largely done out of the public eye, is only sustainable via obscurantism. That is to say, if the wider public knew how far the UK had already gone on this topic, that they&#39;d want to roll it back, and the only reason they&#39;re not rolling it back is because they don&#39;t know. Between high-profile trans people in sports, and the escalation of activism in general, they are now increasingly noticing and not liking it. The real nuclear button on this would be treating refusing to date trans people as transphobic, [because the overwhelming majority of people will refuse to date them.](https://www.researchgate.net/publication/325490626_Transgender_exclusion_from_the_world_of_dating_Patterns_of_acceptance_and_rejection_of_hypothetical_trans_dating_partners_as_a_function_of_sexual_and_gender_identity)

This survey result is certainly interesting. It also counters the idea that there&#39;s an ever-leftward drift on all social issues.

As a side not, I&#39;d be interested if anyone can approximate &#34;what percent of the UK&#39;s population would be banned from twitter / other social media if they were to clearly state their views on trans&#34; from the full survey results.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female</title><updated>2022-08-01T11:48:56Z</updated><author><name>Athanasius_19</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female representation among police officers to 30%](https://30x30initiative.org/about-30x30/)

&amp;gt; The 30×30 Initiative is based on the importance of achieving at least 30% representation to empower a group to influence an organization’s culture. This 30% threshold is where change begins to happen, but it is not our end goal. 30×30 is working with policing agencies to improve recruiting practices and establish community partnerships so that agencies become truly representative of the jurisdictions they serve. While 30×30 is focused on advancing women in policing, these principles are applicable to all demographic diversity, not just gender.

The website claims that women are better suited for police work, since &#34;women officers use less force and less excessive force; are named in fewer complaints and lawsuits; are perceived by communities as being more honest and compassionate; see better outcomes for crime victims, especially in sexual assault cases; and make fewer discretionary arrests.&#34;

They cite intersectionality as a cornerstone of the project, and several big police departments are listed as participating in this initiative. There are a few companies and activist groups backing it, including Microsoft. There&#39;s also a &#34;steering committee&#34; with a bunch of names I don&#39;t recognize, and would&#39;ve skipped over until I noticed that all of them are women.

Thoughts on how this would affect police relations and effectiveness? My prediction is that police work will slightly improve in safer communities, but that in more dangerous areas there will be a negative effect towards more crime, since crime rates aren&#39;t something the page mentions outright.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihhuxc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There is a group of specialists in Germany that work on designing signage/Symbol</title><updated>2022-08-01T08:48:11Z</updated><author><name>thatnoisy</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There is a group of specialists in Germany that work on designing signage/Symbols that can communicate to people 1 million years from now. The reason for that is the government&#39;s requirement that radioactive waste must be stored securely for 1 million years at least. This seems silly to me. 

Yes radioactive waste is no laughing matter but are we really so concerned about hypothetical people in the far future digging up some barrels of (by then) mildly radioactive debris? This is assuming that A Humans still exist and B They lost the ability to produce Geiger counters. Really what pushes this into hypocrisy territory to me is that we actively don&#39;t give a shit about real actual humans right now. We could feed and shelter homeless people with the money that we&#39;re using to pay these historians and linguists. I just don&#39;t get it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihhuxc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iigbkjf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there a sub with an ongoing discussion of the continuing takeover of /r/scien</title><updated>2022-08-01T01:13:45Z</updated><author><name>SunRaSquarePants</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there a sub with an ongoing discussion of the continuing takeover of /r/science with &#34;social science&#34; political agenda posts?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iigbkjf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iifwx1y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] The main CW thread seems to be roughly half as many comments as usual, any specu</title><updated>2022-07-31T23:14:38Z</updated><author><name>exiledouta</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">The main CW thread seems to be roughly half as many comments as usual, any speculation as to why?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iifwx1y/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat </title><updated>2022-07-31T18:49:40Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat hackers in the 90s. It&#39;s nice to read such a close account of something that I&#39;ve only vaguely heard of in news reports. So far Par&#39;s story has been gripping and sympathetic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iie1yph/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What’s the issue/position that you’ve most recently changed your mind on?

I&#39;ll </title><updated>2022-07-31T15:13:45Z</updated><author><name>Just_Natural_9027</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What’s the issue/position that you’ve most recently changed your mind on?

I&#39;ll start with saying each and everyday I am more convinced that ignorance is bliss particular with regards to political and culture war discourse.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iie1yph/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidzg8g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Not sure if it matches the typical Sunday question thread theme, but I&#39;ll be vis</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:55:36Z</updated><author><name>margotsaidso</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Not sure if it matches the typical Sunday question thread theme, but I&#39;ll be visiting San Diego for a few days. Anyone have recommendations for must-see things or something off the beaten path to check out?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidzg8g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especiall</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:26:54Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especially related to reinforcement, learning type stuff, more advanced than basic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidoauk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there anything stopping Elon Musk from just buying Twitter stock at the marke</title><updated>2022-07-31T13:29:22Z</updated><author><name>zataomm</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there anything stopping Elon Musk from just buying Twitter stock at the market price before he potentially loses his lawsuit?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidoauk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies </title><updated>2022-07-31T13:27:10Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies to society or morality, or at least that&#39;s the best way I can think to describe it. I realise I&#39;m treading philosophical old ground here but it is something I&#39;ve been thinking about recently.

In the Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma, and the Tragedy of the Commons etc, we have the general case of rational individual actions leading to negative outcomes for everyone.

What this really reminds me of egoist, classical realist, amoral (individualist, even) philosophy, perhaps best exemplified by Machiavelli&#39;s *The Prince*. That is generally a purely self interested individual with no concern for the common good. But there is a glaring issue with Machiavellian philosophy. No one would ever want to work under the Prince, over him or with him, because he would betray you in a heartbeat, and would be constantly looking for opportunities to undermine you for his own benefit. If everyone took Machiavelli&#39;s advice and acted like the perfect Prince, there could be no society. Everyone would just be continuously trying to screw each other over, there can be no true cooperation or common good.

This has kind of given me the idea of a kind of &#39;social parasitism&#39; (yes I am aware of the association of the term with Soviet political prisoners - I using it in an different sense. It&#39;s an apt label here). Machiavelli&#39;s Prince is basically a &#39;social parasite&#39;, in the sense benefiting himself while harming society and others generally. Just like an actual biological parasite, the social parasite needs the host (&#39;society&#39;) to thrive, yet if there are too many social parasite, it will leech too much off the host and kill society and itself (metaphorically), causing society to devolve into chaos and bloody anarchy. The Prince can only exist by exploiting the system he is ultimately undermining by his actions.

If I can think of any benefit that the Prince might provide to society, it might be if there is only one who gains supreme power and thus could theoretically rule competently (after all, this was the original intent for the Prince. But that requires there to only ever be one and only one Prince or would-be Prince. (Maybe you could use this as justification for some kind of elitism)

Sociopaths are essentially naturally this, amoral and a callous disregard for others, only concerned with their own benefit, abusing others trust. But too many sociopaths would cause everyone to become distrustful and thus collapsing the whole system that sociopaths love to exploit.

In some sense, I think this also applies to the constantly debated mistake vs conflict theory around here, with conflict theory obviously representing social parasitism. Conflict theorists can make easy gains by exploiting unassuming mistake theorists, but too much conflict results in dysfunction and collapse of social institutions which the conflict theorists are trying to overtake in the first place. The mistake theorists are the ones actually trying to solve issues, after all. I also wonder if there&#39;s a conflict theorist Schelling point, where the number of conflict theorists reaches critical mass, they create more problems than mistake theorists can solve, so mistake theorists are left with a choice, to either: become a conflict theorists and try to grab whatever resources are around before the collapse, or &#34;die&#34; a mistake theorist. (e.g. a previously principled scientist becoming politicized to secure his job even if it undermines the integrity and value of said job).

This is obviously not a new observation, but then moral systems (historically religions) primarily exist as enforcement mechanism, as a means to dissuade people from becoming social parasites. It&#39;s the Mafia don in the Prison&#39;s Dilemma who threatens the prisoners to keep their mouths shut.

I guess another question is, does social parasitism exist in mostly stable or unstable equilibrium? Does the system tend towards a sustainable number of social parasites, only forced out of balance by extreme external events? Or is there a natural, cyclical boom-bust pattern, where increasing social parasitism will ultimately destroy institutions, and mistake theorists will have to build new institutions from scratch before the cycle repeats.

Maybe I&#39;m looking at it backwards. Maybe the conflict theorists surge *after* the collapse of an institution, rushing to pick at the scraps like a vulture collecting carrion. Attempting to carve out a little niche for themselves, while stunting the ability for mistake theorists to rebuild. Maybe this is what we are seeing with the death of God, decaying social cohesion, and the attempt to establish some new common morality again.

Yeah I don&#39;t really know where I&#39;m going with this. I would like to hear everyone else&#39;s thoughts on this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiczkhv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] When looking at an url for a potentially sketchy website, which end should I be </title><updated>2022-07-31T08:35:29Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When looking at an url for a potentially sketchy website, which end should I be looking at- the front or the back?   
In other words, the     

&amp;gt;www.microsoft...    

or the     

&amp;gt;...microsoft.com/    

?    

I&#39;m assuming at least one end can show legitimacy at a glance. I saw [this gif](https://i.redd.it/sgp2jxdqmte91.gif) recently and got curious.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiczkhv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicun3i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] For our Russian posters:

How are things in Russia for the average person? How&#39;s</title><updated>2022-07-31T07:29:07Z</updated><author><name>S18656IFL</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">For our Russian posters:

How are things in Russia for the average person? How&#39;s the mood? How&#39;s the personal economy? 

There are a lot of numbers floating around but they often fail to communicate how things are on the ground.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicun3i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicqf8c/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there a term for deep happiness and fulfilment spiked with the bitter knowled</title><updated>2022-07-31T06:34:26Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there a term for deep happiness and fulfilment spiked with the bitter knowledge that this too shall pass, sic transit gloria mundi, memento mori, remember you are dust?
  
These days I feel like I&#39;ve achieved nearly all of my life goals, but I&#39;m pained with the knowledge that I can&#39;t stay in this particular stage of my life forever.  The summer of my life will one day end, and I&#39;ll pass into autumn and winter.  There&#39;s a bittersweet beauty to how transient life is and how fleeting moments of fulfillment are.  It&#39;s both pleasurable and painful, like just the right amount of DOMS after a good workout.  I wish I were more poetic or artistic so I could express the sensation better than this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iicqf8c/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iicjaqt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Crazy story about a property developer in LA whose hubris led to bankruptcy and </title><updated>2022-07-31T05:11:28Z</updated><author><name>bulksalty</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Crazy story about a property developer in LA whose hubris led to bankruptcy and a swanky mansion.  

https://archive.ph/5pncd

Chalk up another tale that reminds me that property development seems like an absolutely insane business.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iicjaqt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iibil29/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anyone use decentralized apps?

I&#39;ve poked around again and the survivors o</title><updated>2022-07-30T23:54:27Z</updated><author><name>slothlikesamwise</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anyone use decentralized apps?

I&#39;ve poked around again and the survivors of the big boom a few years ago seems to be Dat protocol and IPFS. Any cool uses for them that aren&#39;t just filesharing?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iibil29/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/iiav0qs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] As something of an AGI skeptic, I want to make a confession. In scoffing at the </title><updated>2022-07-30T20:51:27Z</updated><author><name>commonsenseextremist</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">As something of an AGI skeptic, I want to make a confession. In scoffing at the imminent prospect of creation of thinking machines, I&#39;m partly motivated by existential anxiety.

 As eggheads keep getting closer to sciencing intelligence, creativity and other parts of human soul, things do not look bright. It&#39;s not implausible that in a few years a good gaming PC will do satisfactory job on simulating all of the typical human functions...call it AGI or not (&#34;a rose by any other name...&#34;) it sucks. It&#39;s disturbing. And I don&#39;t care about GDP per capita improvements it will bring. 
I want to be special. I don&#39;t want to be something that can be accurately approximated by a glorified calculator. 
Yet science, as always, keeps stripping the pleasant illusions in which men find comfort, one at a time.

Here&#39;s my fermi paradox explanation - living things volve, build civilizations, but before they spread among stars they invariably figure out just how pointless of an endeavor that, or anything else, would be. They are just meat robots following predefined cosmic script and who will eventually die...and that&#39;s it.

 That would make modern rise of nihilism and depression first symptom of a malady that will eventually kill our civilization.
Is there a cure? Like Lovecraft says in [this brilliant, prescient passage](https://goodreads.com/quotes/193944-the-most-merciful-thing-in-the-world-i-think-is) the only remedy is to abandon science and pursuit of knowledge in general and pretend it never happened. Not a nice resolution, if you ask me. Or maybe a new mindset, new philosophy, mentality shall rise - man of the future will consider what scientific discoveries tell him about his place in the universe...and shrug, never thinking about it again.  Yes, I think I met people like that already.  Some of them were even clever and introspective. Aside from things I describe above, it&#39;s people like that who scary me the most.

I guess that category of people would include myself, with latest uptick of nihilistic ruminations some weeks behind me. Believe or not, I&#39;m feeling perfectly okay right now and I had a lot of fun writing this post.  At some point I&#39;m becoming just too tired to be scared and worried and I just hope that ultimately, at the end of the day, things are not that bad, and poverty of my meager human intelligence doesn&#39;t allow me to understand that I&#39;m no different from a teenager freaking out over a new pimple.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/iiav0qs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iian6cu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Looking for gaming suggestions:

1. Has progression elements. Buying upgrades, g</title><updated>2022-07-30T19:53:52Z</updated><author><name>cjet79</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Looking for gaming suggestions:

1. Has progression elements. Buying upgrades, gaining experience, etc.
2. Has skill elements. Like an FPS, action rpg, or some other game that requires some skill.
3. You can become God like. By the end of it I want my cumulative game skill and upgrades to make the game stupidly easy. Slaughtering foes without a thought, and only the hardest of bosses presenting the slightest challenge.

I can find plenty of games with the first two elements. It&#39;s the third element that is difficult to find.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iian6cu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii6wb1t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Anybody got any genius miracle cures for &#34;brain fog&#34;?

I can&#39;t explain why but i</title><updated>2022-07-29T23:08:53Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Anybody got any genius miracle cures for &#34;brain fog&#34;?

I can&#39;t explain why but it feels like screen time might be the culprit so might try to limit that since it is the weekend</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii6wb1t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii63rde/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Yesterday, I switched to a new Internet provider and got decent speed. Not coinc</title><updated>2022-07-29T19:47:34Z</updated><author><name>netstack_</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Yesterday, I switched to a new Internet provider and got decent speed. Not coincidentally I also reinstalled *League of Legends* for a few rounds with my brother.

It’s popular enough that this kind of gets taken for granted, but the premise is really clever.
On one hand, there’s the distillation of an RPG into each game: do tasks, numbers go up, steer the character to a style you want. There’s a balance between fundamental gameplay loops to improve and broader game *knowledge* to accrue. On the other is the pure PvP aspect using humans as a seed to keep things fresh.

But what really gets me is the specialization. I like a game which gives a specific job, a part of the machine. You get to play to strengths and watch the whole thing come together. And *League* does this better than a lot of games.

Anyone care to share recommendations in this “specialist” genre?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii63rde/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii60d0o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anybody have a link to Yarvin&#39;s essay that covers why he thinks modern poet</title><updated>2022-07-29T19:24:51Z</updated><author><name>SeeeVeee</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anybody have a link to Yarvin&#39;s essay that covers why he thinks modern poetry sucks?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii60d0o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5ks9g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What are your go-to hotel chains, where you always feel like you get good servic</title><updated>2022-07-29T17:41:43Z</updated><author><name>eBenTrovato</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What are your go-to hotel chains, where you always feel like you get good service, a clean room, and your full money’s worth? i.e., what’s the Chick-Fil-A of hotels?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5ks9g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight F</title><updated>2022-07-29T17:24:38Z</updated><author><name>DWXXV</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight Further

In 1997 a little game came out called “Final Fantasy 7.” You may have heard of it. The game is wildly influential, often considered one of the best games of all time…and has aged like moderately fine vinegar. If you weren’t active in gaming at the time it’s hard to overstate the influence of the game. It was fantastic, for many people it changed what they thought games were capable of, and one of the spoilers was for decades afterwards (although less so now) was often uttered along with “Vader, father” as one of the top spoilers of all time.

A big part of the game was the music. Nobuo Uematsu and the rest of the sound team had been doing fantastic work with severe technical limitations for ten years at that point, and some of the music from this era transcends videogaming to become some of the best music period (I’d argue Chrono Trigger for this one). Uematsu loved progressive rock, and while he was excellent at classical compositions he loved to inject a flavor that was rare at the time into his music. Compare Dragon Quest with the average Final Fantasy battle theme. 

The music of FF 7 was fantastic. “One Winged Angel” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ce7gVYs7Em0) is still considered one of if not the best compositions in gaming. “Bombing Mission” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VCcSmvGrGx8) can be unironically (and has been) performed by a massive orchestra. 

Excellent battle tracks have always been a tradition in JRPGs, since you’ll be hearing a lot of them, and in the old days you had to stretch one track for almost all the fights in the game.

The battle track for FF 7 is “Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DotavimguEU). Limitations in fan translation resources and official releases resulted in this being generally translated (literally) as “Those Who Fight” if you wanted to pirate a MIDI and listen to it on a Walkman or something like that. Sometimes it would be translated as “Fighting” and later, official releases would land on “Let the Battles Begin!”

It’s fine. Not the best FF has done, but it wouldn’t get that stale for most people. Most encounters are short anyway.

Not so for boss battles. The boss battle theme needs to be a banger, especially in a game that mostly uses one theme for all the bosses.

AND IT FUCKING IS.  

“Sara ni Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z_GUWdkJQgw) is still excellent, if limited by the technology of the time. Translated literally as “Those Who Fight Further” and occasionally as “Still More Fighting” the song often appears in top FF battle music lists. Later official translations would label it “Fight On!” which I think is a shame since it loses the character of the initial battle/boss battle names. Listening to it now you can tell that something great is hidden in this track limited by technology.

And we’ll get there.

In the years since the initial release FF 7 has remained influential. The music has been remixed thousands of times, it’s been a fixture in orchestral video game concerts, and Nobuo even made a metal band that plays some of these songs (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NzFh9GuE0rA). Gamers have been clamoring for a remake of the game. In 2020 they got it.

The game is controversial for reasons we won’t get into, but the music is not. With a massive team including the original composer they made a truly next gen sound track for a next gen game. Fans had some trepidation, these songs had been remixed by the community, professional composers, and the man himself tons of times. What were they going to do?

Well the answer was use everything learned about these songs and game composition over the last 20+ years. The soundtrack is absurdly good. From modern takes like an atmospheric exploration theme that turns into a battle theme when a fight starts (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5S49M40hv4) , to taking a one note joke enemy and turning it into an absurd and energetic boss battle (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQgXZ2HDiCQ). The game has everything.

The original battle theme still lives all over the game (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lu-dHQxxv4w), with variations to fit the mood and location of interest. But they hold back on the boss battle music. Yeah it shows up at the end of the first chapter (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AdGOnPsE-Xs). And it’s good. But is this it? Is this the epic remix?

No.

At the end of chapter 7 you fight a boss that was pretty much a joke in the original game. The fight is epic. And this fucking plays (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cQDLBKpbXQU). It has everything. I challenge you to drive the speed limit with this on. They held back, made you think they pretty whiffed on the remix for the boss theme, but they fucking stuck the landing. 

The rest of the soundtrack has some damn good tracks, but nothing injected nostalgia directly into my veins like The Airbuster. 

Never forget how powerful music can be.

Thank you for coming to my Ted Talk.

DW out. 

Anyone who has anything they want to add or correct is welcome!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii4mf7k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] /u/2cimarafa Did you ever find that subreddit about obscure test taking? Seemed </title><updated>2022-07-29T13:58:25Z</updated><author><name>margotsaidso</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">/u/2cimarafa Did you ever find that subreddit about obscure test taking? Seemed like a great Friday Fun Thread topic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii4mf7k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3sijm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I am really enjoying the new army logistics series on aCoUP: https://acoup.blog/</title><updated>2022-07-29T09:03:26Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I am really enjoying the new army logistics series on aCoUP: https://acoup.blog/2022/07/29/collections-logistics-how-did-they-do-it-part-ii-foraging/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3sijm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3jab4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recently for the first time, I tried alcohol. The high was really pleasurable an</title><updated>2022-07-29T07:02:53Z</updated><author><name>DandyPandemonium</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recently for the first time, I tried alcohol. The high was really pleasurable and I felt extremely guilty about the hedonistic behaviour. It&#39;s only for this reason that I was hesitant about trying an inebriating substance, afraid that I might get addicted. But, any suggestions for fun activity/activities while being high, preferably something eye opening? I usually just listen to tool and other metal songs on shuffle and go into a peaceful zone.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3jab4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3exax/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [two Bay Area meetups in August](https://sonya.substack.com/p/august-2022-picnic</title><updated>2022-07-29T06:12:02Z</updated><author><name>sonyaellenmann</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[two Bay Area meetups in August](https://sonya.substack.com/p/august-2022-picnics) that are perhaps of interest to the rest of you dorks as well &amp;lt;3</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii3exax/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ii0xv4c/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How do those of you in the private sector estimate your salary and value? 

I&#39;m </title><updated>2022-07-28T18:51:21Z</updated><author><name>thisismymilitaryalt</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How do those of you in the private sector estimate your salary and value? 

I&#39;m job hunting again and a lot of job applications are asking for a salary range. In the military my salary was almost entirely up to the whims of Congress so I never really thought about it that much. I have a pretty precise budget so I know the minimum I can live on, but I&#39;m having trouble figuring out how high to go on top of that. On the one hand, I don&#39;t want to price myself out of a job but on the other hand I don&#39;t want to lowball myself and get taken for a ride. Suggestions?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ii0xv4c/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihzz0i8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any recommendations for a podcast?</title><updated>2022-07-28T15:08:42Z</updated><author><name>Anouleth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any recommendations for a podcast?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihzz0i8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvm026/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I’ve been reading some studies on alcohol. I’m pretty sure our culture is drinki</title><updated>2022-07-27T17:29:26Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I’ve been reading some studies on alcohol. I’m pretty sure our culture is drinking incorrectly. Alcohol has a significant *retrograde* enhancement on memory; it especially enhances positive-valence memory and (perhaps) social/language memory, but only post-learning.  I don’t think the mechanism is conclusive but the hypothesis is that it works by reducing memory interference on information presented post-ingestion. There is no benefit to drinking *before* learning on memory acquisition, there is only a benefit *after* learning on memory *consolidation*. Drinking before any learning will negatively influence acquisition and retention. Or so studies suggest.

This would mean that, if we are to drink, we ought to (1) not pre-game; (2) exposure ourselves to a context where we desire to create preferentially happy memories, (3) drink immediately following the context. If we are drinking to bond socially, we want the bonding to be before the drinking starts. If we are drinking with a book, we may want to start reading before we start drinking. It would also seem that if we have to do some annoying negative thing, alcohol will enable it to be done without much negative effect on mood when it is over.

It’s surprising to read historical accounts of writers and thinkers drinking so much. It’s likely that culture used to be oriented toward this more beneficial style of drinking. Think: drinking in ode of some emotionally-charged celebration (wedding, then after-party); drinking the wine *in memory* of Christ; etc.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvm026/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvigze/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Sometimes I have trouble falling asleep because I keep ruminating on things that</title><updated>2022-07-27T17:07:15Z</updated><author><name>sargon66</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Sometimes I have trouble falling asleep because I keep ruminating on things that don&#39;t much bother me during the day.  Any suggestions for how to stop doing this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvigze/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvee4s/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] A few months ago somebody mentioned the [Stronglifts 5x5 regimen](https://strong</title><updated>2022-07-27T16:42:03Z</updated><author><name>udfgt</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">A few months ago somebody mentioned the [Stronglifts 5x5 regimen](https://stronglifts.com/5x5/) to get into shape, and I was inspired to join a gym. I&#39;ve never been a weightlifter, as my exercise has always been cardio of some form primarily (running, swimming, biking). I fell off the horse a little during and immediately after college, and getting married added a lot of things onto my plate that let me gain quite a bit of weight.

So, after a few months of kicking the can down the road, I finally got a gym membership a month ago and have been going consistently. I was prepared for the effects to take a while and I&#39;ve been slowly incrementing weight to where I&#39;m pushing 20 lb plates now. I have actually been mildly surprised at how quickly I have been dropping weight and building muscle. My stomach fat has declined somewhat, and my running pace to and from the gym has increased noticably to where I am running, not jogging, and it feels incredible.

I&#39;m still trying to manage my diet, as my and my wife&#39;s schedules give us a lot of excuses to take the easy route of not cooking. However, I&#39;m finding better alternatives to what I was eating and drinking and I&#39;m slowly building new eating habits. I don&#39;t have a scale to measure myself, but my activity, vitality, and attitude have been sky-high for the last month.

Ultimately my crazy goal is to train for a triathlon. I&#39;ve been gassing up some buddies for years and I finally am in a place where I can consistently work out. I have my sights set on a half ironman, as I trained for and failed to complete one years ago. My goal weight is a bit up in the air, but I want to hit 20%ish body fat before I start training hard again. Ideally, I&#39;m 5&#39;11&#34; so my guess is around 180-200, but I&#39;m not sure how muscle weight works into that.

I know there are some endurance guys in this community, as well as some fitness-focused people. I&#39;m kind of curious to gauge what the community might think about a collective fitness challenge. Something like a &#34;complete a tri&#34; or &#34;complete a half marathon&#34; with some sort of meet-up for a race somewhere. Let me know if there is interest in something like that and I can brainstorm some ideas to follow up with. I&#39;m going to aim to do races anyway, but getting some sort of community to aim with is something I haven&#39;t really done before, and it would be a cool challenge. Comment and critique is obviously welcome.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvee4s/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvc4ob/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anyone have a recommendation for an online (remote) personal trainer? I.e., some</title><updated>2022-07-27T16:28:06Z</updated><author><name>reverend_bayes</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anyone have a recommendation for an online (remote) personal trainer? I.e., someone who makes a diet and workout routine for you and checks in once a month or so to update it. In particular, I&#39;m looking for one that&#39;s very metrics-/goal-oriented, which is why I thought this sub might be a good place to ask.

(I&#39;m a guy looking to gain muscle rather than lose weight. I know that there are free online workout plans I can follow instead that are just as good but spending money to overcome procrastination &amp;amp; motivation issues is a good tradeoff for me here.)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvc4ob/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihv798g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Started taking Metformin last week.  So far no issues.

I took a blood test befo</title><updated>2022-07-27T15:57:28Z</updated><author><name>bored_at_work_guy</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Started taking Metformin last week.  So far no issues.

I took a blood test beforehand.  Had good free testosterone levels but high cholesterol.  Will be interesting to see how these change when I get tested again in a couple months.

In addition to life extension benefits, I&#39;m hoping for a reduction in body fat.  Might not work since I&#39;m already giving myself license to eat more carb heavy meals.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihv798g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihui2ep/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I’ve been smoking 2-3 of these [binoid THCP carts](https://www.binoidcbd.com/col</title><updated>2022-07-27T13:04:34Z</updated><author><name>AdviceThrowaway1901</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I’ve been smoking 2-3 of these [binoid THCP carts](https://www.binoidcbd.com/collections/thcp-products) a month. They’ve definitely improved my mental health a lot and I’ve even become more productive. Haven’t noticed any adverse health effects. Is there any good reason I should stop?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihui2ep/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>