<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-19T21:51:20Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igu416v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Ukraine war updates

This is a slow grinding war of Artillery trenches and drone</title><updated>2022-07-19T21:51:20Z</updated><author><name>ussgordoncaptain2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Ukraine war updates

This is a slow grinding war of Artillery trenches and drone scouting. Ever since Gennady took over Russia has been steadily and slowly taking ground on [june 19th](https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-june-19) Papasna was the frontline and now on [July 18](https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-july-18) Papasna is firmly in russian territory and the new frontline is Bakhmut. One major issue with reporting on this war is that it&#39;s pretty hard to report on a war where most of the conflict is 50000 artillery shells a day (no seriously) getting fired into a fairly small area followed by a small advance and more artillery. Perhaps the best way to find shelling information is [Thermal anomaly](https://firms.modaps.eosdis.nasa.gov/map/#t:adv;d:7days;l:noaa20-viirs,viirs,modis_a,modis_t,street;@37.8,48.1,7z) data because a large scale artillery campaign is visible from such data.

Perhaps the best breakdown I could find of the Ukraine war comes from the [Austrian Military academy](https://youtu.be/dEbLuAPobao) showing just how russian progress has been (slow methodical but definitely moving forward). The grinding down of the Ukrainian forces has been steady, with the UKR forces going from 81 Battallions to 60 while the russians have gone from 93 BTG&#39;s to 108 after new reinforcements. (though remember that it&#39;s hard to assess the strength of the BTGs) While Thermal anomaly data definitely showed that new NATO weapons had a temporary decrease in russian effectiveness the data appears to show that russian artillery shelling has come back after the operational pause for (what appears to be) logistical reasons.

New NATO weapons are probably going to make an impact, though given that the US has sent roughly $7 Billion worth of equipment to UKR it&#39;s hard to say how much each marginal unit enables. Remember this is also NATO $7 billion so while the weapons work they&#39;re not necessarily very good in the &#34;bang for the buck&#34; department. In the report by Mr.Resner it&#39;s pointed out that the M777 is really vulnerable to damage from Shrapnel, and needs constant repairs to maintain it&#39;s combat effectiveness. 
.
.I keep getting conflicting reports on air defenses, it appears that Ukrianian air defenses are good enough to prevent bombing but they have no defense against air to ground long range missiles., though it appears such ATG missiles aren&#39;t very cost effective. 

I know reporting on what has become World war 1 with drones is a little boring, but still I&#39;m surprised at how little discussion there is about the only political event to actually remain relevant 5 months after it started in 2022.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igu416v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igu27zk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So who has watched the first episode of Nathan Fielder&#39;s new HBO show The Rehear</title><updated>2022-07-19T21:39:26Z</updated><author><name>Fruckbucklington</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So who has watched the first episode of Nathan Fielder&#39;s new HBO show The Rehearsal? If you haven&#39;t, go watch it. Don&#39;t read up on it, don&#39;t even watch a trailer, go in blind and watch it. If you are prone to overthinking things - aka a motter - I can almost guarantee you will like it. It is amazing. Like all my favourite things, it is both really smart and beyond idiotic. I want to try to keep this spoiler free so I will be a little circumspect - do you think he confessed at the end? Would you?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igu27zk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtlhuq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] https://twitter.com/disclosetv/status/1549460928328077314

Seventeen members of </title><updated>2022-07-19T19:54:35Z</updated><author><name>okay-dot-com</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">https://twitter.com/disclosetv/status/1549460928328077314

Seventeen members of congress were arrested today for protesting the recent SCOTUS decision re: Roe.

There&#39;s a video in that thread of AOC seemingly pretending to be handcuffed, but she raises a triumphant fist at one point, so maybe she didn&#39;t realize what it looked like she was doing.

I don&#39;t really know how to come at this from a TheMotte perspective. I just find it so humiliating that this is our government. From top to bottom, the US Government is a total embarrassment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtlhuq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtkil9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Since the start of Covid-era public health policies, one of my hobbyhorses has b</title><updated>2022-07-19T19:48:28Z</updated><author><name>Walterodim79</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Since the start of Covid-era public health policies, one of my hobbyhorses has been beating up on public health agencies, supporting bureaucracies, and related research and being even more scathing when it comes to the science reporting targeted at general audiences. So naturally, when I heard about [a new study](https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736\(22\)00847-9/fulltext) out on the impact of alcohol on health and read a couple [news articles](https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/jul/14/alcohol-is-never-good-for-people-under-40-global-study-finds) on it, my first instinct was to be similarly scathing regarding the quality of evidence and the reporting thereof. Instead of that though, I want to step back and try to tease apart just how different it is to evaluate that evidence from a public health lens and a personal advice lens. For the moment, let&#39;s assume that the quality of data and imputed causal relationships are basically valid and use them as a jumping off point:

&amp;gt;The study, published in the Lancet, found that 59% of those who drank harmful amounts were aged 15-39 – people for whom alcohol provided no health benefit and posed risks, including injuries relating to drinking or car accidents, suicides or murders.

I probably do buy that straightaway - I would bet a fair bit that drinkers are more likely to be in car accidents, commit murder, or kill themselves. From a public health perspective, this is at least suggestive of a plausible causal relationship, even if it doesn&#39;t really provide the necessary evidence to legitimize compulsory policies without randomized control trials to accumulate better evidence going forward. 

On the flip side though, should this tell me, a guy in my thirties that probably does drink a bit too much, much of anything about the likely impact on my longevity? Does it make me more inclined to suggest to friends that they cut back or stop drinking altogether? My immediate inclination is to think that my risk of car accidents, suicides, and murders are changed by a rounding error by drinking, even by drinking heavily - I don&#39;t drink and drive, I&#39;ve never had a remotely suicidal impulse, and I&#39;m a pretty non-violent guy that doesn&#39;t carry a weapon. *Maybe* there&#39;s some marginal change, but it&#39;s not much. What about my advice for others? Well, I suppose I can&#39;t know their inner state as well - some people are visibly sullen or violent when drinking, so it might be best for them to knock it off. I have no way to weight the benefits for others accurately, but I personally gain quite a bit of joy from the culture and experience of good beers and bourbons and do not suffer any apparent emotional or material impacts on my life.

This isn&#39;t really about alcohol though (although I do invite commentary on that), it&#39;s about how the reactions of public health people. The policy people say things like:

&amp;gt;Dr Richard Piper, chief executive of Alcohol Change UK, said: “The emerging science on alcohol, over hundreds of studies over the past 20 years, is telling us very clearly that alcohol is very damaging to the human body in multiple ways. We were previously unaware of this, and too many of us continue to drink as though this revolution in our knowledge hasn’t happened.

&amp;gt;“If you care about your health, by far the best approach is not to drink at all. If you do choose to drink alcohol, listen properly to the UK’s chief medical officers, and do not exceed 14 units a week (about six pints of lager or a bottle and a half of wine), have at least three alcohol-free days a week, and never exceed more than six units in one day.”

The closing paragraph of the linked Lancet study includes:

&amp;gt;The findings of this study support the development of tailored guidelines and recommendations on alcohol consumption by age and across regions and highlight that existing low consumption thresholds are too high for younger populations in all regions. Additionally, our results suggest that guidelines should not incorporate sex-specific recommendations, given the absence of variation in TMREL and NDE by sex across geographies and locations. Finally, recognising that the majority of the world&#39;s population consuming harmful amounts of alcohol are young adults and predominantly young males, in order to minimise health loss due to alcohol consumption it is important to prioritise interventions targeted at these demographic groups.

The thing about public health is that it&#39;s inherently a fairly blunt instrument. If the appropriate conclusion is that many people drink too much, resulting in them causing carnage to the tune of thousands of gruesome excess deaths among the young annually from car accidents, suicides, and homicides, it&#39;s pretty rational for the policy people to start thinking about how to get people to drink less. They generally can&#39;t afford to undercut their message by hedging and saying, &#34;well, ya know, unless you&#39;re just not going to kill yourself, then it doesn&#39;t matter much&#34;.

As a final thought, it&#39;s still worth taking a swipe at the journalists - &#34;Alcohol is never good for people under 40, global study finds&#34; is just an absolutely shit summary of the finding.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igtkil9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igt16bp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] An update on [this](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_wa</title><updated>2022-07-19T17:47:44Z</updated><author><name>badnewsbandit</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">An update on [this](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifzejpk/) story from last week. [Charges against Jose Alba dismissed](https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/nyc-crime/ny-charges-dismissed-harlem-bodega-worker-jose-alba-20220719-wpukj3ga2zfrdgomjh7efybbke-story.html).
&amp;gt;Prosecutors said Alba had at least two strong self-defense arguments to pursue: That he feared Simon might kill him, and that he believed Simon was committing a burglary by stepping behind the counter without permission.

...
&amp;gt;But other facts of the case weighed in Alba’s favor, the prosecutor wrote. Simon was 26 years younger than Alba and five inches taller. The bodega clerk is 5-foot-7.

&amp;gt;“Simon’s conduct in entering the store’s small, private area, throwing Alba against the wall to a place he could not escape, and grabbing him by the collar could inspire deep fear in an older and shorter man as to what might be in store next,“ Sigall wrote.

&amp;gt;Sigall added, “This was also in the context of the girlfriend saying five minutes earlier that her boyfriend was going to “come down here right now and f--- you up.”

Much that seems inline with various comments noting the physical disparity between the two men and how that might factor into a self-defense claim as well as the initial remarks from the girlfriend threatening Alba and their impacts on self-defense/robbery.

Initially I was a bit confused about the prosecutors in dismissing the case saying they didn&#39;t think they could prove beyond a reasonable doubt that Alba was not justified but apparently in New York, self defense is a [justification](https://ypdcrime.com/penal.law/article35.php#p35.00) not an affirmative defense which balances things much more in favor of the defendant.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igt16bp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igsz3wz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The first hearing in Twitter&#39;s lawsuit against Elon Musk for specific performanc</title><updated>2022-07-19T17:35:01Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The first hearing in Twitter&#39;s lawsuit against Elon Musk for specific performance was today. This hearing wasn&#39;t about any merits issues for the case but was more about scheduling when the trial will take place. I was unable to tune in for most of the hearing, I only caught the judge&#39;s opinion at the end but I know a [couple](https://twitter.com/AkivaMCohen/status/1549403466036117504) lawyers who [live-tweeted](https://twitter.com/Kolyin/status/1549407533269504002) it. You can read Musk&#39;s opposition to Twitter&#39;s motion to expedite [here](https://corpgov.law.harvard.edu/2022/07/18/twitter-vs-musk-musks-opposition-to-expedited-proceedings/) and Twitter&#39;s reply to Musk&#39;s opposition [here](https://www.plainsite.org/dockets/download.html?id=308108891&amp;amp;z=0555e1b7).

The short version is that Twitter wanted a trial in September. This is not *unprecedented* in Delaware courts but it is a very aggressive schedule. Musk wanted a date *next February* which, while also not unprecedented, is much longer than these actions typically take. The Court split the difference (not really) and set the trial for five days in October. This seems to bode pretty poorly for Musk, assuming all the time he wanted before the trial is time he thought he would actually need.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igsz3wz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igsmj99/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The UK conservative party will soon pick another leader who will automatically b</title><updated>2022-07-19T16:17:02Z</updated><author><name>sargon66</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The UK conservative party will soon pick another leader who will automatically become Prime Minister.  [Betting markets](https://electionbettingodds.com/NextUKConservativeLeader2022.html) give Liz Truss a 47% chance of winning and Penny Mordaunt an 12% chance.

Dominic Cummings (rationalist, Brexit Mastermind, and former top adviser to Boris Johnson) [writes](https://dominiccummings.substack.com/p/snippets-6-the-leadership-race-sw1?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email):

&amp;gt; PennyM is a true idiot. She would be total fiasco as PM

&amp;gt; LizzT is a bit less stupid but much more crackers and would also be a total fiasco.

&amp;gt; Either of them would not just fail, they could destroy the party. Which means that many will be cheering for one of them.

&amp;gt; Boris is supporting Truss. Why? 1) He thinks it’s the best way to stop Sunak. 2) He knows Truss is mad as a box of snakes and is thinking, ‘there’s a chance she blows, there’s another contest and I can return’.

&amp;gt; And with the human handgrenade [LizzT], she may catastrophically escalate the war — remember she has defined the goal as pushing Russia out of Crimea, which if seriously attempted would be seen by the vast majority of Russians Iincluding anti-Putin Russians) as an attempt to destroy Russia and could lead to nuclear weapons.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igsmj99/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igrrykb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What’s everyone’s feeling/thoughts about the economy?

I’ve been watching some Y</title><updated>2022-07-19T12:46:32Z</updated><author><name>Noticer_</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What’s everyone’s feeling/thoughts about the economy?

I’ve been watching some YouTubers who like to forecast world events, and they’re all seemingly blaring red alert that we are in for a major rough patch of human history, and they’ve been like that for months now. Not just an economic recession is predicted but also worldwide famine, due to the Russian war and poor weather affecting crop yields. Further, because boomers are all starting to retire en masse, we are also just beginning to see the effects of low
Birth rate on western economies. Europe looks
Pretty screwed right now, with high energy prices and low productivity the new standard for them. Can they survive with their current standards of living intact? Same goes double for China, with the one child policy and mass corruption causing them to over count their population to the tune of a one hundred million, constant Covid lockdowns, and an insane housing bubble leading to one of the worlds worst economic calamities on the horizon.

There’s just so much chaos that is seemingly around the corner. And no one’s talking about it here, it seems odd!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igrrykb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igqxz7m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I’ve noticed that the term incel has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejo</title><updated>2022-07-19T06:54:33Z</updated><author><name>buttfaceszn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I’ve noticed that the term incel has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejorative for sexism of any kind (at least on the internet) which strikes me as odd. I don’t really like when people use the term incel as an insult to people who bring up redpill/PUA/manosphere-type things, since I suspect there’s a lot of non-incels who find these things interesting and I personally think some of it has value. But from the perspective of someone who is trying to insult a redpill/MRA type in a heated Reddit argument, it at least makes sense to call them an incel. Incels afaik do really tend to be into these ideas, and people who excessively harp on them can come across as resentful about their own personal struggles with women.  

What’s odd to me is when I’ve seen it used to describe people who make fun of the WNBA, or say that women shouldn’t be NFL coaches, or don’t like women comedians, or make banal observations about women being more sensitive or dramatic or whichever stereotype. The reason it’s odd is that in my experience, low-level sexism or observations/jokes about sex differences are extremely common, even more so among guys who are typically successful with women. I suspect I have a relatively more “normie” upbringing than the typical commenter here, I played sports like football and baseball in high school, went to a good but not elite large public university, was in a social fraternity, and have many uncles and cousins who are all blue-collar tradesmen types. I can’t think of anyone I am close with from sports, HS, college, family, etc. who has had any trouble with women, and definitely none who are redpill types or incels.  

My whole life, among men of all ages, races, incomes etc. it seems like it’s extremely common to be “casually sexist”. Making “women be shopping”-tier observations about gender differences, or saying women are more [insert stereotype] is very normal, and some more mean-spirited or harmful things like making fun of the WNBA, or saying women couldn’t be NFL coaches, or calling certain women “gold-diggers” wouldn’t be uncommon. It also seems common for my girlfriend or my mom and their friends to make similar observations about men, calling them clueless or lazy or unable to pick up on social cues or not knowing what to do with babies. It also seems these kinds of jokes or observations were popular in sitcoms and comedy movies in the past. It just seems odd to me that this kind of thing would come to be associated with “guys who can’t get laid”, especially since it seems like misogyny/sexism is also somewhat associated with the jock/frat bro stereotype. 

I’m not trying to argue whether any of this is good or true or sexist or not. It just always seemed like it was relatively common to me and mostly lighthearted. (I also don’t want to argue whether casual sexism is *harmful* I am just saying the things I am describing aren’t *intended* to be *hateful*).  

I guess my questions are: am I correct that this is normal or am I in a particularly sexist bubble? Was it normal in the past, but isn’t anymore? Or am I just overthinking this, and random people on the internet are just using incel to mean “vaguely sexist” without really caring about being accurate? I suspect it’s the last one and potentially a mix of the other two, but I do wonder if there is a genuine taboo-ing of even the most harmless kinds of gender-stereotype humor among younger generations. Or possibly: I am I just way off on where the line is between “casual/acceptable/normal” level sexism, and something like “making fun of the WNBA” is more in the “hateful towards women” category of sexism?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igqxz7m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq8pkg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What does Napoleon tell us about ideology? He was the culmination of a revolutio</title><updated>2022-07-19T02:45:50Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What does Napoleon tell us about ideology? He was the culmination of a revolution between a far right and a far left. He took control undemocratically, became Emperor, and both sides were just… okay with it. Widespread support, yet dictatorial; attempted to balance the Left and Right, but motivated by personal ambition.

There’s something illustrative in this whole thing, but I’m too lazy to read Thomas Carlyle. It’s almost like both sides simply wanted practical improvements and a good story, and Napoleon more than sufficed.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq8pkg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igq5z71/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Regarding woke capitalism, a common argument is that wokness is profitable, and </title><updated>2022-07-19T02:24:51Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Regarding woke capitalism, a common argument is that wokness is profitable, and that the rising share prices of multinational companies that adopt wokness confirm this. 

I think finally we may be seeing our fist notable, multinational woke undoing. It&#39;s too early to blame wokness for sure, but Disney stock has been doing horribly lately, way worse than the S&amp;amp;P 500. 

Disney is at $95, a 53% decline from its peak just 16 months ago, versus a 20% decline for the S&amp;amp;P 500. Moreover, Disney stock is unchanged since early 2015, lagging the S&amp;amp;P 500 considerably there too. 

This difference is huge:  over the past 5 years the S&amp;amp;P 500 is up 56% (excluding dividends) but Disney is down 11%

https://i.imgur.com/RmCX3Ms.jpg

Too early to celebrate but this could be a sign of things to come. Same for Netflix, which has also done horribly. I think however Google and Facebook will prove more impervious.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igq5z71/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq05ea/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] This comment&#39;s just a notice to anyone who might be recreating my personality so</title><updated>2022-07-19T01:41:30Z</updated><author><name>TJ11240</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">This comment&#39;s just a notice to anyone who might be recreating my personality some time in the future through all these years&#39; worth of comments, I&#39;d like to remind you I&#39;m usually working on a buzz in the evenings so that probably should be accounted for.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igq05ea/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igpi2uj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Link from my blog [The stakes are low for US politics, and America’s rivals are </title><updated>2022-07-18T23:26:55Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Link from my blog [The stakes are low for US politics, and America’s rivals are weak and apathetic](https://greyenlightenment.com/2022/07/18/the-stakes-are-low-for-us-politics-and-its-rivals-are-weak-or-apathetic/)

In this post I argue that America&#39;s political problems and division, in spite of social media outrage, are low stakes historically speaking. America&#39;s biggest rivals, China and Russia, are also quite weak too even compared to the Cold War.

&amp;gt;Or like the second half of the 20th century, which witnessed several assassinations of statesmen and other important people, including John and Robert Kennedy, Malcolm X, and Martin Luther King Jr., and also the attempted assassinations of Pope John Paul II and Ronald Reagan, in addition to the civil rights movement, the South flipping from Blue to Red, and endless crime waves and race riots that continued until the mid 90s, when crime finally began to fall. Regarding Roe v. Wade, unlike the aftermath of George Floyd’s death, there has been close to zero civil disobedience regarding abortion rights. The BLM riots of 2020, as bad as those were, had far far fewer deaths and injuries compared to the Rodney King riots. Jan 6th is not like 911, as much as the left wishes it was. Yeah, there is a lot of societal decay, such as homelessness and drug use, but this is not destabilizing, nor will it lead to unrest. Elites will continue to retreat from everyone else and the decay, forming their own enclaves and close-knit communities.

I think Pinker&#39;s  [Long Peace](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Peace) thesis is still intact even though things may seem worse, thanks to social media , which has the effect of amplifying bad news, so it&#39;s hard to look at things in the correct context.  Thanks to social media, every small or isolated event of unrest is broadcast worldwide to billions of people in real time, whereas 40+ years ago similar events would have gone ignored or only mentioned in passing in a local newspaper.  Russia&#39;s war with Ukraine does not threaten this post-ww2 geopolitical &#39;order&#39;. Compared to the conflicts of Vietnam, WW2, or even the Yugoslav Wars, the Russian-Ukraine war doesn&#39;t  even measure up to a single battle of WW2, let alone the entire thing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igpi2uj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igph8wf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Rightists are not put-upon victims nor the innocent objects of left-wing mendaci</title><updated>2022-07-18T23:20:46Z</updated><author><name>Extrayesorno</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Rightists are not put-upon victims nor the innocent objects of left-wing mendacity. 

This framing pops up again and again, [here&#39;s an example from a few hours ago](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igotl8u/) that inspired this comment. 

The idea is that the left is just pushing *too far* and if leftists had been a bit more charitable or a bit more reasonable, then rightists would have been happy to compromise. Explicit or implicit is a historical fantasy where the right was sitting passively until the left showed up and tried to implement some change, which the right happily (or at least agreeably) permitted. But then the left just *kept pushing* until the right, like a beaten dog, was finally forced to bite back.

This is, indeed, fantasy. No left-wing policy, law, program, or ideal has ever been put through except in the teeth of right-wing opposition. Nothing from the decriminalization of sodomy, to desegregation, to women&#39;s suffrage, to universal *male* suffrage, to the abolition of slavery (that one necessitated a military defeat, and even then the rebels were whining that they were only fighting this war because the damned abolitionist fanatics had pushed them to it) has been gotten through except by the defeat of the right, whether that be economic, political, social, or military defeat. 

(As an aside, there are committed reactionaries who will happily admit that they *do* think the decriminalization of homosexuality, women&#39;s suffrage, abolition of slavery, democracy, republicanism, etc. were indeed mistakes, and none of this applies to them, they are at least honest and consistent)

When rightists, historically, has said, &#34;okay, I&#39;ll grant you this one,&#34; they&#39;ve never said it out of magnanimous good-faith, they&#39;ve said it at bayonet-point (literal or metaphorical), when they had *no choice* but to grant it anyways. 

The idea that the right wouldn&#39;t be so angry and would have been happy if we hadn&#39;t just kept pushing has always been nonsense, and the right has never been a hapless victim, but rather an enemy on the back foot. 

Any leftist or liberal who is tempted to buy this rightist line of &#34;hey, we would have been glad to meet in the middle, you guys just got so *crazy*&#34; and to see the right as victim rather than a (temporarily) weakened foe ought to remember that old fable about the farmgirl and the wounded serpent.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igph8wf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igoxug5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The tactical AAR on the Uvalde school shooting is out, and full of information f</title><updated>2022-07-18T21:05:56Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The tactical AAR on the Uvalde school shooting is out, and full of information for those who want to dig in deeper. Link [here](https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqbGVQV3o2dDdUMzBSRUFzM3ZVdTNhdFgxNmtLUXxBQ3Jtc0ttcWxEblJ2cGlCSWh1aTlYaG1VWFJvSmRkazVJM05OYVM0V1N4TkNZS05ZSUdUVjZmMnJiNGZEZXNSNXRwRkxCMHFJVk5YUjBlSllsNHBObEVORDliSVQ1eVpsOUlkaWFVWjUtU1MzOGt0T0VZeWk0RQ&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2F3yBSEsN&amp;amp;v=u_f6lvwVyfE).

Some highlights to point out:

&amp;gt;Prior to the suspect’s entry into the building at 11:33:00, a Uvalde Police Officer on scene at the crash site observed the suspect carrying a rifle outside the west hall entry. The officer, armed with a rifle, asked his supervisor for permission to shoot the suspect. However, the supervisor either did not hear or responded too late.

Prior to anyone dying there was an armed police officer on site with a bead on the shooter *after* he had fired on two civilians and into the school from the outside. He did not engage the shooter.

&amp;gt;At 11:35:55, all three Uvalde Police Department (UPD) officers entered the structure through the west door into the west hallway. These officers were equipped with the following: one with external armor and two with concealable body armor, two rifles, and three pistols.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 11:36:00, four officers entered the south hallway through the south door closest to the suspect. It is not clear what equipment these officers had with them. Four more officers entered the west hallway through the west door at 11:36:03.

Within three minutes of the shooter entering the building, there were at least *eleven* police officers in the building, all with firearms and vests of some sort. At least two, possibly more, had rifles. They do not engage the shooter.

&amp;gt;At 11:38:37, an officer outside of the hallway advises the suspect “is contained.” (BWC)  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 11:40:58, the suspect fires 1 round according to audio estimates. (ISS)  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 11:41:30, dispatch asked via radio if the door was locked, a UPD officer responds, “I am not  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;sure, but we have a hooligan to break it.” (BWC)  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 11:44:00, the suspect fires one more round according to audio estimates. (ISS)  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;LAW ENFORCEMENT RESPONSE ASSESSMENT 8  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 11:48:18, a UCISD PD officer enters through the west hallway door and states, “She says she is shot,” referring to his wife. He is escorted outside of the building.

Despite being just behind the shooter, who continues to fire intermittently throughout the standoff, the cops hole up and carefully insert their thumbs deep into their collective rectums.

&amp;gt;At 12:06:16, UPD RL notes that no Command Post is set up, advised bodies needed to keep parents out.

No one is in charge and the only concern of the cops is to keep anyone who might tackle the shooter out of the school, be it their own officer whose wife was at that moment bleeding out mere feet away, or the parents.

&amp;gt;By 12:13:00, dispatchers had received numerous 9-1-1 calls from a child explaining that there were several children and one of her teachers deceased and another teacher hurt in room 112.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 12:15:27, it appears tactical team members of United States Border Patrol Tactical Teams (BORTAC) arrive  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 12:21:08, four shots are fired by the suspect from within one of the two classrooms. (ISS)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;From 12:21:16 until 12:34:38, a continuous conversation takes place in the south hallway,  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;involving UCISD PD Chief Arredondo and a UPD officer discussing tactical options and  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;considerations including snipers, windows, and how to get into the classroom. They also discussed  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;who has the keys, testing keys, the probability of the door being locked, and if kids and teachers  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;are dying or dead. (BWC)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;From 12:37:45 until 12:47:25, UCISD PD Chief Arredondo attempts to negotiate with the suspect, speaking in English and Spanish  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;At 12:50:03, an ad Hoc team assaults room 111, neutralizing the suspect

So that&#39;s the greatest hits of the timeline. To push in on some issues we discussed previously:

Windows:

&amp;gt;The exterior walls of each classroom had two 3’ x 4’ windows near the opposing corners of each classroom (see Figure 3). The bottom of each window was approximately 3’ from interior floor level, and they were equipped with mini blinds. From the exterior, the windows were approximately 4’ from ground level.

So four windows total covering both classrooms, and at a height that a normal size man would have no trouble seeing/shooting through from the outside.

External door:

&amp;gt;on this day the door was not locked, and because it was not locked, the attacker was able to immediately access the building.

Internal door:

&amp;gt;the suspect is seen entering the room, exiting the room, and then reentering the room again prior to officers entering the building at 11:35:55. The only way to engage the lock is to insert a key from the hallway side of the door. At no point is the suspect observed entering the hallway and engaging the locking mechanism. Based upon this, we believe that the lock to room 111 was never engaged.

Jesus H. Shitfucking Christ. Then there&#39;s this gem:

&amp;gt;As noted in Figure 6, there was a window in the center of each classroom door. Officers could have utilized the window to send accurate return fire back at the suspect.

Initial attempt of the police to enter:

&amp;gt;As the officers approached the doors, the suspect began firing.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;This gunfire caused both teams of officers to retreat from the doors. We note that the officers did not make contact with the doors (i.e., they never touched any part of the doors)

This was at the point in time when they had eleven officers with at least two rifles available. Only two officers (one with a rifle) attempted to get to the door, and they both ran away as soon as rounds started coming through the drywall. The &#34;grazing injuries&#34; seem to be fragments of the wood/drywall rather than bullets.

So what should the officers have done, according to the experts?

&amp;gt;Perhaps the simplest plan would have been to push the team back down the hallway and attempt to control the classrooms from the windows in the doors. Any officer wearing rifle rated body armor (e.g., plates) would have assumed the lead as they had an additional level of protection. A team of 4 officers could have utilized the windows in the doors to control a large portion of the classroom from the hallway......  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;If the officers believed that they could not establish control through the doors, they should have found another way to stop the killing and dying. One option would have been to breach the exterior windows of the classrooms.....  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Both options a and b could have been done simultaneously. The window breaks could have been used to signal the start of the assault and draw the suspect’s attention from the doors. The window officers would stay behind the cover of the exterior wall while the door officers had priority of fire. Then the window officers could stand and cover the rest of the room.

Well fuck me running, what sort of tactical genius would it take to have thought of that?

[https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vb5h8j/culture\_war\_roundup\_for\_the\_week\_of\_june\_13\_2022/iciz2ij/?context=3](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vb5h8j/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_13_2022/iciz2ij/?context=3)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igoxug5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igo3c52/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-07-18T17:45:28Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igo3c52/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ignw4bz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Trans ideology and all it’s strands is becoming a big winning issue for the poli</title><updated>2022-07-18T16:57:53Z</updated><author><name>culprith</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Trans ideology and all it’s strands is becoming a big winning issue for the political right in the West</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ignw4bz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ignl1wi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Not sure if it&#39;s the correct thread to post this.

I remembered [this comment](h</title><updated>2022-07-18T15:45:03Z</updated><author><name>Sinity</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Not sure if it&#39;s the correct thread to post this.

I remembered [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vlopk0/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_27_2022/idwelna/) by /u/ZorbaTHut about trying to generalize the problem of (supposedly existing) people who can&#39;t understand conditionals. And I wonder if there&#39;s any connection with inability to understand pointers and recursion by some people described [here](https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2006/10/25/the-guerrilla-guide-to-interviewing-version-30/). Indirection?

&amp;gt; I’ve come to realize that **understanding pointers in C is not a skill, it’s an aptitude**. In first year computer science classes, there are always about 200 kids at the beginning of the semester, all of whom wrote complex adventure games in BASIC for their PCs when they were 4 years old. They are having a good ol’ time learning C or Pascal in college, until one day the professor introduces pointers, and suddenly, they don’t get it.

&amp;gt; They just don’t understand anything any more. 90% of the class goes off and becomes Political Science majors, then they tell their friends that there weren’t enough good looking members of the appropriate sex in their CompSci classes, that’s why they switched. **For some reason most people seem to be born without the part of the brain that understands pointers. Pointers require a complex form of doubly-indirected thinking that some people just can’t do**, and it’s pretty crucial to good programming. A lot of the “script jocks” who started programming by copying JavaScript snippets into their web pages and went on to learn Perl never learned about pointers, and they can never quite produce code of the quality you need.

&amp;gt; That’s the source of all these famous interview questions you hear about, like “reversing a linked list” or “detect loops in a tree structure.”


Through now that I checked, recursion was already covered in that 4chan post Scott referenced

&amp;gt; Other interesting phenomenon around IQ involves recursion. For example: &#34;Write a story with two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue.&#34; Most literate people can manage this, especially once you give them an example. &#34;Write a story with two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue. In this story, one of the characters must be describing a story with at least two named characters, each of whom have at least one line of dialogue.&#34; If you have less than 90 IQ, this second exercise is basically completely impossible. Add a third level (&#39;frame&#39;) to the story, and even IQ 100&#39;s start to get mixed up with the names and who&#39;s talking. Turns out Scheherazade was an IQ test!
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Time is practically impossible to understand for sub 80s. They exist only in the present, can barely reflect on the past and can&#39;t plan for the future at all. Sub 90s struggle with anachronism too. For example, I remember the 80-85s stumbling on logic problems that involved common sense anachronism stuff. For instance: &#34;Why do you think that military strategists in WWII didn&#39;t use laptop computers to help develop their strategies?&#34; &#34;I guess they didn&#39;t want to get hacked by Nazis&#34;. Admittedly you could argue that this is a history knowledge question, not quite a logic sequencing question, but you get the idea. Sequencing is super hard for them to track, but most 100+ have no problem with it, although I imagine that a movie like Memento strains them a little. Recursion was definitely the killer though. Recursive thinking and recursive knowledge seems genuinely hard for people of even average intelligence.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ignl1wi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ign9fxu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Wesley Yang is out with a short [new piece](https://wesleyyang.substack.com/p/ye</title><updated>2022-07-18T14:25:41Z</updated><author><name>Maximum_Publius</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Wesley Yang is out with a short [new piece](https://wesleyyang.substack.com/p/yes-things-are-really-as-bad-as-youve) by a leftie public school teacher who works in a blue state and a blue city but who nonetheless can acknowledge some of the craziness coming out of the woke left these days. Nothing all that new here but it&#39;s nonetheless bracing to be reminded about how deep some woke stuff goes.

The most shocking part:

&amp;gt;&#34;1) I once attended a meeting where we brainstormed strategies to increase AP enrollment. When we moved to discuss the gap in enrollment between Black and white students, a senior teacher said that trying to register more children of color for AP classes is inherently racist and that putting greater value on AP classes at all is an expression of white supremacy. To clarify: I don&#39;t mean that a senior teacher expressed a complex set of ideas regarding racial justice that could be uncharitably reduced to those claims. I mean I sat in a room where a senior teacher literally spoke the words Trying to register more students of color for AP classes is inherently racist and Putting greater value on AP classes at all is an expression of white supremacy, to an audience of other teachers who nodded along or otherwise kept quiet.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;2) I once attended another meeting - lots of meetings when you’re a teacher! - where we were working to approve a new weekly schedule for students. When I said I was concerned that it would require leaving some sections of the curriculum untaught, a colleague said that might actually be a good thing, because most of our students are white and their test scores dropping slightly would help shrink the racial achievement gap in our state. Again, to clarify: I don’t mean my colleague had a a more nuanced approach to testing that a dishonest interlocutor could twist to sound like that. I mean my colleague literally spoke those words. (To be fair, one other teacher did speak up and challenge them this time, albeit very politely.)&#34;

I don&#39;t have a ton to add here. I&#39;ve read dozens if not a 100+ articles like this in the past couple years, but they haven&#39;t stopped getting my blood boiling. What hope is there for a society captured by an ideology like this?

Sometimes I feel a little sad that I haven&#39;t had kids yet (I just turned 30). But then I think: If I had had kids earlier (and when I was more of a true believing leftist), then they would probably have been exposed to this kind of toxicity by now. At least having kids later will mean I&#39;ll know better than to let them into public schools (or for that matter even into most private schools, many of which are also woke-captured sometimes to an even greater degree than public schools).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ign9fxu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igmkq5i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] https://archive.ph/lLUbr

Reddit is now straight-up banning opinions it doesn&#39;t </title><updated>2022-07-18T10:39:41Z</updated><author><name>sp8der</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">https://archive.ph/lLUbr

Reddit is now straight-up banning opinions it doesn&#39;t like. I post this both as a warning to be ready to jump, and to provoke discussion; if one side&#39;s arguments are outlawed entirely by the rules of engagement, surely nobody can pretend that the forum is not a far-left dominated venue anymore?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igmkq5i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igmj9y6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m looking for a study that shows that teaching quality is more important for g</title><updated>2022-07-18T10:20:46Z</updated><author><name>Greenei</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m looking for a study that shows that teaching quality is more important for good students than bad students, i.e. the learning achievements of good students increase more quickly with teacher quality. Scott may have linked it once as well. Anyone know where to find it? IIRC it was an experimental study.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igmj9y6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wedne</title><updated>2022-07-18T06:14:39Z</updated><author><name>QuarkweightGOAT</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifofoo2/)

Week 3/60 is now behind me.

I fasted Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday and most of Saturday. 

Unfortunately, I had a drinking lapse. Either Thursday or Friday I justified to myself, in usual alcoholic fashion, to drink “just one last time.” The plan was to grab a “mickey” of rum (contains 8 standard drinks) for my last eating day of the week (Sunday) and factor that into total calories. I grabbed it on Saturday since liquor stores open late on Sundays which would prevent me from beginning to drink right away on the Sunday (yes, I know). Couldn’t resist the urge to have a few drinks that same day and ended up drinking the whole thing. Was very surprised by the effect. Tolerance went way down partly because I didn’t drink for a few weeks but also the fasting did a number. I grabbed another mickey earlier today. I finished drinking around 2pm EDT so pretty much sober now. I know I said I would abstain throughout this at the outset but am more committed to doing that now than before. I have derailed myself many times through drinking and won&#39;t do it for this. I will abstain 100% until the end of the 60 weeks. Words are cheap and I can&#39;t time travel but am confident in my ability to stay sober while I finish this transformation at the minimum.

Positive news. I continue to lose fat at a rapid rate. As mentioned last week, I am increasingly noticing loose skin around lower stomach in certain light. Hard to make a firm distinction between between stretch marks and sagging skin. Remaining fat around stomach also feels squishier than usual - do not know if this is a function of the density of adipose tissue itself or a loose skin issue. I unexpectedly caught the least flattering view possible of aforementioned skin a couple of days ago and was pleasantly surprised by how unbothered I was by its unsightliness.  Must say that I did not at all expect it to look that bad since I hardly notice it in most other settings yet I felt mostly indifferent. I was fixated on this concern previously because the bulk of my considerable weight gain went to my torso, the appearance of stretch marks,rapidity of weight gain, and the fact that I have an unusually slender build. 

After this leaning out phase is done I think I am going to see what can be done over the remainder of the 60 weeks about loose skin and be satisfied with the effort regardless of result. I initially undertook fasting specifically to address this concern but not sure if it helped at all. I am pretty confident in stating that it didn&#39;t hurt despite rapid fat loss. Conventional wisdom is that slow weight loss mitigates loose skin but that’s based on little more than intuition. Logic of fasting was autophagy and the body relying on excess skin as a protein source. Still mostly conjecture but whatever. Anyway, not to bothered by it so far. Maybe it will bug me more once I lose a bit more fat. We’ll see. 
Will likely apply some or all of the following measures which are purported to help with loose skin pending more research: topical vitamin c, hyaluronic acid, dry brushing, high fluid intake, moisturizing, microneedling, collagen supplementation, and of course resistance training to maybe help fill in volume. Time seems to be the most important factor but also important to temper expectations. 

Final week of fasting lies ahead. I will fast Monday, Tuesday, eat maintenance on Wednesday, and then fast for the remaining 4 days of the week. Will slowly work to maintenance the following week. I will post pictures in 2 weeks after I have eaten roughly at maintenance am a few days removed from a calorie-deprived, depleted physical state. 

Will provide update next week. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing some</title><updated>2022-07-18T05:02:13Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing something to celebrate. 

Started air-layering a couple hundred laurel starts last summer, planted them in a composted trench along the most exposed section of my frontage this spring, and only just got [the last of the weed barrier and wood chips down](https://files.catbox.moe/9hohcv.jpg).  
Total cost was about $20 for some rooting hormone and a lot of grunt work, and while it feels really good to be finished, I can&#39;t think of anything to treat myself to.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglayom/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Weird question, but does anyone having dining room chairs they recommend?   I ha</title><updated>2022-07-18T01:53:17Z</updated><author><name>bored_at_work_guy</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Weird question, but does anyone having dining room chairs they recommend?   I hate mine, but I&#39;m afraid I&#39;d hate whatever replacements I got as well.

Factors: Comfort, appearance, durability, slides across floor nicely.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglayom/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igl6cyu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What is the best physical state to be in when studying? Alone, with someone else</title><updated>2022-07-18T01:15:30Z</updated><author><name>cant-feel_my-face</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What is the best physical state to be in when studying? Alone, with someone else, at home, outside?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igl6cyu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igkfte0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What are the odds the center-left and center-right adopt the traditional gay pri</title><updated>2022-07-17T21:46:31Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What are the odds the center-left and center-right adopt the traditional gay pride flag as a way to signal opposition to the far-left positions on gender and sexuality?

It could be flown to mean *Not* The Progress Flag, but at the same time, the left would have a really hard time throwing -phobic labels at someone flying the rainbow flag.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igkfte0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjsk8b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What are your vices?

For me personally, compulsive snooping. I can&#39;t not snoop.</title><updated>2022-07-17T18:59:44Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What are your vices?

For me personally, compulsive snooping. I can&#39;t not snoop. When I start a job, I tell people, look I&#39;m a snoop, don&#39;t leave files open a file on my computer and expect me not to read it, don&#39;t leave a confidential letter open on the conference table when we&#39;re meeting there, don&#39;t have a &#34;private&#34; conversation in the car with me, I will read/listen/etc. Can&#39;t help myself. My wife and I are the same way, and as a result we&#39;ve always kept phone passwords because we just can&#39;t help ourselves and it&#39;s too much information to share.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjsk8b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjglwo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Nystrom&#39;s *Project of a New System of Ari</title><updated>2022-07-17T17:34:20Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m reading Nystrom&#39;s *Project of a New System of Arithmetic*, which makes the case for switching to a hexadecimal system for things like clocks (seems like a 16-hour day with 90 decimal minutes per hour?). Skimming it shows that he somehow applies hexadecimal to other things like music. Does not seem like anyone has ever taken it seriously, but it&#39;s short and maybe interesting.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjglwo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjflgq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I dislike earbuds with earplug-nipple-things. It seems like the brands that didn</title><updated>2022-07-17T17:26:59Z</updated><author><name>cae_jones</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I dislike earbuds with earplug-nipple-things. It seems like the brands that didn&#39;t use them might be moving in that direction, though. What&#39;s a reliable no-plug wireless earbud brand? Preferably cheap and unlikely to disappear in the next x years?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igjflgq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1y51/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Theists of the Motte, what are your thoughts on the Problem of Evil?</title><updated>2022-07-17T15:46:47Z</updated><author><name>NondualGenie</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Theists of the Motte, what are your thoughts on the Problem of Evil?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1y51/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1bj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is eating organic good for anything besides draining your bank account?

Curious</title><updated>2022-07-17T15:42:09Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is eating organic good for anything besides draining your bank account?

Curious how much of a sucker I&#39;ve been for the past ~1 year</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igj1bj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

F</title><updated>2022-07-17T13:27:30Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

For instance, if I am a feminist, it’s important to factor in the fact that people can be reared to value *either* feminist values *or* traditional values. Humans are this malleable, that they can be raised to value particular things according to what they consume and how they model rewards. Men, for instance, can be raised to value the Spartan way of life, the Athenian way of life, or the Puritan way of life. By simply changing some variables we can have people value different things.

This is important, because it means we can just think dispassionately “what is best for the whole of society”, without much care for what people happen to value at this particular point, ourselves included. I have little doubt that if I were born a Spartan I would love war and that if I were born a Puritan I would love prayer. People did not historically deviate from their culture’s values except in times of strong propaganda against the values, eg counterculture 60’s with their strong and vivid media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igifq3r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] How many people here actually own a firearm, and if you don&#39;t mind saying, is it</title><updated>2022-07-17T12:43:00Z</updated><author><name>ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">How many people here actually own a firearm, and if you don&#39;t mind saying, is it a hunting rifle/handgun/AR style whatever?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igifq3r/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ighen4v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ahmad ibn Fadlan [recounts the funeral rites of the Varangians](https://ethicsof</title><updated>2022-07-17T04:50:04Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ahmad ibn Fadlan [recounts the funeral rites of the Varangians](https://ethicsofsuicide.lib.utah.edu/selections/ibn-fadlan/):

&amp;gt; I had been told that when their chieftains died cremation was the least [sic?] part of their whole funeral procedure, and I was, therefore, very much interested to find out more about this.  One day I heard that one of their leaders had died.  They laid him forthwith in a grave which they covered up for ten days till they had finished cutting-out and sewing his costume.  If the dead man is poor they make a little ship, put him in it, and burn it.  If he is wealthy, however, they divide his property and goods into three parts: one for his family, one to pay for his costume, and one to make nabid [probably a Scandinavian type of beer] which they drink on the day when the slave woman of the dead man is killed and burnt together with her master.  They are deeply addicted to nabid, drinking it night and day; and often one of them has been found dead with a beaker in his hand.  When a chieftain among them has died, his family demands of his slave women and servants: ‘Which of you wishes to die with him?’  Then one of them says: ‘I do’; and having said that the person concerned is forced to do so, and no backing out is possible.  Even if he wished to he would not be allowed to.  Those who are willing are mostly the slave women.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; So when this man died they said to his slave women: ‘Which of you wants to die with him?’  One of them answered, ‘I do.’ From that moment she was put in the constant care of two other women servants who took care of her to the extent of washing her feet with their own hands.  They began to get things ready for the dead man, to cut his costume and so on, while every day the doomed woman drank and sang as though in anticipation of a joyous event.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; When the day arrived on which the chieftain and his slave woman were going to be burnt, I went to the river where his ship was moored.  It had been hauled ashore and four posts were made for it of birch and other wood.  Further there was arranged around it what looked like a big store of wood.  Then the ship was hauled near and placed on the wood.  People now began to walk about talking in a language I could not understand, and the corpse still lay in the grave; they had not taken it out.  They then produced a wooden bench, placed it on the ship, and covered it with carpets of Byzantine dibag [painted silk] and with cushions of Byzantine dibag.  Then came an old woman whom they call ‘the Angel of Death’, and she spread these cushions out over the bench.  She was in charge of the whole affair from dressing the corpse to the killing of the slave woman.  I noticed that she was an old giant-woman, a massive and grim figure.  When they came to his grave they removed the earth from the wooden frame and they also took the frame away.  They then divested the corpse of the clothes in which he had died.  The body, I noticed, had turned black because of the intense frost.  When they first put him in the grave, they had also given him beer, fruit, and a lute, all of which they now removed.  Strangely enough the corpse did not smell, nor had anything about him changed save the colour of his flesh.  They now proceeded to dress him in hose, and trousers, boots, coat, and a mantle of dibag adorned with gold buttons; put on his head a cap of dibag and sable fur; and carried him to the tent on the ship, where they put him on the blanket and supported him with cushions.  They then produced nabid, fruit, and aromatic plants, and put these round his body; and they also brought bread, meat, and onions which they flung before him.  Next they took a dog, cut it in half, and flung the pieces into the ship, and after this they took all his weapons and placed them beside him.  Next they brought two horses and ran them about until they were in a sweat, after which they cut them to pieces with swords and flung their meat in to the ship; this also happened to two cows.  Then they produced a cock and a hen, killed them, and threw them in.  Meanwhile the slave woman who wished to be killed walked up and down, going into one tent after the other, and the owner of each tent had sexual intercourse with her, saying: ‘Tell you master I did this out of love for him.’
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; It was now Friday afternoon and they took the slave woman away to something which they had made resembling a doorframe. Then she placed her legs on the palms of the men and reached high enough to look over the frame, and she said something in a foreign language, after which they took her down.  And they lifted her again and she did the same as the first time.  Then they took her down and lifted her a third time and she did the same as the first and the second times.  Then they gave her a chicken and she cut its head off and threw it away; they took the hen and threw it into the ship.  Then I asked the interpreter what she had done.  He answered: ‘The first time they lifted her she said: “Look!  I see my father and mother.”  The second time she said: “Look!  I see all my dead relatives sitting round.”  The third time she said: “Look!  I see my master inParadise, andParadiseis beautiful and green and together with him are men and young boys.  He calls me.  Let me join him then!”’
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; They now led her towards the ship.  Then she took off two bracelets she was wearing and gave them to the old woman, ‘the Angel of Death’, the one who was going to kill her.  She next took off two anklets she was wearing and gave them to the daughters of that woman known by the name ‘the Angel of Death’.  They then led her to the ship but did not allow her inside the tent.  Then a number of men carrying wooden shields and sticks arrived, and gave her a beaker with nabid.  She sang over it and emptied it.  The interpreter then said to me, ‘Now with that she is bidding farewell to all her women friends.’  Then she was given another beaker.  She took it and sang a lengthy song; but the old woman told her to hurry and drink up and enter the tent where her master was.  When I looked at her she seemed completely bewildered.  She wanted to enter the tent and she put her head between it and the ship.  There the woman took her head and managed to get it inside the tent, and the woman herself followed.  Then the men began to beat the shields with the wooden sticks, to deaden her shouts so that the other girls would not become afraid and shrink from dying with their masters.  Six men entered the tent and all of them had intercourse with her.  Therefore they laid her by the side of her dead master.  Two held her hands and two her feet, and the woman called ‘the Angel of Death’ put a cord round the girl’s neck, doubled with an end at each side, and gave it to two men to pull.  Then she advanced holding a small dagger with a broad blade and began to plunge it between the girl’s ribs to and from while the two men choked her with the cord till she died.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; The dead man’s nearest kinsman now appeared.  He took a piece of wood and ignited it.  Then he walked backwards, his back towards the ship and his face towards the crowd, holding the piece of wood in one hand and the other hand on his buttock; and he was naked.  In this way the wood was ignited which they had place under the ship after they had laid the slave woman, whom they had killed, beside her master.  Then people came with branches and wood; each brought a burning brand and threw it on the pyre, so that the fire took hold of the wood, then the ship, then the tent and the man and slave woman and all.  Thereafter a strong and terrible wind rose so that the flame stirred and the fire blazed still more.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I heard one of the Rus folk, standing by, say something to my interpreter, and when I inquired what he had said, my interpreter answered: ‘He said: “You Arabs are foolish.”’  ‘Why?’  I asked.  ‘Well, because you throw those you love and honour to the ground where the earth and the maggots and fields devour them, whereas we, on the other hand, burn them up quickly and they go toParadisethat very moment.’  The man burst out laughing, and on being asked why, he said: ‘His Lord, out of love for him, has sent this wind to take him away within the hour!’  And so it proved, for within that time the ship and the pyre, the girl and the corpse had all become ashes and then dust.  On the spot where the ship stood after having been hauled ashore, they built something like a round mound.  In the middle of it they raised a large post of birch-wood on which they wrote the names of the dead man and of the king of the Rus, and then the crowd dispersed.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ighen4v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igg1gya/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Got an old network attached storage device, HDD-based, that I&#39;d like to securely</title><updated>2022-07-16T21:49:02Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Got an old network attached storage device, HDD-based, that I&#39;d like to securely erase. There doesn&#39;t seem to be any low-level way to access it and DBAN it. Do you think just writing a script to fill it to the brim with txt files a few times over would do the trick? Seems like it should but curious about opinions here.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igg1gya/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igb5i4r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Anyone know any fun academic terms or concepts?

Emic and etic are used for the </title><updated>2022-07-15T20:27:42Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Anyone know any fun academic terms or concepts?

Emic and etic are used for the &#34;inside view&#34; and &#34;outside view&#34; of a group respectively.

The gnomic aspect is the tense of aphorism.

E&#39; (E-Prime) ~~is~~ means English without using the verb &#34;to be.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igb5i4r/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igac6mg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] &#34;There are reports that the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) at</title><updated>2022-07-15T17:11:47Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">&#34;There are reports that the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) at one point banned the game from the ARPANET due to its popularity.&#34;

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maze_(1973_video_game)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/igac6mg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9dgwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Adding to the theme of FFT gaming posts. There’s been talk online about [how vid</title><updated>2022-07-15T13:14:32Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Adding to the theme of FFT gaming posts. There’s been talk online about [how video games aren’t as fun as they used to be](https://youtu.be/j4QKSCushmo). The ascribed reasons vary, from differences in design to superstimuli alternatives like Tik Tok. But there’s an important element that has been missed: the fun of video games is in some sense *charged* from the boredom of everyday life. The more boredom you have habituated to in daily life, the more fun video games will be.

When childhood life around the 00’s and before consisted of boring schoolwork and activities, and you did not have the ability to find anything on YouTube and message your friends 24/7, the fun factor of video games stands out. This fun factor is relative to your default living condition. When you’re at school, simply getting free time to eat lunch and stand outside for recess is fun, or watching a boring documentary on a crappy TV. But over summer vacation this fun factor no longer stands out. Fun is relative to what we are accustomed to. And so back when life was more boring, the fun of a Halo or other game is stronger and more memorable. 

You might remember seeing your first “modern” television, and how captivating the image was. Maybe you remember when YouTube switched from 720p to 1080p. Maybe you remember recording a show on TiVo and being able to skip through commercials (!). The pleasantness and novelty of this is also relative. 

The importance of understanding this dynamic is that it proves to us a certain vanity of pleasure. A fun video game is fun, but it makes real life less intrinsically fun. A colorful dramatic television drama is engaging, but it makes our real life relationships less engaging. “Fun” is our mind being lit up by easy pleasure. Going from boring middle school life to GTA San Andreas is overwhelmingly fun. Going from modern GTA to San Andreas is no fun at all. Waking up on Christmas and playing Oblivion is fun; going from modded Skyrim to Oblivion is less fun. And don’t get me started on Chess. 

This fun differential is most evident in open world games, because the fun of the open world game is charged from real life participation; but open world games sap our pleasure from real life participation, to some degree.

This explanation is the least fun answer to the question of why video games are no longer fun. Because like a Renaissance vanitas painting it shows us clearly the vanity of games. Sum total fun was not increased in your life from your game playing, it was just transferred from real life to an artificial consumer product.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9dgwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9bzx0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What are your favorite examples of famous quotes whose meaning changes a lot in </title><updated>2022-07-15T13:02:47Z</updated><author><name>NondualGenie</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What are your favorite examples of famous quotes whose meaning changes a lot in context? Two I learned this week (coincidentally both about religion) are:

Marx’s “religion is the opium of the masses” is actually  &#34;Religion is the sigh of the oppressed creature, the heart of a heartless world, and the soul of soulless conditions. It is the opium of the people.&#34; Also opium was much more widely accepted in Europe at the time.

John Adam’s quote about how “the US is in no way a Christian nation” was from a treaty signed with Muslim Tripoli and guaranteed by the Ottomans. The full quote is: “the Government of the United States of America is not, in any sense, founded on the Christian religion,—as it has in itself no character of enmity against the laws, religion, or tranquility, of Mussulmen [Muslims],—and as the said States never entered into any war or act of hostility against any Mahometan [Mohammedan] nation, it is declared by the parties that no pretext arising from religious opinions shall ever produce an interruption of the harmony existing between the two countries.” Adams himself was a deeply religious, church-going Unitarian.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9bzx0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9bwz9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Polo shirts: tucked or untucked?</title><updated>2022-07-15T13:02:08Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Polo shirts: tucked or untucked?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9bwz9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig956er/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Been spending a bunch of time working on a homebrew D&amp;amp;D campaign. [Got rough</title><updated>2022-07-15T12:03:37Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Been spending a bunch of time working on a homebrew D&amp;amp;D campaign. [Got roughly half of it planned out now.](https://imgur.com/O1CjK2x) Got two groups that&#39;ll be starting in a couple weeks. Sort of exciting, sort of panic inducing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig956er/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig8o333/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Though I&#39;m a big proponent of video game modding, there&#39;s a part of me that miss</title><updated>2022-07-15T08:36:36Z</updated><author><name>wunr</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Though I&#39;m a big proponent of video game modding, there&#39;s a part of me that misses the era of video games where data mining and leaks weren&#39;t so prevalent and people actually had to search for secrets. Playground rumors of Sonic in Smash Bros Melee, creepypastas centered around unsettling things in otherwise cheery and colorful games, the multi-year community effort to search for [a last big secret in Shadow of the Colossus.](https://youtu.be/jQNeYbBiCKw) There&#39;s a certain magic to it all that I can&#39;t quite put into words, and I don&#39;t think younger generations of gamers will be able to experience that kind of thing firsthand. There&#39;s been an endless amount of examples in recent years where a game developer attempts to hide interesting secrets behind tough puzzles in their game only to have all the secrets datamined within hours of release.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig8o333/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheM</title><updated>2022-07-13T23:18:46Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?context=3). I did indeed start swiping on other guys on Tinder. I somehow got four matches in a couple days, and two of them didn&#39;t even ghost me immediately! We switched to Snapchat texts and everything.

...which was *absolutely exhausting*. I don&#39;t understand how people chat over text with near-strangers they&#39;re trying to possibly date. The notification sound now produces not so much butterflies as the panic response.

One guy gave me kind of pushy/weird vibes after a bit, so I blocked him, solving one problem. The other guy seems pretty cool so far. I followed TracingWoodgrains&#39; advice of suggesting an in-person meeting soon, which seemed to go over well, but he&#39;s not going to be free until the weekend, dooming me to several days of awkward texting. We might do a call soon at least.

On one hand, I hope it goes well, but on the other, I wouldn&#39;t be too upset if this connection disintegrated. Perhaps I should hold out for meeting people in-person or as friends of friends. The board game group this week involved a guy who I&#39;m pretty sure is gay; he&#39;s well outside my age range, but there being any gay guys there is progress.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig03xrr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Disclaimer: Not from the US.

Pretty bummed out about not getting a specific job</title><updated>2022-07-13T15:30:59Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Disclaimer: Not from the US.

Pretty bummed out about not getting a specific job. I applied for a a job that was exactly what I was looking for. I had the exact tech stack they were looking for as well. Pay was good too (60k no tax, without bonus, not the US so this is a good pay). 

However, as a part of the interview process, I got handed an &#34;aptitude test&#34;, which was a blatant IQ test. I have never done a real IQ test, but my scores are mensa.no (130), mensa.dk (135). Now I don&#39;t put in too much weight into those numbers but I don&#39;t think I am stupid. My IQ is probably around 120 if we go by proxies of IQ. 

I failed their IQ test hard. They didn&#39;t give me a percentile, but I got 61/100. Mind you this test was a lot harder than standard IQ tests. All the questions were 3-d instead of the normal 2-d patterns. My score was below their minimal threshold. Now are they looking for the next Einstein for a junior role, idk. But I am still quite salty about it. I know IQ has real predictive power over interviews and other proxies, so I got told straight to my face that I am not smart enough, which isn&#39;t pleasant even if you know about it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig03xrr/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] 
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble match</title><updated>2022-07-13T13:52:37Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble matches message me in the last week, despite typically getting less than one a month. I’ve been incelposting a bit more than usual lately, so maybe writing this up will provide some context for my point of view as well as allowing  others to offer perspective and point out errors in places where I may be blind.

Match number 1 was a thin blonde who opened with “How are you doing handsome?” Yellow flag. That is not something that women say to me, especially not as an opening. I’m not grotesque or repulsive(I don’t think), but I’m certainly not “handsome”, otherwise I wouldn’t be a mid 20s kv. As we continue chatting it immediately becomes clear that this person is both horny and forward with said horniness to an extent that I find very suspicious. This isn’t how I’ve known girls to act, but she doesn’t talk like a scammer or bot and her pictures seem real. It’s a work day so I try to stall until the weekend with some playful flirting. At some point she drops “I’m male but very feminine”. Mystery solved. I don’t see a “report as wrong sex” button on the app, so I just unmatch and move on. 

Match number 2 was more what I would consider “my type”. She’s a good bit overweight but has a cute face. She’s from the exurbs not the suburbs, has no visible tattoos or piercings, and overall seems to have a more conservative view of gender roles than the median woman on these apps. She sends me a “heyy” and I say hey back. No response. A few days later, after the debacle with match number 1 has played out, I admit I get desperate. I ask me friends if she’s out of my league, just to check if I’m being delusional. I get a “definitely not, go for it”. She has her Snapchat name on her Bumble profile, so I add her. We start texting on Snap. She replies very slowly, sometimes not at all, but there are a few moments where it feels like things are going well and there might be something there. 

I’ve had dating apps since my first year of college, but for most of that time I never really used them. This is the furthest I’ve ever gotten with a woman from these apps, and the furthest I’ve gotten with a woman since my not-really-a-gf gf in 8th grade that never got past holding hands. In the long breaks waiting for her replies, I notice my mental state deteriorating. It’s all I can really think about. I’ve never met her in person, but for the first time since early college I have a plausible path towards getting a girlfriend (or at least some kind of intimacy). I haven’t gotten the same butterflies when someone texts me since high school. I start checking my phone obsessively even though I have notifications on. When she leaves me on read I start to panic. I keep texting her. She never says stop, but I’m not a complete moron. I know what the most likely outcome is. At this point I almost want it just to have my sanity back. Finally she blocks me. I hate myself, but I’m free. No more obsession. It’s over. 

After writing this all out I am reminded of Scott Aaronson wanting to chemically castrate himself over fears he might harm a woman if he did not. I am not and have never considered going that far, but I do have to ask the question: Is it ethical for me to continue looking for a partner? Every woman who has ever swiped right on me either wishes she hadn’t or is indifferent. 

I’m 6’3 and make 70k a year if that’s relevant. Something is wrong with me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzla0z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anyone have advice on how to improve my text game? I do pretty well with women i</title><updated>2022-07-13T13:21:35Z</updated><author><name>disposablehead001</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anyone have advice on how to improve my text game? I do pretty well with women irl but getting them to the first date is a struggle. I also don’t have enough matches to feel like I can I get in decent practice. I was ghosted by a cool match (into Feynman and nuclear energy, be still my heart) and I’m pretty sure I made two or three errors that killed that convo. When I get my next exciting match in 3-9 months, I don’t want to fuck it up again, but I expect I will because I don’t have a way to stay in form.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzla0z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a b</title><updated>2022-07-13T11:52:31Z</updated><author><name>JosephinesOtherMan</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a baby?  Almost all of our friends moved away from our city during or after COVID.  

My wife and I traveled for a friend&#39;s engagement party (one of those friends who moved away)--it was fine.  The day after, we met up with an old friend of mine and an old college friend of hers who live there, and we had a much better time with them than we&#39;ve had with any of our friends at home in a really long time.  

... I&#39;m finding myself feeling a little sad after that for two reasons:

1. Most of our friends at home have moved away, and while it&#39;s not too hard to make little acquaintances or Jane Jacobs-esq &#34;public friendships&#34; around (especially with a baby), it seems very hard to find or develop close friendships at this point in our lives.
2. Meeting up with those old friends made me realize how distanced a lot of my friendships at home were--we were a large crew of folks who met up to have fun together, but ultimately we weren&#39;t very close (the contrast between the friends at the engagement party and the old friends the day after felt fairly extreme)

I have a handful of close friends who mean a lot to me, but almost all of them are distributed around, and we keep in touch when we can, though a lot of formerly close friendships have gotten a little less close over COVID for whatever reason too.  I vaguely worry that the only person who I can rely on is my wife (my family isn&#39;t reliable), and it scares me a little.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifz2ezj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Anything to watch out for besides oxybenzone (potential endocrine disruptor) in </title><updated>2022-07-13T10:19:49Z</updated><author><name>70rd</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Anything to watch out for besides oxybenzone (potential endocrine disruptor) in  sunscreens? Titanium dioxide was ruled [unsafe](https://www.efsa.europa.eu/en/news/titanium-dioxide-e171-no-longer-considered-safe-when-used-food-additive) as a food colorant, doesn&#39;t say anything about topical use however (this [study](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3423755/) suggests it should not be too bad.

I&#39;ve found [EWG](https://www.ewg.org/sunscreen/report/the-trouble-with-sunscreen-chemicals/)&#39;s post but am unsure how reliable of a source they are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifz2ezj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>