<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-08T13:38:22Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I re</title><updated>2022-07-08T13:38:22Z</updated><author><name>Nightmode444444</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I recently ran across an external forum that is totally fascinating. It’s a fairly large and active community of Christian polygamists. They’re not associated with a denomination (definitely not Mormon) and seems to be legitimate biblical scholars. They have reasoned their way into polygamy with carful reading of scripture. If you liked watching Big Love and want to really see how modern polygamists live. Here’s your shot. 

Some observations:

* They seems to be quite persecuted within mainstream Christiandom. As you would expect.
* They also seem to be quite intelligent and know the Bible inside and out. They can support their position quite well and it seems difficult find a flaw in their logic. As a Catholic, I can’t say that I’m an expert on scripture and the only argument I have against their logic is that The Church has taken a very diffierent view on sex and marriage. Without having The Church as an authority, I don’t know how evangelicals who stick to the Bible as ultimate authority can pin these people down. 
* There does seem to be some motivated reasoning going on here. Some posters are clearly looking to justify their lust and build a harem, but most seem to be quite sincere. 
* The community is surprisingly healthy with lots of activity and very collegial users. Reminds me of themotte in some ways. 

I find the whole thing fascinating. Besides the whole intellectual discussion of polygamy and the Bible there are quite of few gems in here. Ever want to see a bunch of Christian men painstakingly discuss whether or not lesbiansism between sister wives is a sin (spoiler: it’s not)? Ever want to see full throated defense and encorgament of patriarchy? I’ve always loved to observe these types of communities that I would otherwise not know about. Reminds me of early internet days. 

I won’t link to the the forum, but you can google christian polygamy forum and find it quite easily. 

Enjoy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcbz0w/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recommend some gems on Xbox Gamepass I can try.  Small-scale stuff is fine.  I&#39;m</title><updated>2022-07-08T13:36:53Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recommend some gems on Xbox Gamepass I can try.  Small-scale stuff is fine.  I&#39;m getting an Xbox S so I can spend more time with my brother.  So, come to think of it, good co-op campaigns are particularly welcome.

I&#39;ve played most of the classics; I think the only big single-player shooter franchise I&#39;ve never touched is Gears of War.  I&#39;ve been strictly PC Master Race or Playstation before now.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcbz0w/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifc80g8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **On not assimilating**

People here often complain that minorities coming from </title><updated>2022-07-08T13:06:03Z</updated><author><name>GrandBurdensomeCount</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**On not assimilating**

People here often complain that minorities coming from third world countries don&#39;t assimilate into western culture and keep up their own cultural traditions from back home and do not mix with the natives to any significant degree. When you tell them that white &#34;expats&#34; are just as guilty of the exact same behaviours the standard refrain is that the expats aren&#39;t going to permanently live in their new country and so it&#39;s fine, and besides they are net contributors to the economies of the foreign countries so they should be grateful of such people.

However this fails to account for the large  number of e.g. white retirees from countries like the UK that go off to spend their dotage in a place like Spain with more sun and less rain. These &#34;expats&#34; are going off to permanently live the rest of their lives in their new countries and are a net drain on public finances because of all the healthcare expenditure associated with old age. Also, the pensioner emigres also display the exact same insular behaviour of not learning the languages/creating their own internal communities they spend all their time in that third world immigrants/expats do. And yet, we do not see anywhere near the amount of criticism of this behaviour from westerners that they dispense towards minority immigrants doing the exact same stuff. To me this feels extremely hypocritical and something that should be called out.

EDIT: I&#39;m getting lots of replies in the form of &#34;pensioners don&#39;t have kids which makes it all completely different&#34; and I can&#39;t help but be reminded of a common tactic I see (principally from the left) where they say &#34;X is true&#34; and you counter with &#34;what about situation Y where X is not true&#34; and they then say &#34;but in Y there is factor Z so it doesn&#39;t count&#34; where they never ever brought up factor Z during their initial &#34;X is true&#34; statement. I think that is bad reasoning, and equally I think this too is bad reasoning, you&#39;re looking for minute differences between the situation I presented and that of immigrants to the west and saying that those differences render my argument invalid.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifc80g8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc776u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Of course this is subjective but;

I think East Asian cuisine (Korean, Chinese, </title><updated>2022-07-08T12:59:27Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Of course this is subjective but;

I think East Asian cuisine (Korean, Chinese, Thai, NOT JAPAN) is a tier above all other regional cuisines. Everytime I catch myself voraciously craving something savory or reflecting on a meal I had long after it&#39;s over, its usually from those cuisines.

I had a Korean meal (rice, kimchi jigae, banchan, spicy fried chicken) yesterday and I can&#39;t get it out of my mind. It ticked all the boxes of sweet, umami, spicy, tangy, fatty, varied textures.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc776u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc4ovs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Does anyone feel like big social media and social media adjacent companies are s</title><updated>2022-07-08T12:38:15Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Does anyone feel like big social media and social media adjacent companies are sitting on a goldmine of social science research? 

The recent conversations on Tinder/dating got me thinking that I would really like to see a plot of &#39;average x/10 rating&#39; vs &#39;match rate&#39;. My gut instinct tells me it would be a sigmoid function with the range [0,30].</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc4ovs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc3y7g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Anyone here ever listened to the podcast Decoding the Gurus?
[They have a new ep</title><updated>2022-07-08T12:31:50Z</updated><author><name>genieanus</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Anyone here ever listened to the podcast Decoding the Gurus?
[They have a new episode on Lex Friedman and Jonathan Heidt.](https://decoding-the-gurus.captivate.fm/episode/lex-fridman-jonathan-haidt-the-techno-monk-the-social-scientist)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifc3y7g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifbxzqu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] We&#39;re gonna witness a global trend of demographic decline, and have received mix</title><updated>2022-07-08T11:35:02Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">We&#39;re gonna witness a global trend of demographic decline, and have received mixed signals about its implications, to say the least. A lot of conservative demographic enthusiasts held that fertility is tied to religiosity, this [thread](https://twitter.com/akhivae/status/1543364479655755777) seeks to refute this assertion. We&#39;re also seeing declining birth rates in both India and Bangladesh. The author also argues [against](https://medium.com/@akhivae/demography-is-not-destiny-the-problem-with-demographic-reductionism-44d092f2e52c) the significance of demographics.

A counter might be that both these societies are facing a  &#34;demographic clog&#34; and home a lot more people than they could afford to. Its also worth noting that in both these countries are moving out of agriculture and more education and other resources are going to be required for children. Not to mention, abortion has been legal in India for decades now. Private schooling is also extremely expensive yet very vital for upward mobility, since the public education infrastructure is kafkaesque, which probably also limits fertility. I think demographic decline is inevitable but perhaps religiosity can slow the decline in sustainable proportions and avoid a South Korea style age quake.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifbxzqu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifbt2f0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I recall a study done by someone who followed up with people who give obviously </title><updated>2022-07-08T10:39:16Z</updated><author><name>Mantergeistmann</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I recall a study done by someone who followed up with people who give obviously wrong answers on studies (&#34;I work 30 hours a day&#34; or &#34;everyone I know is an extraterrestrial&#34;) and took down the justifications people gave a about their answers. My Google-fu is failing me here, though. Is anyone else familiar with it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifbt2f0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifase74/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Japan former Prime minister Abe has been shot , likely dead

[Shinzo Abe, former</title><updated>2022-07-08T03:36:38Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Japan former Prime minister Abe has been shot , likely dead

[Shinzo Abe, former Japan prime minister, shot during speech – report](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jul/08/shinzo-abe-former-japan-prime-minister-shot-during-speech-reports)

&amp;gt;Japan’s former prime minister Shinzo Abe is in a “state of cardiopulmonary arrest” after collapsing while making a speech, with initial reports saying gunshots had been heard shortly before he fell to the ground.

&amp;gt;NHK, Japan’s public broadcaster, said Abe – the country’s longest-serving prime minister until he resigned in 2020 – appeared to be bleeding from the chest after being shot from behind with a shotgun on Friday morning.

&amp;gt;NHK said a man had been taken into custody but provided no further details. Abe had been in the city of Nara to make a campaign speech ahead of this Sunday’s upper house elections.

The shooter has been detained but the motive is unknown. Given that he&#39;s not longer the PM, he does not seem like an important target, so it&#39;s hard to understand what the motive could possibly be. From the video on twitter , it would seem as if he had no security and the shooter simply rushed him and shot him in the back.

Japan is held up by the media as a gun control success story, yet stuff like this still happens.  it shows how the problem is not necessarily the guns but people.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifase74/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifapav5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **More drama in the Canadian Conservative party leadership race**

I&#39;ve written </title><updated>2022-07-08T03:11:24Z</updated><author><name>TheGuineaPig21</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**More drama in the Canadian Conservative party leadership race**

I&#39;ve written several posts on the troubles of Canada&#39;s Conservative party ([here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/sgv76g/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_january_31/hvg0wzx/?context=999), [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/sbg7zr/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_january_24/huo263m/?context=999), [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/k8bxy1/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_december_07/gf783sz/?context=999), and presumably elsewhere as well). They&#39;re in the middle of a leadership campaign right now, with Pierre Poilievre as the favourite. I&#39;ve described him as the Canadian equivalent of Ben Shapiro: young, scrappy, no life experience outside of politics, sort of a partisan attack dog, makes youtube compilations of owning the Libs, etc. He&#39;s primarily being opposed by two more moderate candidates: Jean Charest and Patrick Brown. All three candidates were engaged in a veritable arms race of fundraising and signing up new party members to vote.

Or I should say Poilievre *was* being opposed by two moderate candidates. The Conservative Party announced two days ago that Patrick Brown was [being expelled from the leadership contest](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/patrick-brown-ouster-vassy-kapelos-1.6512385) for vague claims of breaching the Elections Act; today a whistleblower came forward to claim that Brown was knowingly using [private funds to pay campaign staff.](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/whistleblow-brown-disqualification-payment-1.6514122)

Now this might normally be your typical scandal. But it&#39;s creating a lot of speculation because this isn&#39;t the first time that Patrick Brown has been conveniently ousted for a more &#34;true blue&#34; candidate. In 2018 he was the leader of the Ontario Progressive Conservative party heading into a provincial election he was projected to win in a landslide, when, several months before the vote there [emerged allegations of sexual misconduct](https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/patrick-brown-resigns-ontario-pc-1.4503040), and within hours his entire staff had quit. He resigned the next day despite protesting his innocence, and was ultimately replaced by Doug Ford (brother of the dearly departed Rob, and still the Ontario Premier). Ultimately the allegations against Brown all fell apart under scrutiny, and he [won a settlement against CTV News for defamation.](https://globalnews.ca/news/8670496/patrick-brown-story-ctv-correction/) (This is just gossip, but pretty much everyone in the know thinks this episode was a coup orchestrated by Vic Fedeli to oust Brown and prevent him from becoming Premier).

So for Brown to be the victim of yet *another* conveniently timed scandal raises some eyebrows. In fact, the timing is so convenient that [his name will remain on the ballots](https://www.ctvnews.ca/politics/conservative-party-not-printing-new-ballots-despite-patrick-brown-s-disqualification-1.5976994) despite being disqualified. 

I&#39;m not sure what&#39;s true in this story. I must say I have a bias towards Brown and against Poilievre, and certainly it stinks to high heaven that his is happening to him *again*. This isn&#39;t the only recent conservative leadership campaign in Canada to suffer from these kind of shenanigans; Kenney&#39;s leadership bid in Alberta featured all kinds of skullduggery and there was enough bad blood over Andrew Scheer&#39;s win for the federal party that it caused the loser(?) Maxime Bernier to start a schism. The new rules for the leadership race that strongly encourages trying to sign up as many new members as possible (legitimately or not) may be fostering all kinds of nefarious plots. In any case it makes for top-end political popcorn.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifapav5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if8qh52/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **So, what went wrong for Boris Johnson?**

Back in 2019 Boris was flying high s</title><updated>2022-07-07T18:53:47Z</updated><author><name>SensitiveRaccoon7371</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**So, what went wrong for Boris Johnson?**

Back in 2019 Boris was flying high securing a huge majority in the elections and seeing off the challenge of Corbynism. He was &#34;getting Brexit done&#34; and successfully broke through the red wall of Labour voters in middle England. With the left sinking more and more in the morass of identity politics, the conservatives were well-positioned to win the working-class voters who were fed up with woke politicians playing to the prejudices of the urban professional-managerial class. In 2020 with the spread of BLM fads in the summer of race riots in America the conservative government had successfully posed as defenders of history and tradition against the ignorant rioters. Their performance on covid was also praised because Brexit enabled the government to avoid being yoked to the inefficient Brussels bureaucracy. Given the continuing culture wars, with their leftist opponents reliably picking the wrong side, it seemed that the conservatives were poised to just keep winning.

Yet today Johnson has resigned. This came after a bunch of his ministers quit the government in the last 48 hours. Boris was stampeded to the exit by his own party, shrugging  in his resignation speech that &#34;them&#39;s the breaks&#34;. Notably for all the comparisons to Trump, this never happened to the latter for the GOP was much more house-trained under Trump than the Tories ever were under Johnson. This has already been described as a slow-moving coup perpetrated by the liberal media with their never-ending drip-drip of various &#34;scandals&#34; and &#34;-gates&#34; which panicked conservative MPs and whetted their appetites for back-stabbing once they smelled the blood in the water. Ultimately, Johnson has only himself to blame because losing control of your own party in a parliamentary system is fatal.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if8qh52/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if7s8d3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Is This the End of Newsmax and OAN?**

This is coming a bit late, but over the</title><updated>2022-07-07T15:12:53Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Is This the End of Newsmax and OAN?**

This is coming a bit late, but over the past month or so, a court in Delaware has denied motions to dismiss in Dominion&#39;s lawsuits against Newsmax and Fox News. The court hasn&#39;t ruled on a similar suit against OAN yet but, given that it is, in my opinion, the strongest of the three, I&#39;d be willing to bet that this one moves forward as well. Dominion is suing these media companies for defamation, claiming that statements concerning their Venezuelan ties, role in rigging the 2020 election, etc. have damaged their business to the tune of billions of dollars. 

The reason I&#39;m seriously wondering if these two networks are finished is because, with these rulings, Dominion has cleared the biggest hurdle of the lawsuit. When defamation involves public figures and matters of public interest (as this defamation undoubtedly does), plaintiffs must show that the defendant acted with &#34;actual malice&#34;; that is, they must prove that the defamatory statements were made either with the express knowledge that they were false or with reckless disregard for their truth or falsity. This is a tough standard to meet and is why celebrities haven&#39;t put supermarket tabloids out of business. Media companies in the United States are given pretty wide latitude to report on rumors, allegations, and other items where certainty isn&#39;t exactly bulletproof. But if they have actual knowledge that something is untrue, and publish it anyway, they can be held liable. &#34;Reckless disregard&#34; is much slipperier, but the general idea is that if you have piles of evidence that strongly suggest that something isn&#39;t true you can&#39;t just publish it without cautionary language indicating the uncertainty surrounding it. As a caution, I&#39;m only explaining all this to provide context for how this case may play out. I&#39;m not interested in debating whether it&#39;s fair that something some liberal network said should be considered defamatory, because first, these cases are very fact dependent and I don&#39;t know all the facts about hypothetical MSNBC cockups, and, second, it&#39;s irrelevant unless there&#39;s actually a lawsuit. 

Anyway, this standard is notoriously difficult to meet, mainly because most entities worth suing are sufficiently sophisticated to avoid making false statements of fact. It should also be noted that the decisions don&#39;t conclusively say that the networks acted with actual malice, simply that Dominion has alleged enough facts that a reasonable jury could conclude that they acted with actual malice. I&#39;d also note that I left Fox out of the headline because the case against them appears to be significantly weaker than the cases against Newsmax and OAN, and in any event they are more likely to be able to pay a settlement or verdict. Having failed to get a motion to dismiss, the networks can assert a number of defenses:

**Truth:** I doubt they&#39;ll actually assert this, as it would essentially involve proving that Dominion has ties to Hugo Chavez and created software designed to rig the election. If the networks had any evidence of this they wouldn&#39;t have held onto it to be used in a future lawsuit.

**Statement of Opinion:** Opinions are protected under the First Amendment. However, merely couching a defamatory statement as an opinion isn&#39;t enough to overcome a defamation claim; the courts aren&#39;t going to make it so you can get away with anything as long as you preface it with &#34;I think.&#34; This is one defense the networks are likely to assert, but proving it is going to be difficult. Given the sheer amount of coverage OAN and Newsmax gave to the Dominion allegations (with OAN seemingly airing Mike Lindell documentaries as fast as he could produce them), claiming that they were merely expressing an opinion with no intention of presenting the reporting as factual is going to be a hard sell.

**Privilege:** Occasionally, there are certain situations where one is privileged to make defamatory statements without consequence. These usually relate to official proceedings—court testimony, legislative sessions, etc. The one privilege that Newsmax, in particular, is claiming is a &#34;neutral reportage&#34; privilege that says in essence that when public figures make statements about matters of public concern, news organizations are privileged to report those allegations without fear of defamation. There are two obvious problems with this defense. The first is that it is derived from certain Circuit Court decisions that imply it&#39;s a First Amendment issue. This means that it&#39;s not a recognized common-law defense and isn&#39;t necessarily a protected constitutional right. So Newsmax is arguing that a state court should apply precedent from a Federal court that isn&#39;t even controlling over the entire Federal Court system; in effect, they want a Delaware court to give non-controlling law the force of a constitutional imperative, which isn&#39;t exactly firm footing. The second problem is that even if the court takes them up on their offer, it&#39;s highly unlikely that Newsmax meets the criteria required for protection. Without listing all the elements, it&#39;s clear that the privilege, to the extent that it exists, is intended to protect media agencies who neutrally and dispassionately report the contents of defamatory allegations without taking sides. Newsmax and OAN became All Fraud All the Time for months following the election, and repeatedly had guests like Sidney Powell repeating the allegations to sympathetic interviewers who offered little to no pushback, and in many cases parroted the allegations themselves. It&#39;s unlikely that any reasonable person could have watched either network&#39;s coverage of the election challenges for any period of time and come to the conclusion that they weren&#39;t putting forth any particular point of view. 

**Retraction:** If a defendant retracts the defamatory statements in a timely manner it will usually serve as an effective defense. This is a nonstarter her, however, since Dominion repeatedly asked the networks to issue retractions and not only did the networks refuse, but continued airing defamatory material in spite of these requests.

Given that the Actual Malice hurdle has been cleared and the available defenses aren&#39;t good, I&#39;d say that the chances of a jury verdict are pretty high. The only real question is damages, but given that they&#39;re confident in asking for over a billion dollars, even a significant reduction would still be disastrous for Newsmax and OAN. These aren&#39;t large networks with a ton of cash lying around, and this probably wouldn&#39;t be their only debt. If a jury awards a tenth of what Dominion is asking they&#39;re probably looking at bankruptcy.

The most obvious counterargument to this is &#34;If the networks&#39; cases are so bad, they&#39;ll just settle.&#34; The problem with this is that the networks couldn&#39;t offer any amount of money to make it worth it for Dominion to settle (the exception is Fox, but the case against Fox is much weaker and Fox has more money). Dominion isn&#39;t suing second-tier networks because it expects to get a lot of money. It&#39;s suing them to get vindication and rehabilitate their public image. The biggest issue for Dominion moving forward is that the taint of these allegations makes it difficult for them to get contracts. If a county is looking to replace its voting machines or renew an existing contract with Dominion, there is going to be a certain amount of public pressure to go with another vendor &#34;just to stay on the safe side&#34;. I don&#39;t know the ins and outs of every state&#39;s bidding  procedures to know if a county can be forced into accepting a Dominion contract, but if there&#39;s any room for discretion a county may opt to ignore Dominion entirely just to avoid any possible controversy. The potential damages are unknowable, and Dominion is obviously erring on the high side, and Dominion knows that it can&#39;t possibly hope to recover for all the damage the allegations did. What they can hope for, however, is that a jury verdict stating not only are the allegations unproven or lacking in evidence (as some of the Powell lawsuit dismissals implied), but are demonstrably and indisputable false. False to the point that we&#39;re making those who repeated them publicly pay large sums of money. It&#39;s not perfect, but it&#39;s probably the best Dominion can hope for.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if7s8d3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if66ryn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] short post, but are there any legitimate arguments against the genetic race/iq s</title><updated>2022-07-07T05:16:42Z</updated><author><name>SebJenSeb</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">short post, but are there any legitimate arguments against the genetic race/iq stuff anymore?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if66ryn/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if5qk02/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I developed some bad habits in my past, and now I feel trapped.  Trapped as in &#34;</title><updated>2022-07-07T02:47:13Z</updated><author><name>rekruldas</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I developed some bad habits in my past, and now I feel trapped.  Trapped as in &#34;I&#39;d be killing myself tomorrow&#34; were my parents dead. They&#39;re not, so I can&#39;t. Don&#39;t know what to do with myself.

No career, no CV, no friends. Not that I alienated them, a little of that, but mostly,  I had few friends, and they all drifted away after I dropped out of uni.  Before that, friends from high school drifted away because I went to another city for uni.No context anymore, and I felt ashamed too. I don&#39;t feel like getting to know any people. There&#39;s nothing I can offer them, and where would I get to know them anyway ? Gym ? People go there to exercise, not to socialise.

Longer re-statement of my malfunction in a reply to this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if5qk02/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if5bnke/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why are there nearly no Revolutionary War films?

I was looking for something to</title><updated>2022-07-07T00:52:26Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why are there nearly no Revolutionary War films?

I was looking for something to watch on the 4th and it seems the only (at least only big) film is The Patriot. There&#39;s also 1776 and Hamilton, but the focus isn&#39;t on the war, and then also John Adams and Turn though they&#39;re TV shows.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if5bnke/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4jc0o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **The death of the American Middle-Class**.

Much has been written about this to</title><updated>2022-07-06T21:25:57Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**The death of the American Middle-Class**.

Much has been written about this topic in terms of outsourcing or trade, but the NYT has a decent [data-rich article](https://archive.ph/m93RC) showing how US cities are increasingly bifurcated onto &#34;poor&#34; or &#34;rich&#34; areas with a disappearing middle. 

A few excerpts:

&amp;gt; And in Orlando, nearly 70 percent of area residents lived in “average” neighborhoods back in 1990, according to census data. In 2020, the same was true for just 46 percent.

&amp;gt;That leaves a lot of people feeling like they are on the outside looking in.
Michael Street is a union electrician who moved from Nashville to Goodlettsville about 25 minutes away. 

&amp;gt;He said he spent his days driving around Nashville, working on houses that have all been rehabbed, rebuilt or rendered unrecognizable in neighborhoods he can no longer afford.
“Either you’re poor, or you’re rich,” he said. “Middle class is kind of phasing out. Either you have a lot of money, or you’re just barely getting by.”

This raises a few questions. First, should we aim for a more evenly balanced income distribution in residential areas? If not, should we at least try to mix people socio-economically even if they don&#39;t live in the same neighbourhoods? This seems to be the underlying premise of the article. 

Second, is it even possible to achieve? The forces of self-segregation appear to be structural. It&#39;s an important reminder that while the US remains obsessed about race, class is often just a salient issue, if not more so.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4jc0o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4iq46/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Ask HN: I’m 41 and still unmarried – what should I do?](https://news.ycombinato</title><updated>2022-07-06T21:21:43Z</updated><author><name>Fevzi_Pasha</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Ask HN: I’m 41 and still unmarried – what should I do?](https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31961992#31970883)

A woman asked the above question to hacker news (central Internet forum for tech nerds and entrepreneurs) and the discussion is just fascinating for many reasons. Totally recommended to read all the comments at least in the first page to get a good display of how different priors and communication methods people have for such a central issue in human life. 

The whole thing made me wonder.. what should one actually say if a friend in this exact situation (assuming this lady isn’t purposefully lying about anything) asked for help? Any ideas? This forum focuses a lot on the male side of dating so I am curious</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4iq46/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if44t2h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] 
Do you you guys got any good advice for young adults in genral?

Like to how be</title><updated>2022-07-06T19:44:57Z</updated><author><name>Nerd_199</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">
Do you you guys got any good advice for young adults in genral?

Like to how better social skills/personal financial?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if44t2h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if42mlj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] On the topic of spooky culture war items, someone [blew up](https://news.yahoo.c</title><updated>2022-07-06T19:29:30Z</updated><author><name>bulksalty</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">On the topic of spooky culture war items, someone [blew up](https://news.yahoo.com/georgia-guidestones-explosion-live-large-171102114.html) one of the stone pillars that make up the Georgia Guidestones.  

For those not familiar the [Georgia Guidestones](https://creepycatalog.com/georgia-guidestones-a-complete-guide/) are a monument created by a secretive person or group that list a set of guidelines for some post apocalyptic society.  One of the most famous guidelines is to maintain the human population at 500 million.  

They&#39;ve been pretty popular in conspiracy circles since their mysterious creation.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if42mlj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white,</title><updated>2022-07-06T18:04:36Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white, just finished a master&#39;s degree, starting a career in software engineering, normal-looking (though skinny; I&#39;m working on that), and shy in large groups of new people (but alright one on one). The main problem is that I&#39;m gay in a moderate-size city in the US South, population 150,000, whose main university was recently ranked the least LGBT-friendly public university in the nation.

Due to general awkwardness and being busy during college and grad school, I&#39;ve never kissed a guy or been on a date, but girls have definitely liked me, so I think I would do alright if I could just meet some gay guys that are at least slightly nerdy. My question is then how to do that.

There are gay bars in town, but bars aren&#39;t at all my scene, I personally don&#39;t drink for genetic reasons, I&#39;m not looking for a hookup (I could just use Grindr if I was), and it just seems like my kind of guy is unlikely to be at a bar. But maybe I should try anyway?

I tried Tinder and Bumble, but the pools are so small (I exhausted them in just a couple hours) and a large proportion of guys smoke (a deal-breaker for me) or are just looking for a hookup. I got a couple matches, but they almost immediately stopped responding, which I suppose is to be expected on the apps.

To make some regular friends in town, I&#39;ve started going to a board game club. There used to be a pretty active programmers community in town, which apparently kind of collapsed during the pandemic, but I&#39;ll keep an eye on it. For some physical activity I&#39;m thinking about joining a recreational soccer league this fall.

Thoughts on any of this would be appreciated, thanks!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says tha</title><updated>2022-07-06T16:38:45Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says that some specific poor vision habits plus slightly-too-powerful glasses induce myopia, and that some other specific good vision habits plus different glasses can reverse it.

&amp;gt; In various corners of the internet there is an overwhelming abundance of anecdotal claims from people who aren&#39;t sockpuppets (I checked) that the model&#39;s interventions are effective. This is what led me to try it. A lot of the information here is based on a synthesis of the perspectives provided by people in various communities attempting this process.

https://www.losetheglasses.org/

The key idea seems to be not to over-correct your vision for your current task. If you are looking at a computer for 8 hours a day, do not wear your full strength distance glasses, but a weaker pair that are just strong enough to see the screen.

This sounds plausible and fairly cheap to try.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3cld0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Woke up at midnight, puked, had to shower to get cleaned up, restless sleep off </title><updated>2022-07-06T16:32:52Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Woke up at midnight, puked, had to shower to get cleaned up, restless sleep off and on, 101 fever.

Go online to order some comfort foods. Payment declined. Check bank, card hold, $1000+ in fraud charges. Cancel card, won&#39;t have new one for up to 2 weeks.

Anyways, send wellness please. I am out of wellness.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3cld0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if355gc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What do normal Republicans and moderates actually make of 1/6? Do they see it as</title><updated>2022-07-06T15:44:49Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What do normal Republicans and moderates actually make of 1/6? Do they see it as a riot, or as an attempted coup? Do they believe Trump deliberately instigated it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/if355gc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2tf3d/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] https://www.painscience.com/articles/pain-is-weird.php#sec_welcome

Really neat </title><updated>2022-07-06T14:26:28Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">https://www.painscience.com/articles/pain-is-weird.php#sec_welcome

Really neat article about the way pain functions. Situated a lot of things into context for me. 

Does anyone have reading recommendation talking about the way our brains act in moments of acute stress, from a somewhat larger angle? One thing I want to cultivate is calmness in times of crisis.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2tf3d/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2soy3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I need to log off. Terminally online leftists are really getting to me. Bullies,</title><updated>2022-07-06T14:21:19Z</updated><author><name>SomewhatEmbarassed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I need to log off. Terminally online leftists are really getting to me. Bullies, the lot of them. Rotten and self-righteous without any substance to back up their principles. I&#39;m tired of their justifications, because it too often results in the wrong people getting hurt by them. 
I don&#39;t want to fall victim to divide-and-distract tactics, and yet when I feel so alone in my frustrations, it&#39;s difficult to focus on more important things.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2soy3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2s33v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Is there a point where some sort of law of diminishing returns kicks in with res</title><updated>2022-07-06T14:17:00Z</updated><author><name>GrendelBlackedOut</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Is there a point where some sort of law of diminishing returns kicks in with respect to cardiovascular fitness? I hate exercising. It brings me no pleasure whatsoever. I would, however, like to have as much high quality time with my wife and kids as possible. My current cardio routine consists of running a 5k on a treadmill twice a week (typical time \~23:30-24 minutes) and a 5-mile outdoor run perhaps once every 3-4 weeks (typical time \~40-42 minutes). Is there any incremental utility in running more or could I be happy just maintaining this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2s33v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2o0jm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I say many word, when few word do trick. 

However, I cannot think of few-word u</title><updated>2022-07-06T13:47:07Z</updated><author><name>Weaponomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I say many word, when few word do trick. 

However, I cannot think of few-word until I have already said many-word. 

(For example: I have revised 5 full paragraphs into what you see here, with almost no loss of content.)

How fix?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2o0jm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2h0sf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Started getting into olympic weightlifting. It&#39;s a fun thing to organize my stre</title><updated>2022-07-06T12:51:10Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Started getting into olympic weightlifting. It&#39;s a fun thing to organize my strength training around, and the incredibly technical nature of the snatch/clean-and-jerk would probably appeal to a lot of y&#39;all. So many layers to dig into with these two moves. 

It&#39;s a great sport because it requires strength, balance, flexibility and a Motte-level obsession with analysis and details.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2h0sf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week a</title><updated>2022-07-06T07:20:30Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week as the gym is 45 minutes away.

Not great progress but programming is quite fun although taxing. My aim for this week is to workout 3 days a week and work 4-6 hours daily while ensuring I get plenty of sleep at the right time.

It&#39;s genuinely bad but still honest progress and with achievable goals.

Here&#39;s also a text exchange between me and a friend of mine that describes an event which will be the last part of my post. 

So I met my classmate who got into IIT Kanpur today for breakfast
He was here with two other dudes from his uni, one was from CS and the other from materials.
My classmate and the CS dude hadn&#39;t taken a year off like I had and they went from being wierdo nerds who were prentious to well adjusted people who&#39;d indulge in hedonism and doing well in life.
Good to get periodical reminders like today.
I don&#39;t have any girls I text for now and will keep it that way.
You&#39;re right about time man.
I can have all the fun in the world but for now, back to work.

IIT Kanpur is the best uni in the country and is above the one I go to. Both these people have gotten selected by different grad schools (UIUC and CMU respectively) with a bare minium research profile since the recommendation of faculty there matters a lot. 

My point is that there&#39;s a time and place to have fun and there&#39;s a time and place to just study, my current situation is the latter. 

I was genuinely surprised when I was able to solve programming questions and got a sense of joy doing that so shall continue. Working out is a tad hectic and people mock me for even trying since I&#39;ve been doing it on and off for the past year but would go for a week and not go again for a month due to the pajeet exam schedule. 

Anyway, have a fun week ahead.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezyfh8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **On The Concept of Male Entitlement**

As an example to get the ball rolling: [</title><updated>2022-07-05T22:03:21Z</updated><author><name>Primaprimaprima</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**On The Concept of Male Entitlement**

As an example to get the ball rolling: [Feminism and the Question of Theory](https://ravenmagazine.org/magazine/feminist-critical-consciousness-and-the-question-of-theory/)

&amp;gt;The men who engage in sexual assault are not, as the narrative goes, hapless victims of changing sexual mores. They are, at worst, pretending they don’t know that what they are doing is wrong; or, what is almost as bad, they are utterly clueless: they are unable or unwilling to listen to women because their own sense of entitlement drowns out everything else.

The concept of &#34;entitlement&#34; is frequently used in feminist discourse to explain male sexual behavior, particularly in cases of rape and sexual assault.  I am skeptical of this concept and its explanatory power, and I&#39;ll attempt to outline why.

My own personal theory is that male sexual behavior, good and bad, is largely explained by the fact that men simply desire to engage in the sexual acts that they carry out, in the same way that the fact that people eat food is largely explained by the fact that people get hungry and food tastes good.  My intention in this post is not to defend the desire theory though - it&#39;s just to critique the entitlement theory.

Actually, I&#39;m skeptical that the idea of &#34;acting out of a sense of entitlement&#34; is even coherent.  Entitlement seems to me, first and foremost, to be an objective relation that obtains between you and something else, not a psychological attitude that you take towards something else.  To be entitled to X is to be in a legal or social relation with X that grants you control over or access to X.  Your attitudes and motivations don&#39;t enter into the picture.  

Indeed, when I try to imagine thought experiments where I or someone else is primarily motivated to act by a &#34;sense of entitlement&#34;, I&#39;m not sure if I can do it.  It always seems more appropriate to use other concepts to explain the motivations instead - raw desire, or protecting one&#39;s wounded pride, or maintaining the coherence of one&#39;s self-image, or any number of things.  But it&#39;s hard to think of a scenario where &#34;entitlement&#34; seems like an appropriate psychological concept to explain someone&#39;s motivations.  Ultimately, it seems that it&#39;s just a sneer-like word, too pre-loaded with moral judgment to be explanatorily useful.

It seems more plausible to defend the idea that someone could act out of a *mistaken belief* that they are entitled to something, rather than acting out of raw entitlement itself.  These sorts of scenarios are much easier to imagine.  But is this what men actually do?  I think not.  What man actually believes that he&#39;s entitled to sexual access to women in today&#39;s Western society?  I&#39;ve seen no evidence that any sizable number of men actually believe this, but I&#39;ve seen plenty of evidence to the contrary.

Consider the discourse that circulates in &#34;manosphere&#34;, &#34;The Red Pill&#34;, and &#34;pick-up artist&#34; forums.  I don&#39;t know how you can walk away with any belief other than that these men are *acutely* aware that they are *not* entitled to sexual access to women in any way.  They become completely obsessed with the idea of self-improvement, because the only alternative in their view is dying bitter and alone.  Every day is a constant Darwinian struggle against other men for access to extremely scarce reproductive resources.  Even if they are able to secure a long-term relationship or even marriage with a woman, they are never allowed a moment&#39;s rest.  They constantly have to be on top of their game, always striving to assert dominance, otherwise their woman will leave them for Chad Thundercock at the drop of a hat.  How could anyone think that this paints a psychological portrait of an entitled individual?

Given the flaws with the entitlement theory, why are feminists so attracted to it?  I have two hypotheses:

One is a simple failure of imagination on the part of women.  In the female experience, there is no analogue of male sexual desire.  (Probably there are many feminists who reject the idea that men and women experience sexual desire differently at all).  Women have a hard time believing that men could really just want sex *that fucking much*, to the point that it drives men to do the sorts of insane and violent things that men are known for.

The second is that feminism demands a theory of male sexual desire that renders it socially mutable.  If men do what they do because of biological drives, then that means we just have to live with it, which is horrifying.  But if men do what they do because they&#39;ve been instilled with a false sense of entitlement, then we can just educate them on the appropriate way to have relations with women and everything will be fine.  So the thinking goes.  I make no judgments here - I&#39;m just outlining my thinking on why feminism is structurally predisposed to adopt certain theories over others.

Of course, I don&#39;t think that male sexual behavior *entirely* reduces to basic biological desires.  Certainly sexual behavior can be rooted in other motives as well, like social validation.  But I&#39;m skeptical that entitlement has a role to play in the overall picture.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezyfh8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezttog/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In other news, [a large farmer&#39;s protest is going on right now in the Netherland</title><updated>2022-07-05T21:31:36Z</updated><author><name>tricksandcandlewicks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In other news, [a large farmer&#39;s protest is going on right now in the Netherlands](https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/dutch-farmers-protest-by-blocking-supermarket-distribution-centres-2022-07-04/). This bears a similarity to the trucker&#39;s protests in Canada in the mode of operation - large vehicles blockading key roads and chokepoints. The difference here is that the issue they are protesting is much more directly threatening their livelihoods - the Dutch government wants farmers to reduce livestock counts and fertilizer use to reduce Carbon emissions. Naturally, this would be a great blow to the farmer&#39;s incomes and ability to keep the surrounding areas well fed.

In fatter times, I would expect that the Dutch government and the EU could easily get away with crushing this kind of protest. When Europe is already reeling from supply chain issues and the declining availability of cheap Russian gas and covid overregulation harming business, this seems more and more like it could start seriously harming the camel&#39;s back. If people start going hungry and the German economy collapses, that&#39;s probably the end of the EU. 

Speaking as an American, though, I have no idea what local reactions to this protest are - would like to hear some. Or steelmanning all of the recent decisions made by European politicians in regards to climate and energy policies and Russia - these in concert completely baffle me in their capacity for self destruction.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezttog/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iez9pon/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There are many, many valid reasons to oppose the overturning of Roe. But I think</title><updated>2022-07-05T19:16:52Z</updated><author><name>Texas_Rockets</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There are many, many valid reasons to oppose the overturning of Roe. But I think it’s dangerous and inaccurate to frame this solely as women’s rights being taken away. That’s absolutely an element, but we need to be cognizant that we’re not just talking about a Pap smear here. Framing this as only being an issue of womens rights necessarily means that anyone who supported the ruling is literally just out there to rescind the rights of women. And that misses that, ultimately, abortion laws are about at what point a fetus becomes a life, and therefore at what point it becomes wrong. Most people agree that late term abortions are wrong, so I think most concede that to some extent. But those who supported this ruling did so because they think that a fetus is a human almost immediately. To me this really just illustrates the detrimental and all-consuming impact of identity politics, in which everything is viewed first and foremost with respect to one’s identity. There are important factors outside of that and that is not always the primary consideration. 

Really, though, what I want to drive home is that viewing this solely in terms of women’s rights guarantees that you miss the other sides POV and necessarily means they are just evil people. And failing to consider this ensures that this debate is never actually going to reflect the real issue here. People are just going to view it as good v evil. And I wanna be clear here and say that I am not defending those who supported the ruling.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iez9pon/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieywk50/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ####Illiteracy of Christianity

Apologies for the rambling tone.

I recently sta</title><updated>2022-07-05T17:49:38Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">####Illiteracy of Christianity

Apologies for the rambling tone.

I recently started playing *Wasteland 3* and been having a lot of fun. Early on in the game, there is [a cover](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXeHwhLPKz8) of the Christian hymn [*Are You Washed in the Blood?*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Are_You_Washed_in_the_Blood) that plays as part of a dramatic setpiece battle. I found the cover really quite catchy, and went to listen to it outside the game and find the original hymn (I hadn&#39;t heard it before). Apparently I wasn&#39;t the only one who enjoyed the song and many other Wasteland 3 players did the same. However, I found their comments on the &#39;genuine&#39; renditions by actual Christian artists to be very strange to me. They frequently describing the tone and lyrics (and the Youtube comments of Christians) on the song as &#39;creepy&#39; or &#39;cultish&#39;.

It&#39;s obvious why people find the Wasteland 3 version creepy. It&#39;s a pretty sinister sounding rendition and you hear it when you the player are fighting a post-apocalyptic inbred redneck cult family while destruction and blood surround you. The &#39;genuine&#39; versions are more tricky. Clearly [many Christians listening to the hymn](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJWgpljckbA) don&#39;t feel it&#39;s creepy, but fulfilling and positive.

Maybe the non-Christians finding it creepy have a point. Lyrics like &#34;washed in the Blood of the Lamb&#34; and &#34;are your garments spotless&#34; do sound very strange or creepy devoid of any context. But these lyrics *aren&#39;t* devoid of context, it&#39;s clearly a Christian hymn. Rather, non-Christians (secularized Americans) don&#39;t *understand* the context. They don&#39;t know what the &#39;Blood&#39; or &#39;Lamb&#39; means or represents. They are illiterate of the language of Christianity. As a cultural/lapsed Catholic, I wouldn&#39;t consider myself *fluent* in &#39;Christian&#39;, but I&#39;m certainly literate enough that I don&#39;t find the lyrics of the song creepy and can easily understand their meaning.

It&#39;s like hearing an idiom literally translated from another language. e.g. the Swedish idiom &#39;*to shit in a blue cupboard*&#39;. Removed from its linguistic and cultural home makes it sound like the Swedes are crazy. There was an image that reached the front page of reddit recently of [an ethnic group in Indonesia that exhumes their ancestors&#39; bodies to dress them up and spend time with them](https://old.reddit.com/r/interestingasfuck/comments/vqeptq/the_toraja_people_in_indonesia_periodically_dig/), something that would seem absolutely ghastly and creepy to many Westerners despite being a positive and joyous event for this ethnic group.

This is not really a brand new thought for me, but rather this was just a crystalizing event. I recall a [public lecture from Camile Paglia](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nvmTHQviAHM) where she describes teaching a class 15 years ago on the art of song lyrics where she was playing the hymn &#39;Go Down Moses&#39;. After a lack of engagement from the students, she came to the shocking revelation that virtually none of the students knew who Moses was. Seemingly the only engagement contemporary secular America has with Christian themes is negative, cynical and superficial portrayals in media. Typically some evil redneck evangelical doomsday cult that serves as than antagonist who is more that happy to use Christian symbols in their evil plans. Obviously *Wasteland 3*, but media like *Farcry 5* or the Netflix movie *The Devil All The Time* and many others. Sure, Americans might know some superficial details, like Christmas being the celebration of Jesus&#39; birth, but they have no real understanding of Christianity.

The reason I think this is important for the US (and its cultural sphere) is it renders secular Americans unable to communicate, understand and ultimately find common ground with American Christians, who still make up a sizable portion of the US population. I don&#39;t believe this was the case in the past (though I have no strong evidence), where secular individuals or even atheists understood Christianity in the broad sense, being an important part of American life. It also breeds hostility, as there is a tendency to view people one cannot understand with suspicion (exacerbated with the negative portrayals of Christianity in media). I also suspect this illiteracy is largely unidirectional too, as most Christians are exposed to the glut of secular/liberal media that exists.

Edit: Just to add an addendum, I do wonder what the consequences of this are. A lack of understanding of the cultural history of the West, a lack of understanding of the most influential moral system in the word, is this a void that secular religions are rushing to fill? Is America truly culturally secular now?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieywk50/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iey8d9l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;m seeing some discussion of [this paper](https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full</title><updated>2022-07-05T15:09:58Z</updated><author><name>naraburns</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;m seeing some discussion of [this paper](https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/00323292221100220) popping up on [Twitter](https://twitter.com/MattGrossmann/status/1544319680441098240/photo/1), and I think some of you might be interested (though you&#39;ll need SAGE database access if you want to read the full thing).

As the political scientist who shared this notes:

&amp;gt; Across 21 countries, the left has lost most support among low education, high income voters. Left gained most among high education, high income votes, but only reached parity there. So left support is now concentrated among high education low income voters.

I&#39;ve skimmed the paper, and it does not appear to raise any discussion of Peter Turchin&#39;s [elite overproduction](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elite_overproduction), but I feel like that is the natural direction to take the research.  Here is a bit from the conclusion:

&amp;gt; The emerging party positioning in the policy space has led to a deteriorating partisan representation for high-education/high-income and--especially--low-education/low-income citizens. While liberal parties in some countries adopted right-libertarian positions that are attractive to high-education/high-income voters, the main party on the right typically drifted toward authoritarian positions. Low-education/low-income voters fared worse: in no country [of the 21 studied] do viable left-authoritarian parties exist. Without obvious political homes, therefore, the low-education/low-income and high-education/high-income groups have become cross-pressured voter groups--up for grabs--between the left and right fields of parties.

Of course, many people live in countries ruled by left-authoritarian parties; most of those people are Chinese.  I doubt many will be surprised to hear that wealthy democracy is incompatible with redistributionist authoritarianism; to me it sounds like a clear contradiction in terms.  But the specific data on how &#34;polarity reversal&#34; happens *given* cross-pressured voter groups seems interesting.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iey8d9l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexyxng/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I don&#39;t know where else on Reddit to put this so it&#39;s going here: Every argument</title><updated>2022-07-05T14:02:43Z</updated><author><name>CoventryDemon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I don&#39;t know where else on Reddit to put this so it&#39;s going here: Every argument about abortion that I&#39;ve seen both the Right and the Left use is utter garbage. 

The right:

* No. The left is not out to &#34;kill babies&#34;. (see below under the left)
* The bible doesn&#39;t ban abortion and nor should your religion dictate what others do.
* The idea that a clump of cells is a person is ridiculous. 
* In Ohio, right wing policymaking just denied an abortion to a raped ten year old. 
* Preaching adoption and then not adopting any kids smacks of hypocrisy. 

The left: 

* The people on the right believe that abortion **kills a baby**. The folks on the left don&#39;t agree with that, but insist on ignoring this motivation. I cannot tell you how disingenuous this is. &#34;Your motivation isn&#39;t what you say it is, but instead is whatever I get to define it as&#34;. It is nothing more than the other side of the coin to &#34;the left is out to kill babies&#34;. Taking the worst argument of the right and inverting it is unforgiveable. 
* Your body autonomy arguments are all incoherent. Each and every one of them is perfectly cogent so long as you assume the fetus inside you isn&#39;t a person. The right has already assumed the fetus is a person so the argument is a non-starter. To the right, it&#39;s like saying, &#34;If I was at the edge of the cliff and someone was hanging onto my arm so as not to fall into a chasm and die, it&#39;s TOTALLY not murder for me to shake them off my arm. Because it&#39;s **my** arm and they&#39;re not allowed to use it!&#34; It&#39;s an echo chamber argument that has zero chance of convincing the opposition. 
* Instead of spending the age of social media trying to win over hearts and minds, you have taken every opportunity to silence yourself to the people who need your voices the most. How many times have we seen &#34;If you agree with \[insert right wing policy\] then unfriend/unfollow/etc. me!&#34; You should have been working to reach people this whole time, but you didn&#39;t.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexyxng/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexrshj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A short bit of [anecdata](https://thenewdaily.com.au/opinion/2022/07/02/the-stat</title><updated>2022-07-05T13:05:16Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A short bit of [anecdata](https://thenewdaily.com.au/opinion/2022/07/02/the-stats-gug-indigenous-census/) from Australia about the rise of self-identification among aboriginal Australians.

&amp;gt;One figure, more than anything else, jumped out at me. Australia’s Indigenous population went up steeply to 813,000 people (3.2 per cent of the population).  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;This increase of 25 per cent compared to 2016 data is huge. Obviously, this increase can’t, by definition, be driven by migration and wasn’t the result of an outrageously high birth rate either. Rather, more people self-identified as Indigenous on the census form.

This is a wonderful thing:

&amp;gt;We collectively created an environment where more people are confident enough to proclaim their heritage loudly and proudly.

But, of course, they run into the Warren Paradox.

[https://cphce.unsw.edu.au/news-events/news/2017/01/introducing-chetres-new-indigenous-health-lead-suzanne-ingram](https://cphce.unsw.edu.au/news-events/news/2017/01/introducing-chetres-new-indigenous-health-lead-suzanne-ingram)

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lidia\_Thorpe](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lidia_Thorpe)

[https://womensagenda.com.au/latest/10-indigenous-women-blazing-a-trail-in-australia-today/](https://womensagenda.com.au/latest/10-indigenous-women-blazing-a-trail-in-australia-today/)

[https://edition.cnn.com/2017/03/05/asia/her-linda-burney-australia/index.html](https://edition.cnn.com/2017/03/05/asia/her-linda-burney-australia/index.html)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexrshj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iexr7y5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] There was a post here some time ago about the ever-increasing health catastrophe</title><updated>2022-07-05T13:00:20Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">There was a post here some time ago about the ever-increasing health catastrophe that awaits a culture which only produces 1-3 births. The argument was that there are too many immune and genetic problems being introduced into the population, since all births have a higher chance of living into teenage years, whereas historically about half died in childhood. The children that died historically were the most ill. Then you have fewer generally dying from disease. Then there are not enough maximally healthy people producing children, whereas in the past they might produce a dozen.

This was very persuasive to me, but I don’t know any data. It seems reasonable that to maximize genetic health you want (1) the least healthy not producing and (2) the most healthy producing exponentially. We see with all animal. I’ve been seeing it occur outside my window, as a single house wren family has birthed four babies each of the past four seasons. Of their 16 kids, surely not all are expected to continue living, and probably only a few would continue exponential birthing. 

Anyway does anyone have any relevant information to this question?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iexr7y5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iewbcpg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ## Followup Monday

A [while ago](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ijs</title><updated>2022-07-05T02:53:17Z</updated><author><name>SlightlyLessHairyApe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">## Followup Monday

A [while ago](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ijs526/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_31_2020/g40dx0u/) u/mcjunker opined that in 18 months after election, Biden would be less popular than Trump. 

In retrospect, it&#39;s not clear if this was meant as &#34;at the same point in their presidency&#34; or &#34;at that moment&#34;, although I lean towards the former since approval ratings of those not in office isn&#39;t usually a topic of discussion. 

In that case, this seems to be narrowly [coming true](https://www.cookpolitical.com/analysis/national/national-politics/two-different-paths-41) by a few percentage points, just barely enough past the margin of error on the polls to call it anyway.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iewbcpg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieuxana/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I love reading and thinking about the future of robotics and artificial intellig</title><updated>2022-07-04T20:10:04Z</updated><author><name>MustPavloveDogs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I love reading and thinking about the future of robotics and artificial intelligence, and am a fan of works such as Blade Runner/Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?, iRobot, and other media that explores the possibilities of artificial intelligence. I don&#39;t have the most sophisticated understanding of them, but I enjoy discussing them with others.

Assuming that 1) We develop androids that can pass the Turing Test and 2) Humanity doesn&#39;t destroy itself before we reach this point, how do you imagine the fight for android rights, the possible &#34;final frontier of civil rights&#34; playing out?

It occurred to me that future discussions on android rights could mirror current discussions on transgender rights.

(NOTE: I am NOT at all trying to compare trans people to robots or imply that trans people aren&#39;t human. I&#39;m only comparing the discourse around their treatment in society.

Also NOTE: I&#39;m using the term &#34;androids&#34; mostly, but if you&#39;d prefer to focus on AI as a separate thing, that&#39;s fine with me)

I imagine one argument against androids being given the same rights as humans would boil down to:

*&#34;They&#39;re not really humans, they&#39;re only acting how they think humans behave.&#34;*

Replace &#34;humans&#34; with &#34;men&#34; or &#34;women&#34; and you&#39;ve got one of the most common complaints in the current &#34;trans rights&#34; discourse.

Assuming we can get through the [Uncanny\_Valley](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncanny_valley) and create androids that look identical to humans in addition to sounding like them--in other words, &#34;passing&#34; as human--how does that affect the discussion? Would it be better to have androids that don&#39;t look too human, or would that negatively impact their chance for greater rights?

A few other questions to consider:

\- Will &#34;robosexual&#34; and &#34;robophobia&#34; become mainstream terms?

\- Will the robots destroy us all before we even get to that point...or perhaps will the debate lead to them destroying us?

\- Would you be a human ally to android activists?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I thought this would be a good place to have an intelligent, honest discussion. I hope it&#39;s enjoyable for everyone.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieuxana/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieutf9m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I was at the doctor&#39;s office the other day, and I saw a curious poster on the wa</title><updated>2022-07-04T19:41:55Z</updated><author><name>urquan5200</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I was at the doctor&#39;s office the other day, and I saw a curious poster on the wall. I can&#39;t remember the organization that sponsored the poster, and unfortunately I can&#39;t find it online, but I remember the concept it promoted: it was about **moral injury**, which is an idea I&#39;d never heard of before. I looked it up, and apparently [the core concept](https://moralinjuryproject.syr.edu/about-moral-injury/) is about war:

&amp;gt; Within the context of military service, particularly regarding the experience of war, &#34;moral injury&#34; refers to the lasting emotional, psychological, social, behavioral, and spiritual impacts of actions that violate a service member’s core moral values and behavioral expectations of self or others.

In other words, it&#39;s the deep spiritual and psychological damage that happens when soldiers are ordered to do things that conflict with their personal moral codes: killing people, taking actions that lead to civilian casualties, having to abandon friends on the battlefield to accomplish the mission. Serious, earth-shattering things like that. Some of the deepest horrors of war.

But the poster I saw wasn&#39;t about the experiences of veterans or the terror of the battlefield. It was about &#34;a nurse who feels ashamed of having a medical condition because she&#39;s a nurse.&#34;

To me, this feels like a substantial deviation from the original definition of &#34;moral injury.&#34; An &#34;injury to pride,&#34; maybe. Or perhaps it&#39;s best described as a psychological struggle with unnecessary shame. I&#39;m not saying that a medical professional being ashamed of having a medical condition is a good thing, that there shouldn&#39;t be therapies and programs that help people overcome this unnecessary shame and stigma, or that having posters in doctor&#39;s offices promoting awareness of this problem is a bad idea.

All I&#39;m saying is, maybe it&#39;s not such a good idea to use the same term to describe this phenomenon that we use to describe soldiers facing the terrible moral horrors of warfare.

I know the medical field is hard. Sometimes earth-shatteringly hard. I know it can sometimes feel like a war-zone, a constant fight against death and injury that can never be won, a perpetual Afghanistan withdrawal. I also know it can be especially hard on nurses, who do so much to keep our hospitals and clinics going and are often under-appreciated (is that too much of a cliché?). I know that the job&#39;s so hard that we have a [major nurse shortage](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK493175/) in part due to high rates of burnout. And I know medical professionals often have to deal with belligerent patients, and sometimes they have to take actions -- like restraining or sedating a delirious patient, or holding someone against their will for a psychological evaluation -- that would be unacceptable in normal life.

But it just feels wrong to me, equating the experiences of people in a profession whose cardinal rule is &#34;first do no harm,&#34; with a profession whose cardinal rule, as set out in international law, is [&#34;well you can harm *some* people&#34;](https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2018/06/28/621112394/the-rules-of-war-are-being-broken-what-exactly-are-they). Especially when what&#39;s being compared isn&#39;t the experience of violating one&#39;s moral code and finding one&#39;s ethical conception of the self and maybe even the world being shattered, but the personal shame of a nurse who feels like having a serious illness is unfitting for her. (I use a female pronoun not to claim that all nurses are women, although the [vast majority in the United States](https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/hr/gender-ratio-of-nurses-across-50-states.html) are, but because the original poster I saw depicted a woman as the nurse in question.)

This feels part and parcel of a social tendency that concerns me: the &#34;social traumatization&#34; of society, where more and more life experiences are described in terms of trauma and in increasingly intense ways.

Medical professionals experiencing shame because of a personal diagnosis is a problem, and it&#39;s a problem I hope they&#39;re able to receive help for, so they can move on with their lives and receive proper treatment for the physical ailment. But although it&#39;s a problem, it&#39;s not an &#34;I had to kill a man to survive in the trenches, it was either him or me&#34;-level problem.

Removing the terminological distinctions between these things, I believe, eliminates essential social and psychological information that helps people contextualize their negative experiences and find peace in overcoming them.

automod_multipart_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieutf9m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ietsysm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there a compilation of all the discussions on this sub on urbanism and cars? </title><updated>2022-07-04T15:25:03Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there a compilation of all the discussions on this sub on urbanism and cars? Or just some links for me to read through. 

I want to start off with this subs pov because it seems to be a somewhat one-sided politically charged topic and there are a lot of sneaky politics on what should be otherwise objective discussions on the pros and cons of different types of design.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ietsysm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iesmh8u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Appropriate for the date:

Does anyone have any idea how my parents (in their ea</title><updated>2022-07-04T07:58:44Z</updated><author><name>Capital_Room</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Appropriate for the date:

Does anyone have any idea how my parents (in their early 60s), and some others their age, came by their belief that the American Revolution was fought — and won — entirely or almost entirely by independent, disorganized individuals armed only with their hunting rifles, slipping through the woods in primitive camouflage, picking off the British who &#34;were sitting ducks, standing in the open in neat lines wearing their bright red coats, like morons,&#34; and said British doing nothing but impotently protesting &#34;that&#39;s just not cricket!&#34; as these lone Patriots violated all the contemporary &#34;rules&#34; of war — &#34;were terrorists,&#34; as my Mom put it? In short, that the Revolution was fought and won through lone-wolf terrorism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iesmh8u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq8zqf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] (Not really a question.) I think as I’ve gotten older, I’ve realized that the pr</title><updated>2022-07-03T18:54:31Z</updated><author><name>2cimarafa</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">(Not really a question.) I think as I’ve gotten older, I’ve realized that the primary reason (at least intellectually, I make no claim to deeper analysis of my subconscious motives) for my continued general agnosticism is that the concept of an afterlife (or really reincarnation or eternal life in any form) just seems too good to be true, and tailor made to what seems like a fundamental human desire for permanence in a world in which none exists. 

This is a relative of, although not quite identical to, the old le atheism “why should your god *specifically* be the one” line of questioning, but it isn’t really meant as a gotcha. Only that it should seem awfully convenient, terrified of death that we are, that life (in some form) goes on. I am quite confident that higher powers than ourselves exist in our universe. They may even care what happens here, though I’m less certain of that. But that they should be so attuned to taking care of our greatest fear would appear to be a stroke of luck too far.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq8zqf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq4k4r/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m rereading Gibson&#39;s *Neuromancer*. It has been a w</title><updated>2022-07-03T18:22:07Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m rereading Gibson&#39;s *Neuromancer*. It has been a while, but Armitage still haunts my imagination every now and then. Gibson&#39;s obsession with the materials things are made of can make it an odd and slow read, but it is one of the best.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieq4k4r/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iepzcui/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Bought a new evaporator fan motor for my fridge because the old one was noisy. F</title><updated>2022-07-03T17:44:25Z</updated><author><name>ShouldHaveVotedGore</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Bought a new evaporator fan motor for my fridge because the old one was noisy. Fixed the problem but I&#39;m slightly concerned that the old one had a third wire that connected to the metal housing, while the new one lacks this wire. Is this any sort of hazard?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/iepzcui/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoyoma/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Looking for history book recommendations. I&#39;m trying to read more real books and</title><updated>2022-07-03T13:11:14Z</updated><author><name>dalinks</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Looking for history book recommendations. I&#39;m trying to read more real books and history is always fun. I&#39;m open to any really good books, but I&#39;d specifically like

* Rome (Been rewatching Rome on HBO Max)
* Indian history, esp Partition. Thats a big blank spot on my history knowledge
* Economic history is fun. I always enjoy hearing about the behind the scenes factors that led to our modern world.

I usually prefer larger scope to smaller, though there have been notable exceptions. Not usually into biographies but willing to give them a shot.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoyoma/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoufhi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Would you prefer to die after being completely bedridden for 20 years or being c</title><updated>2022-07-03T12:28:27Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Would you prefer to die after being completely bedridden for 20 years or being completely demented for 20 years? Assume no other options, including suicide, are possible. Does the answer change if the question is about your parents?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieoufhi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and ma</title><updated>2022-07-03T12:03:27Z</updated><author><name>mustardEconomics</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and marry someone?

---

For most of my adult life, I wasn&#39;t really interested in romance, relationships, or women in general. This has recently changed. I&#39;ve grown increasingly interested about the idea of falling in love and marrying someone. There are a number of reasons for this. Lately, more and more frequently I&#39;ve been feeling unhappy about being alone and lacking connections, and I like the idea of someone genuinely feeling attracted to me. I sometimes feel like my current life is pointless overall; creating a family and fathering children feels like a good way of making myself feel that I&#39;ve amounted to something. And, to be honest, I want to actually share my sexuality with another living person. 

On the other hand... I&#39;m pretty introverted. Social interaction exhausts me quickly. There are days where, after having to endure others&#39; company for many hours, I just want to spend an entire evening without hearing another person&#39;s voice. Now, I&#39;m not *bad* at social interaction: When I need to, I&#39;m good at talking with people, acting smooth, suave, and confident. But it tires me out fast. And, to me, it always feels like I&#39;m putting on an act, pretending to be someone I&#39;m not. 

This makes me worry if marriage is really a good idea for me. Social interactions wears me out, but if I got married, I suppose I&#39;d need to socially interact with my wife (and later children) all the time. Getting to be alone would become the exception rather than a daily occurrence. It might make me miserable rather than happy. 
Also, while I&#39;m confident that I can get a woman interested in me by charming and intelligent conversation, I&#39;m scared of accidentally deceiving her. She might get the false idea that I&#39;m *always* a smooth-talking charmer, and will be disappointed to find out I&#39;m an introvert who doesn&#39;t really like talking much. 

So my question is, are these desires compatible? Should I aim for marriage if I find social interaction to be tiresome work? Perhaps some of you have experience with being married (or otherwise in a permanent relationship) while introverted?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieo612g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Took a flight yesterday.  I feel like you have to be almost 40 now to remember t</title><updated>2022-07-03T06:54:57Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Took a flight yesterday.  I feel like you have to be almost 40 now to remember this; but remember inflight meals?

Serving meals on flights makes absolutely no sense, but at the same time I kind of miss it.  It had to be expensive to serve meals on flights because it’s literally added weight and taking up expensive space.  No one on the ground would pay the price I think it costs.  My guess is $20-30 a meal.  They are sort of like MRE for the military.  Very specific portion sizes.  Supposedly the portion size that a person is suppose to eat; which is smaller than what eat but then you had more courses than I eat.

From nostalgia perspective the food was different than what you would buy on the ground.  It was optimized to taste ok in the air.

The economics of why we got rid of that are obvious.  No one is willing to pay $30 for an in flight meal that’s terrible compared to ground food.

And yes I know you can still fly first and get that, but it use to be any 3 hr flight.  And now we have an entire generation that has never experienced bad but interesting in flight meals.

And how I know it’s bad economics for in flight meals - would anyone pay $35 a person if I opened a restaurant with airline food?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieo612g/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>