<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-21T01:17:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il4zgw1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Obituary #3.

Darya Dugina, the daughter of the philosopher and Culture Warrior </title><updated>2022-08-21T01:17:30Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Obituary #3.

Darya Dugina, the daughter of the philosopher and Culture Warrior [Alexander Dugin](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleksandr_Dugin) whom I&#39;ve been sporadically translating here over these years, was killed some hours ago. Maybe it&#39;s a traffic accident, but then it seems to be [of the explosive kind](https://www.thedailybeast.com/darya-dugina-daughter-of-putin-propagandist-alexander-dugin-killed-in-car-bomb-reports-say).

She was a member of the «International Eurasianist movement», with all that entails (e.g a LARPy black robe with a golden Chaos star); she was supporting the «special military operation», and got added to American and UK sanction lists. But she likely wasn&#39;t the target: her father ^1 was expected to be in the Toyota Land Cruiser she was driving on Mojaiskoe highway near [Bolshiye Vyazyomy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bolshiye_Vyazyomy) in the Moscow Oblast. They were returning from a certain «Tradition» fest.  

Being a high-profile Russian Nationalist is a reliable way to cut your life expectancy. Igor Shafarevich had made it to 93, dying in 2017, but he had always been built differently. In the two Covid years preceding the Z day, it&#39;s been getting rough. Eduard Limonov: March 2020, 77. Konstantin Krylov died in May 2020, aged 52, from a stroke. Maxim Martsinkevich [got suicided](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/iseo9j/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_september_14/g5n3d1i/) in prison in September 2020; he was 36. [Egor Prosvirnin](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/rphmgp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_december_27/hqq1tfi/), as I&#39;ve reported before, had flown out of the window and crashed into the asphalt on December 27th, 2021, at 35. Darya was 30.  
I&#39;m reading another Darya sometimes: Kozeko, Yale-educated, @digitalgonzo96 (account inactive). She comments on boylove fiction and local sushi restaurants, opportunistically wages «information warfare» and complains about shelling noise and water supply breakdowns. She&#39;s living in Donetsk. Probably I won&#39;t be reading any new Kozeko at some point in the not too distant future.  

As for Dugina, the obvious suspicion falls on Ukrainian agents, aided by Western intel, or perhaps on their local sympathizers. Ukrainians have demonstrated their capacity to carry out assassinations *on the outskirts of Moscow* [years ago](https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2016/09/20/ukrainian-separatist-murdered-in-moscow-restaurant-a55399) – though Russia pointedly refuses to consider that one politically motivated. 

Logically speaking, Galkovsky&#39;s family is next. Holmogorov, Krasovsky or Prilepin are more immediately deserving, but they&#39;re more directly state-affiliated, and thus presumably harder targets. Maybe Olshansky, Kashin and some other journalists of that sort are on the kill list. ^2

I wonder if they&#39;ll come for translators. 

More generally, I think this should be taken as a good message for reactionaries and conservative contrarians everywhere, TradCaths, groypers, alt/dissident-rightists of whatever is the current euphemism; all sorts of political Platonists who think and act as if the world can bend to their mind, like Dugin&#39;s sensei and alchemist Golovin taught. A very old-school, Kipling-style message, in the case QANON, Jan 6th and its consequences weren&#39;t enough for everybody over there.  
You&#39;re not playing games when you exercise your wordsmithing ability in public. Be cautious of your wishes coming true. This world is physical and unforgiving, an arena where sober-headed causality engineers wrestle with brute chance, emergent complexity and each other; posing as Gigachads and portraying your better-organized opponents as crying Soyjaks will earn you nothing but misery in the long run. Wars are won not with spirit and meme magic and Idealism but with boring stuff like skills, manpower, logistics and strategy. Including wars of the mind! When you fight a war, even a Culture war, it&#39;s obscene to treat it as a game.  
Alexander Heliyevich Dugin has been playing word games all his life and got lost in their rhizomatic abyss, a perpetually edgy boy with an uncanny and uneven erudition, although adorned with a solid grey beard (by the way, he&#39;s only 60 despite his looks, a decade younger than his clean-shaven, botoxed, small-minded God-Czar; this *starchestvo*, performative embrace of the aging process, is a political statement). He has already lost more than his sanity. Most likely it&#39;ll be easier for him to spin this loss into another ^3 bitter cause for doubling down than to admit having been fundamentally wrong. Don&#39;t be like Alexander Heliyevich Dugin, if you can. The real world deserves being taken seriously.   

---

**1:** To make it clear: I think assassinating Dugin is fair game, though perhaps not worth the effort. He&#39;s a warmonger and he considers philosophy to be a form of combat, and the highest form at that. Indeed, the last post on his vk.com account (predating the event by half a day) begins with: 

&amp;gt; Mental warfare should be handled by people with a high quality of mentality. That is, above all, philosophers. After all, we are talking about Noomakhia, **wars of the mind**. In my opinion, to put this in the context of the Defense Ministry is grotesque and absurd.  

Philosophy aside, he has always directly encouraged the violence and, what offends me more, the escapist fantasy of prevailing through the denial of «Titanism», even resorting to clear tomfoolery (On the subject of import substitution: «There will be a lot of products from Belarus. Even more than now. Including textiles and cosmetics. **And also washbasins**. But Belarus will be the State of the Empire». What?). Half a year ago, back when I was still [in denial](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/sgv76g/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_january_31/hvqh1kw/) about the impending war, he was clamoring for the ruination of Ukraine, and he deserves his label as the [intellectual father of Russian Fascism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rashism#Aleksandr_Dugin). 

I used to find those extreme aspects of him clownish, mere delusion of an ideologue who&#39;s been used and discarded by a corrupt bureaucratic apparatus he glamorizes. But it turns out that a clown mafia state can still try to act out esoteric fascism. Like they say: «It looked like we&#39;ve punched through the rock bottom; then we&#39;ve heard knocking from below». 

**2:** Solovyev&#39;s death would be satisfying to hear about, but [one alleged attempt](https://meduza.io/feature/2022/06/21/dva-mesyatsa-nazad-fsb-ob-yavila-o-sryve-pokusheniya-na-vladimira-solovieva) had already failed; and I&#39;m afraid he&#39;s the type to repent, be graciously forgiven and get his assets back, proceeding to bang empty-headed Russian Studies co-eds and write cringe-inducing lit crit and mawkish memoirs until his centennial anniversary. (Then again, that&#39;s what *Westerners* can offer him; Ukrainians are a healthy Eastern European people, somewhat cruder. And they&#39;re getting into their «the only good Russian is a dead Russian» mindset deep enough to train their pitchforks on [Maxim Katz](https://youtu.be/ZMNIHvuaG8U) now).  

**3:** an excerpt from Dugin&#39;s interview in *Moskovsky Komsomolets*, a rather free-wheeling outlet, titled «“Solar” Putin has defeated “Lunar” one», Mar 30: 

– Alexander Gellievich, I was rereading one of your interviews about the existence of two Putins. «Solar» and «Lunar.» «Solar» is [about] Crymnash (Crimea Ours), the restoration of the Eurasian empire, messianism. «Lunar» is a rational practitioner, a realist, an adherent of capitalist economy, acting with regard to the collective West. At the time, you lamented that Putin just won&#39;t commit to the «Solar» path, preferring to combine both. And how is it today – has the choice been made?

– Yes, of course, the «Solar« Putin has won, and I&#39;ve been saying that he would win not a year ago, but for many years in a row. I have even published a book about this, «Putin vs Putin», dedicated to the main paradox of Russian politics – it has been translated into many languages and in it I present my theory in detail. 

There is an interesting author in historical science, Ernst Kantorovich, who wrote a study called «The Two Bodies of the King». It is about the fact that any great ruler is always dual. On the one hand, physically, he is certainly a man, and on the other hand, he is a historical figure, part of a continuous historical process. As a man, he can think in a certain way; but as a historical figure on which the fate of peoples and states depend, he may act very differently.  

This duality creates the deepest tension, the drama of the ruler, and is characteristic of a variety of political regimes. It does not matter whether we are dealing with democracy, as in the case of Churchill or Roosevelt, or with monarchy, as under Ivan the Terrible or Nicholas II. It is a split that arises in the soul and in the heart, in the consciousness of the ruler, when he is truly aware of his responsibility before history, when the future of humanity depends on his actions and his decisions made with reliance on himself and his destiny, on the depths of his «I».

An ordinary, normal person acts rationally, by inertia – this is what I call the «Lunar» side. He adapts to circumstances and recognizes the rules of the game, follows moral and ethical norms.

The «Solar» side, on the other hand, compels him to perform a great deed. In the image of our president this is expressed very vividly.

On the one hand, Putin is devoted to the sovereignty of Russia as a state, but on the other, rational hand I think he was well aware of the consequences of a persistent insistence on his position. In this respect, Putin&#39;s «Solar» beginning is extremely tragic, because it means struggle with the ideas and values of the West. **But Russia has crossed the Rubicon, which I am personally very happy about.**</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il4zgw1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il2bi0i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Are pity and sympathy a form of power? Rather than a kind of compassion that the</title><updated>2022-08-20T13:24:28Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Are pity and sympathy a form of power? Rather than a kind of compassion that the powerful feel toward the weak, should it be seen as a form of social capital that the powerful use to subjugate the weak?

When you examine how much is needed to create a truly sympathetic account of something today — the domination of a social environment to trap an audience, writers and designers, publications, media, attractive spokesmen, storytellers — it reads like a veritable army. All of these “soldiers” work together to create a sympathetic portrayal of an event in the hopes of influencing opinion. If you can raise an influencer army, are you really weak? And if you are a captured audience to sympathetic messaging, are you really powerful?

We see that enemy powers fight over sympathy. Israel and the Arab world use their influence to fight over dominant sympathy. The truly weak party finds themselves at the disadvantage, lacking the prerequisite capital for strong messaging. 

A documentary is not a documentary[1]. A documentary is never a documentary. It’s more like a special military operation, or espionage behind enemy lines. “The Lobby” encapsulates this idea. State-owned *Al Jazeera* used (expensive) investigative journalists to uncover the lobbying efforts of Israelis in the UK and America, who ostensibly use their power to promote sympathetic portrayals of themselves and unsympathetic portrayals of their enemies. In the first series of the documentary, the Israelis keep a “hit list” of pro-Arab politicians to socially “take down”, using their social capital in the media, and accusations of oppression (anti-semitism) are brought against pro-Palestinians. And the Arabs responded by creating this documentary, a one-sided portrayal of all of the above, which lead to government inquests and the election of a Muslim student leader. In the second series, we learn that a wealthy Israeli businessman runs a website that accuses anti-Israeli activists of oppression (anti-semitism) in an attempt to, well, oppress them (shaming and blackmailing). However, this documentary never officially aired — Israel pressured Qatar to can airings of the documentary; Republican congressmen asked Jeff Sessions to label Al Jazeera a foreign agent, and the Justice Department to investigate Al Jazeera. The *Zionist Organization of America* boasted of lobbying the Qatari government to can the documentary.

This documentary was not small potatoes, as evidenced by the “exaggerated” Israeli response. But their reaction wasn’t exaggerated at all. A documentary is a weapon of sympathy, and Israel and the Arab world are fighting over control of sympathy. I question whether there is any organic sympathy left to be found that is not boosted by powerful sponsors.

[1] https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lobby_(TV_series)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il2bi0i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/il1dgn9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] How plausible is a scenario where a patient world-optimizing AGI develops the te</title><updated>2022-08-20T06:36:12Z</updated><author><name>kcu51</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">How plausible is a scenario where a patient world-optimizing AGI develops the technology and capacity to create an synthetic human representative; and from then on works as much as possible through synth proxies (or natural humans directed by the synths)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/il1dgn9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driv</title><updated>2022-08-20T04:28:31Z</updated><author><name>gearofnett</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driven by some goal that I would set for myself, but I&#39;ve managed to achieve everything I wanted in the past few years, and the new goals I try to set for myself are not motivating enough for me to change my behavior. My regular day consists of waking up at 12-3pm, browsing the internet/reading a book/watching youtube or movie + 1 hour of work (if needed) + cook food, then going to bed at 3-6am. It&#39;s not all bad, on the weekends I go out with friends, and I also travel 3-4 times a year, but I understand that my regular day schedule is extremely unhealthy. If I keep living like that I won&#39;t be well physically or mentally. Even though I understand the consequences, it&#39;s still not motivating enough to change my ways. I try to fix my sleep, but after 2-3 days I&#39;m back to that degen schedule because I literally don&#39;t have a reason to be awake early. I work for myself, so I don&#39;t need to be up early. All my friends and family work regular jobs, so I can&#39;t interact with them at that time either. I&#39;m physically fit (as much as one can be when not working out consistently) and don&#39;t eat junk food, so I don&#39;t have an urgent need or want to go to the gym. I used to work out in the past and I know how much of an impact it has on your mental, but again, for some reason me knowing all that is not enough to push me to change. 

I&#39;m very tempted to get a regular 9-5 job or join the military just for the sake of having responsibilities that would force me to have a normal human schedule and hope that the habits I learn during that time stick with me for the rest of my life.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikznn5w/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Humans are not equal**. 

I expect most people here would probably agree with </title><updated>2022-08-19T21:46:43Z</updated><author><name>Lorelei_On_The_Rocks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Humans are not equal**. 

I expect most people here would probably agree with that statement reflexively, insofar as most people here probably agree that all people do not have equal capabilities, whether we’re talking about physical capabilities or the more controversial mental capabilities. 

However even most people who are quick to admit to this are just as quick to follow it up with the caveat that practical inequality does not imply *moral* inequality, and that all persons regardless of ability are worth equal moral consideration. 

I think this is self-evidently false. Leftists, the paladins of “equality,” understand this, which is why inegalitarian thought frightens them so much. If, in fact, humans are not practically equal, then it is self-evident that they are not morally equal, either. A dullard is worth less than a genius. It is obvious. 

IMO the right can never really win against the left until it defends the proposition, yes, some people are inherently better than others on all relevant metrics. 

It is difficult to argue against economic redistribution, to give one example unless you accept this. To make an argument that people should not have their wealth expropriated for the sake of others, you cannot make purely practical arguments (i.e it won’t have the desired results, it’s inefficient, etc.) because this leaves one open to all sorts of moralistic sophistry. One must make the point that the intended recipients of the redistribution simply are not worthy of the goods of better people. 

Likewise, with the axiom of human moral equality taken for granted, right-wingers will flounder to explain why an intelligent, respected, sober, successful man deserves more consideration than a stupid, habitual drunken layabout. Sure, the former might make better decisions, but if the two share some fundamental moral equality, shouldn’t their desires, interests, and well-being merit equal consideration?

To argue for “equality of opportunity” instead of “equality of outcome” is an equally (ha) silly thing to do. What does it even mean, when one gets down to it? We haven’t sprung fully formed from the aether. We are all products of our ancestors, and the environments produced by our ancestors. There was “equality of opportunity” at the beginning of time, and we are living with its results. It’s possible someone whose ancestors are all imbecilic failures, and who lives in a community of imbecilic failures, will prove as capable (in whatever respect) as someone whose ancestors are all intelligent, competent persons, but it is unlikely enough that no resources or energy should be expended on giving that former someone “his shot.” 

I suspect this line of thinking viscerally would disgust and upset even a lot of people who consider themselves “right-wing.” I submit that this merely shows the extent to which even self-considered conservatives or reactionaries have been mind-colonized by leftism in the present day. For the past sixteen plus centuries of human civilization, no one ever dreamed that the life of a slave was worth the life of a free man. 

I would amend the first statement to, **humans are not equal in *any* sense.** Except perhaps the most banal and uninteresting sense in which two humans are equally humans, in the same sense that a boulder and a pebble are equally rocks. Conceding “equality” in any sense other than this plants the seed of a thousand errors.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikznn5w/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikz4q8q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] 
This is sorta old, but the NFL is [no longer](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/0</title><updated>2022-08-19T19:40:40Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">
This is sorta old, but the NFL is [no longer](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/02/sports/football/nfl-wonderlic-test.html#:~:text=Wonderlic%2C%20the%20N.F.L.-,Finds%20Other%20Ways%20to%20Test%20Football%20I.Q.,other%20assessments%20of%20football%20acumen.) (archive version https://archive.ph/WPfD0) requiring the Wonderlic  test (although it&#39;s still being administered by teams on request)

A Google search shows it&#39;s inconclusive if the Wonderlic  is predictive of NFL success. I think it&#39;s possibly more predictive at the low-end, meaning that low-scorers are more likely the be unsuccessful, in the aggregate, than high scorers are super-successful. Football is a pretty technical game compared to other major sports (such as the use of playbooks, and having to make quick decisions in chaotic environments) so it&#39;s not surprising that the test is of some value.  

It&#39;s popular these day to downplay the predictiveness of standardized testing  and IQ scores...if you want to be a wedding photographer, then, yeah, the SATs do not matter or predict much, but for technical jobs, in which preciseness is important, then they are predictive. Second, the correlation between SATs and GPAs/grades is strong at all score ranges, which counters the narrative that standardized tests undersell the abilities of low-scorers.  If these tests didn&#39;t mean anything then we should see employers not value credentials highly correlated with them. In lieu of degrees, thousands of employers use something called the Wonderlic test, for this reason, which is like an IQ test; for example the following question:

https://preview.redd.it/rh16krsjufe81.jpg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=33844a6352f34597934e52a905764a33adff6bb7

The fact that cognitive screening is so important and prevalent despite the political backlash to them, suggests that in spite of the unpopularity of such teats that companies still value productivity more than political correctness, which I think is obvious.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikz4q8q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxwcd1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Recently,  the Senator Thorpe who identifies as Australian Aboriginal from *Aust</title><updated>2022-08-19T14:54:03Z</updated><author><name>georgioz</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Recently,  the Senator Thorpe who identifies as Australian Aboriginal from *Australian Greens* party made an oath in Australian Senate. Here [is the video](https://youtu.be/HAJQ_K_CzCE) and what follows is a rough transcript.

Senator Thorpe goes down to read the oath with [Raised fist](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raised_fist) salute and declares that:

&amp;gt; I, sovereign Lidia Thorpe do solemnly and sincerely affirm and declare that I will be faithful and I bear true allegiance to the **colonizing** Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth, the second ....

At  that point she had to be reminded that this is not what was written in the oath presented, and she had to repeat the original transcript. Thorpe&#39;s whole body language as well as tone of voice expressed that she does not think of this oath as genuine.

And this is an interesting point here, should government officials who make oaths to &#34;protect the constitution&#34; or other oaths be given a pass obviously demeaning it and signaling that they do not agree with their oath? I think this is an interesting &#34;foreshadowing&#34; of the things to come, where the legitimacy of the government and its institutions is obviously and explicitly ignored. I am not an Aussie so I can be educated on the ramification of this act by Thorpe, but to me this seems like an interesting case of how will the institutions react to such a blatant disrespect of the spirit of law although the letter of law was adhered to in the end.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxwcd1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxroo7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] An [interesting article from Politico](https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/20</title><updated>2022-08-19T14:23:34Z</updated><author><name>Ben___Garrison</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">An [interesting article from Politico](https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2022/08/19/fallout-mar-a-lago-search-00052799) today on how the Mar-a-Lago search&#39;s real fallout has been another step towards widescale civil breakdown. 

&amp;gt;The political consequences of the FBI’s search of Mar-a-Lago, former president Donald Trump’s Florida residence, have been shrill but predictable. Most Democrats have welcomed it as gratification long delayed, Trump loyalists have condemned it as a “Deep State” abuse of power, and more measured Republicans have split the difference. Observers have also pointed to the danger of riling up Trump’s base and stoking his determination to retake the presidency.

There were attacks against the far right before, like the siege of Waco during the 90s, and right-wing counterattacks like the Oklahoma city bombing. But it mostly stopped there, as the Oklahoma bombing had a chilling effect that delegitimized political violence among the mainstream right. Soon enough, 9/11 turned the focus of domestic terrorism towards Muslims for much of the 2000s and 2010s, but as divisions are growing deeper between the right and left the specter of rightwing extremism is returning:

&amp;gt;For one, there’s the newfound legitimacy of domestic political violence. In the 1990s, the militia movement was merely percolating, committed to resisting government but not interested in taking the offensive or prepared to do so. Mainstream American liberals and conservatives both firmly considered domestic political violence unacceptable. Only conspicuous law-enforcement debacles could inspire even an extremist like McVeigh to lethal terrorist action against fellow Americans. Today, though, Blue and Red are arguably irreconcilable, and Trump has hauled the far right to the surface and enlisted it in his personal service. Some of his supporters are so convinced that his presidency was stolen from him that they apprehend the subdued, circumspect, non-violent execution of a search warrant on his residence as a casus belli, and authoritative and admired figures encourage them to do so.

&amp;gt;Steve Bannon labeled the FBI a “gestapo.” Georgia representative Marjorie Taylor Greene called for Congress to defund the FBI. Far-right pundits have proclaimed “This. Means. War.” and characterized the search as a “declaration of war.” Posts on far-right internet forums have been more violent than any since January 6. Last weekend, armed Trump supporters clad in body armor held a protest outside the FBI’s Phoenix office. Threats against federal law enforcement have spiked, intensifying a growing trend. Some extremists have “doxxed” FBI agents, publicizing their personal information to enable others to harass them or target them with violence. Such behavior seems intended to mobilize those of McVeigh’s ilk.

The growth of militias has further catalyzed this process. In the 90s militias were atomized, but with the advent of social media they&#39;ve been able to talk and coordinate with each other much more effectively. They&#39;ve stockpiled more weapons as well, with lax gun laws in red states. Departments like the ATF have responded in turn, buying up military-grade gear to turn previously routine operations into SWAT-style force protection. There&#39;s also concerns within the ATF and FBI that many agents are sympathetic to the plight of the far right, and there&#39;s anecdotal evidence that there were tensions within the FBI due to the Mar-a-Lago raid. Risks of a new civil war are overstated, as the geographic distribution of reds vs blues doesn&#39;t really lend itself to secession. However, risks of a Troubles-like insurgency are very real:

&amp;gt;Mature democracies have gone too far in the past. In 1969, the British government sent troops to Northern Ireland to quell growing community unrest over Catholic nationalist political and civil rights protests. The soldiers were initially welcomed as peacekeepers. But as grievances could not be immediately addressed and protests escalated, the British government resorted to more extreme measures, including direct armed confrontation, mass internment of those suspected of paramilitary activities, the statutory establishment of “scheduled offenses” for political violence, and the creation of dedicated, non-jury courts for trying those charged with them. The IRA exploited this too, orchestrating marches and demonstrations that would prompt the Royal Ulster Constabulary to break out the riot gear, which served to confirm their narrative of state oppression, generate sympathetic headlines and news spots, and win recruits to the armed struggle. Eventually, the public came to see IRA militants as soldiers in a civil war. By the mid-1970s, London understood that demilitarization and normalization would make the conflict more tractable, but by then the gouge was set: the Troubles would last 25 years, extend violence to the British mainland, and palsy Northern Irish society.

What does the motte think about preventing the coming civil breakdown?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxroo7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikxlm5f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m attempting to smoke two huge pork shoulders that are a total of 16 lbs this </title><updated>2022-08-19T13:42:17Z</updated><author><name>yofuckreddit</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m attempting to smoke two huge pork shoulders that are a total of 16 lbs this weekend. The story of my smoking experiences with pork are ones of being off by multiple hours in terms of completion, so I&#39;m working a whole day ahead of time. If I get done early, which has never happened, I&#39;ll wrap the meat in aluminum trays and keep it warm. 

Since most of y&#39;all are on the west coast I assume the proclivity for cooking vast cuts of meat this way isn&#39;t as popular as it is around my neck of the woods. But right now I have a small electric Masterbilt smoker. It was unbelievably affordable in my estimation, it&#39;s relatively easy to clean, but I&#39;ve been electrocuted while it&#39;s sprinkling a couple times and I&#39;ve always wondered if I should be stepping up to a pellet grill at some point. Any comment from someone who&#39;s made the move would be welcome. I only smoke stuff 6-7 times a year, so perhaps it&#39;s a luxury I shouldn&#39;t be considering anyway.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikxlm5f/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikwl5po/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] It&#39;s Janmashtami today. Janmashtami is the day when Lord Krishna was born. He is</title><updated>2022-08-19T07:19:12Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">It&#39;s Janmashtami today. Janmashtami is the day when Lord Krishna was born. He is an incarnation of Lord Vishnu and is one of the most beloved deity.

He was the charioteer for the supreme warrior Arjun during the Mahabharat. Arjuna didn&#39;t want to fight the war and Lord Krishna had a long conversation with him about life which is known as the Gita, the supreme Scripture for many Hindus.

I shall fast today and spend time with my family, read some theology thanks to Gita Press Gorakhpur.

The very first thing this commentary on the Gita says  is that one must appreciate being born a human. We can experience, conceive and feel divinity, something no other being can do and no matter how bad things are, we will always be lucky as compared to most animals.

This isn&#39;t the same as me going out for talking to girls or consuming substances but I like this a lot. I find theology quite profound and enjoyable to read. I find it more than just fun and hence the motif to post about today here.

May Lord Krishna bless us all. Happy Janmashtami to everyone reading this.

Jai Shri Krishna.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ws5dhg/friday_fun_thread_for_august_19_2022/ikwl5po/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikvg8f1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Posted on culture war thread but told I should put here:

I have a friend who&#39;s </title><updated>2022-08-19T00:59:13Z</updated><author><name>thejawaknight</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Posted on culture war thread but told I should put here:

I have a friend who&#39;s suddenly gone very far to the left and she believes that we need a violent revolution against today&#39;s &#34;systems.&#34; She also thinks she needs to constantly keep a &#34;revolutionary mindset&#34; in order to overthrow the government. Has anyone else had experience with friends becoming this radical?

 I still intend to stay friends with her but I just wanted to see what experiences other people might have had with this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikvg8f1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikvarq7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I have a friend who&#39;s suddenly gone very far to the left and she believes that w</title><updated>2022-08-19T00:18:27Z</updated><author><name>thejawaknight</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I have a friend who&#39;s suddenly gone very far to the left and she believes that we need a violent revolution against today&#39;s &#34;systems.&#34; She also thinks she needs to constantly keep a &#34;revolutionary mindset&#34; in order to overthrow the government. Has anyone else had experience with friends becoming this radical?

 I still intend to stay friends with her but I just wanted to see what experiences other people might have had with this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikvarq7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikva0zo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Do you like AI?**

I&#39;ve been thinking about how the discussion about AI art ca</title><updated>2022-08-19T00:12:59Z</updated><author><name>Primaprimaprima</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Do you like AI?**

I&#39;ve been thinking about how the discussion about AI art can be linked back to the culture war, since that is our *raison d&#39;être*.

Most of the discussion here has focused on the object-level issues concerning AI art: the economic impact to artists, the projected rate of progression of the technology, etc.  What I&#39;m interested in here, though, is the psychological profiles of the participants in the debate.  It&#39;s clear to me that there are people who *like AI*, and there are people who *don&#39;t like AI*.  That is, regardless of your object-level beliefs about the inevitability of the development of the technology, or how many jobs it will displace, or what potential benefits it may bring to society and culture at large, people tend to enter the debate with a preexisting positive or negative emotional affect towards the concept of AI itself.  Some people are happy that the technology exists; some are not.

What causes someone to join one group or the other?  What sorts of underlying beliefs and values are at play here?  What patterns can we observe?

To make things clear up front, I *don&#39;t like* AI, and I especially don&#39;t like AI art, so part of the analysis will inevitably take place from that point of view, although I ultimately hope to touch on the underlying psychological motivations of both groups.

Let&#39;s dispose of some of the simple and obvious explanations first: the idea, for example, that the only people worried about AI art are artists who are afraid of losing their jobs, and any other sane person should be happy to reap the rewards of increasingly democratized access to the means of cultural production.  I can&#39;t object to this idea from an *entirely* neutral point of view, since drawing and painting are more tied to my identity than they are for the average person, but I can still object to it from a semi-objective point of view.  I have no musical ability whatsoever, nor do I have any interest in ever developing any, but I still don&#39;t like AI music.  I&#39;m pretty sure it&#39;s been years at this point since I first heard about AI composing pieces in the style of Bach and Beethoven, and I didn&#39;t like that stuff when I first heard about it either.  It rubs me the wrong way.

Nor can opposition to AI be reduced to simple technological luddism, or a knee-jerk preference for what is familiar over what is new and unfamiliar.  I am not opposed to all technological progress on principle - I welcome the advent of interstellar travel, and the curing of diseases like cancer and ALS.  Conversely, I am skeptical of technologies that have been a familiar part of my life since childhood.  I can hardly remember a time when I didn&#39;t have access to the internet, and yet my feelings towards it are mixed at best.  It&#39;s a double edged sword - it has brought many great things, but also many terrible things.  If I could somehow freeze publicly-available internet access at a level of development comparable to the late 90s, I probably would.  But that&#39;s another story.

It&#39;s not hard to enumerate factors that I *incidentally* find distasteful about AI art - that it will flood the world with a glut of low-effort content, that it will inflate the egos of people who think they are &#34;artists&#34; when they are in fact nothing of the sort, that it will discourage people from developing genuine creativity because it will be easier to settle for a half-hearted, inauthentic substitute - but I think that none of these considerations truly strike at the heart of the issue for me.  My intuition is that there is something deeper going on, something that can be related to the culture war, because I think I can see familiar patterns from the culture war repeating themselves.

My highly speculative thesis is that people who like AI are motivated by an *aesthetics of success*, and people who don&#39;t like AI are motivated by an *aesthetics of failure*, or a tragic aesthetics.  These positions also correspond in a very loose way to the left/right divide, respectively.  I&#39;ll try to explain what I mean.

Traditionally, leftism since Marx was founded in a belief in utopian progress - that we could resolve social problems through willful, rational action, ultimately culminating in a terminal optimal social order that was free of contradictions, or as Marx put it, &#34;the riddle of history solved&#34;.  Now, it&#39;s possible to claim that modern (or even classic) leftism is not about this at all, and that it&#39;s actually a thinly disguised form of ethnic warfare.  That may be true.  But even so, you can&#39;t deny that this utopian impulse did exist in and continues to inform leftism, and more importantly, people who *enjoy* this vision of the future, people who find it *aesthetically* pleasing, people who hear the idea of an optimal non-contradictory social order and think &#34;hey that sounds like a good idea&#34;, tend to be drawn to leftism.

The same utopian impulse from Marxism also underlies the transhumanism of, for example, Yudkowsky&#39;s [Fun Theory](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/K4aGvLnHvYgX9pZHS/the-fun-theory-sequence).  The idea (as far as I can tell from lightly skimming it) is that we could construct a perfect reality that satisfies every constraint we could ever wish to optimize for - it&#39;s exactly as exciting as we need, exactly as pleasant as we need, exactly as challenging as we need, and if for some reason you wish to meet a tragic end where you fail to fulfill all your goals, well hey we can arrange for that too.  It is logically perfect in every way - no one is excluded, no one could ask for more, even the people whose very wish is to be excluded from the utopia.  I think the relation between this kind of transhumanism on the one hand, and the development of AI on the other, is pretty obvious - if you enjoy, on an aesthetic level, the idea of a perfect transhumanist future, then you probably also enjoy on an aesthetic level when AI smashes through fundamental human limitations.

I am *in no way* saying that everyone who gets warm fuzzies for AI and transhumanism is a leftist.  Certainly we have many counterexamples on this forum.  Nor does every leftist like the idea of AI - there are plenty of leftist artists complaining on twitter about AI art as we speak.  But I do think that leftists and people who like AI are aligned on this general pro-utopian axis - they agree that a utopian future is fundamentally desirable, even if they disagree on implementation details, and many other contemporary political issues besides.

The key thing to understand about the other side, the opposition to this utopian ideal, is that *not everyone thinks that utopia is desirable*.  Some of us consciously reject it.  I mean this in a very deep way, as deep as you can possibly conceive.  I mean that even in the most logically perfect utopia you can imagine, one where everyone gets the exact amount of challenge and pain and tragedy that is suited to them, one where I can live in my tragic broken reality and you can live in your blissful nice one and we can somehow coexist simultaneously - *I still don&#39;t want that*.  I don&#39;t want reality to be like that.  I don&#39;t want reality to be at peace.  I want there to be failure in the very nature of things.  I want us to never reach a final state of peace, even if there is fire and brimstone built into that overarching peace.

From Zizek&#39;s &#34;Less Than Nothing&#34;:

&amp;gt;It is true that one finds in Hegel a systematic drive to cover everything, to propose an account of all phenomena in the universe in their essential structure; but this drive does not mean that Hegel strives to locate every phenomenon within a harmonious global edifice; on the contrary, the point of dialectical analysis is to demonstrate how every phenomenon, everything that happens, fails in its own way, implies a crack, antagonism, imbalance, in its very heart.  Hegel&#39;s gaze upon reality is that of a Roentgen apparatus which sees in everything that is alive the traces of its future death.

I find this to be an immensely aesthetically pleasing passage - it&#39;s how I want reality to be.  I imagine that transhumanists will not feel as warmly towards it (although this is an empirical hypothesis that is subject to refutation through counterexamples).  To you, there is beauty in triumph; problems are meant to be solved, and then quietly and safely set aside, conquered, dealt with.  You want to [resolve on the I chord](https://youtu.be/6aezSL_GvZA?t=430).  We won, you say; there&#39;s no need to go backwards now.  Man stands victorious at the summit of his knowledge.  You thought we couldn&#39;t make a machine that paints beautiful pictures?  Well, we did it.  We put the sum total of man&#39;s visual knowledge into a machine.  That&#39;s what we were able to accomplish; our triumph over this domain is total.  The beauty of our actions is measured by the strength of the gods we have slain.

To me, there is beauty in failure - no problem ever fully solved, no debate ever put to rest, no point of finality ever reached.  Not because there is an angry God who will slap us down if we exceed our station, but because *failure is built into the very nature of things*.  The moment of triumph becomes the moment of defeat, not due to any external force, but because of the necessity of its own inner movement.  Reality as a demonic house of mirrors where every moment of recognition is the moment of misrecognition, every realization comes too late that the act of will was actually the ultimate act of self-sabotage - this is reality as I *aesthetically* want it to be.  Doesn&#39;t mean it is.  But it&#39;s what I want - it&#39;s what I like.  And our likes and dislikes are awfully important when it comes to motivating our actions.

Hopefully there&#39;s something here to discuss.

&amp;gt;Out of love for mankind... I conceived it as my task to create difficulties everywhere.

- Kierkegaard</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikva0zo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikv9b16/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] https://youtu.be/JrCmrMnJUIc

I was listening to a podcast which interviewed a p</title><updated>2022-08-19T00:07:36Z</updated><author><name>thejawaknight</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">https://youtu.be/JrCmrMnJUIc

I was listening to a podcast which interviewed a parent about social emotional learning in their school. She believes that it&#39;s a form of mind control. Does anyone know that much about the subject and its flaws/strengths?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikv9b16/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikutiu1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Guessing C For Every Answer Is Now Enough To Pass The New York State Algebra Ex</title><updated>2022-08-18T22:16:58Z</updated><author><name>Tarnstellung</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Guessing C For Every Answer Is Now Enough To Pass The New York State Algebra Exam](https://medium.com/@newyorkteacher/guessing-c-for-every-answer-is-now-enough-to-pass-the-new-york-state-algebra-exam-93bac55b3e24)

&amp;gt;He wasn’t even present in my classroom for most of three marking periods. At the end of the year, he asked me how he was supposed to pass the state test.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“No problem,” I said. “Just pick all Cs.”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“What?”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“Try it. I bet it will work.”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;It worked.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; (...)
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;This problem has a clear solution: make the algebra exam an exam that actually tests a student’s ability to do algebra.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Unfortunately, this solution is difficult to implement. Implementation is difficult because of all the reasons that drove NYSED off the cliffs of insanity in the first place. Look at the incentives. NYSED and local school districts have large financial incentives to graduate as many students as possible. These incentives were put in place by both federal and state legislators who meant well and were trying to encourage good public school performance (good performance == graduation, of course, in their eyes). Teachers and principals have large quality-of-life incentives to pass students. Failing students brings scrutiny, parent and student complaints, superintendent pressure, guidance counselor inquisitions, paperwork, and meeting after meeting. It’s much easier to pass everyone.

TL;DR: The criteria on an exam needed to graduate from high school in New York have been lowered to the point that it can be passed by someone who barely attended class.

I first saw this on /r/slatestarcodex. In [the comments](https://old.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/wro3vz/guessing_c_for_every_answer_is_now_enough_to_pass), someone asked why the SAT wasn&#39;t more widely used by universities and employers, given that it is more standardized and objective. A discussion concerning this question would probably move in a &#34;culture war&#34; direction; hence, this post.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikutiu1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikuljbf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Three of my family members have gotten Lyme disease (edit: actually one case is </title><updated>2022-08-18T21:25:23Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Three of my family members have gotten Lyme disease (edit: actually one case is some other tick borne illness) this summer. I&#39;d never heard of anyone I know getting it before. There seems to be an epidemic. Any advice on how to avoid it?

It seems like a horrible disease to get, much worse than Covid.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikuljbf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iku9dfu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Where can I buy a really good umbrella? I&#39;ve been annoyed or disappointed by mos</title><updated>2022-08-18T20:09:37Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Where can I buy a really good umbrella? I&#39;ve been annoyed or disappointed by most umbrellas I&#39;ve owned, so I&#39;ve never really used them much. somebody out there must make a good one right?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iku9dfu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktra5n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Sam Harris finally just says the quiet part out loud with respect to how it appe</title><updated>2022-08-18T18:14:04Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Sam Harris finally just says the quiet part out loud with respect to how it appears a lot of democrats feel about Trump and the importance of the democratic process: https://twitter.com/JackPosobiec/status/1560257627237539845

&#34;It doesn&#39;t answer the people who say it&#39;s completely unfair to have not looked at the laptop in a timely way and to have shut down, you know, the NYpost&#39;s twitter account.  Like that&#39;s just a left wing conspiracy to deny the presidency to Donald Trump.  Absolutely it is, and I think it was warranted.&#34;

The podcast hosts press him on this, and he does admit that actually, yes, it is completely fine to suspend the idea of democracy simply to prevent Trump from getting the presidency, because he believes that Trump is a big enough threat that this is warranted.  The comparison he makes is to an asteroid heading for earth that will destroy all life on this planet, and that in that case you would do *anything* to stop it.

I think to anybody who has been paying attention to politics for the last two years, and especially to anybody who has spent much time looking at the 2020 election, this sort of thing won&#39;t be surprising.  My question to people who are still of the mind that the left isn&#39;t pushing us towards a less democratic society is: do you agree with what Sam is saying here?  Like for instance: would it be okay to cheat, or to suspend democratic norms to prevent Trump from winning again?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktra5n/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktljtx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Quick check: has the sub just been put into that delayed mode where you can only</title><updated>2022-08-18T17:36:53Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Quick check: has the sub just been put into that delayed mode where you can only see new comments in [the feed](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/) for the first 10 minutes? Everything posted less than that long ago gives the &#34;there&#39;s nothing here&#34; error when you view them directly.

I&#39;ve seen that happen a lot lately. Is it a sauron sign?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktljtx/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iktdbsz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I can recommend [this episode of Andrew Huberman&#39;s podcast](https://www.youtube.</title><updated>2022-08-18T16:43:24Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I can recommend [this episode of Andrew Huberman&#39;s podcast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DTCmprPCDqc) to anybody interested in longevity, exercise, nutrition, testosterone/estrogen and similar health and science-related topics.  
Phenomenal episode, I learned a ton from it.  
 In fact, I kind of wish we had a monthly or yearly megathread for discussing self-improvenent in the context of high-quality scientific studies. I think this is a topic with surprisingly little discussion for how significant the potential benefits are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/iktdbsz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikswpuv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Culture war in Finland: Stupidest day in Finnish politics for a long time**

C</title><updated>2022-08-18T14:53:34Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Culture war in Finland: Stupidest day in Finnish politics for a long time**

CONTEXT: It&#39;s not a new thing that Finnish PM Sanna Marin, 36, has been frequently seen out and about, drinking and dancing in clubs and such. Of course it&#39;s not a new thing for Finnish politicians to use alcohol or even get into accidents and such while doing so, but this is the new era and everyone has smartphones.

Previously the [major affair was in December](https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-finlands-prime-minister-sanna-marin-apologises-for-going-clubbing-after-coronavirus-exposure-12490903), when she was out late in a Helsinki club even though she had been exposed to Covid and there were still Covid restrictions for various things; even though the restrictions didn&#39;t affect what she, specifically, was doing, it was considered improper. On these evenings she&#39;s been spotted with an entourage of local pop stars and other celebs.

Anyway, last week, she was at one of the major music festivals in Finland, Flow Festival - not the biggest, but a classic hipster festival and certainly &#34;upscale&#34; - and had pics taken [with the attending celebs](https://is.mediadelivery.fi/img/468/7089604209104a472752cf1aa503aeb2.jpg). This caused some tut-tutting about behaving immaturely during great crises in Europe and the world. Whatever.

Now it turns out that one of the members of her entourage took a [video of being a drunk party](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9C-djV-ptEM) with her entourage and posted it on IG - private account for 92 people, to be sure, but of course something like that&#39;s going to get out. The video started spreading yesterday, and the entirety of today has consisted on Finnish social and traditional media obsessing about the clip, specifically about the specific charges of whether her entourage uses cocaine.

Of course PM partying in an entourage that&#39;s on drugs would be scandal in other countries, too, whether they took coke personally or not, but Finland tends to currently be particularly conservative on drugs compared to other Western countries - even pot decriminalization is not really soemthing that most would be consider to be short-term achievable.

Hard drugs are, of course a whole other question. I haven&#39;t used anything stronger than pot in my life and it&#39;s been years since I&#39;ve even smoked, but my understanding is that coke has been a facet of celebrity life at some level. However, it&#39;s only recent years when it has really hit the scene in Helsinki. Usually, the hard drug of choice for Finns has been speed.

Now, none of the celebrities are actually snorting anything up their nose in the video, so what&#39;s the evidence for drug use? Well, apart from the fact that they&#39;re, ya know, smiling and having fun and so on in the video (Finns might drink alcohol, but we do it to get drunk, not to actually have fun), at some parts of the video, some of them shout &#34;Fuck it, this makes me feel good&#34; in reference to something unseen and the word that might be &#34;jauhojengi&#34; (&#34;flour gang&#34;) or something else. Also, some claim that some of the pixels in the video indeed make it look like there&#39;s coke on the table. (Others claim it&#39;s a phone.) One particular claim is even that people on the video must be on drugs since there are so few bottles or glasses seen.

&#34;Flour gang&#34; has instantly became a meme here, even though it&#39;s now unclear 1. whether &#34;flour&#34; is actually Finnish drug lingo, or whether it has ever been used to refer to powder drugs here by anyone and 2. whether the words &#34;jauhojengi&#34; are actually used - the video features people dancing to and singing washed-up pop rapper Petri Nygård&#39;s lyrics for the old hit song &#34;Selvä päivä&#34; (&#34;Sober day&#34;), which is about, as you might guess, drinking. (You can find [translated lyrics](https://lyricstranslate.com/en/selv%C3%A4-p%C3%A4iv%C3%A4-sober1-day.html) here if you really wish.) The word heard as &#34;jauho&#34; might well instead be a reference to &#34;jallu&#34;, or Jaloviina, an iconic Finnish booze brand that&#39;s 50 % brandy and 50 % vodka and features in a metric ton of local music.

Several medias took the whole &#34;flour gang&#34; thing and ran with it, probably one reason being that earlier in the week they were criticized for going too easy on Marin and her government. Now others are attacking media for pushing a theory originally spread (at least on Twitter) by conspiracy theorist accounts that have otherwise taken a pro-Russian narratie. Yes, there are even references to whole thing being a Russian disinfo campaign.

Marin has herself [had to comment on this](https://www.theglobeandmail.com/world/article-finnish-pm-sanna-marin-says-no-drugs-just-lots-of-dancing-at-wild/), saying that she is disappointed in the video leaking, that she only had mild alcoholic drinks and doesn&#39;t use drugs and that she&#39;s willing to even take a drug test (not that it would show cocaine use anyway, more than a few days having passed from the party). Of course it still might turn out one or more of the celeb entourage members have been on drugs, who knows?

All in all, it would probably be the best if the PM quit back on partying or at least chose better friends to avoid embarassing stuff leaking out (also, you know, for general security reasons), the first rule of the Flour Gang is to never talk about the Flour Gang, PMs should find better music to dance to than a local whiteboy 50 Cent and politics here can indeed be as dumb as anywhere else, especially with the social media and stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikswpuv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iksffji/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Would it be good idea to have regular &#34;practical life advice&#34; thread like &#34;welln</title><updated>2022-08-18T12:52:05Z</updated><author><name>Eetan</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Would it be good idea to have regular &#34;practical life advice&#34; thread like &#34;wellness wendesday&#34; is for health and fitness?


Thread dedicated to questions about education, jobs, money, &#34;what gizmo should I buy&#34; &#34;my gizmo broke, how to fix it&#34; and any other real life problems you can imagine.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iksffji/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iks5awc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] What is empathy? Does it exist? Are there multiple types? Is it several differen</title><updated>2022-08-18T11:22:10Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">What is empathy? Does it exist? Are there multiple types? Is it several different concepts that are conflated? Can people have different amounts of empathy? Can empathy be turned off on purpose? These are but a small sampling of the questions I&#39;ve asked myself, and I don&#39;t have answers. I don&#39;t know what empathy is, but I know 1. I have less of it than most people do, if I even have it at all and 2. a lot of people have empathy only when it&#39;s convenient. I waffle on whether people in my outgroup/people whose outgroup includes me are particularly unempathetic, or whether my cognitive bias just makes me think that they are.

I&#39;ve tried to understand this concept of empathy not because I think it&#39;s important to understand, but because the word &#34;empathy&#34; gets tossed around a lot and I&#39;d like to know how to interpret it. Maybe it&#39;s one of those words like &#34;racism&#34; or &#34;woke&#34; that has no precise definition and is, at best, a direction.

As a rule, I don&#39;t like seeing people suffer. However, when someone is suffering, I cannot say I feel their pain, because I&#39;m not them. I only know what it&#39;s like to be me and have the particular experiences that I&#39;ve had. The closest I can get to putting myself in the place of another person is thinking back to an experience I&#39;ve had that made me feel a certain way and acting as though that&#39;s exactly how my interlocutor feels. That&#39;s not empathy, but an approximation. The way people describe empathy makes it sound like a superpower, like mind reading. But people often act as though they can read minds (hence the concept of dog whistles), so maybe this is all one big LARP too?

I was lurking on r/ThePurplePill and I saw [this comment ](https://www.reddit.com/r/PurplePillDebate/comments/wr2ls0/people_need_to_stop_saying_men_are_lonely_because/ikrjnql?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share&amp;amp;context=3) that approximates my feelings on humanity and the phony concept of empathy.

Sorry if this comes off as rambly. Basically, I&#39;m asking for a &#34;CMV: empathy isn&#39;t real&#34; or &#34;ELI5: What is empathy?&#34; I&#39;m not going to those subs, though, because I trust The Motte more than either of them. (Huh, I sound kinda close-minded when I put it like that.)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iks5awc/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikq6pg1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any tips on getting a good Job Without going to college? Like internship or Cert</title><updated>2022-08-17T23:41:56Z</updated><author><name>Nerd_199</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any tips on getting a good Job Without going to college? Like internship or Certifications , Etc. I am personal real worry about getting myself in debt.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikq6pg1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition</title><updated>2022-08-17T20:45:16Z</updated><author><name>Gorf__</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition for a long time, and for a while I&#39;ve been circling this as probably the best approach to food long-term for health and longevity. The ethics side of it is nice too, but I&#39;m not super interested in discussing that. This is mostly an experiment to see how I feel, and how my weight and blood markers look after a while. I&#39;m trying to take a 90/10 approach, eating as plant-based as possible for all of my staple meals at home, but allowing some meat and dairy in when necessary, mostly when eating out. I haven&#39;t eaten any red meat or poultry in a few weeks, but I&#39;ve had fish here and then when out at restaurants, as well as some dairy stuff - some cheese here and there and ranch dressing.

Generally I&#39;ve been a hardcore meat-eater, so up until about 3 weeks ago, every dish was very focused around meat, and any vegetables were there as condiments or just because I felt like I &#34;should&#34; make myself eat some broccoli. It seems to me that this is an extremely common approach to food in the US. Everyone I know eats this way. Most of us have this idea that if you take away meat and dairy then you&#39;re stuck just eating salads all the time, but that&#39;s not the case at all. I&#39;ve been eating oatmeal + fruit + some agave for breakfast; a smoothie and usually some sort of leftovers for lunch; and the formula for dinner is roughly: some a carb (whole grain pasta, brown rice, quinoa, etc) with a few vegetables mixed in and some kind of sauce for flavoring. The other night I made whole grain spaghetti with homemade tomato sauce (just cook down canned diced tomatoes and throw in some garlic and spices), sautéed mushrooms, roasted asparagus, and then topped with sautéed spinach, and then I ate that for lunch yesterday and today, and it was delicious.

So it&#39;s been a big change, but I&#39;m loving it. When you&#39;re eating a wide variety of fruits and vegetables, there&#39;s just a lot more variation in flavor and texture going around. I&#39;m finding out that meat itself is kind of boring: it&#39;s mostly texture, salt, and fat flavor. It&#39;s all of the stuff surrounding it that makes it good. Really, meat is already losing its allure to me altogether.

I also feel less full and bloated after a meal. I&#39;ll be full because of the bulk of all the vegetables I just ate, but that goes away pretty quickly; otherwise I feel much better than I would after pounding a burger and fries.

Why am I using the term &#34;plant-based&#34; and not vegan? To me, vegan has a connotation of doing it more for ethical concerns, and plant-based has a connotation of being based more on nutrition. But that&#39;s just my own perception. A whole food plant based diet is one where you focus on eating plants that came from the ground more or less directly, maybe heating, chopping, and/or seasoning them first, but not much alteration beyond that. Ie, avoiding as many processed foods as possible - so while it&#39;s probably ok to have an Impossible Burger every now and then, it shouldn&#39;t be a staple. Folks who eat vegan for ethical reasons are probably more likely to eat processed foods like tofurkey or whatever, which isn&#39;t really any healthier than just eating meat all the time.

So the inevitable question is: _so where are you getting all of your protein?_ First of all, the whole &#34;incomplete protein&#34; thing isn&#39;t true - all plants have all amino acids. Yes, the amounts of each vary, but if you&#39;re eating a variety of plants then it&#39;s nothing to worry about. Incomplete proteins were written about in this popular vegetarian book in the 70s, and the author later realized her mistake and backed off of it, but it was too late - the idea had already been solidified in public consciousness.

Second, the actual amount of protein we need is probably majorly inflated for most people. Sure, bodybuilders might need more, but even they are probably majorly overdoing it. There&#39;s some good discussion about this in the book _Proteinaholic_ by Garth Davis.

In any case, it&#39;s pretty easy to hit solid protein numbers from eating plants, especially if you&#39;re getting lots of legumes. And protein shakes are still a thing if you need even more.

The only issue I&#39;ve had so far is that I&#39;m farting a lot, and the farts are pretty bad. I think I went overboard in going from eating like 10-15g of fiber a day to like 50g. I&#39;m going to try dial that back and then ramp it back up more slowly. So maybe more white rice and pasta for a bit as I give my GI tract more time to adjust to the massive amounts of fiber.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpds17/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m near the end of pregnancy, and I&#39;ve got a few problems going on.

A month or</title><updated>2022-08-17T20:29:21Z</updated><author><name>sagion</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m near the end of pregnancy, and I&#39;ve got a few problems going on.

A month or so ago I was diagnosed with gestational diabetes. It&#39;s not fair. Of the [risk factors](https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/basics/risk-factors.html):

&amp;gt;You’re at risk for gestational diabetes (diabetes while pregnant) if you:

&amp;gt;   * Had gestational diabetes during a previous pregnancy.
&amp;gt;   * Have given birth to a baby who weighed over 9 pounds.
&amp;gt;   * Are overweight.
&amp;gt;   * Are more than 25 years old.
&amp;gt;   * Have a family history of type 2 diabetes.
&amp;gt;   * Have a hormone disorder called polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS).
&amp;gt;   * Are an African American, Hispanic or Latino, American Indian, Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander person.

I have one - over 25. Never been tested for PCOS, so I guess I can&#39;t completely rule that out, but there&#39;s a reason I&#39;ve never tested for it. As far as my doctor and I can tell, this was random chance. My pancreas isn&#39;t processing insulin right because of pregnancy hormones from the placenta. Now I have to track my diet for carb intake, limiting but not avoiding carbs, test my blood glucose, and maintain some daily exercise (been getting harder to do). The diet is the most frustrating part. Ok, no, the long term risks to both my baby and me are the most frustrating thing. There&#39;s not much risk of a large-baby-birth, which I&#39;ll come back to, but the birth issues are worrisome if unlikely, and then the higher chance of both of us getting type II diabetes is, again, unfair. I would like to know the weight of that risk when controlled for the other risk factors. When your gestational diabetes may have been random chance and not because of factors that also influence type II diabetes (weight, family history, activity level), how big is that risk increase? My doctor thinks in all likelihood everything will turn out fine as long as I stick with the plan.

As I mentioned, the low-carb diet is a bit frustrating. I&#39;ve adapted for the most part, but planning consistent meals is still tricky, particularly when my pizza-craving husband forgets my restrictions. We&#39;ve gone out of town a couple of times and had family come stay with us. Those worked out ok mostly. I had to find a couple of creative spots to test myself, and once while out I broke down in tears after spending 15 minutes looking over a couple of walkable cafes for a quick, low-carb lunch option only to find my choice opened at 11 but didn&#39;t start the kitchen until 11:30, when we had to be elsewhere. I had also skipped breakfast and passed up getting a latte, chai, or pastry, which would all be bad diet choices. In general, it takes a lot more time and thought to pick out a restaurant that won&#39;t wreck my numbers. So much bread, rice, potatoes, or noodles that I&#39;d rather not spend money on to not eat. And then there&#39;s looking up food nutrition, guessing what information gets close to what I&#39;m actually having. Not fun when calorie counting, even worse when my baby&#39;s health is on the line. Less bad when I&#39;m home and can go with home cooking, but still tedious.

On top of this, my baby keeps hovering in the 20th percentile of fetal weight. My doctor is a little concerned but otherwise chill about this, believing that he just may be a genetically small baby since I&#39;m small myself (5&#39;3&#34; and petite). My husband, however, is very worried about the negative effects of a low-weight birth and wants me to gain weight. That&#39;s not very compatible with what I&#39;m supposed to do to manage my gestational diabetes. Low carb cuts out a lot of high-calorie stuff, particularly *yummy* high-calorie foods. I may have dropped a pound in the first few days of the diagnosis, before I got the guidance, when all I came up with as &#34;safe to eat&#34; and easy was salad. Now I&#39;ve got more meat, dairy, and nuts in there. I&#39;ve agreed with my husband to try tracking my calories to make sure I am getting enough, and he&#39;s agreed to try to attend the next appointment to talk to my doctor about the baby&#39;s weight. It&#39;s stressful and bizarre to hear my husband say he wants me to get fat. I don&#39;t want my baby to be too small, but I also don&#39;t want to exacerbate the gestational diabetes by gaining excess weight. Throw in typical late pregnancy bad sleep, and it&#39;s all so stressful to balance. I&#39;d just like our little guy to get here healthy, safe, and sound.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpds17/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikp4cjy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I have a £500 &#34;learning&#34; budget from work, and no idea what to spend it on. I am</title><updated>2022-08-17T19:30:53Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I have a £500 &#34;learning&#34; budget from work, and no idea what to spend it on. I am a software tester looking for a programming job, but all the programming resources I use range from free to very cheap. I could buy physical textbooks, but prefer digital (which are free or piratable).

Budget can be spent on learning &#34;anything&#34;, e.g. pottery lessons, but I must be a boring person and don&#39;t have many hobbies or ideas.

Any suggestions? Good programming resources to spend money on? Novel ideas?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikp4cjy/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikp0kve/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;m not a parent and don&#39;t plan to become one, but I&#39;m curious. Should American </title><updated>2022-08-17T19:07:06Z</updated><author><name>kcu51</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not a parent and don&#39;t plan to become one, but I&#39;m curious. Should American parents be more concerned than they are about the US Pledge of Allegiance? Wouldn&#39;t it be simple to &#34;inoculate&#34; a child against it by having them take a counter-pledge in advance that negates it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikp0kve/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikoxkaa/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Why is the argument so common that because a system had origins in oppression (r</title><updated>2022-08-17T18:48:19Z</updated><author><name>thejawaknight</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Why is the argument so common that because a system had origins in oppression (racism/misogyny/homophobia) the system is automatically irredeemable and can only be fixed by a revolution outside the system?

It seems like a form of magical thinking to me as if the structures were suffused with some ethereal quality of racism in them. I feel like you would need to demonstrate how those systems operate in an oppressive manner today rather than just constantly pointing to history.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikoxkaa/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikorm5k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Where does the talking point about men trying to control women&#39;s bodies in relat</title><updated>2022-08-17T18:11:20Z</updated><author><name>thejawaknight</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Where does the talking point about men trying to control women&#39;s bodies in relation to abortion come from? I always saw it as conservatives believing that the fetus has moral value and I&#39;m not sure why people say that they just want to control women.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikorm5k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikof5fq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How likely is it that various common minor health problems (e.g. tinnitus) are c</title><updated>2022-08-17T16:53:19Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How likely is it that various common minor health problems (e.g. tinnitus) are caused sexually transmitted infections? If they are, is there a way to undo the damage or get rid of the infection?

EDIT: This was not a question specifically about tinnitus. That was just an example.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikof5fq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikoevdl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Is Adrafiil available anywhere?  If not, any suggestions for a replacement?</title><updated>2022-08-17T16:51:35Z</updated><author><name>Iconochasm</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Is Adrafiil available anywhere?  If not, any suggestions for a replacement?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikoevdl/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iko5pes/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The results of the Republican primary in Wyoming are in, and [Liz Cheney is out]</title><updated>2022-08-17T15:53:53Z</updated><author><name>tricksandcandlewicks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The results of the Republican primary in Wyoming are in, and [Liz Cheney is out](https://apnews.com/article/2022-midterm-elections-donald-trump-presidential-wyoming-alaska-48a5444f247727d26cf67a0a72f14637). This is after Cheney voted to impeach Trump in 2020, and then provided various choice quotes in the Jan 6 hearings against him. It seems the Republican voters are committed to enforcing party loyalty to Trump, and now Cheney will either have run to the Democrats or accept she no longer has a voice in the party.

This combined with the recent FBI probe on Trump&#39;s home, and the confirmation of the incident in &#39;the Beast&#39; make Trump seem only further like the best candidate for the GOP. The system is doing all it can to put him down, and is making life worse and worse for the average person. Trying to squeeze swing voters with a moderate candidate at this stage just looks like giving in to people with the worst of intentions.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iko5pes/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmw6jf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I need to find a new hobby that&#39;s worth my time and provides immediate rewards w</title><updated>2022-08-17T09:35:25Z</updated><author><name>societal</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I need to find a new hobby that&#39;s worth my time and provides immediate rewards when I&#39;m done with it and incentive to do it more?  Any advice?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmw6jf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmstw7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-17T08:49:39Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmstw7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/w</title><updated>2022-08-17T08:44:43Z</updated><author><name>whenhaveiever</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/wellness_wednesday_for_june_22_2022/id9zyuu/). Has it really been eight weeks?

The pregnancy has been coming along nicely. We&#39;ve had two sets of ultrasounds so far, and our kid is the size of a lemon now. I&#39;ve heard about pregnancy cravings, but I&#39;d never heard of pregnancy aversions. They&#39;re apparently a thing, and it hops from one food to the next, including long-time favorite foods, so finding something that she&#39;s willing to eat can be challenging. But morning sickness barely showed up, and nothing like in the movies, so we&#39;re thankful for that. We&#39;re starting to figure out how to rearrange the house and loosely thinking about names. Instead of paying some $700 for a DNA test now that would tell us the sex, we&#39;ll wait until the week 20 ultrasound to find out for free. In the meantime, I&#39;m more accustomed to using the singular *they* than my mom is, and accidentally had her thinking we were having twins since I kept saying *they*.

I visited my parents (on the other side of the country, so I&#39;m not there very often). I got there in time to help my dad come home from rehab, and help both my parents through a remodel of their ground floor to add a shower plus room for a wheelchair to negotiate through the bathroom. That way dad can have everything he needs without stairs. He eats very little, and when we try to encourage him, he says he &#34;just can&#39;t.&#34; Finding something that *he&#39;s* willing to eat can also be challenging. Because he&#39;s anemic, his doctor put him on prenatal vitamins as a cheap source of easy iron, and with a few things going on in his gut, he&#39;s gotten a few ultrasounds. It&#39;s odd how life rhymes sometimes. Since I&#39;ve been back on this side of the country, dad was in and out of the hospital another time. They suspected a fistula and he was going to get surgery, then they decided he doesn&#39;t have one and just gave him antibiotics. I&#39;ve lost count of how many times he&#39;s been in there in the last year and a half, and while each one is necessary at the time, each time he comes back weaker and has to spend weeks regaining his strength.

We also visited her parents (not as far away as mine, but far enough that it had been awhile). Since that trip, I&#39;ve found it hard to get back to the normal routine. It seems especially more difficult to get up in the morning, and I have to really push myself to get going. I hope it&#39;s just a slump. I think part of it is regretting that I moved away from my parents way back when, and that I&#39;ve spent so much time away from them. I think part of it is in some way realizing that I&#39;m going to be sleeping much less once the baby comes, and so I might as well enjoy it while I can. But I&#39;m also not enjoying it. It makes me feel like crap.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iklaeru/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So while we seem to have managed to add to the record every political hot take o</title><updated>2022-08-17T00:04:58Z</updated><author><name>GrapeGrater</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So while we seem to have managed to add to the record every political hot take of the last week, we somehow completely missed the arrest of the Tornado Cash developer, Alexey Pertsev in Amsterdam. This is a fairly interesting omission from the forum in its own right as this forum has at least traditionally had a strong SF Tech overlap. 

But for those who didn&#39;t get the story, Tornado cash is a new Smart Contract that is intended to obscure the block-chain addresses used in transactions by bundling them together to obfuscate any single transaction. The US Treasury blacklisted the coin blacklisted and declared it illegal for Americans to own or use following it being used to funnel money to North Korea [see: https://nitter.net/RyanSAdams/status/1558129960140816384#m, https://www.pcmag.com/news/tornado-cash-developer-arrested-as-blacklisted-crypto-site-goes-down, https://www.foxbusiness.com/financials/dutch-authorities-arrest-suspected-developer-tornado-cash-platform-launder-billions]. 

Dutch authorities (Pertsev is Dutch) have claimed to have an independent investigation and the arrest was for concealing criminal financial flows and money laundering on behalf of the Dutch prosecutor&#39;s office. [https://nitter.net/sccanavos/status/1559530518043148290#m]

This obviously has many developers in arms. Tornado Cash was VC backed and worked to follow the law [https://nitter.net/jonst0kes/status/1558196851169452034#m, https://nitter.net/dystopiabreaker/status/1558196263190876161#m]

Fight For the Future (remember them?) and The EFF have weighed in favor of the developer [https://nitter.net/fightfortheftr/status/1559297577694429184#m, https://nitter.net/EFF/status/1559224086491934720#m] With the EFF taking the long-standing stance that code is free speech (remember that argument)? Coin Center has promised a lawsuit, likely in conjunction with the EFF and FFTF.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iklaeru/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikkgj7m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Alright, we&#39;re up to the next step of the site changeover!**

We have a dev si</title><updated>2022-08-16T20:34:54Z</updated><author><name>ZorbaTHut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Alright, we&#39;re up to the next step of the site changeover!**

We have a dev site at https://www.dev.themotte.org/. I strongly encourage you to make an account and test stuff out. Change settings, try to break it, make sure it works how you&#39;d expect it to. Can you find problems? Please find problems! Report them here, or at the, uh, dammit, I don&#39;t trust Reddit to not filter this. Report them at the repo on https://github.com/themotte that says it&#39;s for the website. If they&#39;re sensitive for some reason, feel free to PM me.

The standard posting rules do apply, with the major exception of the low-effort rule. Low-effort posts are still disallowed, but no-effort posts are explicitly allowed! Post Lorem Ipsum! Post the bee movie script! Write &#34;I am a fish&#34; 400 times! Go wild! Obviously this is a dev-site-only change, this is just to make it easier to test stuff.

If you want to join the dev team, [it&#39;s over here](https://discord.gg/KChpcdaNJC). I cannot emphasize this enough: *this would not be happening if it wasn&#39;t for our volunteers*. They are great. I seriously need to put a Credits page on the site, I haven&#39;t done that yet, but I will. Thank you!

Again, please report any issues you run into, from site-breaking issues to mild inconveniences; every bit of info is useful. I can always triage minor things down, but if I don&#39;t know about them, they won&#39;t ever get fixed.

2-hour-later edit: we&#39;re up to 9 new bugs found, y&#39;all are great, keep it coming

5.5-hour-later edit: 16 bugs/requests filed</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikkgj7m/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikk4m00/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [87,000 Racists](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/87000-racists) 

tags: \[self promo</title><updated>2022-08-16T19:17:47Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[87,000 Racists](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/87000-racists) 

tags: \[self promotion\]\[meme analysis\]\[systemic racism\]\[tax enforcement policy\]

Inflammatory title I know, but that&#39;s how traffic works these days. I beg forgiveness on that.

The article basically analyzes the conservative claim on social media from last week that the 87,000 tax collectors in the Inflation Reduction Act would be used to attack poor people. While the maps seem to indicate that, and further seem more specifically to be targeting *non-white people*, the truth of the matter is more nuanced. The audits are disproportionately attacking folks who file the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC) due presumptively to some systemic flagging mechanism within the IRS. And since that&#39;s a measure specifically for poor people, their audits also predominantly hit poor people.

Part of this has to do with changes in staffing. They have more low grade &#34;tax examiners&#34; and fewer higher grade &#34;revenue agents,&#34; and the examiners are largely issuing &#34;correspondence audits&#34; which are simpler things which basically just demand more information. But since they&#39;re demanding them from poorer folks who may not have all the information or understand the cryptic language the correspondence audits are issued in, targeting them pumps the enforcement numbers up and makes the auditors look good.

So now if we set that on a shelf and examine one of the more popular definitions of &#34;systemic racism&#34; (Socioeconomic and government systems which produce differential racial outcomes) then it is apparent that the IRS&#39;s EITC flagging criteria are a result of a &#34;racist system&#34; because it fits the definition in use.

Whether this provision within the Inflation Reduction Act itself then qualifies as &#34;racist&#34; will in the end depend on whether the $80 billion earmark in the law includes a way to fix the racist system, or whether it will just be thrown at increasing operations as they currently exist, in which case the EITC audits will just increase.

Article has numerous charts, maps, and references.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikk4m00/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjvwmp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Question for you, TheMotte users that are part of the zoomer-millennial demograp</title><updated>2022-08-16T18:22:56Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Question for you, TheMotte users that are part of the zoomer-millennial demographic;

Have you noticed that, in your middle-upper class bubble of fellow z-millennials, that a big chunk of people vote left only for lgbt rights?

I mean, anedoctically, a big percenteage of my acquiantances vote left only for that reason, also if they do not agree at all economically or politically with them (and are completely straight so they have no skin in the game) 

Real quotes:
&#34;I think that their economic policy is stupid, but I vote them for DDL Zan (a failed law on discrimination in Italy)&#34;
&#34; I hate them because they are not too left wing, but they support lgbt&#34;
&#34; Meh, they looks the only one that protects gays&#34;

It is also true in your experience?
And if so, how is possible that this question has become so important for so many people that have no skin in the game?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjvwmp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjpzhs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;ve noticed an interesting shift among the progressive movement lately. I think</title><updated>2022-08-16T17:45:29Z</updated><author><name>Texas_Rockets</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;ve noticed an interesting shift among the progressive movement lately. I think there&#39;s starting to be a recognition that the fervor and policies born in 2020 were fairly flawed, as evidenced by the legacy of ideas like defund the police, and elections in fairly left areas in which people rejected the progressive candidates in places like NYC, NJ, VA, and SF (the [SF one](https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/05/chesa-boudin-recall-san-francisco-crime/629907/) in particular is interesting. Chesa Boudin really served as a microcosm of progressivism who was given free reign, as were the city council elections that took place around the same time, thus his election served to some extent as a referendum on progressivism).

But what&#39;s interesting is that progressives, in self reflecting and having to analyze why this has occurred, have blamed progressive white people. And to a considerable degree the same thing has been occurring with respect to the policies corporations instituted during 2020. Which is so crazy to me. On the one hand, I agree and find overeducated white progressives who come from wealthy families to be among the most insufferable demographics. But on the other, their only real crime is that they listened to what was being demanded of them, that they be allies and use their supposed privilege to advance the views of anti-racists. It&#39;s kind of like they&#39;re being told &#34;Lol you thought we were serious with all of that stuff? What the fuck is wrong with you?&#34; It sort of validates the view that anti-racists have anti-white undercurrents. Like if they did unambiguously have anti-white undercurrents, how would they respond to the recognition of the ideological excesses of 2020? They would blame white people. Like if you’re a white progressive and want to support movements and ideas like that, at this point I don’t know what the fuck you’re supposed to do. If you don’t support it you’re part of the problem as identified by people you agree with, and if you do support it you’re going to be the scape goat when shit goes south and it becomes clear that the policies you supported to advance the ends you were told to advance were deeply flawed.

I think it also reveals a lack of strategy on the part of people working to advance those ideas, even within their own paradigm. Their view is that white people wield disproportionately more institutional power than non-white people do, so if that’s true you would want those people with outsized power and who agree with you to use that power to advance your ends. But instead they are condemning them and de-incentivizing their participation. It just seems very counterintuitive.

I think it really comes down to the fact that activists are insatiable. when they’re actually given the reins, asked what exactly they want, and allowed to implement policies, they don’t actually know. or if they do have proposals it&#39;s always impractically radical stuff that only makes sense to the small group of people who agree with them like just razing institutions and starting over or defunding the police or something equally as bizzare. it reminds me a lot of the occupy wall street people. They’re the dog that caught the car. They aren’t there to actually catch the car, they’re there to chase the car. implementing the change that they desire requires an understanding of things as they are (you have to understand the problem before you can develop a solution), but activists’ characteristic commitment to ideology precludes them from interpreting the world or developing solutions that go even a bit outside the scope of their ideology. Like can anyone seriously envision a series of events and policies that would have caused BLM to be like &#39;welp. that&#39;s pretty much what we were asking for. you did it and solved the problem. guess we can just pack up our shit and go home.&#39; like even over the course of their ideas being implemented over 10 years I can&#39;t envision that occurring. 

Progressive activists are the dog that caught the car, and once they caught the car and fucked it away they blamed it on the person who served as the distraction that slowed the car down and opened the door for the dog to do what it wanted to do. I think this is indicative of intellectual rot and my view is that to some extent the movement has been exposed and they sorta blew it when they had the spotlight.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjpzhs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikeni69/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I asked this in the [previous thread](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments</title><updated>2022-08-15T17:21:22Z</updated><author><name>escherofescher</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I asked this in the [previous thread](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijl6gb9/) but got no hits. I&#39;ll ask one more time, hoping that maybe this time it&#39;ll get more eyeballs, then commit myself to silence:

Is there a modern expansion or critique to Popper&#39;s &#34;Open Society and Its Enemies&#34;?

I&#39;ve found his arguments strongly convincing. Even if I disregard the large part about historicism, the open/individual vs closed/collectivist model continue to make sense to me.

I wonder if someone picked up his ideas and continued to develop them? Or if someone found flaws?

I know Soros published some books in the same area (open society/capitalism reform), but haven&#39;t looked at any of them yet.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikeni69/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ike0zu9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] How do you teach a kid learning algebra to recognize square numbers?

My kid kno</title><updated>2022-08-15T14:53:28Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">How do you teach a kid learning algebra to recognize square numbers?

My kid knows how to factor `a^2 - b^2` but cannot recognize that `121x^2 - y^2` is of that form.

I do not know how to *not* see 121 as a ~~prime~~ square number, so I am not much help here.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ike0zu9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikaie1b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Any recommendations for worthwhile subreddits? Or other forums?</title><updated>2022-08-14T19:42:45Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Any recommendations for worthwhile subreddits? Or other forums?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikaie1b/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikac6ei/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Vernor Vinge&#39;s *A Fire Upon the Deep*.</title><updated>2022-08-14T18:59:41Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Vernor Vinge&#39;s *A Fire Upon the Deep*. I&#39;ve been hearing about this book for years, but finally decided to read it when I realized that it&#39;s the same person who wrote the well-known paper *The Coming Technological Singularity*.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ikac6ei/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ika0y4x/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] The second story of my home, where I have my desk and computer set up, overlooks</title><updated>2022-08-14T17:42:31Z</updated><author><name>Walterodim79</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">The second story of my home, where I have my desk and computer set up, overlooks a park. I&#39;ve considered this one of the nicer features of my home, particularly given how many cityscapes don&#39;t have all that nice of views. In the past couple months, a group of indigents have taken up residence in the park and seem to be escalating their degree of permanence; what started with someone sleeping with their head on their suitcase moved to having a couple mattresses, and today I see that a tent has been added. During the day, more of their friends show up and spread out more mattresses and blankets and drink all day. 

What&#39;s the appropriate reaction to this? How would you feel and react to it? I&#39;ve done nothing about it at present other than comment to my wife that I think it&#39;s going nowhere good, but I&#39;m trying to process whether I should be doing anything about it or just dealing with the fact that this is just how American cities are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ika0y4x/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticul</title><updated>2022-08-14T14:29:24Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticuline](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reticuline) is for neurons?  I’m trying to figure out whether reticuline is neurotoxic like alcohol or something more serious. There’s some cool herbalism involving it but I don’t want to take chances.

I can only find its toxicity in relation to Annonacin where it’s written “annonacin is a thousand times (1000x) more toxic to cultured neuronal cells than reticuline”. Regarding annonacin, “Studies in rodents indicate that consumption of annonacin (3.8 and 7.6 mg per kg per day for 28 days) caused brain lesions consistent with Parkinson&#39;s disease. An adult who consumes a fruit or can of nectar daily over the course of a year is estimated to ingest the same amount of annonacin that induced brain lesions in the rodents receiving purified annonacin intravenously.”

One study has,

&amp;gt;we exposed mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons in culture to the total extract (totum) of alkaloids from Annona muricata root bark and to two of the most abundant subfractions, corexi- mine and reticuline. After 24 hours, 50% of dopaminergic neu- rons degenerated with 18 􏰀g/ml totum, 4.3 􏰀g/ml (13 􏰀M) coreximine, or 100 􏰀g/ml (304 􏰀M) reticuline.

Now a lancet correspondence from 99 says,

&amp;gt; Although the two studies did conclude that simple 1-benzylated TIQs are “relatively weak neurotoxins” that can cause behavioural signs of parkinsonism in animal models, they did not examine the structurally more complex reticuline, a morphinan precursor (or any of its N-methylated alkaloidal derivatives or metabolites). As with many isoquinoline alkaloids, reticuline has pharmacological activity at diverse neurotransmitter synapses and uptake sites. However, a myriad of studies going back nearly 30 years have never revealed it to be neurotoxic. If anything, with its phenolic groups, reticuline is more likely to be a n t i o x i d a t i v e 4 , 5 a n d , t h u s, n e u r o - protective against the free radical- initiated toxicity that is commonly linked to neurodegenerative mechanisms.

The cell culture study looks pretty bad though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik8mt3g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Has the world gone fucking insane?  

Is this an appropriate question?

Edit： Ap</title><updated>2022-08-14T10:52:18Z</updated><author><name>George_E_Hale</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Has the world gone fucking insane?  

Is this an appropriate question?

Edit： Apparently it&#39;s not an appropriate question.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik8mt3g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik8ht6s/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does the FBI and/or CIA have it in for Donald Trump? And if so, why?</title><updated>2022-08-14T09:43:29Z</updated><author><name>throwaway-7744</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does the FBI and/or CIA have it in for Donald Trump? And if so, why?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik8ht6s/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>