<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-26T02:15:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decl</title><updated>2022-07-26T02:15:24Z</updated><author><name>ussgordoncaptain2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decline&#34; which I disagreed with but the modal motte user agreed with.

Therefore I need to tease out what people meant by &#34;the west&#34; and meant by &#34;decline&#34;.

Survey&#39;s are popular so I [made 1](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScbtLqP8cf6ae4C3JeRXXXXNpCBlVF28B9QuDshf9oswPBHXg/viewform?usp=sf_link).

Most of the questions are replicated below.

1. What G20 nations are in &#34;The west&#34; (most notable countries, being Russia, Japan, and South Korea) 

2. What countries are in Decline? 

3. What do people mean when they say &#34;Decline&#34;? Do they mean relative decline or absolute decline?
        
       3a. A country loses her imperial holdings but the mainland grew 5x in the time period, did they &#34;decline&#34;

       3b. A global power grows 5 fold with stable borders but the rest of the world grew 10 fold, did they &#34;decline&#34;  
        3c. A country grows 5 fold in 30 years becoming one of the major powers, but then in the next 30 years grows only 1.5x and falls from 1/3rd as strong to being 2/9ths as strong as the main superpower.


When people say the west is in decline I tend to disagree, with the exception of the fall of the British and French empires, The west has not declined, merely risen slower than contemporaries. Even then since the fall of the berlin wall only 1 nation (china) has risen to surpass the Medium powers of Germany/France/Britan. Though Japan surpassed them as well, Japan also became &#34;west&#34; somehow.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihmd0bz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Reposting my link to a survey. I didn&#39;t get any responses from The Motte users (</title><updated>2022-07-25T19:55:56Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Reposting my link to a survey. I didn&#39;t get any responses from The Motte users (I got some from the other two subs) so I&#39;m posting it here, I think the CW thread might get all the traffic as opposed to the front page. 

Recently there was a post trying to survey the general knowledge of the motte. The post got removed. And various people accused the survey of having various shortcomings, from it being a troll, to OP having some kind of agenda with the questions asked. 

Therefore I created a new survey for general knowledge. 

~~1. Its timed. There are 39 questions. With 35 minutes to answer all of them.~~ 

~~2. They are all multiple choice, with only 1 valid answer.~~

There is a math, CS, geography, history and economics section.

I tried to design the questions such that they can be answered without any niche/esoteric knowledge. I did not include any of my personal pet questions or anything like that and tried to frame the questions such that you can use incomplete knowledge to answer them, as long as you have a rough idea of the mechanisms that guide those fields. 

Feedback appreciated. 

DISCLAIMER: Email only to log in, I can&#39;t see the emails. 

Link to the survey here. https://forms.gle/S2a8BY7Ln8kPcCpj9


________________________

edit - Very controversial. I will count more than one answer to the *vague* questions as correct when I do the final eda. My ultimate goal is to do a subreddit wide survey, not individual survey, so don&#39;t put too much weight into your own score. Add +1 or 2 points because some questions are vague, if you want a rough estimate of your score were the questions less vague.

edit2- Certain questions most people were getting wrong, people are getting right now. Either there is data leakage from the comments, or a different demographic is onto it. Hmmmmm</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihmd0bz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihm3sny/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Only know a little on how computers work.  But when I code in my limited experie</title><updated>2022-07-25T18:57:04Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Only know a little on how computers work.  But when I code in my limited experience I have to things perfectly grammatically for the machine to understand.

How does this work at the machine level?  Why doesn’t the whole thing crash if a few bits degrade which I assume happens?  Is their something that corrects the silicon for errors?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihm3sny/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihllphv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, you know how when you examine the porn consumption habits vs. political beli</title><updated>2022-07-25T17:02:29Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, you know how when you examine the porn consumption habits vs. political beliefs, you can always find something worth a laugh?

[https://lawsuit.org/general-law/republicans-have-an-obsession-with-transgender-pornography/](https://lawsuit.org/general-law/republicans-have-an-obsession-with-transgender-pornography/)

Here it is again: Conservatives fucking LOVE trans porn, and liberals don&#39;t seem to know it exists. 

Likewise, conservative as a population love cuckoldry(BLACK), cheating, and Teen; while liberals seem to go in hard for BDSM, rape play, and power dynamic shit.

You can&#39;t really do anything useful with this other than score the meaningless dunks on the more naïve type of lib or con; but I always wonder if there is anything meaningful you can take from it?

That is, I don&#39;t really have anything interesting to say about it that hasn&#39;t been said, other than I still don&#39;t understand the why this would be the case to consistently and none of the explanations I&#39;ve heard have an air of truthiness.

Anyone have any links that they feel explain this well?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihllphv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub. </title><updated>2022-07-25T16:37:27Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub.  I thought I&#39;d share some thoughts on it.

There is a technique that old SysAdmins will recognize called tarpitting: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarpit_(networking)#SMTP_tarpits

The technique is to prevent spammers from being able to abuse a mail server (send too many messages) by simply wasting their time.  If the mail system detects something it believes is a spammer, it will simply make everything take a really long (relatively) time.

Instead of being able to send 1000 messages/second, it might limit you to one message ever 5 seconds (this is exaggerated).  The idea is that a normal user won&#39;t notice this, but a spammer trying to send thousands of messages will.  It&#39;s a very clever, and also effective strategy.  I like it.

There is something that I&#39;ve noticed especially on reddit, which feels like an evolution of Gish Galloping: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gish_gallop

The way it might go is that an uncharitable discussion partner will write long posts with very little substance in which they repeatedly ask the same questions, or sortof &#34;play dumb&#34; and ask for explanations for things which have been discussed *extensively* in the past.

I notice it here, but I notice it on other subreddits as well.  To put on a tinfoil hat for a short second: a lot of times the accounts which engage in this behavior seem to spend an almost *unbelievable* amount of time posting things on reddit, and often only on one subreddit.  So my tinfoil hat question is: are these really good GPT bots?  GPT-3 is *quite* good, and it seems within the realm of possibility that there are conversational-tarpitting bots that exist.

My question is: has anybody else noticed this behavior and charted it at all?  If so how do you identify it and what framework do you use for thinking about it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihle362/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anybody else been seeing a significant ramp-up in spam emails getting past Gmail</title><updated>2022-07-25T16:14:19Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anybody else been seeing a significant ramp-up in spam emails getting past Gmail&#39;s spam filter?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihle362/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] *Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought th</title><updated>2022-07-25T15:10:46Z</updated><author><name>codergenius</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">*Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought that it would be too culture-wary for the small questions thread*

**What is the actual difference between arranged marriages vs love marriages (failure modes, happy paths, why would be one be better than the other based on certain frameworks, and so on)?** 

After looking on the internet, I found that the differences account for context to be already present. I found out that I could not grok that context as I am too &#34;autistic&#34; (God I hate that word, along with nerdy). I am trying to understand it as an alien that has come to the earth for the first time or in the rationalist terms, I am trying to taboo the words &#34;love&#34;, &#34;arranged&#34; and &#34;marriages&#34;.   
  
I would really like views with the framework stated, if that is not too much or better yet, links to forums that you have seen where these concepts are discussed in detail. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihl3m3y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] When I was trying to learn how to swim a mile, I followed this plan [Zero to 165</title><updated>2022-07-25T15:06:05Z</updated><author><name>codergenius</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When I was trying to learn how to swim a mile, I followed this plan [Zero to 1650 in six weeks](http://ruthkazez.com/SwimWorkouts/ZeroTo1mile.html), albeit with some allowances for slack and injury concerns. Do you know of a similar plan for 

* Learning a musical instrument (guitar)
* Cooking (French/Italian cuisine)
* Comedy (Improv Theatre, sketch writing)
* Target practice (Guns, archery) 

Basically, I am looking some kind of plan as a beginner that I could rework for intermediate and advanced levels. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihl3m3y/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihkt65w/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Here&#39;s a writing prompt: 

Since I now view Star Wars as a dead franchise, the o</title><updated>2022-07-25T13:52:53Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Here&#39;s a writing prompt: 

Since I now view Star Wars as a dead franchise, the only thing left fun to do with it is armchair-write-produce-direct it.

Write a better version of The Last Jedi.  (Which means Force Awakened happened.  Deal with it)

Hardmode: Keep as much of the original film&#39;s elements as possible.

Funmode: You get to Ignore The Force Awakens.  Do whatever you want with a new Star Wars trilogy</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihkt65w/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/cul</title><updated>2022-07-25T13:31:45Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?context=3) about oil prices a few days ago.

One of the sub-questions I was curious about was why oil companies weren’t investing more in digging new wells.  A few commenters replied that this was probably because of Biden – he opened up his term by cancelling the Keystone XL pipeline, removing permits on drilling on federal lands and saying we should move towards fully green energy.  My reply was that Obama basically did all that stuff too and oil production doubled under him, so are these kinds of regulatory policy moves really that important to investors?

Users u/LeninLovedUncleTom and u/Pulpachair offered more information on how technology breakthroughs and the relatively high price of crude oil opened up the new shale market under Obama and led to that crazy growth.  But there’s still a lot of shale and crude prices are crazy high again and no one’s drilling.  I think [both](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih8bt2a/?context=3) [users](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih89f6l/?context=3) made compelling arguments (if i followed them), substantiated with the articles I can find with quotes from oil leaders, that the primary driver of investment isn&#39;t really regulatory policy, it&#39;s the fact that everyone is too worried about massive market fluctuations.  OPEC cratered prices after the initial shale boom and hurt a lot of investors, and Covid saw barrels going for negative prices.  Who wants to invest in drilling more when the market could switch up on you and completely destroy your profits?  [To quote](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-02-18/shale-wildcatters-send-bullish-oil-price-signal-with-output-restraint):

&amp;gt;“Whether it’s $150 oil, $200 oil, or $100 oil, we’re not going to change our growth plans,’’ Pioneer Chief Executive Officer Scott Sheffield said during a Bloomberg Television interview. “If the president wants us to grow, I just don’t think the industry can grow anyway.’’

I think here this offers us two possibilities, with two questions I’d ask everyone.

1:  If we assume government policy can’t make a huge difference on oil investment relative to the market, and the market experiences such dramatic fluctuations that investors literally won’t invest in drilling more even when it would be profitable, and that this common sense market rationale means we all have to eat high gas prices: is this not an extremely strong argument for trying to divest away from oil?  To invest full scale in nuclear and renewables (edit: and battery storage technology) and microgrids and the infrastructure to make electric vehicles possible and widespread?

Much is talked about the intermittency issues with renewables, but should the fact that Russia and China each control 15% of the world’s oil production, and petroleum sales can always be used as a carrot or stick in conflicts like the current one, and that we don’t have the ability to control OPEC with their further 44% of the world’s production – shouldn’t all this be seen functionally as an broad scale intermittency problem as well?  You can address shortfalls with wind and solar in a number of ways, like using combined heat and gas systems or only using them to complement nuclear power, but in crisis situations where 15% of the world’s oil disappears off of the western markets there doesn’t seem to be any quick fix – our oil companies outright say the won’t drill more no matter what the president does!

I’m well aware this would be a cost intensive and technologically challenging road, and that renewables in particular have other huge limitations and could perhaps never fully fill the gap fossil fuels played, but wouldn’t shrinking our fossil fuel dependency alone go significantly far towards reducing our exposure to these kinds of crises?  Would the eventual problems we might face in a country that invested to the hilt in electric cars, nuclear energy, renewable energy systems and decentralized microgrids be worse than what we’re dealing with now?  Would it be worse than the fact that our country is always vulnerable having the pipe turned off from the outside?

2:  Alternatively, maybe none of the obvious stuff Biden could do would help oil.  But let’s pretend he can - what if he did all the non-obvious stuff as well?  What if Biden completely deregulated oil, cut their taxes down to zero, gave them (more) massive subsidies and promised to insure any losses from market fluctuations, slashed wages, cut all zoning laws, worker’s rights, safety regulations and environmental regulations and finally got domestic oil production to rise.

Would it be worth it?

Sometimes I’m jealous of China’s powerful industrial base.  Then I think about their horrendously polluted waterways and their skies full of smog and their workers paid pittances to labor for crazy hours in often unsafe conditions, and I wonder if it would be worth having to do all that to compete with them on some kind of even footing.

Would it be worth producing two, three, four times as much oil, enough that we have dominance over the world price and never have to worry about this situation again, if we also had to trade away our centuries of hard-fought worker’s rights? If all of our gorgeous national parks were studded with oil wells and refineries and our waterways and skies groaned under the weight of their pollution?  This is an exaggerated example to be sure, but in a world where oil executives outright say the President’s normal policy levers won’t change their investment outlook, it bears worth asking: how much are we actually willing to give up to change that?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ihiks18/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wedne</title><updated>2022-07-25T00:20:47Z</updated><author><name>QuarkweightGOAT</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/)

Week 4/60 is behind me. Easily the most difficult week. A lot of fatigue, cravings, low mood, etc. Still feeling that right now even though I would have been overjoyed to be in this position at my fattest.  

As I had planned, I fasted the first two days of the week and then final four days as well with Wednesday off. Feeling very lethargic but fortunately I am all done with trying to lose fat. Going to bed hungry tonight but I get to eat tomorrow. No alcohol and I finished the last pack in my carton of cigarettes yesterday. Won&#39;t be buying more. I started doing calisthenics this week to get an early start on delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS) which results from beginning a new exercise regimen particularly rigorous resistance training. 

I lost less than I expected this week given that I fasted for 6 days total. I guess my body revolted and slowed my metabolism way down. Or maybe a touch of dysmorphia. Have a bit of fat left around my lower stomach and lower back but it&#39;s not a lot. I didn&#39;t weigh myself throughout the 4 weeks of fasting. If I had to guess, after I get some food in me and muscle glycogen is restored,  I weigh around how much I weighed when I ran cross country in high school (145ish) at 6&#39;1. I got up to a little over 230 because of the medication situation I briefly mentioned I think in my first post. Will post before and after pictures next week. 

Will do calisthenics for the first half of the week and get a gym membership late next week. Going to use an online total daily energy expenditure (TDEE) calculator and probably subtract a couple hundred calories since my metabolism probably needs time to bounce back. 

Will provide a more detailed account of my plan going forward next week. Thank you.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ihiks18/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihhgg4l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, which is about</title><updated>2022-07-24T19:28:04Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, which is about black hat hackers in the 90s. It seems that it was researched by none other than Julian Assange himself, who was one of the handle-owning hackers featured.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihhgg4l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgvakg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m under the impression that small culture war laden questions are permissible </title><updated>2022-07-24T16:59:43Z</updated><author><name>Jeccems</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m under the impression that small culture war laden questions are permissible - I&#39;m mostly just looking for a reference.  Apologies if I&#39;m mistaken.  

Lynching.  I&#39;m trying to understand the extent and severity.  Is there a good resource for understanding the historical phenomenon as it occurred in the United States?  Hopefully with some high level of detail and specificity?  I am of the impression that it&#39;s incredibly inflated in the minds of modern individuals - occurring a few thousand times over the course of a century, to people of various ethnicities.  Most specifically, I am interested in the reasonableness (for lack of a better word) of the actions.  Extrajudicial violence is, in and of itself, somewhat unreasonable a priori, but how many victims were random citizens taken off the street, and how many were communally killed before the legal system would have (likely) found them guilty of the alleged crimes?  Is there any accounting of this?  Is looking for as much frivolous?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgvakg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgexto/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] iTunes broke my Windows 10 laptop.

Before installing iTunes on my HP laptop wit</title><updated>2022-07-24T15:04:43Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">iTunes broke my Windows 10 laptop.

Before installing iTunes on my HP laptop with Core i5 7th Gen Intel, I could watch fullscreen video without judder, I could have dozens of tabs open simultaneously, I could play video games.

Then I installed iTunes for a work project. Fullscreen video runs at one frame per second, and embedded videos almost as slowly. Even two tabs on Firefox makes it nearly impossible to move my mouse cursor, which moves, freezes, and then reappears halfway across screen.

Now, even after uninstalling iTunes (and its associated tools) and a day later reinstalling my Intel onboard graphics driver, the problems remain. Since I can&#39;t afford a new computer, I&#39;m stuck with this one for now, and I&#39;ll need to use it next weekend to run an RPG, so the clock is ticking. Any suggestions?

EDIT: SOLVED. No more replies plz. Thanks for all the help! Apparently it&#39;s a known problem with Win10, usually drivers, and it&#39;s been solved by people doing things as wacky as disabling their DVD drive or uninstalling their mouse.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgexto/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgdg5n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Where can I find stats on how many IVF babies have been born each year going bac</title><updated>2022-07-24T14:54:04Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Where can I find stats on how many IVF babies have been born each year going back to the 70s?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihgdg5n/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihg1ec7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Are there any major image/media search/collection websites that are not Pinteres</title><updated>2022-07-24T13:22:38Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Are there any major image/media search/collection websites that are not Pinterest/Tumblr?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihg1ec7/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihg15n2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Is there any value to thirst-fasting, eg going x hours of your day without hydra</title><updated>2022-07-24T13:20:32Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Is there any value to thirst-fasting, eg going x hours of your day without hydration? It would seem to fall in line with other kinds of “fasting” that have health benefits (caloric fasting, sleep restriction to increase sleep efficiency). The closest I could find is a study where *not* hydrating *within* an exercise session (but a little after) led to increased cardiovascular gains. My intuition is that there is probably some health benefit to ~8 hours of the day refraining from hydration, followed by over-hydration.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihg15n2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfxd76/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What&#39;s the most right-wing quote from a work of fiction you can think of?

Mine </title><updated>2022-07-24T12:45:42Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What&#39;s the most right-wing quote from a work of fiction you can think of?

Mine is from *No Country for Old Men*:

&amp;gt; &#34;Dope. They sell that shit to schoolkids.&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;It&#39;s worse than that.&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;How&#39;s that?&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;Schoolkids buy it.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfxd76/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfgrug/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Freddie deBoer&#39;s &#34;More Commenting Sadness&#34; post:
&amp;gt; &#34;Comments are off again un</title><updated>2022-07-24T09:23:33Z</updated><author><name>cat-astropher</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Freddie deBoer&#39;s &#34;More Commenting Sadness&#34; post:
&amp;gt; &#34;Comments are off again until I decide otherwise. You know why. I have had enough.&#34;

I wasn&#39;t paying attention and don&#39;t know why.

I don&#39;t and shouldn&#39;t even need to know, but now I want to.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfgrug/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfbi4i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Tips or resources by which I can improve my English speaking? To be more specifi</title><updated>2022-07-24T08:11:20Z</updated><author><name>DandyPandemonium</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Tips or resources by which I can improve my English speaking? To be more specific, to speak more coherently.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfbi4i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihekf5a/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] A post on the CW thread trying to survey the mottes general knowledge and &#34;IQ&#34; g</title><updated>2022-07-24T03:13:46Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">A post on the CW thread trying to survey the mottes general knowledge and &#34;IQ&#34; got removed for supposedly being a troll. I didn&#39;t get to look at the questions, so I can&#39;t vouch for that.

I am thinking of making an actual general knowledge survey with sections on math, physics, biology, geogpraphy,economics and CS.

I plan to only include multiple choice questions that are straight forward and can be answered using intuition alone, no esoteric knowledge or trap questions. 

Any suggestions on other topics? Or how to frame the questions?

I might cross post to a lot of different subreddits and compile the results of each subreddit at the end.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihekf5a/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series\*. I&#39;m already getting ha</title><updated>2022-07-23T17:52:35Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series\*. I&#39;m already getting half a billion dollars worth of [entertainment](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FYS5d_YUEAAPl2D?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=orig) from it, and I&#39;m not even gonna watch.

Also my deeply closeted white trash middle school boyfriend turning out to be Sauron is an acceptable twist, if a lazy and obvious one.

&amp;gt; \* note: I have previously said nothing about the LOTR TV series</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih8alu4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] After not listening to it for several years, I&#39;ve recently revisited &#34;Vessels&#34; b</title><updated>2022-07-22T19:37:34Z</updated><author><name>nagilfarswake</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">After not listening to it for several years, I&#39;ve recently revisited &#34;Vessels&#34; by the Australian melodic death metal band Be&#39;lakor. It is a brilliant record; I think it&#39;s one of the crowning jewels of the genre both musically and in lyrical poetry.

It&#39;s a concept album, tracing the journey of the energy of a photon of light. Each song is its own self-contained story, starting with the entrance of this bit of energy into a life and ending with the extinguishing of that life&#39;s light and the energy&#39;s departure. It starts in the fusion forges of the sun, in [An Ember&#39;s Arc](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IyuDOVm8TG4):

&amp;gt; This cascade of embers,

&amp;gt; Fused into a star&#39;s ignition

&amp;gt; A crucible for their collapse,

&amp;gt; Seething crux of its ambition

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; The axiom of this expanse,

&amp;gt; Unrelenting pressure

&amp;gt; Every moment, in each place,

&amp;gt; Collisions beyond measure

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; An ordinary pair that met,

&amp;gt; Whilst merging into one,

&amp;gt; Heaved and spat a mote of light,

&amp;gt; Adrift within the Sun

and it ends in the funeral pyre of a man in [The Smoke of Many Fires](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ARI0XyTiips):

&amp;gt; Like billions before him regardless of form

&amp;gt; It ended as chance had decided

&amp;gt; So briefly contained an inferno&#39;s refrain

&amp;gt; Having powered and angered and guided

&amp;gt; ---

&amp;gt; At the heart of the blaze awareness dissolved

&amp;gt; Light ascended devoid of desire

&amp;gt; From a trail intertwined life and death strewn behind

&amp;gt; To the stars it returned from the fire</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih8alu4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih7pji9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m taking a break from my ADHD meds.  I switched to 10mg XRs about a year ago, </title><updated>2022-07-22T17:20:47Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m taking a break from my ADHD meds.  I switched to 10mg XRs about a year ago, and after taking an accidental break from them for a weekend, found my depression lifting a surprising amount.  Time passes much faster, I find it easier to sleep.  I find it easier to think creatively.  My performance at work is suffering, but coffee+nicotine+weak weed seems to be getting me through this week compared to last week.  I feel less helpless anxiety when faced with tasks.  I feel better able to keep myself company.

I still hate my life, but the experience of living it is less irritating to me now.  

I&#39;m going to see a different, less-intrusive doctor and get switched back to regular release, maybe up the daily dosage to 20, but see if I can get by only taking 10 or 15.  I just know the XRs aren&#39;t for me.

Has anyone else had similar experiences with XRs vs regulars?  Did you find an alternative to Adderall?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih7pji9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih7phca/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What’s the simplest, most barebones game you can think of? I can’t think of anyt</title><updated>2022-07-22T17:20:24Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What’s the simplest, most barebones game you can think of? I can’t think of anything simpler than Snake.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih7phca/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih6qjeu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I was laid off for the first time in my professional career this week. My (previ</title><updated>2022-07-22T13:30:11Z</updated><author><name>STLizen</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I was laid off for the first time in my professional career this week. My (previous) company dropped about 30% of its workforce.

All in all, it isn&#39;t so bad. They paid good severance and it looks like the labor market is still pretty strong in my area (software engineering). I will also likely get a significant pay bump in my next position.

And yet the entire process has just kinda left my feeling crummy. I (obviously) knew that this sort of thing can happen but the immediate impact of my career and (short term) livelihood being in the hands of someone I don&#39;t know -- where I am just basically a row on a spreadsheet that they&#39;re washing their hands of -- does not feel good. I also really liked the people I worked with (and this seems really hard to screen for ahead of time IMO, more of a crapshoot) and we worked remotely throughout the country, so will likely not really every see one another again. 

My life is pretty hectic at home with a young child at the moment but I definitely want to start thinking about diversifying my income stream outside of just one job.

Not sure the point of this post, just venting I guess.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih6qjeu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih5t22k/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So last week I jumped on a ferry and spent the day touring various sites around </title><updated>2022-07-22T07:25:12Z</updated><author><name>charizard_monster</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So last week I jumped on a ferry and spent the day touring various sites around the D Day landings. 

This was partly designed as a bonding experience with my dad and partly because it feels to me like the liberation of France is arguably Western democracy’s finest hour.

In short, I’d recommend the trip. A number of the sites are extremely high quality and clearly received considerable investment from the US government. I almost skipped it, but I’m glad I stopped at the [cemetery at Omaha beach ](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normandy_American_Cemetery_and_Memorial). The grounds are beautiful, and I found the experience of seeing the graves of so many young men surprisingly moving.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ih5t22k/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recomme</title><updated>2022-07-21T13:25:21Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recommends eating less than a teaspoon of salt per day, while animals our size generally eat a quarter to a third of an oz per day.  
I don&#39;t eat any processed food, so the only salt I get is on meat and fried eggs. Have been developing salt cravings this summer to the point that livestock mineral salt looks really delicious, which is a pretty reliable sign I&#39;m missing _something_.   
Everything out there is just yelling at people not to eat salt, but maybe someone here has done some proper research?

Bonus question: other than a costco multivitamin, what&#39;s a good extra source of zinc and other useful minerals?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1erlm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Another month, another post about relentless negative thoughts. Mostly surroundi</title><updated>2022-07-21T11:51:48Z</updated><author><name>Anouleth</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Another month, another post about relentless negative thoughts. Mostly surrounding the gym, my lack of progress, and generally feeling weak, lazy, fat, etc. Weight gain has unfortunately mostly stalled, due to working a physically demanding job with few opportunities to eat... but difficult to escape the belief that any weight gained wouldn&#39;t just be fat anyway. Have started running again with a friend (who has serious problems controlling his weight). I tend to get awful soreness/tightness in my shins, but seems to be getting less bad. Another friend has returned to the gym with me too, which is nice, except that it&#39;s because he broke up with his girlfriend, so it feels a little bit wrong to take pleasure from a bad event like that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1erlm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igz1v8u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Herman Miller chairs - expensive meme or ergonomic dream?</title><updated>2022-07-20T22:08:07Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Herman Miller chairs - expensive meme or ergonomic dream?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igz1v8u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igyyi6u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I quit drinking and vaping.

According to Fitbit my resting heart rate is alread</title><updated>2022-07-20T21:43:02Z</updated><author><name>Gorf__</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I quit drinking and vaping.

According to Fitbit my resting heart rate is already 10bpm lower, and my HRV is 20ms+ higher.

I’ve tried to quit numerous times but I think this is the actual time. I’m just tired of feeling like dog shit most of the time. I’m tired and haven’t been exercising like I used to.

Vaping was always dumb, I don’t even want that in my life. But I can’t resist it when I’m drunk, and I’m always around it, so I ended up just doing it by default.

Alcohol is mostly just nice because it’s weird to not drink, at least in my friend group. So it’s just avoiding that whole awkwardness. But, it does seem like it’s getting more common to encounter people who don’t drink. Maybe that’s just because I’m getting older. In any case, I’m starting to give less of a fuck about that. Just let me live my life, I don’t need to put garbage in my body just to make you feel better.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igyyi6u/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igym84d/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Any advice for joint issues? I have some chronic ankle problems that my doctor b</title><updated>2022-07-20T20:15:20Z</updated><author><name>wmil</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any advice for joint issues? I have some chronic ankle problems that my doctor brushes aside. 

I&#39;m just curious what has worked for people.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igym84d/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igx4h21/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Is the main point of a therapist to pay someone for the emotional labor of liste</title><updated>2022-07-20T14:20:12Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Is the main point of a therapist to pay someone for the emotional labor of listening to you rant about your problems, nod along, and then provide comforting but non-falsifiable advice? I’ve been skeptical of trying one because I have serious doubts they would help actually solve the problems I have, but lately the closest thing I have to friends have been getting fired of putting up with my needy self-pitying bullshit (frankly I can’t blame them).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/igx4h21/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>