<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Timeline - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-05T00:00:19Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/timeline" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in4d1jz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I have had this sitting for a week but it never seemed to fit in the small-scale</title><updated>2022-09-05T00:00:19Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I have had this sitting for a week but it never seemed to fit in the small-scale or friday fun or wednesday wellness.

So I guess the question is &#34;how evil can a product be?&#34;


https://twitter.com/RayRedacted/status/1562914396732801025?s=20&amp;amp;t=YTSBi61pjYTqsfkgBKOA3Q

Short version: A consumer can buy a 30 TB hard drive off of Alibaba or Walmart&#39;s website (which is a reseller using them as a storefront).

The capacity is fake. Someone wrote hacked firmware so that two flash drives have (each) 512MB of actual storage self-report as 15TB. When you go to use it, the hacked firmware pretends to write the files and creates the whole directory structure. The directory structure is the only permanent part. The file contents start getting overwritten once you put in too much data. Someone could buy this and take a while to realize that their data is dead.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in4d1jz/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in3azg3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Historians advise the president. The problem? The scholars were all white.](htt</title><updated>2022-09-04T19:18:05Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Historians advise the president. The problem? The scholars were all white.](https://www.npr.org/2022/09/04/1120561788/historians-advise-the-president-the-problem-the-scholars-were-all-white)


&amp;gt;When President Biden spoke on Sept. 1st, to tell the nation that democracy is in danger, his warnings echoed the words of many who have been paying attention. Especially those who study the past. Not a month earlier, the president met with a group of handpicked historians who told him that democracy was teetering, hanging on by a thread.

NPR is running this piece in their history section today. Out of five (!) scholars advising the President, all five are *White*. Not a single person of color. The article links to WaPo, which mentions that’s Biden’s speechwriter Vishy Reddy was at the table when the historians advised Biden a month ago. We can assume that this meeting influenced Biden’s anti white nationalism speech.

I find the NPR analysis superficial and misleading. We are meant to believe that these five white historians insufficiently advised the President on the problem of white supremacism. This appears incorrect, given the substance of Biden’s speech. In fact, out of the five historians, three are Jewish, one being the descendant of a Holocaust survivor. Jewish groups are at the forefront of warning about white nationalism and white identity. Jewish groups have historically been one of the most vocal and critical of all sorts of white identity movements.

If we are to care about the absence of black historians at the meeting, we should probably mention that “legacy white” Americans were surprisingly absent. Despite being more than 60% of America’s over-30 demographic (the lower range of anyone advising Biden), they made up only 40% of historians advising Biden. The plain white Americans, Christian white, gentile white, whatever you want to call them are thus not responsible for the under-representation of PoC historians. 

Instead, the 2% of the population who comprise America’s thriving Jewish community made up 60% of the advisors to Biden on the dangers of America, and influenced his anti white nationalism speech. This is a shocking over-representation on its face, but not too unusual in light of Biden’s cabinet and appointments, which are also disproportionately Jewish. If we are to care about over-representation, it seems we should start here. After all, the plain white community and the Jewish community do have different socioeconomic and historical aspects. It’s not like Jimmy the Italian from long island has access to the wealth of the Jewish community. 

As [the Times of Israel](https://www.timesofisrael.com/did-a-jewish-mafia-once-control-the-us-publishing-industry/amp/) reported recently, the Jewish community maintained a “mafia-like” influence on publishing since the 1940s, so the difference between the Jewish community and say the Italian community are real and substantive. This is to say, it’s true Jews are white, but they have historically comprised a unique and somewhat inclusive community with their own levers of influence. NPR castigating 100% of white people for the over-representation of a small subset of that community is unreasonable. And indeed, once Jewish over-representation is analyzed, we can move on to Irish Catholic over-representation, which is nowhere near as high as Jewish over-representation, but there to some degree.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in3azg3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in38d61/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m starting Minsky&#39;s *Society of Mind*, a classic AI</title><updated>2022-09-04T18:59:47Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m starting Minsky&#39;s *Society of Mind*, a classic AI text about building minds from smaller, mindless components. The current zeitgeist seems to be moving away from classic AI, but eventually we&#39;ll need better understanding of where precisely our machine-learning models fit in the broader scheme of knowledge. &#34;Shut up and scale&#34; doesn&#39;t seem entirely satisfactory. Maybe going over some slightly dust-covered ideas might spark some useful thinking. The book itself seems like a mix of aesthetic quirks and precision, and I seem to be in the mood for that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in38d61/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2ynot/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] This will be the last Motte Culture War thread on Reddit. [The Motte has moved o</title><updated>2022-09-04T17:53:14Z</updated><author><name>ZorbaTHut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">This will be the last Motte Culture War thread on Reddit. [The Motte has moved offsite](https://www.themotte.org/); future Culture War threads will be posted there.

If you&#39;d like to discuss this change on Reddit, [I&#39;ve made a Meta post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5t3jh/meta_the_motte_is_dead_long_live_the_motte/).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2ynot/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in2y0fb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Recently [posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/x0wtdt/open_a</title><updated>2022-09-04T17:48:58Z</updated><author><name>sciuru_</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Recently [posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/x0wtdt/open_access_to_research_articles_recent_progress/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) my summary of the article [“Transformative agreements: Do they pave the way to open access?”](https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/leap.1347) (2020) about struggles between publishers and pubic research institutions. I read the article to contextualize US govt [statement](https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/08/25/ostp-issues-guidance-to-make-federally-funded-research-freely-available-without-delay/) from Aug 25, announcing that immediate open access to all taxpayer-funded research articles should be implemented by 2025, thus eliminating current 12 months embargo.

I wanted to ask here first, as my interest is in market power dynamics and bargaining, not consumer perspective. I’d love to know what you think about how it works.

And separately, I’d like to know what is so awful about the post, that no one responded? Is it too long, boring, cluttered, grammar is poor? Want to know how to improve engagement.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in2y0fb/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2uofk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There was a post that was awful that got moderated for blasting every new movie </title><updated>2022-09-04T17:27:07Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There was a post that was awful that got moderated for blasting every new movie for being woke.  But being honest I only like consuming old movie/series.  Am I missing something?  Am I just aging and want to consume things from my prime.

I do notice in the past we had movies where male (usually white) battles world and sometimes personal demons.  Male wins.  I like those movies.  Last two days I’ve watched Jerry Maguire and Goodwill Hunting.  Women plays some emotional support role.  Some reason Man on Fire is coming to my head as a movie I like.  Black man has demons, proceeds to conquer them, saves white girl.

Point I’m getting to I believe is in the past all shows were basically man battles world.  Man triumphs while fighting his weaknesses.  I’m trying to come up with a theory for why all modern film sucks.  And I think it’s because I’m a misogynist.

Woke films suck because deep down we all know men have to lead.  Goodwill Hunting had Matt Damon (the genius) having the trust fund Stanford med school girl begging him to be in love.  Sort of like Steve Jobs and his Stanford mba wife who never worked.

This stuff is just real.  World I grew up in men had to lead.  And it’s still the world I know in the business world.  When I struggle in business I lose interest in dating.  Who would want me if I’m a failure?

Maybe I should embrace this non-patriarchal society though I think it’s against human nature and a reason why new media isn’t believable.  In my world if I don’t win then I don’t get the girl and I don’t deserve her.  In woke world world then I guess I get to be house husband.

Edit:  Also own a lot of HBO stock because I thought they had the best content</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2uofk/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in22r6p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] **European Probation/Early Release Scandals:**

After playing a game that made f</title><updated>2022-09-04T14:23:06Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">**European Probation/Early Release Scandals:**

After playing a game that made fun of him, I read that Josef Fritzl, [World&#39;s Least Popular Austrian (silver medalist)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fritzl_case) might be eligible for probation next year, after 15 years in prison for the whole multi-generational incest rape dungeon business.  
It made me curious: what&#39;s the media environment in european countries like when this happens? Does the press pay any attention to it? Do people ever talk seriously about maybe bus-full-of-nuns-murderers needing to spend more time in prison?  

In the UK it&#39;s usually only the Daily Mail that notices/comes out with headlines about bringing back hanging, while the US sometimes gets some hand-wringing in the serious-people papers if the stars and skin colours align (which is fairly rare due to the 7 million year sentences in such cases).  
Is it basically the same in Europe? The only big one I&#39;m aware of was Pim Fortuyn&#39;s unrepentant assassin being released after 12(!) years to apparently more media attention in the english-speaking press than the dutch.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in22r6p/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1n72i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anybody able to give general advice on hiring a personal attorney for matters re</title><updated>2022-09-04T12:14:17Z</updated><author><name>ItsAPomeloParty</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anybody able to give general advice on hiring a personal attorney for matters related to one&#39;s involvement in an LLC?

Like I need one but have no idea where to start looking for a good one. Is there something like Amazon reviews for lawyers?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1n72i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1mcoe/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What should we make of anti-white propaganda like [this](https://www.youtube.com</title><updated>2022-09-04T12:05:33Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What should we make of anti-white propaganda like [this](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvNNtBmA3SQ)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1mcoe/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1j9vg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] If the US were competent at nation building (meaning we could overthrow dictator</title><updated>2022-09-04T11:31:44Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">If the US were competent at nation building (meaning we could overthrow dictators and actually establish lasting liberal democracies), would we have a moral obligation to do it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x5fpqj/smallscale_question_sunday_for_september_04_2022/in1j9vg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in098y6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [Here&#39;s an awesome song I discovered recently. LoTR fans in particular are likel</title><updated>2022-09-04T02:30:07Z</updated><author><name>Blacknsilver1</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[Here&#39;s an awesome song I discovered recently. LoTR fans in particular are likely to enjoy this one.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uxfoa23skHg)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in098y6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in0149g/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I finally noticed that MATE, a continuation of GNOME 2, exists. I don&#39;t know why</title><updated>2022-09-04T01:24:11Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I finally noticed that MATE, a continuation of GNOME 2, exists. I don&#39;t know why, but GNOME 2 always made me feel like my computer was a place where intelligent things should happen.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/in0149g/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their</title><updated>2022-09-03T23:22:23Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their service](https://blog.cloudflare.com/kiwifarms-blocked/)

The Cloudflare argument (which may be an excuse to cover for political pressure behind the scenes) is that because some user made a threat on Kiwifarms, the website ought to be refused service. This is despite Kiwifarms having strict rules regarding threats and always issuing bans soon after violating posts are published. I’m reminded of when the Florida school shooter literally wrote on YouTube that he planned to carry out his attack, in no uncertain terms, weeks before his attack. Obviously, no one would argue that YouTube ought to be denied DDoS protection (effectively deplatformed) for this. importantly, this judgment by Cloudflare allows malicious actors to eradicate any unpopular discussion website they desire by writing threats using a VPN. The rule strikes me as an insane misjudgment, but then, I don’t think this is as simple as Cloudflare making a misjudgment. I think there may be political pressures behind the scenes, which would be even scarier than Cloudflare making a misjudgment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imywh47/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I was reading about someone who was diagnosed with small intestine cancer , and </title><updated>2022-09-03T20:18:54Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I was reading about someone who was diagnosed with small intestine cancer , and one of his symptoms was he would get a lot of pain a few hours after eating, presumably due to have an obstruction, so in order to mitigate this he ate once every 24 hours . He also kept his daily calorie intake up by drinking   shakes, yet he still lost 3/lbs a week even though his calorie intake was presumably the same.  Some for people with esophagus cancer who go to a liquid diet; they lose so much weight despite consuming unlimited liquid calories. I wonder if liquid diets violate the age-old calorie-in-calorie out maxim.  Of course, some of this weight loss is due   to the cancer itself, but I wonder how much the liquid diet plays a role in this too.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imywh47/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imym8n3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] One thing about Biden&#39;s speech that surprised me was his desperation to get back</title><updated>2022-09-03T19:07:28Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">One thing about Biden&#39;s speech that surprised me was his desperation to get back to &#34;moderate Republicans&#34;. If these MAGA people are so extreme as he claims, wouldn&#39;t he want to encourage their antics so as to continually win general elections?

In places like Philippines or Hungary, the ruling party relishes putting their opposition to the margins, whereas Biden bizarrely wants to *help* the establishment of his opponent.

This is something that seems strangely and uniquely American. I can&#39;t think of any other country where the elite of one party tries desperately to help out the other party&#39;s establishment. In most other democracies, the ruling party just tries to consolidate its gains. 

And lest I be accused of only promoting right-wing populists (e.g. Orban or Duterte), you could look at Scandinavia from the 1950s-1970s for a left-wing equivalent. Those government had no compunction about stacking the odds as much as possible in their own favour.

The generous reading is that Biden&#39;s speech wasn&#39;t about winning but about &#34;saving democracy&#34; even if it means helping the GOP elite, because Biden is such a selfless patriot.

A less generous reading would be that Biden is part of the same &#34;uniparty&#34; as Mitch McConnell and other GOP leaders who are terrified of being swallowed up alive by the forces that Trump ultimately represents however inperfectly. In this reading, Biden trying to bring down a rival faction to the GOP establishment isn&#39;t a selfless act of patriotism as much as naked self-interest.

Whichever reading you prefer, it still remains notable that this type of behaviour is uncommon in other countries. Certainly, the US system seems to produce a unified political class much more unified than other countries.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imym8n3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imw006q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Men torture themselves doing pullups, because no one is nice enough to give them</title><updated>2022-09-03T04:19:42Z</updated><author><name>pmmecutepones</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Men torture themselves doing pullups, because no one is nice enough to give them the upsies they truly want.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imw006q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m se</title><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m searching for mellow upbeat music and anything with lyrics is about sex and crushes. It doesn’t *have* to be this way; I used to listen to post-rock and it was not very sexed. Hymns are rarely sexy. But I like the indie genre, I just get tired of music about girls.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10</title><updated>2022-09-03T00:33:43Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So I ordered a [NuXT](https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_10MHz_832K_XTIDE_MultiIO_SVGA/p6083514_19777986.aspx).  It hasn&#39;t shipped yet.  But I like to be able to code on every piece of hardware I own.  So I began noodling around, trying to set up a cross coding environment today.

I started with Visual Studio Code since it&#39;s crazy flexible.  Then I set up a bunch of task to compile my ASM files using NASM, using the CPU 8086 directive and outputting as OBJ files which need to be linked.  I&#39;m under the impression 16-bit code is the default with this arrangement.  I found a free linker called ALINK which then links the OBJ files into an EXE.  Then I set up, in kind of a janky way, for the Run command to launch DOSBOX and execute it&#39;s debug command on my exe.

I still want to find a way to export my breakpoints from Visual Studio Code and import them into DOSBOX.  I see that this debug version of DOSBOX I have can import breakpoints, and NASM spits out dbg files which I **think** I can parse for the segment:offset&#39;s I&#39;ll need to breakpoint at labels in DOSBOX.  I just am not sure off the top of my head how to export the breakpoint lines from Visual Studio Code.  Oh well, some day.

Anyways, it was a fun day.  Threw together a pretty simple number guessing game program.  It&#39;s a good way to get a grip on the basics.  Reading the keyboard, processing input, converting an ascii number to binary, generating a random number, some basic math, printing to the screen.  Then cause why not, I started fucking around with linking multiple ASM files, with GLOBAL and EXTERN&#39;d functions.  Did some far calls across memory segments.  Wasn&#39;t as bad as I thought it would be.

Probably start fucking around with EGA graphics and ADLIB sound next.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imv9rg4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated im</title><updated>2022-09-02T22:51:29Z</updated><author><name>prrk3</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Are there any writings about the relationship between dreams and AI generated imagery? There are striking resemblances between commonly reported phenomena reported by lucid dreamers and people with above average dream recall and generated images.

The most interesting phenomenon to me is that counting and reading in dreams is impossible. Lucid dreamers use this by counting their fingers or looking at clock as their “reality check” to tell if they are dreaming or not. It seems odd to me that humans can just forget the number of fingers they have. AI generated images have a similar problem with not caring much about discrete units.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imuwrtw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an </title><updated>2022-09-02T21:17:17Z</updated><author><name>stolen_brawnze</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">A game designer has sparked controversy after submitting an image created by an AI text-to-image generator to a state art competition and [taking home first prize.](https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/1/23332684/ai-generated-artwork-wins-state-fair-competition-colorado)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imujvwi/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu8nvt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Income Based Repayment is totally insane.

People had pointed out that it was a </title><updated>2022-09-02T20:00:04Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Income Based Repayment is totally insane.

People had pointed out that it was a reasonable part of the loan forgiveness. I had agreed. Now I think it is the worst, building a time bomb on purpose and refusing to disarm it.

Maybe I am wrong. God I hope so. I laid out a lot of math below. *Part of the reason I wrote this was that someone could tell me where I messed up.* 

**Current regime**

The [current IBR rules](https://www.financialrounds.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-income-based-repayment-ibr/) are that you pay at most 10% of your discretionary income (which I abbreviate DI here). DI is your income past 150% of the [Federal Poverty Rate (FPR)](https://www.healthcare.gov/glossary/federal-poverty-level-fpl/).

If I am a single guy, 150% of FPR is $20,385. If I earn $100K, my DI is about 80K, meaning I never have to pay more than 8K a year. If this is not enough to cover interest, that interest goes away. Even if it were getting capitalized into the balance, [any remaining balance is forgiven after 20 years](https://www.financialrounds.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-income-based-repayment-ibr/) so who cares.

([It used to be 25 years under &#34;old IBR&#34; but now we are in &#34;new IBR&#34;](https://fcaa.org/student-loan-repayment-plans/income-based-repayment/) and I guess we are about to get &#34;new new IBR&#34;.

$8000 is a lot of post-tax spending, but what incentives does it make?

(I am going to make up a 5% interest rate for loans; this should be checked and numbers below reviewed on it changing).

If I take out **$93,000 in loans**, standard amortization means I will spend $8000 a year over 20 years to pay it down to zero. That **is the break-even point**. Each aditional dollar I borrow means $1.08 that disappears at the end.

$93,000 is a lot of debt. [Only 4% get over 56K](https://www.aplu.org/our-work/5-archived-projects/college-costs-tuition-and-financial-aid/publicuvalues/student-debt.html) and only 0.5% hit 100K. Average medical debt is $200,000 but my numbers were based on a salary of $100,000 which doctors will eclipse.

What if I run a family of 4? At $100,000 my DI is $58,375. That drops all the above loan numbers by about 30%. **$68,000 is still a lot of loans** to take out.

But let us change the salary. Average salary for a college graduate is around $55,000. For the single guy, that is a DI of $35,000, meaning annual payments of $3500. This is a DI of 44% of the original value, meaning **the break-even is now $40,700**. About 20% of graduates hit this level, eyeballing the earlier aplu.org link. This is starting to become a serious moral hazard.

For a family of 4 the DI at $55,000 is only $13375. That **requires only $15,600 in debt**. I am not so much worried about financially supporting a family of 4 making $55,000 as I am in giving them a direct incentive to go as expensive as possible once loans hit $15,600.



**Proposed Regime**

The [new program](https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2022/08/26/the-new-income-driven-repayment-system-could-cause-some-big-problems/) has these relevant changes:

* Increase the amount of income not subject to IDR from 150 percent of the federal poverty line to 225 percent of the federal poverty line.

* Eliminate any accrual of interest on IDR-enrolled loans.

* For undergraduate debt, reduce the IDR rate from 10 percent of income beyond the threshold in (1) to 5 percent of income beyond the threshold in (1).

Items 1 and 3 directly change my math. I will get back to item 2 later.

So now our fresh-college-graduate-single-guy-making-$100,000 has a DI of (100000 - 13590 * 2.2) or $70,000 and annual payments of $3500. This means **the break-even point is now $40,700.** If he has (or will soon have) a family of 4 his DI is now just $38,950 and will pay no more than $1,950 per year. **Just $22,600 in loans is the break-even**, meaning there is no difference to him between borrowing $22,600 and $93,000. Might as well go into luxury student housing, move the family in.

That average college grad making $55,000 with a family of 4? Your DI is *less than zero*. In fact, **any income up to $61,050 means you do not have to pay a single cent towards your loans**, as the balance stays flat and the 20-year timer ticks away.

Item 2 is missing from my analysis. If I read it right, as long as your income is below the IBR threshold, no money gets added, but in a lot of my above analysis that did not matter because uncapitalized interest vanished.

I guess it matters if you think you will have many years of salad days and then suddenly earn a lot of money. If you could get an extra dollar in financial aid and put it in a crummy retail bank savings account, that would still be a good idea. Either 20 years hits and you get to keep all the money, or your income goes up and you withdraw the money from the savings account to pay it back.

I want to make up a web calculator that shows the break-even point for given circumstances, but first I need to figure out how many mistakes I made above.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu8nvt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu7i4x/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] After Roe v. Wade was overturned, a common argument was to describe pro-life Rep</title><updated>2022-09-02T19:52:16Z</updated><author><name>ymeskhout</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">After Roe v. Wade was overturned, a common argument was to describe pro-life Republicans as &#34;the dog that caught the car&#34;. There&#39;s some indication that this is true, as Republican political candidates are [slowly walking away from strict abortion bans](https://reason.com/2022/08/30/republicans-supported-abortion-bans-for-decades-now-theyve-gone-silent/).

I was obviously aware of the conservative stance on this topic but truthfully I never took it seriously. Because *Roe* had been a question answered on constitutional grounds, it meant no one could do anything about it short of a constitutional amendment that had no chance of passing. Which meant that advocates could jawbone all they want about wanting to ban abortions without ever having to be made to call their bluff. Blake Masters, Senate candidate in Arizona, used to support a national ban on abortion. But recently, he accused his opponent of mischaracterizing his position, and claims that he&#39;s only opposed to &#34;very late-term and partial-birth abortion&#34;. His campaign website was modified to reflect this new position. Bailey, meet Motte.

I noticed a similar reaction when stories like the 10-year-old rape victim in Ohio popped up. If you said you wanted to ban all abortions no questions asked, you necessarily had to support legally forcing that 10-year-old girl to carry to term. That also necessarily means prosecuting anyone who hinders that prohibition (doctors, pharmacists, anyone who facilitates inter-state travel, etc.) [through the typical avenues](https://www.currentaffairs.org/2017/10/people-literally-do-not-understand-what-laws-are-or-how-they-work), which means people with guns and badges threatening to put people in cages.

There&#39;s an easy way to square this circle. If you genuinely believe that abortion is as immoral as murder (without exception) and that the law should reflect that, then you have to support forcing 10-year-old rape victims into carrying their pregnancy to term. This is plainly justified even by conceding that forcing a child to carry her rapist&#39;s baby is atrocious, because the rejoinder would be terminating that fetus&#39; life is an even bigger atrocity. I disagree strongly with those premises (a position I suspect is widely shared), but I at least genuinely respect their consistency. Now that *Roe* is gone, we get to see how many people are willing to grab the dilemma bull by the horns.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu7i4x/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For </title><updated>2022-09-02T17:57:26Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Probably better for WW or SQS, but to avoid ending up like u/orthoxerox...

For all our optimization/nootropics bros, what&#39;s the best way to adjust my early-bird sleep schedule to go out partying on one night or two and then go right back to my standard sleep schedule?

I&#39;m an early bird, I basically go to sleep by 10:30 at the latest and get up between 4:30 and 5:00 every day. Getting up early is important to me, I like it, I function well that way from years of farm work and crew practice growing up. But as I&#39;m getting into middle age, I find it is getting hard for me to deal with days when I&#39;m at a wedding or a party or a gala or whatever and I want to stay up later and find my body failing me. I&#39;m curious if there&#39;s any scientifically supported evidence for how to handle it beyond pounding a 5 hour energy a couple times in a night.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imtqbwo/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtooq6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;m not sure I agree with the criticisms of Biden&#39;s speech. The speech essential</title><updated>2022-09-02T17:46:36Z</updated><author><name>Texas_Rockets</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not sure I agree with the criticisms of Biden&#39;s speech. The speech essentially functioned to demonize maga republicans. I think his ultimate intent here was to say that a. not all republicans are bad. it&#39;s the maga republicans. and b. that they increasingly pose a serious threat to democracy. i think this also served to actually put a name to that group, because they were previously just regarded as the alt right and there wasn&#39;t much distinction made between republicans and &#39;maga republicans&#39; 

When I read about his speech it seemed to me that he was careful to say that he is not condemning all republicans; it is not that you are a democrat or are evil. 

The narrative surrounding this speech has been that it just fanned existing divisions. but i don&#39;t think that&#39;s the case at all. i think he was trying to alienate those on the far right and create a broader coalition and appeal to more moderate republicans. specifically, i don&#39;t think the intent was to broaden divisions, i think the intent was to frame existing divisions in a more precise light, by saying that it is not left v right it is sane people v maga republicans, which i support. 

and for the record i do agree that maga republicans pose an existential threat to this country. fascism, if you look into it, is actually an incredibly complex political ideology that doesn&#39;t really fit within the current framework of political ideology. so i don&#39;t really use that term. but trump&#39;s supporters are increasingly defined exclusively by the fact that they are loyal to one man and one man only. they increasingly don&#39;t have any platform or foundation outside of unwavering support for trump. just consider how much trump hammered Clinton for a comparatively mild (but still problematic) transgression of keeping classified information safe, and how his supporters were right there with him on that issue. the guy was so dug in on that issue that he actually increased the penalty for that sort of behavior. and he just did not only that exact thing but took it a step further. yet these people are still with him. he also has literally challenged the fundamental legitimacy of any democratic institution that challenged him or did anything but failed to support him. I mean this guy literally said an election was corrupted solely because he lost. his supporters have also demonstrated a willingness to back Trump&#39;s interest with violence. based on their stances, what underlying principles can possibly be said to undergird trump or his supporters&#39; stances? at a certain point we have to b able to recognize something for what it is. and I&#39;ve also heard that republicans are starting to distance themselves from trump after the revelations of the past month, so the timing of this could end up being fairly astute on biden&#39;s part.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtooq6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtiik9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] This isn’t necessarily culture war but I wanted to share what I consider to be s</title><updated>2022-09-02T17:06:27Z</updated><author><name>wear146</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">This isn’t necessarily culture war but I wanted to share what I consider to be some unambiguously good news which defied all of my expectations, namely that California will be saving the Diablo Canyon Nuclear power plant (https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2022-09-01/lawmakers-approve-1-4-billion-loan-for-pg-e-to-keep-diablo-canyon-nuclear-plant-open?_amp=true ). This represents substantial progress as the plant is Californias biggest carbon neutral electric source and I wonder if it represents a turning point for environmentalists to start accepting nuclear energy. I really wish I knew why the political calculation has changed so dramatically! However climate change really starts to appear much more tractable  if this technology is adopted, especially if these attitudes extend to the sorts of small modular reactors which are starting to get regulatory approval (https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-regulator-to-issue-final-certification-for-NuSc )</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtiik9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</title><updated>2022-09-02T15:58:31Z</updated><author><name>CD-ROM_INSTRUCTOR</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What do we think of *Rings of Power*?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imt7ywh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wi</title><updated>2022-09-02T14:14:20Z</updated><author><name>07mk</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Recently, I learned of something called [Terryology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terrence_Howard#Terryology), a form of &#34;math&#34; developed by Terrence Howard, the actor who played James Rhodes in the first *Iron Man* film before he was replaced by Don Cheadle in later films. It seems that he had an issue with the proposition that &#34;1 x 1 = 1&#34; and thus sought to disprove it; here&#39;s a quotation from an argument he claimed he had with a professor:

&amp;gt; How can it equal one? If one times one equals one that means that two is of no value because one times itself has no effect. One times one equals two because the square root of four is two, so what&#39;s the square root of two? Should be one, but we&#39;re told it&#39;s two, and that cannot be.

Apparently he had such a problem with the regular math being taught there that he dropped out of college. I don&#39;t know how much work into Terryology he&#39;s done, but he&#39;s talked about spending time constructing (physical plastic) models to prove his new &#34;math&#34; and once [Tweeted a &#34;proof&#34; of why one times one cannot equal one](https://twitter.com/terrencehoward/status/925754491881877507) in an apparent bid to appease his critics. It&#39;s only 4 pages long, but I&#39;ll admit I could only put in the effort to skim it because of how poor the quality of writing was. But to me it seems that he just lacks a fundamental ability to grasp what addition and multiplication are and ends up confusing the 2 with each other. I was reminded of a podcast I listened to many years ago wherein a physicist being interviewed mentioned how his office gets mail all the time from people claiming to have found some huge breakthrough that would revolutionize the field, and when he happened to read one of them, it showed that the writer had no understanding of momentum and velocity and kept confusing the 2.

Also, [apparently Terrence has discovered some new form of physics](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-44pljnxztg) involving hydrogen bonds that will enable a new way of flying. I don&#39;t know if this is directly related to Terryology or if it&#39;s a completely independent thing he came up with.

I don&#39;t know much about Terrence outside him being an actor, but clearly he&#39;s an extremely successful one. Say what you will about him losing out on the MCU gravy train, but being a major character in even 1 major Hollywood production like *Iron Man* is a level of success that the vast majority of actors can ever dream about. It&#39;s just fascinating to me that someone with this poor an understanding of math, to the extent that addition and multiplication are beyond his grasp, has been able to be not just this functional, but this successful in modern society. Then again, acting isn&#39;t a particularly math-heavy profession, and it&#39;s possible that he hires professionals to handle his finances. It&#39;s just, if he thinks what those professionals are doing is all false made-up bullshit, how does he trust them at all to do what&#39;s right for him?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imss3of/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/</title><updated>2022-09-02T13:47:43Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[Gallery of cereal boxes with mascots generated by DALLE-2](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/cereal_boxes.html). One of my online acquaintances is good at wrangling AI art generators to get surreal stuff. Here&#39;s the rest of [his DALLE-2 gallery](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e/index.html) in addition to [Midjourney](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/midjourney/index.html) and [DALLE-Mini](http://autofish.net/clysm/art/ai/dall-e_mini/index.html) generated stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imsobbh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imse9ru/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A small observation based on the activities of the LOTRonPrime subreddit, that I</title><updated>2022-09-02T12:30:09Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A small observation based on the activities of the LOTRonPrime subreddit, that I followed from the beginning. regarding mood-switching after certain events.

This strange phenomena occured again, after seeing it on subreddit dedicated to Star Wars and Game of Thrones;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\- New product reveal itself, everyone agrees that looks terrible, that it is against the spirit of the original product, it is too woke etc.

\- After some days all big media begin to blast how there have been racist menaces, death threats, accusation or whatever against the show, especially black actors or women.

\- The moderation on the subreddit begin to use power to limit comments and users, blasting how bigotry is not allowed.

\- The overral mood on the subreddit change from negativity to neutrality or positivity. There are still criticism around, but is still limited. 

\- Dissenters from these subreddit go to new subreddit dedicated to criticism, creating the &#34;Witch Covens&#34; we know so well, that became the ideological target of the users of the main subreddits (&#34;See, the nazi exiled themselves! They were nazi all the time, not fans!&#34;)

\- The product ships, it is (usually) terrible, there are review bombing around and new attack from media against the criticizers. 

\- In the wake of the new product, the users of the subreddit are very very supportive of it, attacking everyone as an incel, a nazi, a traitor or a combination or both (it is always about politics or sex!), go check the LOTRonprime sub if you do not believe it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Afteer seeing this happen many times, I am beginning to think that adoption of woke policies and terminologies by entertainment corporations are less of an ideological capture and more of a cynical plot to defend their products from every kind of criticism.

I do not know how it is possible that the mood switch from negativity to positivity after the first media tornado (the purges are effective? The users follow the stream? They attract people that are here only to &#34;own the nazi?&#34; No idea)

But I know that they are very effective, basically controlling the discourse on a social influencial like reddit without any difficulties. Besides, it is not a surprise that there are discourses and discussion around on how the public vote on sites like Rottentomatoes and similars should be forbidden because it is an hotbed of political extremism. Because this position has been told by the same users on the same subreddits.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

What do you think?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imse9ru/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/s</title><updated>2022-09-02T12:15:55Z</updated><author><name>Indi008</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ooh fun yay :) 

I wrote some books...
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57409/spliced

and some short stories:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/58017/the-dumping-ground

AND some poetry:
https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/57952/nothing-here-but-hot-air

Free to read, and somewhat unrelated to this sub, but hey it fits the fun theme, and I&#39;m somewhat trying to write rational fantasy if there is such a thing. Not sure I quite achieved that.

Anyone else here a &#34;writer&#34; who studied science or engineering with the intent of writing technically accurate fiction only to find it&#39;s much harder than you think? I never know quite enough, and when I do, no one thinks it&#39;s a real thing. I once wrote a story about a mechanic and an actual issue I faced with my car and people thought it wasn&#39;t realistic, but my complete fantasy stories are apparently completely believable.

Edit: got a joke for y&#39;all...

Why did the cat fall off the roof?



.
.
.
.



Because it lost it&#39;s mu</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imscl2q/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Satur</title><updated>2022-09-02T08:45:10Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I should start writing down my Friday Fun ideas. They always come to me on Saturday nights, when the next SQS sticky is just around the corner, so I never post them, saving them for the next FF sticky. Now it&#39;s Friday morning, and my head is devoid of ideas beyond going shopping for a pull-up bar and discount male fashion.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imru9vu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqxcae/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Biden gave [a speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wygovCnX8Uw) tonight.  The</title><updated>2022-09-02T02:43:31Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Biden gave [a speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wygovCnX8Uw) tonight.  There was some [interesting imagery](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Fbnb-x5XwAA1LB2?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=medium) from it, although I&#39;m not really a fan of these sorts of photos.  Also somewhat hilariously CNN tried [edit the hue of the stream](https://twitter.com/MiaCathell/status/1565533698795208704) in the middle of the speech, apparently to make it look less sinister.

My thoughts on the speech: I like the *surface version* of some parts of what biden is saying here.  Or maybe a better way to say that is: I like the character he is pretending to play.

Where this goes off the rails for me is: he&#39;s basically saying that almost half of the country is a threat to not just his power, but to democracy *itself*.  He goes on and on about how incredible our nation is (something I agree with), how important our ideals of democracy and free speech are (something I also agree with), but then goes on to say that &#34;MAGA&#34; is a threat to all of this.  Of course this is probably a performance for his followers, and of course this likely isn&#39;t going to move anybody in the direction of supporting him.  Maybe this will rile up his base?

My frustration with everything is: where does this supposedly lead?  If Biden loses power in November, and is removed from office either on or before january 2025, will he &#34;go peacefully&#34;?  Will there be riots?  Will more cities burn?  What happens when he loses an election in 2024?  I certainly don&#39;t think any of his followers will simply accept it and congratulate Trump or Desantis or anybody else.

My other frustration is: what biden is pretending to say here is actually really important.  We actually, truly, need somebody to unite the nation.  Here is what I wish he would do, and think this would make him go down as one of the best presidents in our nations history:

* Blanket pardon for anybody involved in January 6th

* Blanket pardon for anybody involved in summer 2020 rioting

* Blanket pardon for Donald Trump, his family, and anybody related to his campaign WRT anything tax or document related, or anything else that the democratic machine has been running for the last 5 years.

* Support a &#34;MAGA republican&#34; led committee to spend as much time as they want chasing down every conspiracy theory related to election fraud that they want, and encourage the courts to cooperate.  Televise it.

If Biden did this, it would take most of the wind out of the sails of these MAGA republicans, and it would solidify his win in 2024.  The thing fueling those MAGA republicans *is* them feeling like they have absolutely no voice in government right now, and seeing a president that they feel is invalid get in front of a scary red brick background and give an angry speech about how they aren&#39;t really valid as Americans certainly doesn&#39;t make them feel any better.

Just saying: &#34;okay, I&#39;ll listen to you.&#34; would go a long, long, long way to reestablishing some trust *and* I think it would give him what he wants.

Unfortunately I doubt this will happen.  That scares me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqxcae/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqd24j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Possibly the Last? Ban Report**

As ZorbaTHut [has posted](https://www.reddit.</title><updated>2022-09-02T00:10:30Z</updated><author><name>Amadanb</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Possibly the Last? Ban Report**

As ZorbaTHut [has posted](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilj878k/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3), D-Day approaches. The move is a matter of when, not if. I don&#39;t think the exact date for pulling the switch has been set, but it&#39;s possible this will be the last ban report here. (Whether I&#39;ll continue doing these on the new site... eh. We&#39;ll see. Depends on how the mod tools work, how much modding there is to do, how active I am after the changeover, etc.)

Incidentally, there have been 3 AEO actions since the last report. One was someone talking about the dreaded triple parentheses and the admins failing to comprehend the use-mention distinction. One was someone using the newly-verboten g-word. And one was someone making a pretty bad comment about trans women which had already been modded before the admins came by and nuked it.

**The Bans**

/u/DreadnoughtOverdrive - [1 day](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtpaql/comment/ilsnek6/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/dragonslion - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilskynx/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/bgaesop - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilkpsob/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/naraburns

/u/SlightlyLessHairyApe - [3 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/comment/il95nmf/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3link) - /u/ZorbaTHut

/u/darwin2500 - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/comment/iezy5fl/) - /u/naraburns

/u/Kerguidou - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ik2flgc/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/dblackdrake - [5 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijrgzyr/) - /u/Amadanb

/u/jermleeds - [14 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijmwq2y/) - /u/naraburns

/u/JeanStealers - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/comment/ijh5u1t/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/Wangushenpo - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/comment/ij27d4d/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/_Roark - [permaban](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vauj5h/comment/iiwmn1u/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) - /u/Amadanb

/u/RichardRogers - [7 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/comment/iikma5q/) - /u/Amadanb

/u/erkelep - [30 days](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/comment/ihupq7l/) - /u/naraburns</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqd24j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an </title><updated>2022-09-01T21:19:24Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an economist from Harvard, that studies race, policing, and education.

He shares a lot of statistics that contradict popular narratives about the issues, but probably won’t surprise many frequenters of this sub.

For example,

He finds that when that POC (people of color, I think is the term he uses) are not killed by police more.

That black kids are doing worse in school and advocates closing bad schools. 

The pay gap isn’t really 33% or whatever, but it is closer to 9%, and there are concrete things that he can point to that cause the pay gap that aren’t discrimination (in one example it is a difference in overtime worked due to when shifts were scheduled). 

Basically, he is using data to analyze a lot of culture war adjacent topics and looking for actual reasons for discrepancies in outcomes rather than just pointing to discrimination because he really wants to improve the lives of people.

Sorry for the short initial post, but I like to watch.  I’m a free riding, lurker because posting takes so much energy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular</title><updated>2022-09-01T19:38:41Z</updated><author><name>lookingforthrowaway1</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Has anyone on here had any success in convincing a doctor to pursue a particular treatment course? 

A family member is currently experiencing an uncommon health issue on which there is limited research in the literature. I’ve found a few papers indicating that a certain treatment, although aggressive and not usually considered necessary, is 100% effective in preventing a fatal outcome. These are all peer-reviewed papers in respected academic journals written by well-credentialed researchers at reputable university medical schools. 

How can I bring this research up to my family member’s doctor without offending their ego or something? Can I bring a printout with these papers as a reference and summarizing their key points?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imp8wfh/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imp4pty/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Metaphors are useful illustrations for understanding. They are harmful for argum</title><updated>2022-09-01T19:11:30Z</updated><author><name>EngageInFisticuffs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Metaphors are useful illustrations for understanding. They are harmful for arguments.

I recently read a post that was about one subject, mentioned something else as a point of comparison, and resulted in a conversation that was dominated by the metaphorical comparison rather than the subject level issue.

The entire point of metaphors is comparison of two very different things that have certain similarities. In the case of contention, what those similarities are is also likely to come under contention. Many of the metaphors on here turn into argument over the technicalities of the metaphor rather than the object-level issue. 

That has a lot to do with the type of audience you get here, but it still illustrates that metaphors themselves can conceal as much as they reveal. Or even just emphasize and deemphasize certain aspects of the subject. While this is great for rhetoric, it does no favors for clarity of argument.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imp4pty/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imo2yki/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] /u/Ilforte any thoughts on Ravil Maganov‘s death? Seems... dubious... to me, but</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:09:54Z</updated><author><name>Lurking_Chronicler_2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">/u/Ilforte any thoughts on Ravil Maganov‘s death? Seems... dubious... to me, but I’ll admit I know little about Russian internal politics, and I was wondering if you might be more informed on the matter.

(Sorry if this isn’t the right place, but I don’t see any small-scale threads up at the moment).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imo2yki/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:08:17Z</updated><author><name>crowstep</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing.

My live-in girlfriend of one year recently told me that while she loves me, she isn&#39;t &#39;in love&#39; with me. Apparently these things are quite different for her.

Essentially, while she has loved all of her previous boyfriends, there was only one that she was &#39;in love&#39; with, who was from several years ago and not the one before me.

She told me it might take time for her to feel &#39;in love&#39;, but that if she doesn&#39;t feel it, she&#39;ll break up with me. Her parents had a nasty divorce so she&#39;s paranoid about settling down with someone who isn&#39;t her &#39;soulmate&#39;. (Not her exact words, but that was the gist of it).

Overall I feel pretty hurt by this. Saying we loved eachother seemed like a big deal to me, but apparently for her it didn&#39;t really count to the same degree. Now it feels like there&#39;s a timer on our relationship and if I don&#39;t meet some ineffable standard in her head by a certain point, it&#39;s over. I was also pretty stung by the idea that I (and apparently, all her other exes) don&#39;t measure up to the one that got away.

We spoke about it at the time of course, but the more I think about this, the more it bothers me. I&#39;m unsure whether to bring it up or just entrust my fate to the fickleness of female affection and hope that I eventually provoke more feelings in her than I am now. I can hardly guilt her into changing get feelings, so I&#39;m reluctant to bring it up at all. And if I&#39;m honest, I worry that even letting her know it bothered me would make her less attracted to me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the </title><updated>2022-09-01T06:00:20Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the difference between a woman/man born the wrong gender and an actual person born of that gender would you support it?

I think it would change my mind. I personally don&#39;t have a problem with the idea of people being transgender. My biggest problem with it is I think we don&#39;t have the technology to actually do what is being promised and the surgery/transitioning is cruel to vulnerable people. All you have to do is go on /b or /pol to see the results to see that this is not a settled scientific process. I know it sounds gross, but seeing the results of these surgeries just makes me sick to my stomach. And then you have the child side where kids who aren&#39;t even fully developed emotionally/physically getting life changing surgery that can&#39;t be reversed. This is what bothers me the most.

I truly think we will look back on this time the same as we do with lobotomies. It feels like we are doing experimental surgery on vulnerable people who would be better off staying their assigned gender. That&#39;s my argument against this current (what I consider) madness.

I feel that most people agree with me here. However, if transitioning was actually possible, would you change your mind? To me, it makes the debate over. If you can safely and effectively transition people, what is the downside?

Edit: On the 4chan part, I was being glib there. The point I was trying to make is that we only see bad results. With how aggressive the trans lobby is, if they were actually the same in how they looked, people would be saying look it&#39;s indistinguishable. That fact that we don&#39;t see this shows they know it looks unnatural and would be off-putting to most people if they actually saw the results. I’ve never seen a trans person pass irl. If they can’t make a person pass, there’s no way they can make a passing sex organ. The only people I&#39;ve seen pass (and only online) are people who didn&#39;t go through puberty as the opposite sex. But that would basically mean we&#39;d have to transition children, which I am pretty skeptical of.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart con</title><updated>2022-08-31T22:57:55Z</updated><author><name>ebrso</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">My younger brother died suddenly in his sleep earlier today.  He had a heart condition, but this was totally unexpected.  He was in his early 30s.  I had spoken to him on Sunday.  I only found out a few hours ago.  My parents are devastated.  I&#39;m not sure why I&#39;m posting this.  How do people go on after this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/iml50cu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a m</title><updated>2022-08-31T21:21:25Z</updated><author><name>Vorpa-Glavo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a metaphysical naturalist understanding of modern biology, the answer has to be no. &#34;For&#34; implies a purpose, and purpose belongs to agents.

An airplane&#39;s wings are for flying - the intentions of engineers ensure that. But birds had no creator, no agent involved in their existence. We might be able to metaphorically talk about a bird being &#34;designed&#34; or &#34;built&#34; for flight, but it is only that: a metaphor.

If we want to limit our description to what can be described based on an physico-empirical view of reality, then a bird&#39;s wing&#39;s **make flight possible** or **allow them to fly**, but we can&#39;t speak about a bird&#39;s wings being &#34;for&#34; anything at all.

So too with the word &#34;need.&#34;

Does a seed &#34;need&#34; water and sunlight and nutrient rich soil? A metaphysical naturalist would say no. &#34;Need&#34; implies that there&#39;s some sort of goal, or right way for a seed to be, but the universe doesn&#39;t care if a seed dies or grows into a giant tree over many eons.

Humans trying to grow seeds might &#34;need&#34; water, and fertilizer and a location with the right amount of sun in order to fulfill that goal, but regarding the seed itself we can only make predictions about the outcomes of different conditions on the seed.

If the seed experiences Scenario A (X units of water delivered at intervals Y, Z units of soil of composition W, V hours of average daily sun exposure, etc.) then it will grow into a big tree, but if the seed experiences Scenario B (no water, no sun, no soil) it will stay a seed and die, with a thousand possible predictions branching off from these two.

So what do we make of &#34;sex&#34; from this standpoint?

I think the radical thing that this line of thinking implies is to stop thinking about &#34;man&#34; and &#34;woman&#34; as some sort of natural pairing.

Just as there are seeds, and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on the seed, so too there are animals and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on those animals.

If the gamete of animal A finds its way to the gamete of animal B, we might get a zygote, or we might get nothing at all depending on the particular animals involved and the particular gametes.

Things start to come down to categoricity and disciplined pattern formation.

Is a penis &#34;for&#34; a vagina? Is an ovum &#34;for&#34; a sperm? Do men and women have some sort of complimentary relationship?

It is almost certain that humans come pre-installed with social hardware that predisposes them to think of human males and human females as belonging to one type or category in some sense - the human. But if we pull back the curtains, we can see an equally valid way of slicing up reality: men and women are different but &#34;related&#34; things.

Men and women rely on each other to reproduce their own kind. Men can&#39;t make more of themselves without women, and women can&#39;t make more of themselves without men. But why think of them as part of one &#34;species&#34; or &#34;type&#34;? Sure, they share a lot of similarities, and can be contrasted against things like &#34;rabbits&#34; as a whole, even as one can draw parallels between &#34;human males&#34; and &#34;rabbit males.&#34;

I believe it was Bret Weinstein who said that if alien biologists came down to Earth, they would rediscover the concept of sex every day. I don&#39;t exactly take issue with this claim, but I do wonder if the aliens would have the encyclopedia entry &#34;Humans&#34;, or if there would be two encyclopedia entries &#34;[Human-Male]&#34; and &#34;[Human-Female].&#34;

There&#39;s one layer deeper to go here, though. Would the alien biologists even stop there? How would they deal with intersex individuals?

I think a certain form of so-called &#34;binary&#34; thinking is to talk about there being men and women, with intersex individuals being deviations from the norm that can still be forced into one of those two boxes, or filed away into a &#34;freak of nature&#34; box (though we would never call it that with modern social mores.)

But I think this &#34;binary&#34; thinking has exactly the same problem that &#34;needs&#34;- or &#34;for&#34;-based thinking produces: it engages in teleological thinking.

We could imagine that instead of having abstractions at the level of &#34;man&#34; and woman&#34; that the alien biologists have a unique compound word for everything that basically contains every bit of information about that thing known to the aliens.

At this level, maybe the alien biologists could notice patterns between two things, which for us would become categories, but for them remain unabstracted, ungeneralized observations about the entirety of existing things. Maybe these aliens don&#39;t even have the concept of &#34;distinct things&#34; but instead build up observations from correlations of raw sensory data that doesn&#39;t get processed by modules in their brain into &#34;objects&#34; and &#34;animals&#34; and &#34;things&#34;, but instead is dealt with as a Unity with sub-patterns within patterns that can be interacted with and about which predictions can be made.

I think our brain modules do a lot of work in making certain &#34;categories&#34; seem more plausible than others, that is the source of the shadow of teleology projected back out into the world. However, once we see past the shadow, it might genuinely become impossible to pick a point to stop cutting reality at the joints.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imknlnp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Cloudflare has put out a blog post in response to mounting pressure for them to </title><updated>2022-08-31T21:00:07Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Cloudflare has put out a blog post in response to mounting pressure for them to drop Kiwi Farms. Cloudflare had previously terminated services to The Daily Stormer and 8chan, but this time the company says it will take no action, and even suggest the previous deplatformings were a mistake.

Selected quotes:

&amp;gt;Some argue that we should terminate these services to content we find reprehensible so that others can launch attacks to knock it offline. That is the equivalent argument in the physical world that the fire department shouldn&#39;t respond to fires in the homes of people who do not possess sufficient moral character. Both in the physical world and online, that is a dangerous precedent, and one that is over the long term most likely to disproportionately harm vulnerable and marginalized communities.

&amp;gt;[...]

&amp;gt;Just as the telephone company doesn&#39;t terminate your line if you say awful, racist, bigoted things, we have concluded in consultation with politicians, policy makers, and experts that turning off security services because we think what you publish is despicable is the wrong policy. To be clear, just because we did it in a limited set of cases before doesn’t mean we were right when we did. Or that we will ever do it again.

&amp;gt;[...]

&amp;gt;We do, however, believe that in cases where our values are diametrically opposed to a paying customer that we should take further steps to not only not profit from the customer, but to use any proceeds to further our companies’ values and oppose theirs.

&amp;gt;For instance, when a site that opposed LGBTQ+ rights signed up for a paid version of DDoS mitigation service we worked with our Proudflare employee resource group to identify an organization that supported LGBTQ+ rights and donate 100 percent of the fees for our services to them. We don&#39;t and won&#39;t talk about these efforts publicly because we don&#39;t do them for marketing purposes; we do them because they are aligned with what we believe is morally correct.



https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflares-abuse-policies-and-approach/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imknlnp/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [deleted]</title><updated>2022-08-31T20:08:51Z</updated><author><name>[deleted]</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[deleted]</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imkfe12/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis</title><updated>2022-08-31T19:05:00Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis in your hoods?

Finland is getting hit less than Central Europe, but getting hit nevertheless. We haven&#39;t been \*quite\* as dependent on Russian power than many other countries - Russian gas was only 5 % of the energy supply, Russians cut the flow already back in May, and in general Russian electricity imports have formed 10 % of the Finnish electricity use. However, prices are still expected to rise very high in the winter, naturally the season when the society most needs electricity and has to import it.

The crisis is particularly - as everywhere else - hitting those living in detached housing. Even though district heating and, lately, geothermal are increasingly popular for heating, and an increasing amoung of air-source heat pumps have been installed there&#39;s still a lot of them relying on direct electric heating, which on current terms translates to &#34;pay up the nose&#34;. Such houses might well see electricity bills hitting well over a thousand a month, unless nothing is done.

Among various issues:

\- Nordic electricity generation is reliant on water power, and though the Nordic countries haven&#39;t seen droughts on the Central European level, these are still affecting water power generation. Finland has imported electricity from Norway, and now the Norwegians are mulling restricting [electricity exports](https://www.helsinkitimes.fi/finland/finland-news/domestic/22095-lintilae-norway-restricting-electricity-exports-would-play-into-putin-s-hands.html).

\- There would still be a chance to avoid the worst of it - if the Olkiluoto 3 nuclear generator goes fully online before the schedule, or at least is not delayed any more. Olkiluoto 3 has been the white whale of nuclear projects for years now, incredibly delayed and costly project that is now in test use, with those tests also frequently facing unplanned downtimes. The current estimate for Olkiluoto 3 finally starting commercial use is December 2022, but we&#39;ll see. In particular having OL3 being online and without issues would lead to stability - less need to worry about whether winter&#39;s particularly cold and how windy/sunny it is for renewables.

\- While browsing Twitter, I&#39;ve seen a fair amount of what can only be described as &#39;schadenfreude&#39; by pro-Russian right-wingers in various countries mocking Europeans with high energy bills and Ukraine flags in the profile photo. There&#39;s next to none of that here, as the entire Finnish society continues to be broadly pro-Ukrainian. I haven&#39;t seen any major political actors suggesting trying to make nice with Russia as a solution, of course it would be hard to do that by our lonesome anyway as long as we&#39;re a part of the EU, and Russians might tell us to pound sand anyway.

\- The environmental aspect is, of course, a big local culture war, especially in a country where much (most?) of the culture war has been environmentalism-related for a long time. It&#39;s not an easy question, non-/anti-environmentalists say that of course when you do things to drive up the costs of polluting the prices of electricity (which cannot really be produced in any way without \*some\* pollution) environmentalists claim that without the environmental measures the situation would be worse, comparing us to Britain where the junking of &#34;green crap&#34; led to end to insulation efforts or to countries that are more dependent on fossil fuels than us.

\- There&#39;s a back-up power reserve including, among others, Finland&#39;s last electricity-generation-oriented coal plant (other coal plants mainly generate heat). It&#39;s pretty certain that if it comes to firing up the power reserve or rolling blackouts, the power reserve is going to be fired up - that&#39;s what reserves are for, after all - but there are calls to do this already at this point with the electric bills going up, and apparently there are difficulties related to this, such as the fact that the said coal plant would need some heavy maintenance to bring back up.

\- much of the price rise is caused by market issues, Finland being a part of the European electric grid and thus being affected by the comparatively larger issues of the other countries, the sheer uncertainty of the situation hiking up the futures, and so on. Of course, if nations like Norway restrict exports, there&#39;s just going to be a domino effect with it being easier and easier for other nations to do the same when necessity calls. It&#39;s hard to see these sorts of crises as anything less than further evidence in the breakdown of globalization, unless it alternatively finally becomes the crisis the European elites can use to enact the European federation.

The government is planning measures to alleviate the crisis. Currently, the news are reporting that they&#39;re considering a measure for a tax rebate on bills over 500€ / month and a cut on the electricity VAT, as well as some less defined measure to help the poorest families and some throw-ins like doubled child benefits etc.

To me, this seems counterproductive - like tailormade to help the most energy-consumptive housing and the least-well off, but leaving large urban middle classes living in flats or in less-consumptive detached housing with only the VAT benefit. If we want to actually avoid rolling blackouts, and unless there&#39;s some measures that will lead to a lot of new electricity fast, it would seem we&#39;d need to find some ways to reduce electricity use while ensuring that this won&#39;t break family budgets. That might mean models like guaranteeing a certain fixed price for electricity use under some ceiling and leaving market prices in force above that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar</title><updated>2022-08-31T17:35:44Z</updated><author><name>PM_ME_UR_OBSIDIAN</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m looking for a really good personal organizer, ideally a combination calendar and task list. As of today I am using Google Calendar combined with Todoist.

Todoist caveats:

- No tracking of start date, only due date. Any task with a date configured is assumed to be a discrete amount of work to be done on the day that it is due, or shortly before.
- There is no concept of prioritization within a time window. I can&#39;t ask &#34;what is the most urgent task that I need to get done within two weeks?&#34; 
- If I have a daily recurring task and I mark it as done for yesterday, then the next occurence is tomorrow. There is no concept of catching up on overdue engagements.

The app is swell though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imjr65j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started list</title><updated>2022-08-31T14:25:19Z</updated><author><name>GeorgeMacDonald</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Someone on here recommended the podcast The Drive by Peter Attia. I started listening to it and it is a great podcast! I don’t know too much about the science of health besides the very basics so this is pretty cool. 

What episodes do you all recommend? I listened to the skin care episode (forgot which one that was). The upshot was use sunscreen daily, vitamin A cream and interestingly enough vitamin C cream on your face. I have episodes 134 and 206 downloaded which are about preventing heart disease (I have some bad family history there) and exercise respectively. 

Specifically, I am interested in the exercise ones. I do crossfit type high intensity workouts three times per week which is 3 hours of exercise. I have a feeling that some more time with lower intensity exercise would be beneficial to me in addition to what I do but that’s just my intuition not a science based thing. 

Nutrition is also an interest of mine so episodes on that would be nice too. My basic knowledge is to eat less red meat, eat more vegetables inching one’s way into a vegetable based diet (which would be tough for me as I love carbs and meat and when I only eat veggies I get super hungry shortly thereafter). 

The Revolutions podcast by Mike Duncan was also recommended and is very good.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imixmzt/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] What is the best French to English translation software?</title><updated>2022-08-31T10:27:23Z</updated><author><name>6tjk</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">What is the best French to English translation software?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imi5pyi/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>