<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Wellness Wednesday - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-11T03:18:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifofoo2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vn8roc/wellness_wedne</title><updated>2022-07-11T03:18:30Z</updated><author><name>QuarkweightGOAT</name></author><content type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vn8roc/wellness_wednesday_for_june_29_2022/ierzb5z/)

Week 2/60 is behind me. Not much to report. Water fasted Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Saturday, and today. 2 more weeks until I begin resistance training and trying to put on muscle. Shedding fat at a crazy rate but perceptibly losing muscle mass as well as to be expected. I can notice a tiny bit of loose skin around my abdomen in dim lighting but not as bad as I feared. No clue whether fasting is helping on that front but still seems worthwhile since I am leaning out so fast. Am extremely eager to hit the weights in a few weeks. I will post before once I am done dieting in a few weeks.

Current plan is to fast Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, Saturday next week. Then Monday, Tuesday, eat maintenance on Wednesday and then conclude with a 4-day fast to complete my leaning out phase. After that I will slowly reintroduce calories until I get to a calculated maintenance for a week or two and then lift at a small caloric surplus. 

Will report back next week.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifofoo2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkz35p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">So a few months ago, I stumbled upon the [Healthy Gamer Youtube channel](https:/</title><updated>2022-07-10T10:51:07Z</updated><author><name>cae_jones</name></author><content type="text">So a few months ago, I stumbled upon the [Healthy Gamer Youtube channel](https://m.youtube.com/channel/UClHVl2N3jPEbkNJVx-ItQIQ), and found some of the suggestions there helpful as regards creative projects. The trouble is, I kinda feel like I&#39;ve hit a wall. In particular, I&#39;ve been working on a game, under the assumption I&#39;m not going to bother releasing it, which puts me in a weird position where I&#39;m done with all the bits I need to enjoy it, but it&#39;s not really complete-complete. I managed to get sufficiently into the habit of working on it at certain times that not working on it is unpleasant, but I&#39;m having trouble getting myself to either work on the unnecessary-for-me-but-should-probably-do-anyway bits, or starting something different, and so I feel at risk of backsliding into the abyss.

I think maybe I&#39;m not working hard enough at exercise or meditation as habits. I&#39;m not sure why. They clearly help when I do. ???</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkz35p/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkeby3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">My parent is dying and in one of the moments we have had, my parent shared that </title><updated>2022-07-10T06:05:27Z</updated><author><name>it_is_so_weird_to_be</name></author><content type="text">My parent is dying and in one of the moments we have had, my parent shared that my estrangement from my sibling “is killing” them. 

They’ve always hated that I cut the sibling off and have continually pressured me to reconnect for years. The estrangement has gone on since 2010.

The sibling was physically abusive toward me, as well as very emotionally abusive. I have other siblings and they maintain a relationship with this one. When the estranged sibling comes up in conversation with the other siblings, it is almost always complaints about their abusive behavior. Which leads me to believe I made the right decision for my own sanity, and that the behavior that precipitated the estrangement is ongoing. 

This situation with our parent has led the abusive sibling to reach out to me, but the thought of talking to them or even being in the same room as them gives me a great deal of anxiety. I did not respond. 

But I’m getting even more pressure than usual - parent is dying. My estrangement of the sibling is “killing” them. Why can’t I just let bygones be bygones. 

They won’t listen to me when I describe being abused by this sibling, or when I point out the hypocrisy that the dying parent didn’t talk to their siblings for decades because of shitty behavior. They have a history of ignoring abuse, like with another family member who is an accused child molester (I have personal experience that this accusation is 100% true) and is still invited to gatherings. 

I guess I just don’t know how to navigate this. I live in a different state, visiting theirs, and I am trying to spend time with my dying parent but every time we talk, it’s brought up how I need to put aside my differences with the sibling and make amends. 

It makes me doubt my own experiences and makes me feel intense guilt. Part of me wants to placate them. Part of me wants to go home and never contact my parents again. How would you deal with this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkeby3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifih61c/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I&#39;m not interested in the CW aspects of this and more about the social managemen</title><updated>2022-07-09T20:09:40Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><content type="text">I&#39;m not interested in the CW aspects of this and more about the social management and relationship building aspects:

Yesterday night I was at a party (purely social, alcohol and some other substances involved) in Oakland with some friends and got a bit bored, so I asked someone what their most controversial opinion was. Their response was that... they thought Trump was a criminal and should be in prison, an opinion that was well-received by the group. Which left me in a bit of a pickle when the question turned around to me. So I chickened out and offered something off the wall about non-practicing pedophiles being condemned too harshly by society. Which was a bit spicier, but it was carefully constructed not to be relevant to any hot button issues that would actually be controversial. (Yes, it&#39;s pretty crazy that I felt like a NAMBLA-adjacent opinion is less controversial than saying something like &#34;school shootings aren&#39;t a major issue in our society&#34; or &#34;1/6 wasn&#39;t really important or a threat to our democracy,&#34; but there we are.)

But it got me to thinking: where can I find real-life friends or social settings where there&#39;s actual space for debate and discussion? Luckily my girlfriend is pretty open-minded, but (at least among the friends I&#39;ve made, mostly professionals in the Bay Area) it seems hard to find social spaces that are open to discussion to contentious topics without them devolving into insults or attribution of bad motives to someone.

Or am I just being overly neurotic here? Maybe I should have just stated something actually controversial instead of hoping someone else would, since I brought it up in the first place? In retrospect it was probably unfair for me to ask someone else to go out on a limb when I was too scared to myself...</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifih61c/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if5qk02/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I developed some bad habits in my past, and now I feel trapped.  Trapped as in &#34;</title><updated>2022-07-07T02:47:13Z</updated><author><name>rekruldas</name></author><content type="text">I developed some bad habits in my past, and now I feel trapped.  Trapped as in &#34;I&#39;d be killing myself tomorrow&#34; were my parents dead. They&#39;re not, so I can&#39;t. Don&#39;t know what to do with myself.

No career, no CV, no friends. Not that I alienated them, a little of that, but mostly,  I had few friends, and they all drifted away after I dropped out of uni.  Before that, friends from high school drifted away because I went to another city for uni.No context anymore, and I felt ashamed too. I don&#39;t feel like getting to know any people. There&#39;s nothing I can offer them, and where would I get to know them anyway ? Gym ? People go there to exercise, not to socialise.

Longer re-statement of my malfunction in a reply to this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if5qk02/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if44t2h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">
Do you you guys got any good advice for young adults in genral?

Like to how be</title><updated>2022-07-06T19:44:57Z</updated><author><name>Nerd_199</name></author><content type="text">
Do you you guys got any good advice for young adults in genral?

Like to how better social skills/personal financial?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if44t2h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white,</title><updated>2022-07-06T18:04:36Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><content type="text">Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white, just finished a master&#39;s degree, starting a career in software engineering, normal-looking (though skinny; I&#39;m working on that), and shy in large groups of new people (but alright one on one). The main problem is that I&#39;m gay in a moderate-size city in the US South, population 150,000, whose main university was recently ranked the least LGBT-friendly public university in the nation.

Due to general awkwardness and being busy during college and grad school, I&#39;ve never kissed a guy or been on a date, but girls have definitely liked me, so I think I would do alright if I could just meet some gay guys that are at least slightly nerdy. My question is then how to do that.

There are gay bars in town, but bars aren&#39;t at all my scene, I personally don&#39;t drink for genetic reasons, I&#39;m not looking for a hookup (I could just use Grindr if I was), and it just seems like my kind of guy is unlikely to be at a bar. But maybe I should try anyway?

I tried Tinder and Bumble, but the pools are so small (I exhausted them in just a couple hours) and a large proportion of guys smoke (a deal-breaker for me) or are just looking for a hookup. I got a couple matches, but they almost immediately stopped responding, which I suppose is to be expected on the apps.

To make some regular friends in town, I&#39;ve started going to a board game club. There used to be a pretty active programmers community in town, which apparently kind of collapsed during the pandemic, but I&#39;ll keep an eye on it. For some physical activity I&#39;m thinking about joining a recreational soccer league this fall.

Thoughts on any of this would be appreciated, thanks!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says tha</title><updated>2022-07-06T16:38:45Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><content type="text">Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says that some specific poor vision habits plus slightly-too-powerful glasses induce myopia, and that some other specific good vision habits plus different glasses can reverse it.

&amp;gt; In various corners of the internet there is an overwhelming abundance of anecdotal claims from people who aren&#39;t sockpuppets (I checked) that the model&#39;s interventions are effective. This is what led me to try it. A lot of the information here is based on a synthesis of the perspectives provided by people in various communities attempting this process.

https://www.losetheglasses.org/

The key idea seems to be not to over-correct your vision for your current task. If you are looking at a computer for 8 hours a day, do not wear your full strength distance glasses, but a weaker pair that are just strong enough to see the screen.

This sounds plausible and fairly cheap to try.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3cld0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Woke up at midnight, puked, had to shower to get cleaned up, restless sleep off </title><updated>2022-07-06T16:32:52Z</updated><author><name>bl1y</name></author><content type="text">Woke up at midnight, puked, had to shower to get cleaned up, restless sleep off and on, 101 fever.

Go online to order some comfort foods. Payment declined. Check bank, card hold, $1000+ in fraud charges. Cancel card, won&#39;t have new one for up to 2 weeks.

Anyways, send wellness please. I am out of wellness.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3cld0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2tf3d/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">https://www.painscience.com/articles/pain-is-weird.php#sec_welcome

Really neat </title><updated>2022-07-06T14:26:28Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><content type="text">https://www.painscience.com/articles/pain-is-weird.php#sec_welcome

Really neat article about the way pain functions. Situated a lot of things into context for me. 

Does anyone have reading recommendation talking about the way our brains act in moments of acute stress, from a somewhat larger angle? One thing I want to cultivate is calmness in times of crisis.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2tf3d/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2soy3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I need to log off. Terminally online leftists are really getting to me. Bullies,</title><updated>2022-07-06T14:21:19Z</updated><author><name>SomewhatEmbarassed</name></author><content type="text">I need to log off. Terminally online leftists are really getting to me. Bullies, the lot of them. Rotten and self-righteous without any substance to back up their principles. I&#39;m tired of their justifications, because it too often results in the wrong people getting hurt by them. 
I don&#39;t want to fall victim to divide-and-distract tactics, and yet when I feel so alone in my frustrations, it&#39;s difficult to focus on more important things.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2soy3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2s33v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Is there a point where some sort of law of diminishing returns kicks in with res</title><updated>2022-07-06T14:17:00Z</updated><author><name>GrendelBlackedOut</name></author><content type="text">Is there a point where some sort of law of diminishing returns kicks in with respect to cardiovascular fitness? I hate exercising. It brings me no pleasure whatsoever. I would, however, like to have as much high quality time with my wife and kids as possible. My current cardio routine consists of running a 5k on a treadmill twice a week (typical time \~23:30-24 minutes) and a 5-mile outdoor run perhaps once every 3-4 weeks (typical time \~40-42 minutes). Is there any incremental utility in running more or could I be happy just maintaining this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2s33v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2o0jm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I say many word, when few word do trick. 

However, I cannot think of few-word u</title><updated>2022-07-06T13:47:07Z</updated><author><name>Weaponomics</name></author><content type="text">I say many word, when few word do trick. 

However, I cannot think of few-word until I have already said many-word. 

(For example: I have revised 5 full paragraphs into what you see here, with almost no loss of content.)

How fix?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2o0jm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2h0sf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Started getting into olympic weightlifting. It&#39;s a fun thing to organize my stre</title><updated>2022-07-06T12:51:10Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><content type="text">Started getting into olympic weightlifting. It&#39;s a fun thing to organize my strength training around, and the incredibly technical nature of the snatch/clean-and-jerk would probably appeal to a lot of y&#39;all. So many layers to dig into with these two moves. 

It&#39;s a great sport because it requires strength, balance, flexibility and a Motte-level obsession with analysis and details.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if2h0sf/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week a</title><updated>2022-07-06T07:20:30Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><content type="text">I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week as the gym is 45 minutes away.

Not great progress but programming is quite fun although taxing. My aim for this week is to workout 3 days a week and work 4-6 hours daily while ensuring I get plenty of sleep at the right time.

It&#39;s genuinely bad but still honest progress and with achievable goals.

Here&#39;s also a text exchange between me and a friend of mine that describes an event which will be the last part of my post. 

So I met my classmate who got into IIT Kanpur today for breakfast
He was here with two other dudes from his uni, one was from CS and the other from materials.
My classmate and the CS dude hadn&#39;t taken a year off like I had and they went from being wierdo nerds who were prentious to well adjusted people who&#39;d indulge in hedonism and doing well in life.
Good to get periodical reminders like today.
I don&#39;t have any girls I text for now and will keep it that way.
You&#39;re right about time man.
I can have all the fun in the world but for now, back to work.

IIT Kanpur is the best uni in the country and is above the one I go to. Both these people have gotten selected by different grad schools (UIUC and CMU respectively) with a bare minium research profile since the recommendation of faculty there matters a lot. 

My point is that there&#39;s a time and place to have fun and there&#39;s a time and place to just study, my current situation is the latter. 

I was genuinely surprised when I was able to solve programming questions and got a sense of joy doing that so shall continue. Working out is a tad hectic and people mock me for even trying since I&#39;ve been doing it on and off for the past year but would go for a week and not go again for a month due to the pajeet exam schedule. 

Anyway, have a fun week ahead.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>