<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Wellness Wednesday - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T19:09:12Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iiti1r4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I have a seven hour flight tomorrow, can anyone recommend any iPhone/iPad games </title><updated>2022-08-03T19:09:12Z</updated><author><name>wear146</name></author><content type="text">I have a seven hour flight tomorrow, can anyone recommend any iPhone/iPad games or books (I like to read fairly light weight things when I travel, something like The Butchers Boy would be my Goto sort of novel)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iiti1r4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iitfiat/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">Any recommendations for bidets?</title><updated>2022-08-03T18:51:55Z</updated><author><name>disposablehead001</name></author><content type="text">Any recommendations for bidets?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iitfiat/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iite1ng/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">How do you keep an indoor cat stimulated/entertained?</title><updated>2022-08-03T18:42:05Z</updated><author><name>PM_ME_UR_OBSIDIAN</name></author><content type="text">How do you keep an indoor cat stimulated/entertained?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iite1ng/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iit0kaw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I&#39;m moving across the country next week to a small city in the middle of the mou</title><updated>2022-08-03T17:13:22Z</updated><author><name>punishedmicah</name></author><content type="text">I&#39;m moving across the country next week to a small city in the middle of the mountain west. It has a college and is a (very) regional economic hub, but certainly ain&#39;t a social powerhouse.

Any advice for meeting people in their early-mid 20s? I know basically nobody there.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iit0kaw/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iirygg2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">I caught a severe infection my toe which stopped me from working out. I had been</title><updated>2022-08-03T12:57:10Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><content type="text">I caught a severe infection my toe which stopped me from working out. I had been consistent for two weeks and on the last day pulled 60 kgs for 3 sets of 4 reps at a bodyweight of 68. That is some progress.

My life is still in shambles, time management issues, adhd, just the general inability to stick long term but I did have some progress, I did 10 hours (first 10 videos are longer on average for this 120 video playlist) of the [DSA Playlist for my job interviews](https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDzeHZWIZsTryvtXdMr6rPh4IDexB5NIA).

I took me a month to do it and that was all due to me simply not changing my ways, This is still much much better than 0 which is all I have done since beginning college and I do feel good in having made some progress. My aim is to do all 120 plus videos by the end of the month so that I can get a job I desire.

Action leads to more action......Excuses lead to more excuses.Both have their own momentum.- RSD Tyler

I cannot thank this place enough for being rude to me at times and pointing out that I was posting fluff and not actual progress. Here is a little bit of it, not a lot, not good but still a whole lot more than I likely would have done given my track record.

I aim to pull close to 100 kgs and finish the entire playlist by next month, hopefully have a job in hand too. I am in my final year of uni and my uni has firms visit us for jobs so am doing this just for that. Leetcode hard enough and you will get a job.

My low CGPA (6.79/10) is an issue so shall try to bump it up to 7 or above this year and get back to my NLP internship hopefully.

Also my stupid decisions did have their consequences and my brother is paying for it. My parents enrolled him into a third tier BCA(bachelors&#39; of computer applications, A bachelors degree in Computers that is laughed at by everyone for being a meme degree only taken by losers) at a local uni here in my hometown citing my own academic failures as they are extremely worried that if my brother performs like me, they can only get him to pass here and not outside at a better uni. I feel really bad. I am responsible for making the life of my entire family worse and likely permanently.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/weyt58/wellness_wednesday_for_august_03_2022/iirygg2/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>