<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/2cimarafa - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-15T11:50:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/2cimarafa" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig93u57/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Below, /u/oracleoutlook asks someone:

&amp;gt;Are you arguing that the extent a liv</title><updated>2022-07-15T11:50:50Z</updated><author><name>2cimarafa</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Below, /u/oracleoutlook asks someone:

&amp;gt;Are you arguing that the extent a living organism is a human to the extent to which they are cared about?

I&#39;m not interested in how &#39;human&#39; someone is, but it seems sane to me that the value of someone&#39;s life (or rather, the harm incurred by taking it) is related to the extent to which others care about that person. The death of someone surrounded by friends, family, parents, children and so on, all of whom will be deeply sad at their passing clearly causes more harm, more pain and so on to others (namely those people) than the death of a friendless, childless, single orphan. 

The moral harm of someone&#39;s death to their loved ones is central to our conception of the value of life. When a young parent dies, we mourn for their children who will grow up without them. Other than young children we feel sorriest, at funerals, for widows and widowers, not for the deceased who is either gone or (hopefully) in a happier place. In any cliche scene in which someone in a film is begging for their life, what do they say? &#34;I have a family&#34;, &#34;think of my children&#34;, &#34;my daughter needs me&#34;, &#34;I have to look after my sick father&#34; blah blah blah. It&#39;s not &#34;I&#39;d really want to live so I can spend another thirty years enjoying chicken parmigiana and watching the baseball on the weekend&#34;, even if that actually sounds pretty good and even if our reasons to want to live *personally* are typically largely selfish. Our empathy is with those left behind, and the more of them (or perhaps rather the more sympathetic their circumstances), the more harm incurred. 

There are exceptional circumstances (half the country may love a political leader, the other half may hate them, some people have weird parasocial relationships with influencers or TV characters and so on and these are indeed all boring utilitarian questions), but by and large it *is*, in my opinion the case that, religious command aside, human value varies and is largely contingent on our utility to and relationship with others.

(I realise now I should have posted this in the Friday Fun Thread)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig93u57/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>