<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/4bpp - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T17:31:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/4bpp" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijgttes/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] &#34;Cop faces&#34;: to what extent are facial features actually predictive of personali</title><updated>2022-08-08T17:31:35Z</updated><author><name>4bpp</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">&#34;Cop faces&#34;: to what extent are facial features actually predictive of personality? Do meaningful population substructures among, say, white Anglos exist that would correlate with something like authoritarian personality?

I keep circling back to a certain pattern I seem to see, where a person famous for authoritarian or &#34;meddlesome violent pro-social&#34; behaviour turns out to have a facial features that register as similar in some relevant way according to my visual system. The behaviour they exhibit is always a certain palpable glee in public criticism, punishment and humiliation of perceived rule-breakers, especially as such rules are widely agreed upon by society. The cleanest example is the proprietor of [krebsonsecurity](https://krebsonsecurity.com/about/), who is a security blogger who moonlights in investigating random Eastern European credit card flippers and botnet operators and publishes their flailing as they get caught and apologetic letters they seem to send to him personally from jail. Next exhibit is [Mark Rober](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCY1kMZp36IQSyNx_9h4mpCg), a Youtuber who started out in generic DIY tinkering but then pivoted to overengineered revenge plots against package thieves and online scammers. [Matthew Green](https://isi.jhu.edu/~mgreen/) is a cryptographer recently in the news for attacking another cryptographer for suing the NIST for not releasing details on NSA meddling in the post-quantum cryptography standardisation process (so basically carrying water for the NSA), but he seems to be at the outer edges of the (visual) category to me. [John McCain](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_McCain) was a famous person whose face is closer to a central example, but I don&#39;t know enough about the man beyond him having being a seemingly very principled and rule-bound Republican. On top of that, I seem to see the average of these faces in an endless array of movie FBI agents and real-life US border control. 

Does anyone else see the commonalities there, or is it just me? How plausible is it for a pattern like this to exist, and how specific would it be? Am I just seeing something quite general like Moldbug&#39;s Optimates or the distinguishing features one of the tribes of Albion&#39;s Seed, whose ethos and appearance both are stark to me by virtue of being culturally foreign? Could it be a narrower (hitherto unidentified, but perhaps actually sufficiently endogamous to maintain itself) genetically identifiable subgroup (of Anglo-Americans) with distinct temperament, or could there perhaps even be an almost inextricable facial correlate of certain personality traits every time selection pops them out, in the same way in which canids get [domestication syndrome](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domestication_syndrome)?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijgttes/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>