<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/89237849237498237427 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T18:19:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/89237849237498237427" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0u4zm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Fresh off [the lithium debacle](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7iAABhWpcGeP5e6S</title><updated>2022-07-13T18:19:26Z</updated><author><name>89237849237498237427</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Fresh off [the lithium debacle](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7iAABhWpcGeP5e6SB/it-s-probably-not-lithium), Slime Mold Time Mold (SMTM) has a new blogpost on *one weird trick* that causes weight loss: [eating potatoes, and only potatoes.](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2022/07/12/lose-10-6-pounds-in-four-weeks-with-this-one-weird-trick-discovered-by-local-slime-hive-mind-doctors-grudgingly-respect-them-hope-to-become-friends/). The idea is that eating a diet consistent solely of potatoes will lead to considerable weight loss, and the results are plain to see. [No one gained weight](https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ahPd4EygAeEXd2we3MAb5EuX_Wm0sCGBPQ4qYjg6u8iIJF9ppFKh9rO9SQxEzAfTgn-Ts460M6jmjHvf4LOhUuOaEJFXZMD76TUswGpTU8E9K0XmaDEu3ev7O1xU8EX99KkosyQYy9RWuCNVRgU), [mean weight loss was pretty large](https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/SvOOLFA04BaBzC53ckpT2ZvNuAsnUpDzHltfEGBHUJK-LNvlNErRuTsWiTQS0mxhtHOFqmZHwg3QbOeMhlF6Fz1MXDavpQnlQ18k0iyUUUWGUu_dK7A9hlrNqJEsvSu9Nddehv8lr-Sd1hgk1fw), and [results were reasonably consistent by BMI before the experiment](https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/owVbw0OZIQdIiRwq6lRoNtJ0ONOTdFQa5rqEBI41qw68BUqnSvNjKhDnGfe_YtZAaQbyoKDip9eCE_rT-Wm0-dlAkxLcs6BZDtPMXjL_u-ztB1jbubCOorXx-qmD2aOZtW_nq46sgGCEjt5xIKc). SMTM&#39;s post sounds deservedly ecstatic, but it also sounds undeservedly like they think they&#39;ve made a discovery.  
  
Throughout the article, they pepper in comments like &#34;If you predicted (or could have predicted) that the potato diet would cause this kind of weight loss, or if medical / nutritional science could have predicted that this diet was going to be so effective in the short term, and so easy for so many people — then why haven’t doctors and nutritionists been recommending the potato diet to people alongside diet and exercise?&#34; and &#34;We understand if you don’t really get this. We didn’t get it either, despite reading about all the previous success stories, until one of us tried the potato diet for ourselves. Hunger vanishes in a really weird way that is hard to describe to anyone who hasn’t felt it directly. So listen to all our participants who are like “no it’s not calories, it’s not willpower”. Or try it for yourself, you might be surprised!&#34; At a first glance, it&#39;s difficult to imagine someone wrote this with anything like serious intent, and these sorts of quotes are commonplace throughout the blogpost. They stand as solid evidence of virtually complete ignorance of this area of research. I&#39;ll explain by tackling these quotes.  
  
The first one should stand out to SlateStarCodex readers who remember [this review](https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/04/25/book-review-the-hungry-brain/) of Stephan Guyenet&#39;s *The Hungry Brain*. At the beginning of Section III, Scott described a very relevant study: &#34;In 1965, some scientists locked people in a room where they could only eat nutrient sludge dispensed from a machine. Even though the volunteers had no idea how many calories the nutrient sludge was, they ate exactly enough to maintain their normal weight, proving the existence of a “sixth sense” for food caloric content. Next, they locked morbidly obese people in the same room. They ended up eating only tiny amounts of the nutrient sludge, one or two hundred calories a day, without feeling any hunger. This proved that their bodies “wanted” to lose the excess weight and preferred to simply live off stored fat once removed from the overly-rewarding food environment. After six months on the sludge, a man who weighed 400 lbs at the start of the experiment was down to 200, without consciously trying to reduce his weight.&#34;   
  
The study in question is amply described in the book and can be read in full [here](https://nyaspubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1965.tb34828.x) (or [via sci-hub](https://sci-hub.se/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1965.tb34828.x)). It&#39;s really something, but it&#39;s also not the only study of its type. There have been plenty of studies on single-food diets, both with animals and humans. The general tenor of their results is that restriction to a singular type of food leads to weight loss. People who read *The Hungry Brain* will be unsurprised that sort of work is cited. The authors over at SMTM evidently read Guyenet (he is cited twice in the linked post), but never read his book or they could not have written that first quote. But, we know from their series *A Chemical Hunger* (e.g., [here](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/07/a-chemical-hunger-part-i-mysteries/), [here](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/11/a-chemical-hunger-part-ii-current-theories-of-obesity-are-inadequate/)), that they at least cite *The Hungry Brain*, and even had [a blogpost on this exact study](https://slimemoldtimemold.com/2021/07/23/a-chemical-hunger-interlude-b-the-nutrient-sludge-diet/). The blogpost is an unimpressive handwaving exercise by way of ignoring the post-1980 research on this topic and dismissing the pre-1980 research with the reason being that results from before the obesity epidemic really kicked off won&#39;t generalize. But this criticism is too broad. In their own potato diet post, they say that they expect their results will generalize, but for some reason, other monotonous diets will not? Perhaps their criticism only applies to this specific 1965 study, although I have doubts since they focus so heavily on potatoes, to the exclusion of general dietary monotony.  
  
Regardless, if you read just a few pages more in *The Hungry Brain*, you will discover (p. 65) where Guyenet predicts the result of a dietary content restriction: &#34;The fact that sensory-specific satiety drives us to overeat suggests a simple solution to the problem: Limit yourself to a few foods.&#34; What is the potato diet but limiting yourself to a few foods? The quantity of research supporting this point is enormous, so their arguing that it wasn&#39;t predicted - when they have evidently read and even written about material predicting it - should be galling for them. The snide remark they make asking why doctors haven&#39;t recommended eating potatoes only serves to obfuscate the reality that it is not potatoes that made the difference here, but induced dietary monotony. (Which is different from cross-sectional dietary monotony, both in terms of causes and effects.) To answer their subsequent quote
  
&amp;gt; If you knew the potato diet would work, why did you not run this study many years ago? Why are there no clinical trials? Did you think people would not be excited to see this result? 

It&#39;s clear that all that needs to be said is &#34;The studies were done, the trials were run, the results were in, you just ignored them.&#34;  
  
The &#34;We understand if you don&#39;t really get this&#34; quote refers to a reduction in hunger with the diet. My best guess about why they &#34;don&#39;t really get this&#34; is that they misunderstand hunger. Firstly, Guyenet explained their result very well, and his perspective is by no means unique. Secondly, hunger [follows a Circadian-like rhythm](https://eje.bioscientifica.com/view/journals/eje/152/6/1520845.xml) and is reduced to a pittance when you completely restrict caloric intake. Consistent with this, [ghrelin levels fall when you fast](https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/90/2/741/2836628). That is part of the standard explanation why, after a few days of fasting, you suddenly stop feeling any hunger. Even the subreddit /r/fasting [has a FAQ section mentioning this](https://www.reddit.com/r/fasting/wiki/fasting_in_a_nutshell#wiki_5.2._tips_and_tricks). Hunger is similarly reduced by dietary austerity, and more austere diets yield bigger weight losses and less rebounding, but I don&#39;t wish to ramble.  
  
As with the rest of their posts on weight and weight loss, SMTM&#39;s latest comes up short. It ignores things they&#39;ve read, ignores obvious implications, mechanisms, and prior work that should be cited, whilst being replete with generalizability concerns despite failing to acknowledge predictions generalize to cover theories like their own.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig0u4zm/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>