<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/89237849237498237427 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T19:26:39Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/89237849237498237427" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijwb99h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The Second Epistle to Timothy 2:22 in the New International Version reads &#34;Flee </title><updated>2022-08-11T19:26:39Z</updated><author><name>89237849237498237427</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The Second Epistle to Timothy 2:22 in the New International Version reads &#34;Flee the evil desires of youth and pursue righteousness, faith, love and peace, along with those who call on the Lord out of a pure heart.&#34; The principle outlined here has also been called the &#34;Modesto Manifesto&#34;, the &#34;Billy Graham Rule&#34;, and more recently, the &#34;Mike Pence Rule&#34;.   A pithy statement of it is &#34;Never dine alone with a woman&#34;. For Pence, it goes a bit further and he also won&#39;t consume alcohol without his wife present.   
  
When this came to light after Pence&#39;s vice presidential nomination in 2016, it inspired a furor overnight. Some [claimed it was sexist](https://www.latimes.com/local/abcarian/la-me-abcarian-pence-marriage-20170405-story.html), [Kamala Harris called it &#34;outrageous&#34;](https://www.politico.com/story/2019/03/14/kamala-harris-pence-women-1221741), and some commentators have even [questioned its legality](https://www.vox.com/the-big-idea/2017/3/31/15132730/pence-women-alone-rule-graham-discrimination). On the other hand, you have people claiming this is good or inevitable. [One example of the latter](https://wyborcza.pl/Jutronauci/7,165057,25453074,dukaj-wyrazam-niewiare.html) comes from a Polish sci-fi author some of you may be familiar with. In his opinion, movements like #MeToo make Pence&#39;s personal code of etiquette unavoidable because there aren&#39;t other ways to avoid the implied &#34;New Puritanism&#34;. Quoting from [the *Atlantic*](https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2017/03/pence-wife-billy-graham-rule/521298/), &#34;Socially liberal or non-religious people may see Pence’s practice as misogynistic or bizarre. For a lot of conservative religious people, though, this set-up probably sounds normal, or even wise. The dust-up shows how radically notions of gender divide American culture.&#34; With a description as apt as that, whatever you feel about it, Pence&#39;s personal is now [certainly political](https://digitaledition.chicagotribune.com/tribune/article_popover.aspx?guid=0ba7b595-8da9-4e63-a0ec-aec0639e4af6).  

So what happens when we have a society-wide experiment in forcing Pence&#39;s rule on people? [A recent preprint](https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4105976) alleged that was exactly what happened in the area of economic research. The TL;DR of the result is that post-#MeToo, male economists became more wary of collaborating with female economists. This effect was stronger when university policies on &#34;impersonal harassment&#34; were more ambiguous and when the number of past public sexual harassment cases at a university was higher. The effects are a bit scattered, but some clear findings ring out. Despite their proportions of the sample remaining unchanged despite #MeToo, female economists became less productive afterwards. This reduced productivity can be substantially (60%) attributed to the direct effects of having fewer collaborations with male economists, whose own productivity hasn&#39;t been affected. The effect on female economists&#39; productivity was broad. Female economists were not less likely to work with women alone or women and men together, but they were less likely to work with men alone. This extended to new projects and new papers. They were not less likely to collaborate with untenured colleagues, but they were less likely to collaborate with tenured people, and this seems to be due to the fact that the tenured colleagues were at higher-ranking universities, which saw larger reductions in cross-sex collaboration. After #MeToo, female economists were less likely to initiate new projects with new and existing coauthors and this effect was due to reductions in the numbers of new projects with new coauthors inside the university and of new projects with new coauthors outside of their university. The same pattern was seen for coauthorships more generally.   

So this paper argues that what happens when we start practicing what we&#39;re told in 2 Timothy 2:22 is that women take a professional hit. The author of this paper offered [two](https://twitter.com/marinambgg/status/1557714978747981824) [stories](https://twitter.com/marinambgg/status/1557714981587546114) to explain these results.  

&amp;gt;Men think “#MeToo means if I accidentally say the wrong thing, I’ll be cancelled/fired. I’d better stay away from women.” Clear policies show that “saying the wrong thing” doesn’t get you cancelled/fired, so clear policies reduce men’s (perceived) risk of #MeToo. 

and  

&amp;gt;Women think “#MeToo means I don’t have to work with the predator men anymore, so I’ll avoid them.” If that’s the story, we should see the decrease in collaborations regardless of whether policies are clear or not.  
 
And, to be fair, both of these stories might be true to different degrees. Policy ambiguity does not explain the whole reduction in collaborations. Because this *is* the case, unless the authors&#39; policy ambiguity measures weren&#39;t good enough, her suggestion that &#34;#MeToo plus clear policies could create awareness for sexual harassment without hurting women’s productivity&#34; may be misguided. Sure, ambiguity reduction looks like it could cut against these changes a bit, but if we trust her measurement we have to conclude that the damage is done. #MeToo has made us all evangelicals, and women are some of the victims of that change.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijwb99h/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>