<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/abb038c0-d21a - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-03T09:15:42Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/abb038c0-d21a" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib0mxet/</id><title type="text">[CW] *What do we really know about nurture?*

So modern social science tends to presu</title><updated>2022-06-03T09:15:42Z</updated><author><name>abb038c0-d21a</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">*What do we really know about nurture?*

So modern social science tends to presume a blank slate hypothesis, that we know does not and can not hold in general. Thus, much research regarding nature vs nurture mistakenly concludes environmental factors (or even specific types of factors) as the cause of whatever correlations are observed, without considering the alternative hypothesis (inheritance).

To me, that such an elementary mistake is so common is sufficient to render the entire field suspect. Still, I think the issues studied are incredibly important, and I&#39;m curious about how much of the &#39;commonly accepted wisdom&#39; regarding nurture can actually be trusted. 

Some nurture-related hypotheses intuitively seem plausible to me, while some don&#39;t, but I really have no idea which ones we have solid evidence for (i.e. evidence obtained via twin studies or other experimental designs that control for inheritance).

Does anybody here know what the state of our knowledge is for the following hypotheses?

- Do childhood traumatic experiences cause behavioral/emotional problems, or are both the experiences and problems caused by genetics (in parents and in children, respectively)?
- Does fatherlessness cause behavioral/emotional problems, or are both the experiences and problems caused by genetics (in the father and child, respectively)?
- Does bullying cause behavioral/emotional problems, or are both the bullying and emotional problems caused by genetics (in the person being bullied)?
- Are children&#39;s home environments important for outcomes, or does genetics cause both nice home environments and good outcomes?
- Does trauma cause behavioral/emotional problems in adults? All trauma and all adults, or in specific circumstances?
- Do socioeconomic factors affect outcomes, or are both the outcomes and the socioeconomic factors causes by genetics?
- Does education policy matter, or is a student&#39;s success determined by genetics? Which educational interventions work?
- Does welfare lead to better outcomes (in general, and specifically lower crime rates)? Does it continue to do so once abject poverty has been eliminated?
- Do non-welfare social programs (counseling, extra money to schools with problems, &#34;ex-con&#34; programs, etc) lead to better outcomes? If so, which programs and under which circumstances?
- Do rehabilitation programs and softer sentencing reduce the recidivism rate? If so, under which circumstances?
- Do integration policies (welfare, funding for civil society; especially for immigrants&#39; religious/cultural practices) produce better outcomes for immigrants? Under which circumstances?

I&#39;m curious to hear if anybody here has any insight into any of these questions. Perhaps there&#39;s some common nurture-related wisdom I missed, for or against which against we have solid evidence?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib0mxet/"/></entry></feed>