<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/alphanumericsprawl - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-22T02:06:09Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/alphanumericsprawl" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4w2le/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] China&#39;s  SMIC has started shipping domestically produced [7nm microchips](https:</title><updated>2022-07-22T02:06:09Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">China&#39;s  SMIC has started shipping domestically produced [7nm microchips](https://semianalysis.substack.com/p/chinas-smic-is-shipping-7nm-foundry).

This means that they&#39;re the third most advanced chip manufacturer, behind only Samsung in Korea and TSMC in Taiwan. Taiwan and Samsung are both on 5nm and introducing 3nm. Global Foundries is the top Euro-American fab and straggles far behind at 12nm.

Apparently China&#39;s 7nm chips are qualitatively inferior to TSMC/Samsung 7nm since the US is still blocking technology transfers of the special ultraviolet etching technology you need for better production. This may constrain them somewhat in the future. 

However, the situation at present is Samsung &amp;gt; TSMC &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  SMIC &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; everyone else. Samsung got to 3nm first, which upset the usual order of TSMC being number 1. As far as I can tell, all the big players can design chips, it&#39;s only manufacturing that&#39;s seriously difficult. How long will the UV tech sanctions hold back China? They have no shortage of money or brainpower. Let&#39;s also consider that our active sabotage of Chinese semiconductors is somehow less damaging than whatever we did to our own industries. Why is it that China is still ahead of our own fabs?

Contra others in the previous thread who argued that China isn&#39;t a serious threat to US/Western hegemony, I maintain that China is an extremely strong challenger the likes of which we&#39;ve never seen. They have unparalleled industrial scale - they&#39;ve significantly outpaced US naval shipbuilding for years now. When it comes to steel, cars, chemicals, HSR, solar panels and ports they&#39;re well ahead of any Western country. This is what we should expect from a country with a larger population than all Western civilization combined. Efficiencies of scale are no joke.

If you combine industrial scale with high-tech expertise, what more do you need? The best technology and the largest numbers = ultimate power. I&#39;ve argued in the past that we should have put more effort into [suppressing China](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/ln1sv9/maginot_syndrome_bullish_for_han_hegemony/) back when they were weak. We wasted nearly 30 years after Tienanmen square, after the point where it should have been clear that they weren&#39;t just going to capitulate like the Russians. Let&#39;s not forget the 1996 3rd Taiwan straits crisis. If that&#39;s not hostility, what is?

Up until the mid 2000s the US could have obliterated the Chinese nuclear arsenal in a disarming strike. See pages 295-6 of the [Rand report](https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR392.html): they show that Chinese ICBMs were immensely vulnerable. China&#39;s single abysmally noisy and crappy ballistic missile sub would surely get sunk before travelling halfway across the Pacific to retaliate against the US. The US could have dictated terms to China about Taiwan, they could have enforced a blockade with ease. This is no longer the case, the US doesn&#39;t have escalation dominance up to strategic nuclear war. China&#39;s conventional capabilities are immensely stronger than they were, just look at all the green bars going to yellow and orange on the RAND graph. That is what getting weaker looks like.

We are doing something seriously wrong. IBM and Intel used to lead in semiconductor development. [US hypersonics have stagnated](https://www.science.org/content/article/national-pride-stake-russia-china-united-states-race-build-hypersonic-weapons) and now fallen behind China and Russia. They&#39;ve deployed weapons, US tests don&#39;t even [work](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/06/30/politics/us-hypersonic-missile-test-fails/index.html). I believe there is some [malaise](https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/china-acquiring-new-weapons-five-times-faster-than-u-s-warns-top-official) in our cultures that leads us to just take things less seriously than China does:

&amp;gt;“In purchasing power parity, they spend about one dollar to our 20 dollars to get to the same capability,” he told his audience. “We are going to lose if we can’t figure out how to drop the cost and increase the speed in our defense supply chains,” Holt added.

The same sort of effect applies to civilian products - there is surely a reason US semiconductor production died, why California&#39;s HSR takes so long and costs so much. If we&#39;re outnumbered, we need to work harder or work smarter. It doesn&#39;t look like we&#39;re doing either, just coasting on old advantages.

While many say that China doesn&#39;t have global ambitions, they have cultivated border disputes with most of their neighbors. They have an ideological goal in establishing their system as the moral/normative peer of liberal democracy. They also have the world&#39;s biggest trading economy - they naturally have global interests in resources and securing markets. One Belt One Road was an attempt to realign the world economy to favor China. And they&#39;ll get drawn into various conflicts just because they&#39;re so big. Power is seductive and addictive, as the US has discovered. There&#39;s also a lot of nationalism swirling around, a substitute for traditional Maoism/Marxism which they don&#39;t even practice. There&#39;s immense popular resentment with the US over bombing their embassy in Serbia, various aerial incidents, rhetorical support for Hong Kong, military support for Taiwan...

I judge that China has more potential for global intervention than the once-isolationist US back at the start of the 20th century. They have a similarly large industrial base, more need for overseas resources, are closer to Eurasia, are more nationalistic and much more bitter. The story of the 20th century was the US leaving its corner and dominating the world. The story of the 21st may be China doing the same.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4w2le/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>