<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/alphanumericsprawl - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T08:21:11Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/alphanumericsprawl" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:21:11Z</updated><author><name>alphanumericsprawl</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Nuclear weapons are a panacea that would bring us close to world peace were it not for the US**

Every so often, people bring up the fact that Taiwan&#39;s military spending is moribund, somewhere below 2% of GDP (China is at a similar level). The US is around 4%. They call for Taiwan to [get serious](https://international.thenewslens.com/article/123554) with its training and spend more on their own defence. It does not seem fair for the US to spend proportionately more for another countries security...

However, there is only so much that Taiwan can do when outnumbered 20:1 in GDP. Taiwan is totally dependent upon foreign fuel and foreign food. The island produces around 10% of their food, China around 65%. There is only one way Taiwan could hope to deter the vastly larger Chinese military: nuclear weapons. The US [shut down](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan_and_weapons_of_mass_destruction) the Taiwanese nuclear program twice. Now, the US has forward-based nuclear weapons to Taiwan in the past but it is unlikely to do so today, given that China now has the power to hit the US mainland. 

If Taiwan had nuclear weapons, there would be no potential crisis. China would not invade a country with a credible nuclear deterrent. The US enabled this looming disaster by suppressing Taiwan&#39;s nuclear ambitions and giving them vague, indefinite not-promises instead.

Since Pakistan and India acquired nuclear weapons, they had only one small skirmish when in the past they would wage full-scale wars. Naturally, the US [sanctioned and harassed](https://www.eetimes.com/u-s-lifts-sanctions-against-india-pakistan/) them for taking this step towards peace. 

There have been no full-scale great power conflicts since WW2, a 70-year historical anomaly. Nuclear weapons make it unprofitable to wage war, so states don&#39;t do it.

If my country, Australia, had nuclear weapons, we wouldn&#39;t need to fight in expensive, pointless US wars since we wouldn&#39;t need their nuclear umbrella or assistance. We would have genuine strategic independence, we could relax and enjoy mining rent.

Now, one counterargument to my nuclear panacea argument is the tail-risk of nuclear war. If the US weren&#39;t so irresponsible, there would have been a much lower chance of nuclear war during the Cold War. It was the US&#39;s decision to invent the Cuban Missile Crisis, violently objecting to internal defense decisions made by the Soviets and Cubans. There are obvious similarities with the current Ukraine war and there is the mitigating factor that Cuba was in the US sphere while Ukraine is/was/contested in the Russian sphere. I don&#39;t particularly want to get bogged down in the movement of spheres of influence though. The way the US handled the crisis was extraordinarily aggressive. The US imposed a &#39;quarantine&#39; of Cuba, an effective blockade. They flew [U-2 spy planes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuban_Missile_Crisis#Crisis_continues) over Cuban airspace and had the temerity to complain when one was shot down! They dropped dummy depth charges on Soviet submarines to force them to surface, pointlessly causing the drama that legendary Arkhipov had to resolve. The US took various steps to raise tensions, dispersing its bombers around civilian airports and keeping some constantly in the air. They made it look as though they were preparing for nuclear war.

The 1983 nuclear scare is also the US&#39;s fault. Why were they launching [psychological operations](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Able_Archer_83#Psychological_operations) and exercises right next to Kamchatka if not to spook the Soviets? Raising tensions in this way is deeply irresponsible, it erodes the commons of mutually assured destruction to eke out small-scale gains in analyzing Soviet military readiness, observing radar patterns etc... It&#39;s needlessly provocative to mock-punch somebody but pull your fist away at the last moment. SDI was similarly bad - if you don&#39;t want a nuclear war, don&#39;t invite a pre-emptive strike by creating a strategic defense system! Of course, the US is still doing it, they left the ABM treaty and have been building up a large missile defense apparatus via AEGIS and GMD.

While North Korean leadership is regularly labelled as insane, they have not invaded anybody since the 1950s. Iran hasn&#39;t invaded anyone either, though they do wage proxy war (an activity not unknown by the US). On what basis can we argue that they would be irresponsible nuclear powers? Occasional political rhetoric calling for the destruction of Israel should not come before the logic of MAD, which has a far stronger empirical and historical basis. The Israelis have their fare share of [religious terrorists](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_religious_terrorism), yet they have remained responsible with their arsenal. 

Obviously, it&#39;s advantageous for the US (and other nuclear powers to a lesser extent) to sanction and bully other states into refraining from nuclearizing. The more states that have nuclear weapons, the less powerful they become. If Iraq or Libya had nukes, the US couldn&#39;t have attacked them. The US of course has the strongest global power projection capacity and thus the most to lose from massive nuclearization. It isn&#39;t surprising that the US is the most eager to suppress nuclear weapons. 

But I think this is important to consider when we discuss the looming risk of war, of geopolitical conflict generally. The assumption of nuclear risk in my view is excessively high and confuses nuclear risks with US risks. If Ukraine had nuclear weapons, there would be no problem today. What is far more destabilizing are airy promises of unspecified support for countries far away from their nuclear patron. Taiwan is only the most obvious example.

If the non-proliferation treaty didn&#39;t exist, the world would be a much better place and there would be fewer wars.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilapfpy/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>