<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/AlternativeEvent2584 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-02T06:52:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/AlternativeEvent2584" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iim3mt2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] America and Mexico have begun tø merge into one state. Austin is very white. I l</title><updated>2022-08-02T06:52:29Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">America and Mexico have begun tø merge into one state. Austin is very white. I live in Austin, and I spent a week in San Antonio. If you go there, it is Tejano culture 101. If you go there, it&#39;s 70% Mexicans or second gen Mexicans or rich white germans in the suburbs. Essentially everyone there is Mexican. I looked it up and it&#39;s 70% Hispanic, but if you go there it&#39;s 100% Tejano. The nicest hotels are French/Spanish/Mexican and incredibly beautiful. It is literally my favorite city outside of NYC and Chicago.

The great thing about San Antonio is it is essentially a foreign city in America. You will probably hear more Spanish than English there. It&#39;s basically a Mexican city in America.

It&#39;s probably the best argument against HBD because it is actually much cleaner than Austin and way better of a place to party.

But let us circle back. Everyone I know wants to move to Mexico. Mexico, Puerto Vallarta, etc. I know many people whop have moved there.

 When I was growing up, Mexico was considered a shit hole. I actually went to Mazatlan once and it was disgusting. It has now been gentrified and apparently Americans love living there.

Then we have Mexico City, which has become the new Brooklyn. Apparently it has an amazing art scene. Everyone I have talked to says Mexico city is the new Paris with tons of artists.

How will the world work when cities like Mexico City become full of rich Europeans and Americans? When Texas (which is absurdly wealthy) starts to blend with Mexico what is next? And if we are being honest, Mexicans are Catholic vs the Protestans in Texas?

What is next? It feels obvious. Mexico and America integrate further with Americans reversing the trend and moving to Mexico. And unlike Europe with Muslims, it&#39;s a bunch of people with similar culture.

It feels to me like Mexico will converge and be more like Canada in the future. In 50 years, Mexico will be like Canada and just another wealthy country on our border.

Am I crazy for thinking this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iim3mt2/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>