<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/AlternativeEvent2584 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T02:31:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/AlternativeEvent2584" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgw9wl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] What do you think the effect of zero code automation will have on employment in </title><updated>2022-08-16T02:31:29Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">What do you think the effect of zero code automation will have on employment in the future? I&#39;m talking about companies like Appian (who someone I know from my CS program works at) or Microsoft&#39;s power platform. I&#39;m more familiar with the latter, but from playing around with it, it seems like it will allow non-coders to essentially automate everything themselves. For example, at my own job we&#39;re doing a little trial where we&#39;re basically trying out one of our departments automating away the need for temps. This MS Power Platform can create GUIs, connect to SQL databases, write to SharePoint, work with APIs, and many other things. So the goal is to essentially have this department automate this and see if we can get it all working. 

If we can, then temps will essentially be gone. And this is only going to get better as time goes on. Furthermore, it will eliminate the need for a bunch of our sys admins because we&#39;re currently moving everything to Azure/365 so they will have nothing to manage.

If zero code works, this might invert the current view of everything being eliminated by coders and instead subject matter experts in accounting or whatever will do the automating themselves even though they can&#39;t code. The top level coders at places like Microsoft will automate away the need for low level coders and sys admins and then they will just collect on those Power Platform E5 licenses. 

I&#39;m new to this as of a few weeks ago so I could be completely off here. Just curious if anyone else has experience with this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgw9wl/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>