<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/AlternativeEvent2584 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-22T04:44:56Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/AlternativeEvent2584" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5eokf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I want to post something I have thinking about for a while. Just a few caveats, </title><updated>2022-07-22T04:44:56Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I want to post something I have thinking about for a while. Just a few caveats, this is not a ban evasion. I used to post at the SSC forum but got bored with the culture war and deleted my old account. I only created this account because I wanted to post stuff to the Black Company subreddit (shout out to u/mcjunker) on a reread and I&#39;m now sucked back into this shitty site.

That being said, I have a theory about what makes people successful in today&#39;s economy. And slight background on myself: I have a CS degree from a top 50 school but at this point in my career I&#39;m just a glorified sys admin. I&#39;d probably bomb a FAANG interview but I feel like I could get that job if I did leet code for a few months.

Now to my theory. People in my life that are non-technical always ask me how I know so much stuff. To them I&#39;m an expert in everything, especially at my work. I have my hands in pretty much everything at work that&#39;s important in IT so I interact with these people all the time. Plus I&#39;m not rude to non-technical people like most STEM lords are so people always go to me because I&#39;m not going to be rude to them for not knowing something.

I&#39;m not a brilliant person and nothing I do is impressive. BUT my one skill that I have is that I&#39;ll just go learn something if I don&#39;t know it. If for example security buys a new messaging gateway, I&#39;ll just look through their documentation and learn all the ways we can automate stuff. When we buy new software, I&#39;ll just go look at their documentation and play around with it until I get what I want. I recently had to learn C# for a new product we bought, and mostly what I did was just play around wit their API and ask people on SO if I ran into any issues. I was just as confused as they were, but I actually just followed through and just messed with it until I got it working.

To contrast this, my mom has a PhD and is briliant but she just gives up on anything technical after 5 minutes. I contrast this with a woman I work with who is a high level engineer. In the 90&#39;s she got annoyed that she couldn&#39;t get certain data as an accountant and taught herself programming just to solve issues then became a software engineer and is now a millionaire and a director of software engineering at our company. She just was persistent in learning things until she got what she wanted. 

Essentially, the &#34;skill&#34; is how long you&#39;ll persist if the issue is difficult. It&#39;s why people drop out of engineering programs because they have trouble with integrals. Another example I&#39;ll give is a woman I worked with who was having issue with SharePoint. She opened a ticket with us and insisted she be on any emails with Microsoft. She ended up becoming an expert in SharePoint for our company and got the certs and now doubled her salary working as a SharePoint admin for a credit card company. She used me as a reference.

So my point is that intelligence isn&#39;t necessarily that important for an IT or programming career. What you need is to be comfortable being uncomfortable not knowing things and just learning it. Looking at documentation and just playing around with it until you know it. That&#39;s the only reason people at my work think I&#39;m smart is because I&#39;ll just play around with stuff until I get it. I&#39;ll just make an appointment to meet the team that we are able to learn from with their company. That&#39;s it. I&#39;m not some super smart guy. I just have the persistence and ability to not know something and not be embarrassed for not knowing it.

Has anyone else noticed this and used it for their career? People think I&#39;m really smart and it&#39;s not the case. I just go out of my way to learn things. Maybe it&#39;s because I have a CS degree so I learned how to learn, but it feels like most people&#39;s problems with tech is that they just give up quickly. Everything is online if you want to learn it. And how to we instill this in people? It seems to just be a personality trait. As I mentioned before, my colleague became a SharePoint expert on her spare time when she was an accountant and became I high level admin from self taught stuff. This isn&#39;t rocket science, you just need to be persistent and just take the time to learn it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5eokf/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>