<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/AlternativeEvent2584 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-01T06:00:20Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/AlternativeEvent2584" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the </title><updated>2022-09-01T06:00:20Z</updated><author><name>AlternativeEvent2584</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">If we had the technology to actually change genders where you couldn&#39;t tell the difference between a woman/man born the wrong gender and an actual person born of that gender would you support it?

I think it would change my mind. I personally don&#39;t have a problem with the idea of people being transgender. My biggest problem with it is I think we don&#39;t have the technology to actually do what is being promised and the surgery/transitioning is cruel to vulnerable people. All you have to do is go on /b or /pol to see the results to see that this is not a settled scientific process. I know it sounds gross, but seeing the results of these surgeries just makes me sick to my stomach. And then you have the child side where kids who aren&#39;t even fully developed emotionally/physically getting life changing surgery that can&#39;t be reversed. This is what bothers me the most.

I truly think we will look back on this time the same as we do with lobotomies. It feels like we are doing experimental surgery on vulnerable people who would be better off staying their assigned gender. That&#39;s my argument against this current (what I consider) madness.

I feel that most people agree with me here. However, if transitioning was actually possible, would you change your mind? To me, it makes the debate over. If you can safely and effectively transition people, what is the downside?

Edit: On the 4chan part, I was being glib there. The point I was trying to make is that we only see bad results. With how aggressive the trans lobby is, if they were actually the same in how they looked, people would be saying look it&#39;s indistinguishable. That fact that we don&#39;t see this shows they know it looks unnatural and would be off-putting to most people if they actually saw the results. I’ve never seen a trans person pass irl. If they can’t make a person pass, there’s no way they can make a passing sex organ. The only people I&#39;ve seen pass (and only online) are people who didn&#39;t go through puberty as the opposite sex. But that would basically mean we&#39;d have to transition children, which I am pretty skeptical of.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/immjz1o/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>