<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/April16-1457BC - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-07T03:33:02Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/April16-1457BC" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij9ovht/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The Senate passed the [Inflation Reduction Act today](https://www.cbsnews.com/ne</title><updated>2022-08-07T03:33:02Z</updated><author><name>April16-1457BC</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The Senate passed the [Inflation Reduction Act today](https://www.cbsnews.com/news/divided-senate-votes-to-begin-debate-inflation-reduction-act/).  It has [three main funding](https://www.democrats.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/inflation_reduction_act_one_page_summary.pdf) mechanisms, a minimum corporate tax ($313B), IRS tax enforcement ($124B), and negotiating drugs prices ($288B).  The negotiation is perhaps better described as setting drug prices as companies can be fined up to 95% of the revenue unless they agree.  This negotiation is supposed to raise $288B from the big drug companies, as it plans to set the prices for  20 drugs like Eliquis (which I have taken, strangely), Revlimid, Xarelto, Keytruda, Eylea, Trulicity, Imbruvica, etc. and perhaps more later. Some of these may also appear as extras in the Rings of Power. These drugs each bring in between $10B and $3B a year, and basically, the bill demands discounts of 25%, then 35%, then 60%. $100B comes from these price reductions, $100B from limiting price increases to inflation and $122N from repealing a Trump-Era Drug Rebate Rule (something about not allowing rebates to pharmacies to add drugs to their formularies) according to the [CBO](https://www.crfb.org/blogs/cbo-estimates-drug-savings-reconciliation).

The congressional budget office says that this will not reduce new drugs much, claiming that of the 1300 new drugs that will be invented, this will only stop 15.  

However, big Pharma is not that big, and taking $288B from these companies over the next 10 years should be a pretty big hit to their stock.  Their stocks have not moved much.  The big players, BMY, JNU, GSK, MRK, REGN, AMGN, Roche, and LLY are down single digits in the last month, but this seems more like they are tracking the market than they suddenly dropped when news of this bill broke. 

The companies are worth about $1.5T in total, so this is taking 1/5th of their value away.  The market sees to doubt this is going to happen, which is weird. 

Suppose that the bill does actually manage to reduce costs by $300B.  This will reduce the top line of these companies by that much, and they will cut back because that is how companies work.  There are the usual complaints that these companies spend tens of billions on marketing, but presumably, they spend that because it creates positive cash flow.  They can&#39;t cut that spending without losing more revenue than they spend on marketing.  The cuts have to come from something that can be cut without reducing revenue, and that pretty much means R&amp;amp;D or profits.  

Perhaps drug companies do spend too much on developing new drugs, and perhaps we push them to develop the wrong ones, but it seems strange to be to single out drug companies as the one sector of the medical industry (and actually the one sector across the entire economy) that is doing something wrong, especially as we have just emerged from a worldwide pandemic where we were saved by the drug companies.

Big Pharma is who supplied the vaccines (and paxlovid etc.), and they got it done, especially when compared to the rest of the medical industry, which did not cover themselves in glory, especially in the beginning.  I would have thought they would be considered the heroes, not the next in line for the chopping block.

There are arguments that the mRNA vaccines were not created by big Pharma, but by smaller companies that then sold the technology to big Pharma.  This is true but misses the point that the money that the little companies get comes from the big ones.  Reducing the income of the big companies will directly reduce the income of the smaller ones, as the smaller ones get all their money from the big ones.  If you give the shopkeeper less money for milk, this flows back to the farmer getting less for milk, and the cow getting less hay.

It is possible that the bill is so cleverly crafted that it does not reduce the return to future R&amp;amp;D and only reduces the value of these companies current assets, so there is no disincentive, just a one-time expropriation of money from big Pharma, which has no bad consequences, save to the stockholders.  I suppose this is technically possible with a different bill, but it still raises the question of why these investors should be singled out.

So, I am confused by three things:  Why didn&#39;t the stock prices of these companies fall?  Why are the heroes of the pandemic the ones to take the fall?  Why should investors in pharma companies be penalized, as opposed to, say, tech companies, crypto, or big oil, etc?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij9ovht/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>