<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Arminio90 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T12:30:09Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Arminio90" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imse9ru/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A small observation based on the activities of the LOTRonPrime subreddit, that I</title><updated>2022-09-02T12:30:09Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A small observation based on the activities of the LOTRonPrime subreddit, that I followed from the beginning. regarding mood-switching after certain events.

This strange phenomena occured again, after seeing it on subreddit dedicated to Star Wars and Game of Thrones;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\- New product reveal itself, everyone agrees that looks terrible, that it is against the spirit of the original product, it is too woke etc.

\- After some days all big media begin to blast how there have been racist menaces, death threats, accusation or whatever against the show, especially black actors or women.

\- The moderation on the subreddit begin to use power to limit comments and users, blasting how bigotry is not allowed.

\- The overral mood on the subreddit change from negativity to neutrality or positivity. There are still criticism around, but is still limited. 

\- Dissenters from these subreddit go to new subreddit dedicated to criticism, creating the &#34;Witch Covens&#34; we know so well, that became the ideological target of the users of the main subreddits (&#34;See, the nazi exiled themselves! They were nazi all the time, not fans!&#34;)

\- The product ships, it is (usually) terrible, there are review bombing around and new attack from media against the criticizers. 

\- In the wake of the new product, the users of the subreddit are very very supportive of it, attacking everyone as an incel, a nazi, a traitor or a combination or both (it is always about politics or sex!), go check the LOTRonprime sub if you do not believe it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Afteer seeing this happen many times, I am beginning to think that adoption of woke policies and terminologies by entertainment corporations are less of an ideological capture and more of a cynical plot to defend their products from every kind of criticism.

I do not know how it is possible that the mood switch from negativity to positivity after the first media tornado (the purges are effective? The users follow the stream? They attract people that are here only to &#34;own the nazi?&#34; No idea)

But I know that they are very effective, basically controlling the discourse on a social influencial like reddit without any difficulties. Besides, it is not a surprise that there are discourses and discussion around on how the public vote on sites like Rottentomatoes and similars should be forbidden because it is an hotbed of political extremism. Because this position has been told by the same users on the same subreddits.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

What do you think?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imse9ru/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>