<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Arminio90 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-10T12:56:16Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Arminio90" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijpo106/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Italian election coming the 25th of september after the collapse of the technica</title><updated>2022-08-10T12:56:16Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Italian election coming the 25th of september after the collapse of the technical government lead by Draghi , and the electoral campaign is in full swing and fun as always.

The &#34;left-center&#34; anti-right alliance collapsed after 5 days when the leader of Azione (3% party, center-leftish pro-Draghi) left it when the PD (main center-left party) decided to include inside the Sinistra Italiana and the Greens (3% together) in the grand-coalition. 

Azione was also part of another small coalition with the Soros-funded Più Europa party (2%), alliance that collapsed with accusation of betrayal launched against each other. 

- the left accuse Calenda of being a liberal centrist always allied with fascism
- the center left and Più Europa, apart from the fascist libel, are also desperate because Azione was a party liked by a certain kind of leftish intellighenzia more near to the ex-Premier Draghi
- Calenda attacked everyone, saying that Pd and Più Europa did not respected the pact of forming a &#34;Pro-Draghi coalition&#34;, preferring the leftist parties

In general, the grand coalition is not working. The small left is candidating africans and gays, while the center left candidates neoliberal economists and feminists, while everyone complains that, if they are not going to sustain each other, the right &#34;will win&#34; 

The right has also internal problems (Especially with Berlusconi&#39;s Forza Italia, 7%, that lost a big chunk of the leadership to Azione after the fall of Draghi&#39;s government), but they appear more united and less catty. 

Medias are pumping stories daily on black people being beaten or discriminated or gay people, but the survey say that the right coalition can win more than 2/3 of the parlamentarians both in the chamber or in the Senate. 

While the right post cringe boomer memes as their method of propaganda, the other side is going hard on the &#34;vote us or Orban (!!!) wins&#34; 

It is not working.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijpo106/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>