<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Arminio90 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T08:13:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Arminio90" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifyt7j4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Small culture war snippet:


Kemi Badenoch began her race as leader of the Conse</title><updated>2022-07-13T08:13:50Z</updated><author><name>Arminio90</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Small culture war snippet:


Kemi Badenoch began her race as leader of the Conservatives, and the news is that, during her first public event, her staff put &#34;males&#34; and &#34;girls&#34; on the gender neutral bathroom of the event&#39;s building. 
Hence, polemics

I am always surprised by the rhetoric used in these cases, because the main defence from the progressives left is &#34;why we should care about this when we have the economy to care about?&#34;

Mind you, this tactic of &#34;but the economy?&#34; is probably the most used ever by every political side in history, but my point is another:
Is difficult to conserve your face if, suddenly, gender affirmation and the cultural war on it become a very trivial and stupid debate to do if the right do it, while at the same time is a topic that save literally lives if it is not done


How it is possible? The cultural war about gender is one of the main engines of the left today, but suddenly is trivial if the enemy does the same and debate on it? We are supposed to believe that, at the same time, is a stupid issue to die on but it literally save thousands of lives?
Nobody saw the contradiction?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifyt7j4/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>