<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Atersed - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-06T16:38:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Atersed.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/</id><title type="text">[WW] Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says tha</title><updated>2022-07-06T16:38:45Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww.html" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Has anyone managed to reverse their myopia? 

&amp;gt;This is a method that says that some specific poor vision habits plus slightly-too-powerful glasses induce myopia, and that some other specific good vision habits plus different glasses can reverse it.

&amp;gt; In various corners of the internet there is an overwhelming abundance of anecdotal claims from people who aren&#39;t sockpuppets (I checked) that the model&#39;s interventions are effective. This is what led me to try it. A lot of the information here is based on a synthesis of the perspectives provided by people in various communities attempting this process.

https://www.losetheglasses.org/

The key idea seems to be not to over-correct your vision for your current task. If you are looking at a computer for 8 hours a day, do not wear your full strength distance glasses, but a weaker pair that are just strong enough to see the screen.

This sounds plausible and fairly cheap to try.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3dicu/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/iegzixt/</id><title type="text">[FF] Chain-of-thought prompting not only improves the reasoning ability of language m</title><updated>2022-07-01T16:47:06Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff.html" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Chain-of-thought prompting not only improves the reasoning ability of language models, but also of 4 year olds:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gnArvcWaH6I

I&#39;m only talking about the first 50 seconds, but the whole thing is adorable.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/iegzixt/"/></entry></feed>