<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Atersed - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T22:23:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Atersed" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommend</title><updated>2022-08-26T22:23:35Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">This week I learned that the original *The Sims* game manual came with recommended reading. https://archive.org/details/The_Sims/page/n43/mode/2up

Reproduced in full: 

&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED READING
&amp;gt; Here are some titles that might enhance your understanding of some of the background and sociai issues entertained in The Sims.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Warning: all are filled with provocative ideas; Maxis disavows any responsibility for encouraging deep thought.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Home: A Short History of an Idea by Witoid Rybczynski (Juiy 1 987), Penguin USA; ISBN: 0140102310
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Notes on the Synthesis of Form by Christopher W. Alexander (June 1970), Harvard University Press; ISBN: 0674627512
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - A Pattern Language : Towns, Buildings, Construction by Christopher Alexander, Sara Ishikawa, Murray Silverstein (1977), Oxford University Press (Trade); iSBN: 0195019199
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Architecture : Form, Space, &amp;amp; Order by Frank D. K. Ching, Francis D. Ching (February 1996), John Wiiey &amp;amp; Sons; ISBN: 0471286168
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Housing by Lifestyle : The Component Method of Residential Design by James W. Wentling (November 1994) McGraw-Hill; ISBN: 0070692939
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Time for Life : The Surprising Ways Americans Use Their Time by John P Robinson, Geoffrey Godbey (Contributor), Robert Putnam (June 1997)Pennsylvania State University Press (Trade); ISBN: 0271016523
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Maps of the Mind by C. Hampden-Turner (March 1982), MacMillan Publishing Company; ISBN: 0025477404
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Hidden Order: The Economics of Everyday Life by David D. Friedman (September 1997), HarperCollins; ISBN: 0887308856
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Making the Most of Your Llama by Linda C. Beattie (Editor), Araneen Witmer (Illustrator), Kathyrn Doll (Editor), Dr. Linda Beattie (September 1998), Kopacetic Ink; ISBN: 0961963417 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - Finding Your Perfect Love by Arthur Clark, Cassandra Skouras (January 1998), Rosebud Press; ISBN: 0965276902
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; - The User Illusion : Cutting Consciousness Down to Size by Tor Norretranders, Jonathan Sydenham (Translator) (April 1998), Viking Press; ISBN: 0670875791

----

In other news, Will Macaskill worked as a stripper? 

https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/08/15/the-reluctant-prophet-of-effective-altruism

&amp;gt; In graduate school, “I started giving three per cent, and then five per cent, of my income,” he said. This wasn’t much—he was then living on a university stipend. “I think it’s O.K. to tell you this: I supplemented my income with nude modelling for life-drawing classes.” The postures left him free to philosophize. Later, he moved on to bachelorette parties, where he could make twice the money “for way easier poses.”

----

And finally, after playing with Stable Diffusion, I am blown away. A wholly original work of art created inside a minute. Yes, it is hit or miss, but it is amazing that it can hit at all. 

You are probably already saturated with AI art, but [here are a few of my favourites](https://imgur.com/a/lti20Ia). Perhaps you can tell something about a person from the kind of art they generate. Feel free to share your creations.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilxgm3j/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7repi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Where are all the East Asian CEOs? Inspired by [this list of Indian CEOs.](https</title><updated>2022-08-21T17:22:24Z</updated><author><name>Atersed</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Where are all the East Asian CEOs? Inspired by [this list of Indian CEOs.](https://nitter.net/nihalmehta/status/1509512345134972935)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il7repi/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>