<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Athanasius_19 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T11:48:56Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Athanasius_19" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female</title><updated>2022-08-01T11:48:56Z</updated><author><name>Athanasius_19</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Just recently learned about the 30x30 initiative, [which aims to increase female representation among police officers to 30%](https://30x30initiative.org/about-30x30/)

&amp;gt; The 30×30 Initiative is based on the importance of achieving at least 30% representation to empower a group to influence an organization’s culture. This 30% threshold is where change begins to happen, but it is not our end goal. 30×30 is working with policing agencies to improve recruiting practices and establish community partnerships so that agencies become truly representative of the jurisdictions they serve. While 30×30 is focused on advancing women in policing, these principles are applicable to all demographic diversity, not just gender.

The website claims that women are better suited for police work, since &#34;women officers use less force and less excessive force; are named in fewer complaints and lawsuits; are perceived by communities as being more honest and compassionate; see better outcomes for crime victims, especially in sexual assault cases; and make fewer discretionary arrests.&#34;

They cite intersectionality as a cornerstone of the project, and several big police departments are listed as participating in this initiative. There are a few companies and activist groups backing it, including Microsoft. There&#39;s also a &#34;steering committee&#34; with a bunch of names I don&#39;t recognize, and would&#39;ve skipped over until I noticed that all of them are women.

Thoughts on how this would affect police relations and effectiveness? My prediction is that police work will slightly improve in safer communities, but that in more dangerous areas there will be a negative effect towards more crime, since crime rates aren&#39;t something the page mentions outright.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iihvt0j/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>