<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Atherzon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-01T21:19:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Atherzon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an </title><updated>2022-09-01T21:19:24Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just listened to an episode of the Freakonomics podcast with Roland Fryer, an economist from Harvard, that studies race, policing, and education.

He shares a lot of statistics that contradict popular narratives about the issues, but probably won’t surprise many frequenters of this sub.

For example,

He finds that when that POC (people of color, I think is the term he uses) are not killed by police more.

That black kids are doing worse in school and advocates closing bad schools. 

The pay gap isn’t really 33% or whatever, but it is closer to 9%, and there are concrete things that he can point to that cause the pay gap that aren’t discrimination (in one example it is a difference in overtime worked due to when shifts were scheduled). 

Basically, he is using data to analyze a lot of culture war adjacent topics and looking for actual reasons for discrepancies in outcomes rather than just pointing to discrimination because he really wants to improve the lives of people.

Sorry for the short initial post, but I like to watch.  I’m a free riding, lurker because posting takes so much energy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/impovm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imj4q5z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] For those not following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine closely, Ukraine has been p</title><updated>2022-08-31T15:11:58Z</updated><author><name>Atherzon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">For those not following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine closely, Ukraine has been projecting a counter offensive in the Kherson region for two months, and they initiated it two days ago.

It is still very early and the Fog of War is thick, but I think we are about a week until we will have a good idea of how the counter offensive is (or was) going and that will tell us a lot about the future of the conflict.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imj4q5z/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>