<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Beej67 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T14:31:11Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Beej67" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:31:11Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Tracking the Heat Level of the TERF  War](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/tracking-the-heat-level-of-the-terf)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[TERFs/trans issues\]

Article is in three parts.

(1) is a wall of snapshots from the &#34;trending topics&#34; bar on Twitter for the past two weeks, with dates, as well as a snapshot of Google Trends showing that (a) the war between the Trans Exclusionary Radical Feminists (TERFs) and the gender ideology wokes is getting extremely hot, and the burn rate keeps it pretty much squarely on Twitter nonstop, above Ukraine and guns and abortion. The Google Trends graphs show TERF &amp;gt; Intersectionality in interest solidly the past two months and has intermittent peaks well above it, landing the TERF wars in a position where they seem to be overtaking even the heat level of Whiteness related topics during Floyd.

(2) is a recap of the history of the TERF war that most people here can probably skip

(3) is analysis, wherein we attempt to explain why it&#39;s getting so hot, and make predictions about what&#39;s going to happen with it going forward into next year based on an analysis of motivations of either side. Key to the analysis is the presumption that personality traits are probably fairly fixed over time due to genetic factors, which means as religiosity has fallen over time, more people with the &#34;moral certainty and self righteous indignation&#34; traits have had to find another outlet, many of which fell into the Woke bucket. With a fixed (or growing) rate of these in the woke camp, they won&#39;t bend on trans ideology even in the face of all the new entrants to the TERF war driven by school board awakenings and JK Rowling acting as a rally point.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbqfeg/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-a</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:22:47Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Nuclear Power and Hot Air Balloons](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/nuclear-power-and-hot-air-balloons)

tags: \[self promotion\]\[pollution visualization math\]

Not sure this is totally culture war, except for the fact that nuclear power itself has been such a wretched target of environmentalist culture warriors that we haven&#39;t bothered to build any nuke plants in the USA in decades.

The article does the math to figure out how much power is generated by uranium and coal, and calculates an equivalent amount of pollutant for honest comparisons. Really pretty simple. Conclusion is that two nuclear fuel assemblies of uranium, each of which are about a half a meter long and ten centimeters wide, produce the same amount of energy as enough coal to fill up (with CO2) every hot air balloon at the  Albuquerque International Balloon Fiesta (largest hot air balloon festival in the world) almost 24 times over.

Then has some visual comparisons, so people can understand the scales in question.

I also reduced the article into image meme form:

https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/22543e64-aa06-47d3-8761-2207d8ee3e09\_5360x4320.png</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbp7ci/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>