<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Beej67 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T19:17:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Beej67" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikk4m00/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [87,000 Racists](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/87000-racists) 

tags: \[self promo</title><updated>2022-08-16T19:17:47Z</updated><author><name>Beej67</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[87,000 Racists](https://hwfo.substack.com/p/87000-racists) 

tags: \[self promotion\]\[meme analysis\]\[systemic racism\]\[tax enforcement policy\]

Inflammatory title I know, but that&#39;s how traffic works these days. I beg forgiveness on that.

The article basically analyzes the conservative claim on social media from last week that the 87,000 tax collectors in the Inflation Reduction Act would be used to attack poor people. While the maps seem to indicate that, and further seem more specifically to be targeting *non-white people*, the truth of the matter is more nuanced. The audits are disproportionately attacking folks who file the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC) due presumptively to some systemic flagging mechanism within the IRS. And since that&#39;s a measure specifically for poor people, their audits also predominantly hit poor people.

Part of this has to do with changes in staffing. They have more low grade &#34;tax examiners&#34; and fewer higher grade &#34;revenue agents,&#34; and the examiners are largely issuing &#34;correspondence audits&#34; which are simpler things which basically just demand more information. But since they&#39;re demanding them from poorer folks who may not have all the information or understand the cryptic language the correspondence audits are issued in, targeting them pumps the enforcement numbers up and makes the auditors look good.

So now if we set that on a shelf and examine one of the more popular definitions of &#34;systemic racism&#34; (Socioeconomic and government systems which produce differential racial outcomes) then it is apparent that the IRS&#39;s EITC flagging criteria are a result of a &#34;racist system&#34; because it fits the definition in use.

Whether this provision within the Inflation Reduction Act itself then qualifies as &#34;racist&#34; will in the end depend on whether the $80 billion earmark in the law includes a way to fix the racist system, or whether it will just be thrown at increasing operations as they currently exist, in which case the EITC audits will just increase.

Article has numerous charts, maps, and references.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikk4m00/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>