<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ben___Garrison - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-19T14:23:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ben___Garrison" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxroo7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] An [interesting article from Politico](https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/20</title><updated>2022-08-19T14:23:34Z</updated><author><name>Ben___Garrison</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">An [interesting article from Politico](https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2022/08/19/fallout-mar-a-lago-search-00052799) today on how the Mar-a-Lago search&#39;s real fallout has been another step towards widescale civil breakdown. 

&amp;gt;The political consequences of the FBI’s search of Mar-a-Lago, former president Donald Trump’s Florida residence, have been shrill but predictable. Most Democrats have welcomed it as gratification long delayed, Trump loyalists have condemned it as a “Deep State” abuse of power, and more measured Republicans have split the difference. Observers have also pointed to the danger of riling up Trump’s base and stoking his determination to retake the presidency.

There were attacks against the far right before, like the siege of Waco during the 90s, and right-wing counterattacks like the Oklahoma city bombing. But it mostly stopped there, as the Oklahoma bombing had a chilling effect that delegitimized political violence among the mainstream right. Soon enough, 9/11 turned the focus of domestic terrorism towards Muslims for much of the 2000s and 2010s, but as divisions are growing deeper between the right and left the specter of rightwing extremism is returning:

&amp;gt;For one, there’s the newfound legitimacy of domestic political violence. In the 1990s, the militia movement was merely percolating, committed to resisting government but not interested in taking the offensive or prepared to do so. Mainstream American liberals and conservatives both firmly considered domestic political violence unacceptable. Only conspicuous law-enforcement debacles could inspire even an extremist like McVeigh to lethal terrorist action against fellow Americans. Today, though, Blue and Red are arguably irreconcilable, and Trump has hauled the far right to the surface and enlisted it in his personal service. Some of his supporters are so convinced that his presidency was stolen from him that they apprehend the subdued, circumspect, non-violent execution of a search warrant on his residence as a casus belli, and authoritative and admired figures encourage them to do so.

&amp;gt;Steve Bannon labeled the FBI a “gestapo.” Georgia representative Marjorie Taylor Greene called for Congress to defund the FBI. Far-right pundits have proclaimed “This. Means. War.” and characterized the search as a “declaration of war.” Posts on far-right internet forums have been more violent than any since January 6. Last weekend, armed Trump supporters clad in body armor held a protest outside the FBI’s Phoenix office. Threats against federal law enforcement have spiked, intensifying a growing trend. Some extremists have “doxxed” FBI agents, publicizing their personal information to enable others to harass them or target them with violence. Such behavior seems intended to mobilize those of McVeigh’s ilk.

The growth of militias has further catalyzed this process. In the 90s militias were atomized, but with the advent of social media they&#39;ve been able to talk and coordinate with each other much more effectively. They&#39;ve stockpiled more weapons as well, with lax gun laws in red states. Departments like the ATF have responded in turn, buying up military-grade gear to turn previously routine operations into SWAT-style force protection. There&#39;s also concerns within the ATF and FBI that many agents are sympathetic to the plight of the far right, and there&#39;s anecdotal evidence that there were tensions within the FBI due to the Mar-a-Lago raid. Risks of a new civil war are overstated, as the geographic distribution of reds vs blues doesn&#39;t really lend itself to secession. However, risks of a Troubles-like insurgency are very real:

&amp;gt;Mature democracies have gone too far in the past. In 1969, the British government sent troops to Northern Ireland to quell growing community unrest over Catholic nationalist political and civil rights protests. The soldiers were initially welcomed as peacekeepers. But as grievances could not be immediately addressed and protests escalated, the British government resorted to more extreme measures, including direct armed confrontation, mass internment of those suspected of paramilitary activities, the statutory establishment of “scheduled offenses” for political violence, and the creation of dedicated, non-jury courts for trying those charged with them. The IRA exploited this too, orchestrating marches and demonstrations that would prompt the Royal Ulster Constabulary to break out the riot gear, which served to confirm their narrative of state oppression, generate sympathetic headlines and news spots, and win recruits to the armed struggle. Eventually, the public came to see IRA militants as soldiers in a civil war. By the mid-1970s, London understood that demilitarization and normalization would make the conflict more tractable, but by then the gouge was set: the Troubles would last 25 years, extend violence to the British mainland, and palsy Northern Irish society.

What does the motte think about preventing the coming civil breakdown?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxroo7/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>