<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/BenjaminHarvey - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-02T16:41:44Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/BenjaminHarvey" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxhjqq/</id><title type="text">[CW] [https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/14/protests-nigeria-arrests-blasphem</title><updated>2022-06-02T16:41:44Z</updated><author><name>BenjaminHarvey</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/14/protests-nigeria-arrests-blasphemy-killing-female-student-sokoto](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/14/protests-nigeria-arrests-blasphemy-killing-female-student-sokoto)

A young christian woman was lynched by muslim students at the college she went to, supposedly right before she was about to be taken into police protection. There are conflicting reports on what she was killed for, but it seems to be a social media post of some kind. In response, the Nigerian government has declared that the college she attended will be closed.

According to this article there are dozens of lawyers rushing to defend the men accused of murdering her.

[https://thenationonlineng.net/dozens-of-lawyers-to-the-defence-of-sokoto-killers/](https://thenationonlineng.net/dozens-of-lawyers-to-the-defence-of-sokoto-killers/)

Some public figures in the country are supporting the murder. I don&#39;t understand the governmental structure of Nigeria, but I think the Imam in the article below might hold an official government position in Nigeria and not just a religious one.

https://thenewsnigeria.com.ng/2022/05/22/the-apostate-grand-imam-maqari-must-be-removed-from-office-and-tried-soyinka/

Besides improving the competency of the police tasked with protecting potential victims of mob violence, what would you do if you were a high-ranking Nigerian politician to fix your society? The only solution I can think of is to give up on multiculturalism and divorce the country. Or let Nigerian christians have their own cities with borders that they control. Neither solution seems that great to me.

The standard progressive response is to try to educate people, but I am pessimistic about such techniques. Propaganda campaigns of that sort are useful but I think people over-estimate them. I could go into why but I don&#39;t feel like it right now. I think most of you probably agree with me that those sorts of solutions are not super powerful.

So I ask you: what would you do?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxhjqq/"/></entry></feed>