<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/bgaesop - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T10:09:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/bgaesop" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilkpsob/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **What are non-Trumpists supposed to do about The Lie?**

By The Lie I mean the </title><updated>2022-08-24T10:09:35Z</updated><author><name>bgaesop</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**What are non-Trumpists supposed to do about The Lie?**

By The Lie I mean the idea that the 2020 election was stolen. 

What are non-Trumpists supposed to do about the fact that the former President continues to push The Lie? Given that the idea that the election was stolen is both false and obviously false - which, let us be clear, both of those claims are clearly the case - what are those of us who can observe and accept reality supposed to do about the large portion of the population who can or will not? The ones who either have actually been fooled and genuinely believe The Lie, or else who are simply lying to themselves when they say they think that Trump genuinely won the election? 

From my perspective, there is not a good, democratic, peaceful resolution to this. Perhaps during the month or two following the election there was the (quite implausible) possibility that someone could genuinely believe the election actually was stolen, and we really could convince them with evidence. But at this point, it seems quite clear that the election was carried out well within the norms of how all elections in the USA are carried out. 

So what do we do about the people who continue to insist on maintaining The Lie? Given the failure of the soap box and the ballot box, at what point do we resort to other boxes? It seems quite plausible to me that anyone who continues to claim that the 2020 election was stolen is unlikely to accept the results of any other election going forward - once you reject one legitimate election, why not reject them all? And given the correlation between such and gun ownership, it seems very likely that such will result in violence, like it (attempted to) on Jan 6. What should the rest of us, who still desire for the democratic process to work and for the transfer of power to be as peaceful as possible, do about this?

I genuinely have no idea. All I know is &#34;oh don&#39;t worry, Republicans actually do believe in democratic values and care about the peaceful transfer of power&#34; has been demontrated to be a clear and obvious lie, and so we must not proceed as though it were true</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilkpsob/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>