<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/buttfaceszn - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-19T06:54:33Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/buttfaceszn" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igqxz7m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I’ve noticed that the term incel has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejo</title><updated>2022-07-19T06:54:33Z</updated><author><name>buttfaceszn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I’ve noticed that the term incel has begun to be used as more of a catchall pejorative for sexism of any kind (at least on the internet) which strikes me as odd. I don’t really like when people use the term incel as an insult to people who bring up redpill/PUA/manosphere-type things, since I suspect there’s a lot of non-incels who find these things interesting and I personally think some of it has value. But from the perspective of someone who is trying to insult a redpill/MRA type in a heated Reddit argument, it at least makes sense to call them an incel. Incels afaik do really tend to be into these ideas, and people who excessively harp on them can come across as resentful about their own personal struggles with women.  

What’s odd to me is when I’ve seen it used to describe people who make fun of the WNBA, or say that women shouldn’t be NFL coaches, or don’t like women comedians, or make banal observations about women being more sensitive or dramatic or whichever stereotype. The reason it’s odd is that in my experience, low-level sexism or observations/jokes about sex differences are extremely common, even more so among guys who are typically successful with women. I suspect I have a relatively more “normie” upbringing than the typical commenter here, I played sports like football and baseball in high school, went to a good but not elite large public university, was in a social fraternity, and have many uncles and cousins who are all blue-collar tradesmen types. I can’t think of anyone I am close with from sports, HS, college, family, etc. who has had any trouble with women, and definitely none who are redpill types or incels.  

My whole life, among men of all ages, races, incomes etc. it seems like it’s extremely common to be “casually sexist”. Making “women be shopping”-tier observations about gender differences, or saying women are more [insert stereotype] is very normal, and some more mean-spirited or harmful things like making fun of the WNBA, or saying women couldn’t be NFL coaches, or calling certain women “gold-diggers” wouldn’t be uncommon. It also seems common for my girlfriend or my mom and their friends to make similar observations about men, calling them clueless or lazy or unable to pick up on social cues or not knowing what to do with babies. It also seems these kinds of jokes or observations were popular in sitcoms and comedy movies in the past. It just seems odd to me that this kind of thing would come to be associated with “guys who can’t get laid”, especially since it seems like misogyny/sexism is also somewhat associated with the jock/frat bro stereotype. 

I’m not trying to argue whether any of this is good or true or sexist or not. It just always seemed like it was relatively common to me and mostly lighthearted. (I also don’t want to argue whether casual sexism is *harmful* I am just saying the things I am describing aren’t *intended* to be *hateful*).  

I guess my questions are: am I correct that this is normal or am I in a particularly sexist bubble? Was it normal in the past, but isn’t anymore? Or am I just overthinking this, and random people on the internet are just using incel to mean “vaguely sexist” without really caring about being accurate? I suspect it’s the last one and potentially a mix of the other two, but I do wonder if there is a genuine taboo-ing of even the most harmless kinds of gender-stereotype humor among younger generations. Or possibly: I am I just way off on where the line is between “casual/acceptable/normal” level sexism, and something like “making fun of the WNBA” is more in the “hateful towards women” category of sexism?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igqxz7m/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>