<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/buttfaceszn - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-29T18:50:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/buttfaceszn" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii5v75p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] TLDR: I think Deshaun Watson is innocent and is getting extorted by women who ar</title><updated>2022-07-29T18:50:27Z</updated><author><name>buttfaceszn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">TLDR: I think Deshaun Watson is innocent and is getting extorted by women who are essentially prostitutes but operate as masseuses

I am someone who is way too emotionally invested in sports, and Deshaun Watson has been my favorite player since he was in college. I am also very much against “believe all women”, or at least against the “bailey” of that statement which implies men are guilty until proven innocent. So I am overall extremely biased in favor of Watson here and perhaps this is all motivated reasoning. But I think his case is one of the best examples of the MeToo pendulum swinging too far.  

So Watson is(was) a young star at NFL quarterback, who prior to spring 2021 was known for being humble, kindhearted, and a strong leader of excellent character. Now those may be platitudes you hear about every athlete, but I think it’s fair to say that these traits were especially emphasized by coaches and commentators about Watson, given that he came from poverty and was raised by a single mother who was chronically ill with cancer for much of his life.  

Around February or March 2021, a story surfaced that Watson had been accused of sexually assaulting a massage therapist, and had refused to pay a low six-figure settlement before anything went public. His accuser enlisted the services of Texas mega/meme-lawyer Tony Buzbee (look him up), who immediately solicited other women who had been “sexually assaulted” by Watson while giving him a massage. Ultimately, there were something like 25 civil suits filed against him for sexual misconduct, most of which have been settled recently. One or two of the accusations allege forced oral sex, and the remainder allege some version of “he tried to rub his dick against my hand, he asked me to do X sexual act, he ejaculated while I was massaging him”. Additionally, 2 grand juries in Texas have declined to indict Watson on any criminal charges.  

The evidence presented by the accusers, at least what’s been seen by the public, is their testimony, and some Instagram messages or texts corroborating that Watson booked them for a massage. Almost all of these women are “unlicensed massage therapists” who operate via Instagram, many of whom were flown to Texas from out of state. Watson’s defense is that he did see these women for massages, had sexual contact with them, but that everything was consensual. He has also shown evidence that some of the accusers reached out to work with him again after the date of the alleged sexual assault, and that some of them bragged or spoke positively to friends about their appointments with him.  

“Only 1-10% of sexual assault cases are falsely reported. With 25 women accusing him, the chance that they are all false is infinitesimally small! And sexual assault is notoriously difficult to prove. The women who wanted to work with him again after being assaulted are just processing their trauma”. This is the argument you hear from NFL subreddit commenters, who from basically the very beginning have been thrilled to demonstrate how anti-sexual assault they are by condemning Watson as a serial rapist/assaulter/predator.  

Let’s take as a given that the stat about false accusations is true (I don’t think it is, and definitely not for rich/famous people). Well, the 25 women accusing him are not independent events- they all have the same lawyer and all but one or two came forward after the possibility of a six-figure settlement was put on the table. And sexual assault IS notoriously difficult to prove, but don’t the reasons that make it difficult to prove also make it impossible to DISprove? And to the argument about the women who worked with him after being assaulted just “processing their trauma in their own way”, I don’t even have a response because I can’t imagine being that charitable to anybody making evidence-free accusations.

So what do I think actually happened? Well it seems clear that Watson has some sort of fetish for sex with massage therapists. A little weird, but “happy ending” massage places are basically everywhere so not too out of the ordinary. “Unlicensed Massage Therapist who operates via Instagram” sounds a lot like “sex worker with a good cover story” to me. When those unlicensed massage therapists are getting flown from out of state to massage an NFL quarterback, I really have a hard time believing they didn’t know exactly what was happening.  

If you’re one of these “massage therapists” who has worked with Watson and you hear about this lawyer who is soliciting clients who have been assaulted by Watson: you know that you have evidence proving you met with Watson for a massage, you know that any discussion of paying for sex happened in person, you know that it will be impossible to disprove, you know that Watson will not use “I was actually just flying in prostitutes” as a defense, and you know there’s a very good chance of getting a six figure settlement for telling a story about how traumatized you were that Watson asked you to jack him off. Why wouldn’t you take that? 

To me, the most plausible scenario is that the first accuser was looking for hush money thinking Watson would just pay up, somehow Tony Buzbee caught wind of this and that Watson had hooked up with like 60 masseuses in the last year, and saw an opportunity for a big settlement and a whole lot of positive publicity. Every mainstream media source post-MeToo will reflexively support the accusers, Buzbee’s name will be all over the news, and you know if you just keep dragging this out you will get a settlement as Watson can’t waste his prime earning years unable to play football because of the 25 civil court cases. And Watson is now gonna be known as a serial rapist for the rest of his life when he’s really just horny for massages.  

Am I just doing mental gymnastics to defend my favorite athlete here? Or does my theory sound plausible?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii5v75p/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>