<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/buttfaceszn - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-14T03:25:07Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/buttfaceszn" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ig2zc7f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Forgive me if this is too low-effort and unsourced- but does anyone else think t</title><updated>2022-07-14T03:25:07Z</updated><author><name>buttfaceszn</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Forgive me if this is too low-effort and unsourced- but does anyone else think that CTE (Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy) is fake? Or at the very least unconfirmed and asserted as fact?  

I say this after a post in the NFL subreddit about a quote from Hall of Fame linebacker Brian Urlacher, where he says that retired players are falsely claiming CTE to get money from a lawsuit. Now Urlacher is wrong on a key point, in that the NFL’s settlement was paid out to all retired players and there is no pending lawsuit against the NFL. But many if not most of the comments on the post took issue with the fact that Urlacher says there are players falsely proclaiming they have CTE. The most discussed study about CTE, at least among low-information sources like Reddit, was an examination of the brains of 113 former NFL players, of which 112 apparently had CTE. Some people point out that the methodology was flawed, as the sample was sourced from families who suspected their deceased relative had CTE. But even with the sampling bias, it still seems wildly implausible to me.  

I did a very low effort examination of the research, as in I read the abstracts of a few papers about CTE on pubmed, and it does seem as if there is some skepticism among researchers about it. The reported symptoms are all over the place: brain fog, memory loss, depression, anxiety, su*cidal thoughts, erratic behavior, mood swings, difficulty thinking, etc. Now all of these symptoms sound unverifiable and difficult to link to CTE, they also seem like things that are particularly suggestible and prone to confirmation bias, as in if you are told you likely have CTE, it’d be very easy to report having had some of these symptoms even if they were unrelated. The more serious, or at least more easily observable symptoms are early onset dementia/Alzheimer’s, or at least something that seems similar and is similarly linked to a degenerative brain disease. But if 99% of NFL players have CTE, or even 50%, wouldn’t it be very obvious if they were suffering from early degenerative brain diseases at a higher rate than the population? Is there any evidence of this?  


Some of my skepticism also relates to the diagnostic criteria. I am completely unqualified to comment on any of this- but my understanding is that CTE is reportedly caused by an accumulation of tau protein tangles or bundles, and that these are also linked with other degenerative brain diseases. But AIUI, these also naturally occur to some extent in everybody as we age. So is there some threshold of the amount of tau protein that qualifies as CTE, or is it something that you can always find if you look for it? Is there a study comparing the prevalence of this in former athletes against a representative sample of non-athletes?   


As far as I can tell, almost none of the questions I posed have been studied or have a clear answer. Yet for years people have been claiming that they will never let their children play football, that football should be illegal, that every time a former player commits a crime or does something weird that it’s because of their CTE. But to me it seems at least unproven, and very well may not be an issue at all. The long list of vague symptoms seems to sound a lot like some psychosomatic illnesses, or things that could be caused by a number of other issues. Note, the current hypothesis about CTE is that it is caused by repeated, low impact collisions to the head, like from soccer players heading the ball or routine blocks and tackles in football. This is separate from the brain damage caused by repeated concussions, which I am not at all skeptical about. Wondering if anyone else has thought about this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ig2zc7f/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>