<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Caseiopa5 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-01T16:37:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Caseiopa5" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iasy9yh/</id><title type="text">[CW] Might as well discuss this NYT article:

https://www.nytimes.com/2022/06/01/tech</title><updated>2022-06-01T16:37:29Z</updated><author><name>Caseiopa5</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Might as well discuss this NYT article:

https://www.nytimes.com/2022/06/01/technology/fringe-mainstream-social-media.html

Discusses the Buffalo shooter, but the main thesis, and the part we&#39;ll focus on, has to do with the great replacement theory:

***

At the center of the shooting, like others before it, was a false conviction that an international Jewish conspiracy intends to supplant white voters with immigrants who will gradually take over political power in America.

The conspiracy, known as the “great replacement theory,” has roots reaching back at least to the czarist Russian antisemitic hoax called “The Protocols of the Elders of Zion,” which purported to be a Jewish plot to overtake Christianity in Europe.

It resurfaced more recently in the works of two French novelists, Jean Raspail and Renaud Camus, who, four decades apart, imagined waves of immigrants taking power in France. It was Mr. Camus, a socialist turned far-right populist, who popularized the term “le grand remplacement” in a novel by that name in 2011.

Mr. Gendron, according to the documents he posted, seemed to have read none of those; instead he attributed the “great replacement” notion to the online writings posted by the gunman who murdered 51 Muslims at two mosques in Christchurch, New Zealand, in 2019.

After that attack, New Zealand’s prime minister, Jacinda Ardern, spearheaded an international pact, called the Christchurch Call, that saw government and major tech companies commit to eliminate terrorist and extremist content online. Though the agreement carried no legal penalties, the Trump administration refused to sign, citing the principle of free speech.

Mr. Gendron’s experience online shows that the writings and video clips associated with the Christchurch shooting remain available to inspire other acts of racially motivated violence. He referred to both repeatedly.

The Anti-Defamation League warned last year that the “great replacement” had moved from the fringes of white supremacist beliefs toward the mainstream, pointing to the chants of protesters at the 2017 “Unite the Right” rally in Charlottesville, Va., that erupted in violence and the commentaries of Tucker Carlson on Fox News.

“Most of us don’t know the original story,” Mr. Ward of the Southern Poverty Law Center said. “What we know is the narrative, and the narrative of the great replacement theory has been credentialized by elected officials and personalities to such an extent that the origins of the story no longer need to be told. People are beginning to just understand it as if they might understand conventional wisdom. And that’s what is frightening.”

For all the efforts some major social media platforms have made to moderate content online, the algorithms they use — often meant to show users posts that they will read, watch and click — can accelerate the spread of disinformation and other harmful content.

Media Matters for America, a liberal-leaning nonprofit, said last month that its researchers found at least 50 ads on Facebook over the last two years promoting aspects of the “great replacement” and related themes. Many of the ads came from candidates for political office, even though the company, now known as Meta, announced in 2019 that it would bar white nationalist and white separatist content from Facebook and Instagram.

The organization’s researchers also found that 907 posts on the same themes on right-wing sites drew more 1.5 million engagements, far more than posts intended to debunk them.

Although Mr. Gendron’s video of the shooting was removed from Twitch, it resurfaced on 4chan, even while he was still at the scene of the crime. The video has since spread to other fringe platforms like Gab and ultimately mainstream platforms like Twitter, Reddit and Facebook.

The advent of social media has in a fairly short period of time enabled nefarious ideas and conspiracies that once simmered in relative isolation to proliferate through society, bringing together people animated by hate, said Angelo Carusone, the president of Media Matters for America.

“They’re not isolated anymore,” he said. “They’ve been connected.”

***

A couple points of interest:

1. They paint it as a conspiracy theory, and repeatedly refer to it as such, by defining it as being attributed to the jews. This was not, for example, how tarrant (new zealand shooter) framed it, and is otherwise not a neccessary part of such theories. The attribution might be to a variety of things, and might not be a conspiracy theory at all. They track the propagation of adjacent theories to mainstream politicians on facebook. They fail to mention the exact rhetoric used  in facebook ads, but one suspects such ads avoid naming the jew. So the version used by these politicians might not have the part that makes it a conspiracy theory, or even false, at all. So point one is a discussion of the way the media uses dishonesty to reframe issues. And we might also reflect on how this leads to radicalization etc.

2. Such theories are referred to here as being &#34;white supremacist&#34; and &#34;white nationalist&#34;. This is more likely to be true of such theories in general. To what degree does that make them evil? We know, for example, that members of most ethnicities prefer to see the propagation of their ethnicity. We know, furthermore, that when an ethnicity is prevented from propagating itself, this is called genocide, and is one of the worst crimes imaginable. So, clearly we will accept white supremacy adjacent rhetoric in some cases. What specifically about use of such rhetoric by white people makes it evil? Point two thus discusses whether we should allow such rhetoric to exist, or ban it from major platforms.

3. We might go a step farther, and question whether we should *necessarily* agree with such ideas. If, after all, every race (here defined in the old sense, as not being merely skin color) throughout history has been interested in its survival and success, shouldn&#39;t we take the hint that this is a good thing to care about? On the other hand, we modernists seem to be hedonists in the nth degree. What does it matter to us if we achieve anything besides pleasure and pain while living? Or perhaps we care about our &#34;race&#34;, but we define our &#34;race&#34; as *american* (or whatever country you happen to be from). If white americans die out, but brown americans live on, this is hardly a concern for us. But how is the latter reasoning any more valid? Caring about people who happen to be citizens in the same territory as us is hardly more worthwhile than caring about people who happen to share our skin color. Thus, the third point concerns whether we ought to be white supremacists too.

4. Perhaps the problem is specifically that without being a conspiracy theory, such theories are quite meaningless. After all, if the blame for the white race dying is... white people, then we can hardly claim that something evil is happening. Some people are choosing not to reproduce. Others are still having children. Killing a bunch of black people does nothing when the problem is white people. Killing white people would be... counter-productive. There are a slim few policy proposals for raising fertility rates, but none that I&#39;m aware of have been shown effective. Mass shooter rarely propose them anyways. So this white supremacy, good or bad, is merely a dying breath, a swan song. The fourth point questions whether this specifically is why white supremacy is evil. 

5. To wrap things up, we might question the degree to which the media itself is complicit in the decline of white fertility. If the problem were well known, and furthermore was well established as *a problem*, people might reasonably choose to have more children to make up for the slack. Instead, organizations like the NYT choose to publish articles pretending it isn&#39;t happening at all, and arguing that anyone complaining about it is a white supremacist and thus evil. It seems like a major organization like the NYT could choose to turn the issue around, and yet they don&#39;t. So the fifth point concerns the role of the media and broader culture in producing this outcome.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iasy9yh/"/></entry></feed>