<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Chad_Nauseam - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-12T15:49:52Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Chad_Nauseam" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifvc3ol/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] # Why do so many people dislike capitalism?

And I&#39;m not saying in this post tha</title><updated>2022-07-12T15:49:52Z</updated><author><name>Chad_Nauseam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text"># Why do so many people dislike capitalism?

And I&#39;m not saying in this post that there are no good arguments about capitalism, I&#39;m only trying to understand the *modal* argument against capitalism.

I think people inherently don&#39;t like being told what to do. When someone compels you to do something, chances are it benefits them more than it benefits you, so we have an automatic reflex to assume that we&#39;re being shortchanged.

The weird thing is, when you look around at modern society, there&#39;s no one entity that really tells you what to do. If you don&#39;t like your job, you can quit at any time and no one will make you keep working. But then, if you don&#39;t have any job, you&#39;ll probably have to live on the street and that&#39;s not pleasant, so if you want to live a normal life you&#39;ll have to find *someone* who has money and convince them to give it to you.

The system that coordinates this is capitalism, so indirectly, the market forces of capitalism are telling everyone what to do. That inherently makes people dislike it, I think. You can ask yourself &#34;why am I doing something I hate every day?&#34; and trace the causal chain back and eventually you&#39;ll get to &#34;because capitalism&#34;. That&#39;s probably not going to endear someone to capitalism!

People won&#39;t say it explicitly, and it feels like of strawmannish to say out loud, but I genuinely think maybe 50% people who say things like &#34;fuck capitalism&#34; are imagining in their heads &#34;Capitalism makes everyone have to do stuff they hate all day and most people don&#39;t even get paid that much money for it. Wouldn&#39;t it be great if there were a system where nobody had to work and we still had our modern living standards?&#34;

Through this lens, a lot of arguments that seemed weird to me started to make sense.

1. The subreddit /r/antiwork. Enough said I think. Some people say that their real goal is just &#34;workplace reform&#34; or something like that, but I think that&#39;s just the motte. 
2. [Leftie youtube PhilTube made a video about &#34;bullshit jobs&#34;](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_X-812q_Jc). If you&#39;re not familiar, [bullshit jobs](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs) says that half of all work people do in the developed world is pointless. If you look at his examples, like &#34;programmers repairing bloated code&#34;, I think you&#39;ll find this assertion a bit questionable. But you can understand why it&#39;s a very tempting idea: if half of jobs are completely pointless, that means everyone could work 20 hours a week instead of 40 with no loss in productivity! 
3. There&#39;s of course the preference for small businesses over megacorps. When a mom and pop shop hires you to work the register, that&#39;s not capitalism making you do it, that&#39;s just mom and pop asking you to do something for them and paying you for your time. They&#39;re probably giving you a good deal, right? But when Amazon hires you to work in the warehouse, even if they pay better than mom and pop and offer better benefits, suddenly is some weird foreign global system that&#39;s getting you to work for them. They&#39;re probably ripping you off!

Again, to be clear, I&#39;m not saying there are no good arguments against capitalism or anything like that. I think it&#39;s okay to look at bad arguments for position X, as long as you don&#39;t come away from that process thinking that those are representative of the best arguments for position X.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifvc3ol/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>