<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T15:23:57Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9lflo/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Lost in the shuffle last week was an interview between [Trump’s AG Bill Barr]( h</title><updated>2022-08-29T15:23:57Z</updated><author><name>ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Lost in the shuffle last week was an interview between [Trump’s AG Bill Barr]( https://www.commonsense.news/p/bill-barr-calls-bullsht) and Bari Weiss. I don’t normally enjoy writing about this kind of piece because of how heated people can get, but I found this interesting enough that I’ll give it a go.

Tl;dr: Likes:  
-	Trump, the president 
-	The right’s interpretation of Russiagate  
-	Republicans  
-	Joe Manchin and Stephen Breyer  
Dislikes:  
-	Trump, the person  
-	Progressives (unclear to me how wide a net this casts)  
-	Political tribalism  

Barr tells a few stories that echo what has come out about the Trump administration in a number of books and other sources. Stories like this one:

&amp;gt;AG BARR: It was on June 1 when the president was bellowing at a number of his cabinet secretaries, especially the military guys—the secretary and chairman of the joint chiefs. He was calling all of us “fucking losers” at the top of his lungs. 
Or this one, where he tried to resign over the allegations Trump was making of election fraud:
&amp;gt;AG BARR: He was in a little dining room that adjoins the Oval Office. He was as furious as I’d ever seen him. He confronted me and said, “Did you say this to the AP?” And I said, “I did. Because it was the truth.” I went over some of the allegations. He said there was plenty of evidence of fraud. I explained in some detail why the allegations didn’t fly. I told him that there were only five or six weeks to challenge a presidential election because the Constitution requires the Electoral College to meet at a certain date and he didn’t have much time. He’d already wasted five of your six weeks with this crazy stuff about the Dominion machines. He’d wheeled out this clown show of lawyers that no reputable lawyer is willing to work with.  
&amp;gt;I said, “Look, I know you’re unhappy with me. I’m going to tender my resignation.” And he slammed the table. Everyone jumped. And he said, “Accepted.” So I said OK and left. I was getting into my car right outside the White House and all of a sudden, people started pounding on the windows. It was late at night and raining, so it was sort of this eerie thing. The president sent Cipollone, another White House lawyer, out there, to retrieve me and tell me “Nevermind, he’s not going to fire you, and would you come back in?” And I said, “I don&#39;t think there&#39;s any use to going back in tonight. I’m going to go home. But we can talk about it in the morning.” 

I suppose it depends how much credence you lend to his version of events over Trump’s. Barr genuinely seems to like what Trump did while in office, though, if that moves your needle towards believing him. I won’t link those quotes due to space concerns. He also doesn’t lend any credence to the election fraud theories:

&amp;gt;AG BARR: I was somewhat demoralized that he was leaving office this way. The left says, “Oh, you said all these nice things about him in your resignation.” But I felt that what he should do was focus on all his achievements and leave with dignity. Whether he thought there was fraud or not, he had his day in court and he lost.  
&amp;gt;So I was demoralized that he was going out the way he was. I thought it was very unfair to all the people, especially the younger people, who had worked in the administration. It hurt them getting jobs and it also hurt the Republican Party, which I thought up until then, could take the high ground as the party of law and order.  
&amp;gt;I would say it [the January 6th riot] was an effort to intimidate Congress and the vice president. I haven’t heard words from the president that I would consider incitement under the law. That’s a very high bar because of our First Amendment, and it should be a high bar. But I did feel that he was morally responsible for it because he led these people to believe that something could happen on Capitol Hill that would reverse the election. That there’s something they could do involving pressuring the vice president and Congress that would overturn the election. 

Barr also says a number of things about politics that make me think that compromise and a rapprochement are possible. Perhaps I’m projecting, but he seems to argue against reactionary politics and towards something more constructive:

&amp;gt;Something I’m pretty tired of from the right is the constant pandering to outrage. The picking and picking at the scab without trying to channel those feelings in a constructive direction. In my opinion, Ronald Reagan was a great populist not because he followed the frustrated instincts and the outrage of the people, but because he channeled it and was constructive with it…We have these institutions that need reform. The first step is to win an election with a decisive majority that allows you to put a program into effect and fix some of these problems going forward. That is not done by just throwing fuel on the fire of outrage on one side of the equation while the other side does the same thing on their side…I think we should basically try to persuade people. People like Youngkin, the Governor of Virginia, have shown that the Republican Party is a potential majority party.  
&amp;gt;The problem with Trump is that it’s all about running a base election. Whip up your base, get them all upset and outraged, and turn them out at the polls. Both sides do that. That is a prescription for continued hostility and demoralization of the country. The first side to break out of that will do so by restoring politics to what it should be, which is the politics of trying to capture a majority of the people through persuasion and with a decisive enough majority to change things…I say to the people that want to make America great again, “What will it take to do that?” You don’t do it just by making your base madder and madder.  

And yet, at the same time, the way he talks about liberals is depressing:

&amp;gt;although we’ve been sort of harping on the warts of Trumpism, I think the greatest threat to the country is the radical progressive movement and what it’s degenerated into. In 2016, had there been another Democratic administration, I was concerned that we’d have dug an even deeper hole that would be much harder to get out of. I think Trump did serve a historic purpose: He was sort of the wrecking ball and against progressive excess. People were mad about it, and they wanted a no-nonsense person who would be a wrecking ball, and he did that. What I’m saying now is that we need something different moving forward. I give him credit for identifying people’s frustrations and being willing to call out some of the progressive excess that other people were cowering about then.  

&amp;gt;If we’ve left it behind, I don&#39;t think this ends well for the country. I don&#39;t see that this leads to any future for the country. I think we have to return to that if we’re going to have a future. I put this on the doorstep of the radical progressives as their responsibility. They’re the ones who have sharply shifted. The political model before this was the liberal democratic spectrum where you have right and left, but we’re all within the liberal, democratic, Anglo-American political tradition.  

&amp;gt;What we’ve moved to is a bipolar system that’s more typical of revolutionary countries, where you have a party like the Marxists or some other totalitarian party trying to take power. It’s all or nothing and anything goes. It’s war by other means. That’s where we are, and it doesn’t end well.  

&amp;gt;Those of us who are traditional conservatives, Reagan conservatives––I grew up on Bill Buckley and so forth––believe in the Anglo-American system of politics. We have a First Amendment that allows citizens to debate and come to some consensus for the public good. One of the things that bothers me is that people talk about democracy and the threat to democracy. Well, what did the framers think was the threat to democracy? In Federalist 10, Madison says it’s when the majority uses democracy to oppress the minority. When someone takes a transient 51% majority and tries to ram things down the throat of the other 49%, and now we’re finding ourselves sort of oscillating between those two worlds. Get 51 votes, good: Obamacare. You have 51 votes and you shove it down people’s throats. Whereas the institutions that we’ve had before this were meant to require some form of consensus and incremental change. They allowed people to build up some consensus for an approach, and things moved slowly. That’s not good enough for revolutionaries, who want to tear things down or change things instantaneously. I think that’s the basic challenge we face right now.

automod_multipart_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9lflo/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>