<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/cjet79 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T03:41:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/cjet79" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/iljthrd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Anthony Fauci has announced his retirement. Lots of articles gave glowing praise</title><updated>2022-08-24T03:41:58Z</updated><author><name>cjet79</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Anthony Fauci has announced his retirement. Lots of articles gave glowing praise of a man I&#39;ve come to dislike. Which might seem mild, but I normally can&#39;t muster more than apathy for most politicians or bureaucrats. [This article](https://www.aier.org/article/goodbye-anthony-fauci/) captured a bit of what I dislike about him. A career bureaucrat most of his life. His handling of the AIDS crisis was unimpressive, and his handling of covid felt downright criminal.

I do hope there is some kind of come-uppance for this whole thing. Even if the only consequence he suffers is a public shaming, I&#39;d rather have that than just have him quietly get ignored. I doubt any of that will happen.

I do have wishlist coming out of the pandemic. The &#34;wish&#34; part in wishlist is very important here:

1. Accountability for top level bureaucrats. Politicians face elections, which is barely a form of a accountability, but at least it is something. Top level bureaucrats that control agencies should face some form of accountability. The heads of the CIA, FBI, and DOD should all have been torn a new asshole after 9/11. The head of the CDC should face congress after every disease outbreak. The head of the FDA should face congress for every bad drug, ***and*** every delayed good drug. Etc etc.
2. Accountability for dangerous forms of research. Gain of function research *might* not have caused covid. But there is way too much uncertainty. And it certainly did nothing to *prevent* covid. That is the whole point of GoF research, right? Slash the funding to nothing. At worst they were actively harmful, and at best they were completely useless.
3. Acknowledge how dystopian things can get without hard protections in favor of individual rights. China is the extreme case of &#39;no individual rights&#39; and they still thing zero covid makes sense. They&#39;ve locked people in their apartments, and starved portions of a city just to prevent covid cases. Certain areas of America were the only bastions of sanity in the entire world.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/iljthrd/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>