<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/cjet79 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T03:43:09Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/cjet79" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijeczy5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] How do you become a better writer?

I&#39;m thinking the main step (which I am going</title><updated>2022-08-08T03:43:09Z</updated><author><name>cjet79</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">How do you become a better writer?

I&#39;m thinking the main step (which I am going to do) is just start writing more stuff. But tactical advice would be appreciated.

I think I specifically want to be a better writer in three areas:

1. Sharing personal stories. This writing will mostly be used to speak with friends and family. Possibly as a diary. Possibly as a dream journal (I have lots of weird dreams, and I think I should start mining some of them for story ideas).
2. Writing fictional stories. I use to write a story in the past. I maybe burned out, or just lost my passion. But at the time I didn&#39;t feel very skilled at it, I&#39;d like to be better if the passion ever takes me again.
3. Op-ed style writing. Things that can be posted as articles and shared online. I&#39;d like them to be interesting, engaging, factual, and hopefully convincing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijeczy5/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij2pval/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Last week [I asked for gaming suggestions](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/com</title><updated>2022-08-05T16:55:10Z</updated><author><name>cjet79</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Last week [I asked for gaming suggestions](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iian6cu/). Thanks again to everyone that left suggestions. I started with [Hades](https://store.steampowered.com/app/1145360/Hades/), suggested by u/S18656IFL. And I&#39;ve been loving the game. But after about a dozen hours of gameplay I&#39;ve started trying to mod the game. I want MORE POWER! And I&#39;m doing it by adding more levels to the meta power system, and trying to give myself more rooms to go through for each level. I will either break this game or achieve ultimate power.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij2pval/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>