<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/codergenius - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-25T15:10:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/codergenius" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] *Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought th</title><updated>2022-07-25T15:10:46Z</updated><author><name>codergenius</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">*Apologies for posting multiple times at once. Posting here because I thought that it would be too culture-wary for the small questions thread*

**What is the actual difference between arranged marriages vs love marriages (failure modes, happy paths, why would be one be better than the other based on certain frameworks, and so on)?** 

After looking on the internet, I found that the differences account for context to be already present. I found out that I could not grok that context as I am too &#34;autistic&#34; (God I hate that word, along with nerdy). I am trying to understand it as an alien that has come to the earth for the first time or in the rationalist terms, I am trying to taboo the words &#34;love&#34;, &#34;arranged&#34; and &#34;marriages&#34;.   
  
I would really like views with the framework stated, if that is not too much or better yet, links to forums that you have seen where these concepts are discussed in detail. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihl4atv/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihl3m3y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] When I was trying to learn how to swim a mile, I followed this plan [Zero to 165</title><updated>2022-07-25T15:06:05Z</updated><author><name>codergenius</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When I was trying to learn how to swim a mile, I followed this plan [Zero to 1650 in six weeks](http://ruthkazez.com/SwimWorkouts/ZeroTo1mile.html), albeit with some allowances for slack and injury concerns. Do you know of a similar plan for 

* Learning a musical instrument (guitar)
* Cooking (French/Italian cuisine)
* Comedy (Improv Theatre, sketch writing)
* Target practice (Guns, archery) 

Basically, I am looking some kind of plan as a beginner that I could rework for intermediate and advanced levels. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihl3m3y/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>