<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/commonsenseextremist - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-02T13:54:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/commonsenseextremist" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/ieksl2o/</id><title type="text">[FF] 1._I managed to come out of my nose dive. For two days already, I have my shit t</title><updated>2022-07-02T13:54:40Z</updated><author><name>commonsenseextremist</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">1._I managed to come out of my nose dive. For two days already, I have my shit together and I&#39;m getting things done. Nice.

Also, I think somewhere around this week or two marks the point when I started to think about my creative project seriously. 
 I&#39;m yet to define what I want precisely, but I already have a skeleton and I just keep effortlessly coming up with details, approaches, ideas to explore.

It&#39;s worth covering where it all comes from. I had a habit of daydreaming for my entire life. At first it was primitive, obviously derivative of whatever fiction impressed me most at the time, with me as a self-insert - basically me fantasizing about being badass action hero, soldier, mage, genius, and so on. Cringe, yes, though in my defense I never took it too seriously and it wasn&#39;t intentional or even voluntary - you don&#39;t really *think* about what thought you are *going to be thinking* next, right? It is what it is. Good luck not thinking about pink elephants.

Later it got stranger, more complex, and self-inserts (obvious ones anyway) disappeared around the time I (more or less) grew up and ( at least somewhat) figured my identity out.

2._I believe I can see what was the trigger for my creative awakening - the decision to stop playing video games for 12 months as a 2022 New Year resolution. It freed a lot of time, sparked my creative potential and indirectly pushed me to go back to drawing, something I abandoned back in school without achieving much. A realization crystallized in my mind -  the world is full of beauty and I want to capture it. And  beauty perceived visually is what I&#39;m most interested in. 

This naturally complements my day-dreaming - Now I not only dream of ideas, stories, characters, but also visuals. Visions I want to capture and make my own, if only to stop them from tormenting me. Yes, that&#39;s right. They *demand my attention*, and I&#39;m itching to get enough skill to satisfy this demand. What I intend to specialize in is visual storytelling. I guess something like a comic book, however, the most obvious example -  Western superhero comics like Marvel, is not at all what I have in mind. It&#39;s not just that I don&#39;t like superhero stories as a theme - they are all pretty much just illustrated novels for adults, completely boring artistically.*

Another trigger that is nearly as important is Tsutomu Nihei&#39;s *Blame!* that I have read few months ago.  It really made me think about what you can achieve with visuals alone.

Alright, I&#39;m getting tired of writing, and you are of reading. Two more thoughts. 

3._Let&#39;s return to video games.

Games with creative aspect (like making dirt huts in Minecraft) sapped my creative energy, or rather redirected and channeled it in a pleasant yet infertile way.

Games without much creative side (I played my fair share of shooters as well) simply wasted my time. 

The only kind of games I can retrospectively justify is story-reliant ones. 

Really, despite some exceptions, gaming is a trap. It&#39;s optimized to manipulate you (sorry, u/ZorbaTHut !) and takes advantage of various aspects human nature to keep you staring at pixels on the screen, wasting your very scarce, irretrievable time. 

 

4._Of course, I&#39;m not an idiot and I know that I need to establish a firm foundation in my life before I fully commit to creative pursuits. Being a starving artist isn&#39;t fun.  I need good sources of income, ideally passive income as well, solid financial cushion,  so I could live without working for at least a year if I need to, so on. It&#39;s changing my perspective and priorities in a funny way. I never cared much about money - might just be because that I&#39;ve been poor and I know that money doesn&#39;t make you happy and lack of it doesn&#39;t guarantee misery, if your basic needs are covered.  I also have an anti-social side to me and I&#39;m really not into playing the human game of proving to everybody how cool and high in the hierarchy I am. I can keep going like that, but the point is that none of the many reasons why people pursue wealth haven&#39;t impressed me so far. But now I have found it. Time to enter the race.

.


*Though I&#39;m sure there are exceptions, and I&#39;m eager to hear your suggestions for visually interesting Western comics!

Edit: oh, it&#39;s the wrong thread. sorry. Hopefully you have found this ramble fun at least in some respect!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/ieksl2o/"/></entry></feed>