<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/commonsenseextremist - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-30T20:51:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/commonsenseextremist" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/iiav0qs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] As something of an AGI skeptic, I want to make a confession. In scoffing at the </title><updated>2022-07-30T20:51:27Z</updated><author><name>commonsenseextremist</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">As something of an AGI skeptic, I want to make a confession. In scoffing at the imminent prospect of creation of thinking machines, I&#39;m partly motivated by existential anxiety.

 As eggheads keep getting closer to sciencing intelligence, creativity and other parts of human soul, things do not look bright. It&#39;s not implausible that in a few years a good gaming PC will do satisfactory job on simulating all of the typical human functions...call it AGI or not (&#34;a rose by any other name...&#34;) it sucks. It&#39;s disturbing. And I don&#39;t care about GDP per capita improvements it will bring. 
I want to be special. I don&#39;t want to be something that can be accurately approximated by a glorified calculator. 
Yet science, as always, keeps stripping the pleasant illusions in which men find comfort, one at a time.

Here&#39;s my fermi paradox explanation - living things volve, build civilizations, but before they spread among stars they invariably figure out just how pointless of an endeavor that, or anything else, would be. They are just meat robots following predefined cosmic script and who will eventually die...and that&#39;s it.

 That would make modern rise of nihilism and depression first symptom of a malady that will eventually kill our civilization.
Is there a cure? Like Lovecraft says in [this brilliant, prescient passage](https://goodreads.com/quotes/193944-the-most-merciful-thing-in-the-world-i-think-is) the only remedy is to abandon science and pursuit of knowledge in general and pretend it never happened. Not a nice resolution, if you ask me. Or maybe a new mindset, new philosophy, mentality shall rise - man of the future will consider what scientific discoveries tell him about his place in the universe...and shrug, never thinking about it again.  Yes, I think I met people like that already.  Some of them were even clever and introspective. Aside from things I describe above, it&#39;s people like that who scary me the most.

I guess that category of people would include myself, with latest uptick of nihilistic ruminations some weeks behind me. Believe or not, I&#39;m feeling perfectly okay right now and I had a lot of fun writing this post.  At some point I&#39;m becoming just too tired to be scared and worried and I just hope that ultimately, at the end of the day, things are not that bad, and poverty of my meager human intelligence doesn&#39;t allow me to understand that I&#39;m no different from a teenager freaking out over a new pimple.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/iiav0qs/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>