<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/CoventryDemon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-05T14:02:43Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/CoventryDemon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexyxng/</id><title type="text">[CW] I don&#39;t know where else on Reddit to put this so it&#39;s going here: Every argument</title><updated>2022-07-05T14:02:43Z</updated><author><name>CoventryDemon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I don&#39;t know where else on Reddit to put this so it&#39;s going here: Every argument about abortion that I&#39;ve seen both the Right and the Left use is utter garbage. 

The right:

* No. The left is not out to &#34;kill babies&#34;. (see below under the left)
* The bible doesn&#39;t ban abortion and nor should your religion dictate what others do.
* The idea that a clump of cells is a person is ridiculous. 
* In Ohio, right wing policymaking just denied an abortion to a raped ten year old. 
* Preaching adoption and then not adopting any kids smacks of hypocrisy. 

The left: 

* The people on the right believe that abortion **kills a baby**. The folks on the left don&#39;t agree with that, but insist on ignoring this motivation. I cannot tell you how disingenuous this is. &#34;Your motivation isn&#39;t what you say it is, but instead is whatever I get to define it as&#34;. It is nothing more than the other side of the coin to &#34;the left is out to kill babies&#34;. Taking the worst argument of the right and inverting it is unforgiveable. 
* Your body autonomy arguments are all incoherent. Each and every one of them is perfectly cogent so long as you assume the fetus inside you isn&#39;t a person. The right has already assumed the fetus is a person so the argument is a non-starter. To the right, it&#39;s like saying, &#34;If I was at the edge of the cliff and someone was hanging onto my arm so as not to fall into a chasm and die, it&#39;s TOTALLY not murder for me to shake them off my arm. Because it&#39;s **my** arm and they&#39;re not allowed to use it!&#34; It&#39;s an echo chamber argument that has zero chance of convincing the opposition. 
* Instead of spending the age of social media trying to win over hearts and minds, you have taken every opportunity to silence yourself to the people who need your voices the most. How many times have we seen &#34;If you agree with \[insert right wing policy\] then unfriend/unfollow/etc. me!&#34; You should have been working to reach people this whole time, but you didn&#39;t.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iexyxng/"/></entry></feed>