<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/crowstep - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-01T15:08:17Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/crowstep" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing</title><updated>2022-09-01T15:08:17Z</updated><author><name>crowstep</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">This probably isn&#39;t the best place for relationship advice but here goes nothing.

My live-in girlfriend of one year recently told me that while she loves me, she isn&#39;t &#39;in love&#39; with me. Apparently these things are quite different for her.

Essentially, while she has loved all of her previous boyfriends, there was only one that she was &#39;in love&#39; with, who was from several years ago and not the one before me.

She told me it might take time for her to feel &#39;in love&#39;, but that if she doesn&#39;t feel it, she&#39;ll break up with me. Her parents had a nasty divorce so she&#39;s paranoid about settling down with someone who isn&#39;t her &#39;soulmate&#39;. (Not her exact words, but that was the gist of it).

Overall I feel pretty hurt by this. Saying we loved eachother seemed like a big deal to me, but apparently for her it didn&#39;t really count to the same degree. Now it feels like there&#39;s a timer on our relationship and if I don&#39;t meet some ineffable standard in her head by a certain point, it&#39;s over. I was also pretty stung by the idea that I (and apparently, all her other exes) don&#39;t measure up to the one that got away.

We spoke about it at the time of course, but the more I think about this, the more it bothers me. I&#39;m unsure whether to bring it up or just entrust my fate to the fickleness of female affection and hope that I eventually provoke more feelings in her than I am now. I can hardly guilt her into changing get feelings, so I&#39;m reluctant to bring it up at all. And if I&#39;m honest, I worry that even letting her know it bothered me would make her less attracted to me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x261n8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_31_2022/imo2pj9/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>