<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/crushedoranges - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T16:15:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/crushedoranges" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijghq0p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I play a game called Final Fantasy 14. I&#39;ve been wanting to write a post about t</title><updated>2022-08-08T16:15:40Z</updated><author><name>crushedoranges</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I play a game called Final Fantasy 14. I&#39;ve been wanting to write a post about the latest expansion, Endwalker, but in the interests of avoiding spoilers I&#39;ve been keeping it off, but at the eight-month mark I feel safe enough to write about it. 

(Warning: this contains copious amounts of spoilers. If you have any desire to actually play the game, I&#39;d skip this post.) 

In the setting of the game, there exists a precursor civilization known as the Amaurotines (named after the titular city of Amaurot). The inhabitants specialize in the magic of creation: and not only that, their souls are so strong in the energy of aether that their capacity could be said to be godlike. 

Needless to say, a species of human beings that can create anything with a thought can be said to be firmly in the post-scarcity side of the civilization tree. 

But not only can they create material possessions, like clothing, but they can also create life. It is treated as a serious enough matter to be somewhat centralized. Concepts of life must be throughly audited and assessed by your peers before their publication to the population at large.

The lives of these people are endless and death is something they chose. When they have tired of life, they return themselves to the star by dissolving their constituent anther, and return to the planet seeking a new, unclouded perspective.  

And from the textual evidence, the society is both egalitarian and meritocratic. There is no material inequality, and the leadership is chosen by respect and ability. But being a precursor society, their downfall is already written into the story. What sort of cataclysm could cause this perfect society to be destroyed? 

The root cause, as the game suggests, is their society&#39;s indifference to death and their ignorance of suffering. Not that they are naive, or thoughtless, but the society as a whole lacks the ability to cope with such things. Having the ability to create life, they do not hold it in such religious sacredness as we might be accustomed to, not even their own. 

And in them, I see reflections of certain strands of rationalist thought. (Certainly, I would not mind living in Amaurot. But it is not a healthy society). It is not exactly the same, but the same ambivalence towards the human experience and a desire to transcend death and suffering is still there. [This](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cZYNADOHhVY) would sum up the position I feel discomfort for. It&#39;s hard to say why exactly I don&#39;t like it, but I&#39;ll try my best.

The stubborn refusal to accept death, I think, comes from a secular worldview devoid of spiritual comforts. If you truly believe that there is no afterlife you would want to live as long as possible! But I can&#39;t help but see those who hold on to hope of eternal uploaded robot-bodies as the highest form of delusion, even more so than the religiously-minded people they hold with contempt. 

So I can&#39;t help but think of them as coddled scions of a advanced society, much like the Amaurotians. Such utopic dreams of a world without suffering or loss can only be sustained in soap bubbles, in glistening morning dew. Those who seek worldly paradise to escape their own problems will invariably suffer the most.

The game text has a lot to say about existentialism and nihilism, but I think I&#39;ll leave it unspoiled. (I found it kinda preachy, actually, even if I agreed with it.) Does anyone else share my feelings on this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijghq0p/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>