<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/D1m1tr1Rascalov - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T07:37:42Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/D1m1tr1Rascalov" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im3q30m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what&#39;s up with [excess mortality across Europe](https://www.euromomo.eu/grap</title><updated>2022-08-28T07:37:42Z</updated><author><name>D1m1tr1Rascalov</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what&#39;s up with [excess mortality across Europe](https://www.euromomo.eu/graphs-and-maps#excess-mortality)? This dataset received an update last week and has since created a lot of buzz in the vaccine-skeptic/anti-vaxx circles on reddit, Substack and Twitter, while receiving comparatively little airtime on more mainstream publications in relation to the (perceived) importance of the phenomenon. The basic finding is that elevated mortality has continued into 2022 and is currently on track to surpass both 2020 and 2021. This is particularly surprising given that we&#39;d expect a decrease in mortality now that a whole lot of vulnerable people have died already. Also note the sharp increase of mortality for people below the age of 44 and especially below the age of 14.

So far, the possible explanations I&#39;ve seen are:

* it&#39;s the heat wave,
* it&#39;s COVID itself or its long-term effects,
* it&#39;s the consequences from lockdowns, including staff shortages, treatment delays, economical and mental health fallout etc.
* and, most controversially of course, it&#39;s the vaccines

None of these seem particularly convincing to me. Why would e.g. heat waves and treatment delays be causing unusual levels of excess mortality for people below the age of 18? If it were the vaccines or lockdowns, the timing seems off. Europe is back open, mass vaccination happened last year at roughly the same scale and time in every European country, so why is Portugal&#39;s mortality going trough the roof right now while Denmark is mostly staying where it&#39;s at? COVID-infections might be contributing, but confirmed deaths are way down in basically every country and it&#39;s also not a known killer of young people. That widespread infections sort of shifted the general population health Bell Curve towards worse outcomes seems plausible, but studies on the side effects that don&#39;t look at vulnerable or severely ill subpopulations tend to come up with pretty unconvincing results IMO and again it wouldn&#39;t make sense for this to affect specifically young people.

Does anyone have a good idea for what&#39;s going on right now? Is it a combination of some of the mentioned possibilities? Or something else entirely? Or is it overblown, we should just wait a few months/a year or two and mortality will normalize?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im3q30m/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>