<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/D1m1tr1Rascalov - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T14:03:57Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/D1m1tr1Rascalov" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iis7csl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I know that there currently are a number of topics that are more pressing for mo</title><updated>2022-08-03T14:03:57Z</updated><author><name>D1m1tr1Rascalov</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I know that there currently are a number of topics that are more pressing for most people here, but I had to follow up on my mini series of desperate rants about German COVID policy ([1](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/t8jl8a/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_march_07_2022/i058805/), [2](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/tvv1dl/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_april_04_2022/i3c817g/)) given the latest news: while the details are not fully fixed yet, our government coalition seemingly intends to pass a law that will continue to regulate Covid measures into the future. 

For context: the most restrictive measures ran out at the start of April and from then on federal states could reintroduce a number of the old measures via a vote in parliament. Two states, Hamburg and Mecklemburg-Vorpommern, did so to extend things for another month, a triumphant success for the wary majority of Twitter users, journalists, bureaucrats and of course government members, most of whom were in some way opposed to lifting Covid measures. Sadly for them these two federal states actually continually had higher case rates than the rest of the country throughout the entire period they kept up with mandatory masking and vaccine passes. 

In the time after up to today, the manic predictions of many of the people mentioned above did not come to pass, an insult compounded by the result of an investigation by a government commission staffed by experts in the field (many were proponents of stricter measures) which failed to find much or even any impact on health outcomes attributable to anything Germany did during the pandemic. Only mask mandates come out unscathed in the report, but not via a careful analysis of German data, but simply by citing the extant body of scientific literature on the topic.

So, why am I writing all of this? Shouldn&#39;t the (German) Covid hawks be defeated, their doomsday predictions falsified, their prestige trashed, their credibility destroyed, their control mania shown to be useless? Sadly no, it&#39;s Germany after all, we love our rules and [rules we shall have](https://twitter.com/Karl_Lauterbach/status/1554809274412548097/photo/1). The linked picture shows a list of powers that the federal states will have starting October 1, only a few of which are mandatory (masking in public transit and hospitals), but all of those on the left (including mask mandates in public spaces, testing requirements or proof of recent (past three months) vaccination/infection) can simply be put into effect if the local government desires it without a vote in parliament or a veto by anyone. Given the comments by leading figures at the federal state level, it&#39;s all but guaranteed that these things will be enforced right from the get-go.

This new law still has to pass a vote in federal parliament, but given that our health minister is already tweeting out the list from above it seems like it&#39;s a foregone conclusion that it will pass. At this point, I really don&#39;t know what to say anymore. We&#39;re at something like 99% antibody prevalence among the population, the most vulnerable are long dead or vaccinated, hospitals have shown no signs of difficulties, even despite our stringent measures up to March Omicron ran trough and gave half the population a confirmed infection (in reality probably close to everyone), basically every country around us is done with this stuff, and yet here we are, chugging along. Resistance is limited to boomers raging on Facebook and the online comment sections of newspapers and a few stragglers of the much maligned Querdenker (&#34;crossthinker&#34;) movement that had a populist-right and conspiracy theory vibe to it. It seems that basically everyone with an ounce of power or prestige in Germany is determined to keep this up as long as possible.

To make this rant a bit more interactive: what is the state of Covid discourse in your locality? What measures are there still, do people or politicians talk about it a lot, what are the plans, if there even are any, for winter? Also, to our neighboring countries: I am very sorry for everything Germany has done to you, but *please*, [~~Morgenthau~~ ](https://bigthink.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/origin-163.jpg?w=480&amp;amp;h=270&amp;amp;crop=1) us, I&#39;ll learn Polish, Danish, anything (EDIT: Morgenthau might be a bit extreme, see comments below, on googling something like a more extended [Bakker-Schut plan](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_annexation_of_German_territory_after_the_Second_World_War) might be more appropriate).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iis7csl/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>