<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/dblackdrake - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T17:44:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/dblackdrake" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijgvwjj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Ukraine Update time: Shit&#39;s still pretty much the same as last week, no major mo</title><updated>2022-08-08T17:44:34Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Ukraine Update time: Shit&#39;s still pretty much the same as last week, no major movement. 

Ukraine continues to do really well with HIMARS shoot and scoot, but they are feeling that 227mm, and we (the US) are laggin with the 610mm ATACMS, apparently because it can reach pretty deep into Russia and we don&#39;t want to hear about Ukraine doing a little whoopsy and atomizing a square block of Kursk or something.

The pocket from before is getting worse and more secure at the same time, with lots and lots of dudes there now (unconfirmed reports of 25000 with one unchallenged route out and in); this is scary if you are  a troop and need to eat, but also means that Ukraine can&#39;t just muscle their way in, so ???

From the russian end:

A whole bunch of Russian command has been returned to the earth, and a bunch more were recently dismissed for being fucking idiots; this is causing some problems in the short run but might be good for them in the long run, these dudes were obviously not performing super well. It depends if they have anyone competent waiting in the wings who was being help back by office politics. 

Russia is not decreasing their tempo on missile attacks as people have predicted, but are ramping down their use of the good shit. Iskander  and kalibr attacks are down but still exceed rate of replacement, and attacks using soviet era missiles are way up, probably to retain a strategic stockpile of modern missiles incase anything does wrong/ they need them elsewhere.

Finally, Russians are playing a fun game where they park artillery near nuclear plants/ Shell near nuclear plants. This isn&#39;t world ending shit and it won&#39;t effect anyone outside the immediate radius of the plants (and probably not even them), but it is happening and it is like 50 degrees off from the plot of a shitty techno thriller, so that&#39;s exciting!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijgvwjj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>