<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/dblackdrake - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T23:33:25Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/dblackdrake" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought w</title><updated>2022-08-01T23:33:25Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">UKRAIN WATCH TIME: 

2 weeks a go I registered some predictions that I thought were pretty optimistic in Ukraine&#39;s favor; turns out I was too pessimistic. 

Russia is hauling out the museum piece 152&#39;s from the 1920&#39;s for second line units; the tempo of their advance and quantity/quality of artillery fire has dropped off way quicker (Like, an order of magnitude quicker) than I thought it would.

Apparently, the HIMARS shoot and scoot has been working. Ukraine can&#39;t push Russia where they are strong; but Russia can&#39;t advance along an entire front anymore without taking unsafe risks.

This on top of Ukrainian counteroffensives in Kherson; and (maybe? Questionably?) drama amongst the Russians staff running the war (apparently the two top guys hate each other, and refuse to allow one to be elevated over the other.  Water cooler shit though, so who knows.)

Basically: I predicted slow Russian advance for some time until their logistical problems caught up to them and they couldn&#39;t just atomize their problems with a zillion guns, then a frozen front until some political solution was reached or Russia got their economy in gear; which was wrong.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iikpd25/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>