<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/dblackdrake - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T00:56:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/dblackdrake" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgj8k4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Ukraine update time!

Situation remains the same as last week, no major changes.</title><updated>2022-08-16T00:56:34Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Ukraine update time!

Situation remains the same as last week, no major changes. Russia continues to advance at an extremally slow place where they have concentrated artillery, Ukraine continues to attempt to will a counteroffensive into existence through spiral energy.

That said:

Igor Girkin get&#39;s arrested trying to enter the donbas illegally to fight on the front lines. While I, personally, think he is a huge piece of shit it is admirable that he will put his money where his mouth is. 

Russia reportedly  transferring some of their equivalent to training battalions to the conflict areas. This should add some spine to their infantry, and add some offensive teeth to their forces.

On the Ukrainian side:

A Russian airbase in Crimea exploded due to a dropped Lucky Strike. No aerospace equipment was damaged in the massive fireball, according to Russia. Arial photography later confirms at least 6 su-24s and 3(?) su-30s(?) destroyed. The airstrip remains intact, as far as anyone knows. 

In addition, Ukraine has claimed (with iffy visual evidence) to have rendered the Antonivsky and Kakhovka(Man, I don&#39;t know. Languages are hard) bridges unusable for vehicle traffic. Observers have reported fuel and ammunition shortages in Kherson consistent with two blown bridges, but we wont know for sure for a couple days/weeks.

Ukraine claims these strikes were caried out by purely indigenous systems; missle-fuckers think it might be a Hiluxized Neptune antiship missile retrofitted to hit land targets (bridges), which are a type of ship if you think hard enough.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

War remains slow and steady; with predicted russian counter-counter-offensives in the south, and Kherson continues to be the biggest &#39;pocket&#39; since the korean war if it ever actually happens.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgj8k4/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikg3ior/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, if ya&#39;ll wanna feel some second hand embarrassment, watch the Jim Acosta int</title><updated>2022-08-15T23:01:06Z</updated><author><name>dblackdrake</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, if ya&#39;ll wanna feel some second hand embarrassment, watch the Jim Acosta interview with Andrew Yang re. the forward party, featuring lines straight out of the [Simpsons](https://youtu.be/HqjhHVUzl8o) such as

&amp;gt;“I personally think that women’s reproductive rights are fundamental human rights, but the Forward Party has a, not left or right, but forward stance on even the most divisive and contentious issues,”

First of all, this caused me emotional trauma as a dude who was on the technocratic yang train back when he seemed like a going concern, before he had enough exposure to prove he had no idea what the fuck he was doing politically. I still think his heart is in the right place, but even if I were Hugo Chaves I wouldn&#39;t put him into an office where he would have to try to negotiate any sort of real compromise. 

Second, it makes me wish we could lock every elected official and candidate in a room with a non-hostile but also non-friendly interviewer and not let them out until they have committed to all their positions and defended them at least a bit.

Finally, this further confirms my bias re Centrism and how it either impossible in practice or a contradiction in terms; that if you somehow founded a third party in the US it could do nothing but add another pole. ([semi relevant xkcd](https://xkcd.com/927/))</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikg3ior/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>