<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/deadpantroglodytes - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-30T14:13:23Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/deadpantroglodytes" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime085j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **More on Student Loan Relief**

This week, the New York Times published [Why St</title><updated>2022-08-30T14:13:23Z</updated><author><name>deadpantroglodytes</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**More on Student Loan Relief**

This week, the New York Times published [Why Student Debt Relief Isn’t Elitist](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/29/opinion/student-debt-relief.html) by Paul Krugman and [Why I Changed My Mind on Student Debt Forgiveness](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/30/opinion/student-loan-debt-relief-biden.html) (by Susan Dynarski, a Harvard economist). Krugman&#39;s mostly calling out Republican hypocrisy in one form or another (fine as far as it goes), but the substantive part follows:

&amp;gt;The Biden administration says that its plan will provide relief to as many as 43 million Americans. That’s a lot of people, not a small, cosseted elite.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;even if you subscribe to the Trump diner theory of politics — according to which the only voters who matter are blue-collar guys wearing baseball caps — you should be aware that some of those guys probably took out loans to attend trade schools or community colleges, all too often getting nothing but debt in return. Even among those who didn’t take out student loans, many probably have children, siblings, cousins or friends who did. So the Biden plan will touch many people.

Dynarski&#39;s article focuses on the borrowers hardest hit.

&amp;gt;Defaults and financial distress are concentrated among the millions of students who drop out without a degree. The financial prospects for college dropouts are poor; they earn little more than do workers with no college education ...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;And dropout is not at all rare. A bit less than half of college students don’t earn a bachelor’s degree. Some people earn a shorter, two-year associate degree. But more than a quarter of those who start college hoping to earn a degree drop out with no credential.

If we take those articles at face value \[0\], we&#39;re talking about a program that provides relief to about 13 million Americans that fit a very sympathetic profile and badly need it - and a bonanza for another 30 million people, most of whom do not need that relief. \[1\]

**Would Anyone Support Country Club Loan Relief?**

Let&#39;s pretend for a moment that a Republican administration instituted a program subsidizing country club membership. After all, a lot of businesses are built and supported by the informal networks around country clubs, plus people that belong to country clubs tend to be successful.

So picture that: 60-70% of the borrowers do pretty well for themselves. Their businesses improve and they get richer. However, a substantial minority of the loan recipients don&#39;t have access to high-quality country clubs with their impressive facilities and wealthy cohorts. 30-40% take out loans to join municipal clubs or some strange off-brand variation called into being by the amount of money pumped into the system. The people do not flourish, their businesses do not succeed.

I don&#39;t think many people would stand for a country club relief program for both groups, and I don&#39;t think the New York Times would publish multiple defenses of the program in the space of a week.

This comparison might not sound fair, especially if you went to community college or commuter school (to say nothing of a for-profit college), but I promise it is directionally accurate.\[2\]

At liberal arts colleges, most private universities, and flagship state schools (at least), you get unbelievable amenities for your money. It&#39;s not just the oft-ridiculed climbing walls and lazy rivers - I&#39;m talking about the basics, the features of college that predate the crazy expansion of the last thirty (?) years: access to first-rate facilities, people paid to serve you, people paid to do your dishes, and on top of all that, excellent event programming so that, if your studies ever bore you, you&#39;ll still be stimulated.

Ultimately, I&#39;m shocked that so many early reactions to this involve a shrug, or (worse) approval of the policy, seemingly based on the sympathetic profile of a minority of beneficiaries, though maybe that&#39;s my naivete. Another writer here (responding to Trace&#39;s post, I think) wrote convincingly that people probably just conceive of this as &#34;free college&#34; rather than debt. That&#39;s an idea that&#39;s probably more popular than &#34;free country clubs&#34; (and definitely more popular than &#34;free country clubs for the rich&#34;), but I&#39;m not sure it deserves the support.

\[0\] People that have some college but no degree already do moderately better than people with a high-school diploma, [per the US Bureau of Labor Statistics](https://www.bls.gov/emp/chart-unemployment-earnings-education.htm), or [this Northeastern University study](https://www.northeastern.edu/bachelors-completion/news/average-salary-by-education-level), or any of the dozens of links that pop up when you start to research education and income.

\[1\] &#34;More than a quarter&#34; = 30% \* Krugman&#39;s &#34;43 million Americans&#34;, then round it up.

\[2\] Apart from, of course, the educational experience. But I must say, this is easy to overstate, especially if you&#39;ve been [Fred-pilled](https://substack.com/profile/12666725-freddie-deboer).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/ime085j/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>