<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DevonAndChris - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T20:00:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DevonAndChris" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu8nvt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Income Based Repayment is totally insane.

People had pointed out that it was a </title><updated>2022-09-02T20:00:04Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Income Based Repayment is totally insane.

People had pointed out that it was a reasonable part of the loan forgiveness. I had agreed. Now I think it is the worst, building a time bomb on purpose and refusing to disarm it.

Maybe I am wrong. God I hope so. I laid out a lot of math below. *Part of the reason I wrote this was that someone could tell me where I messed up.* 

**Current regime**

The [current IBR rules](https://www.financialrounds.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-income-based-repayment-ibr/) are that you pay at most 10% of your discretionary income (which I abbreviate DI here). DI is your income past 150% of the [Federal Poverty Rate (FPR)](https://www.healthcare.gov/glossary/federal-poverty-level-fpl/).

If I am a single guy, 150% of FPR is $20,385. If I earn $100K, my DI is about 80K, meaning I never have to pay more than 8K a year. If this is not enough to cover interest, that interest goes away. Even if it were getting capitalized into the balance, [any remaining balance is forgiven after 20 years](https://www.financialrounds.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-income-based-repayment-ibr/) so who cares.

([It used to be 25 years under &#34;old IBR&#34; but now we are in &#34;new IBR&#34;](https://fcaa.org/student-loan-repayment-plans/income-based-repayment/) and I guess we are about to get &#34;new new IBR&#34;.

$8000 is a lot of post-tax spending, but what incentives does it make?

(I am going to make up a 5% interest rate for loans; this should be checked and numbers below reviewed on it changing).

If I take out **$93,000 in loans**, standard amortization means I will spend $8000 a year over 20 years to pay it down to zero. That **is the break-even point**. Each aditional dollar I borrow means $1.08 that disappears at the end.

$93,000 is a lot of debt. [Only 4% get over 56K](https://www.aplu.org/our-work/5-archived-projects/college-costs-tuition-and-financial-aid/publicuvalues/student-debt.html) and only 0.5% hit 100K. Average medical debt is $200,000 but my numbers were based on a salary of $100,000 which doctors will eclipse.

What if I run a family of 4? At $100,000 my DI is $58,375. That drops all the above loan numbers by about 30%. **$68,000 is still a lot of loans** to take out.

But let us change the salary. Average salary for a college graduate is around $55,000. For the single guy, that is a DI of $35,000, meaning annual payments of $3500. This is a DI of 44% of the original value, meaning **the break-even is now $40,700**. About 20% of graduates hit this level, eyeballing the earlier aplu.org link. This is starting to become a serious moral hazard.

For a family of 4 the DI at $55,000 is only $13375. That **requires only $15,600 in debt**. I am not so much worried about financially supporting a family of 4 making $55,000 as I am in giving them a direct incentive to go as expensive as possible once loans hit $15,600.



**Proposed Regime**

The [new program](https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2022/08/26/the-new-income-driven-repayment-system-could-cause-some-big-problems/) has these relevant changes:

* Increase the amount of income not subject to IDR from 150 percent of the federal poverty line to 225 percent of the federal poverty line.

* Eliminate any accrual of interest on IDR-enrolled loans.

* For undergraduate debt, reduce the IDR rate from 10 percent of income beyond the threshold in (1) to 5 percent of income beyond the threshold in (1).

Items 1 and 3 directly change my math. I will get back to item 2 later.

So now our fresh-college-graduate-single-guy-making-$100,000 has a DI of (100000 - 13590 * 2.2) or $70,000 and annual payments of $3500. This means **the break-even point is now $40,700.** If he has (or will soon have) a family of 4 his DI is now just $38,950 and will pay no more than $1,950 per year. **Just $22,600 in loans is the break-even**, meaning there is no difference to him between borrowing $22,600 and $93,000. Might as well go into luxury student housing, move the family in.

That average college grad making $55,000 with a family of 4? Your DI is *less than zero*. In fact, **any income up to $61,050 means you do not have to pay a single cent towards your loans**, as the balance stays flat and the 20-year timer ticks away.

Item 2 is missing from my analysis. If I read it right, as long as your income is below the IBR threshold, no money gets added, but in a lot of my above analysis that did not matter because uncapitalized interest vanished.

I guess it matters if you think you will have many years of salad days and then suddenly earn a lot of money. If you could get an extra dollar in financial aid and put it in a crummy retail bank savings account, that would still be a good idea. Either 20 years hits and you get to keep all the money, or your income goes up and you withdraw the money from the savings account to pay it back.

I want to make up a web calculator that shows the break-even point for given circumstances, but first I need to figure out how many mistakes I made above.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu8nvt/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>