<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DevonAndChris - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T14:51:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DevonAndChris" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt</title><updated>2022-08-26T14:51:58Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">They did it.

They made the internet worse: https://i.imgur.com/TysX2LI.png

&amp;gt;!The arrow was fucking *bouncing* in the original.!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilvknaj/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilm1fkk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] 
**The ease of orthodoxy**

A few weeks ago I came across a Paul Graham essay I </title><updated>2022-08-24T16:23:19Z</updated><author><name>DevonAndChris</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">
**The ease of orthodoxy**

A few weeks ago I came across a Paul Graham essay I had missed when it first came out: http://paulgraham.com/heresy.html

The whole thing is good but I want to highlight this paragraph and footnote:

&amp;gt; To unite the conventional-minded, an ideology must have many of the features of a religion. In particular it must have **strict and arbitrary rules that adherents can demonstrate their purity by obeying**, and its adherents must believe that **anyone who obeys these rules is ipso facto morally superior to anyone who doesn&#39;t**. 

&amp;gt; The superficial demands of orthodoxy make it an inexpensive substitute for virtue. And that in turn is **one of the reasons orthodoxy is so attractive to bad people. You could be a horrible person, and yet as long as you&#39;re orthodox, you&#39;re better than everyone who isn&#39;t**.

That explains a whole lot. There are people who are held inline just by fear of crossing the orthodoxy, but even normal people enjoy the thrill of moral superiority.

And then there are the people who behave legitimately horribly but skate by by shouting orthofoxy. It is my default assumption for [mal](https://i.imgur.com/gcRoCAm.png)e [feminist](https://www.vulture.com/article/joss-whedon-allegations.html)s who are banking up brownie points because they know they are going to need them. They have karma and they intend to spend it.

So lo and behold when this week we get a perfect example, [Dan Price](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/18/technology/dan-price-resign-social-media.html). ([Archive link for NYT](https://archive.ph/TDCP5))

**You can count on journalists to do the right thing after they have exhausted all other options**

You remember Dan Price. If not by the name, then as the guy who took a big pay cut from his $1.1 million salary to set a minimum wage of $70,000 for employees at his company, Gravity Payments. He did this because he found it unfair to get paid so much. He got a huge amount of publicity from all the usual sources, doing appearances on the *Daily Show* and similar puffery. Rush Limbaugh, on the other hand, called him a socialist, which if Price was scripting this would be exactly what he would have asked for.

Then-at-Bloomberg reporter Karen Weise found out really quick [that there was a lot underneath the surface](https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2015-gravity-ceo-dan-price/). ([Archive link for Bloomberg](https://archive.ph/v0wdA)). Price&#39;s brother sued him after the announcement because the brother was so mad about the wage increase, do you remember? Seattle Times and Inc magazine sure do.

As background, Price claimed his prior salary of $1.1 milion was set by market rates, but just compared to similar businesses and revenues, you would expect something closer to what was a third of his prior salary, so he was not giving up much. When Weise asked him about that in an interview, he changed the subject and ended the interview.

Well, the reality is that his brother Lucas served him with a lawsuit claiming he was being overpaid. And *then* two weeks later Price docked his own pay. To what level? I have not been able to figure that out, but it could have been &#34;slashed&#34; from 3x market rate to 2x market rate.

When confronted with this:

&amp;gt; In a follow-up interview in mid-November, I pressed Price about the inconsistency. How could what he told me about being served two weeks after announcing the raise be true when the court records indicated otherwise?

&amp;gt; “Umm, I’m not, I have to look,” he said.

&amp;gt; The court document, I said, definitely says March 16.

&amp;gt; “I am only aware of the suit being initiated after the raise,” he replied.

&amp;gt; “The court record shows you being served on March 16 ... at 1:25 p.m.,” I said. “And actually, your answer to it was dated April 3,” also before the pay hike.

&amp;gt; “I am only aware of the suit being initiated after the raise,” he repeated.

&amp;gt; I asked again how that could be, saying the declaration of service shows Price was served with the complaint, the summons, and other documents, “that you are a male, who is white, age 30, 5-feet-8-inches, medium height, dark hair.”

&amp;gt; He paused for 20 seconds. “Are you there?” he asked, then twice repeated his statement that he was only aware of the suit being initiated in late April. “I’d be happy to answer any other questions you may have,” he added.

What else could conme out? His ex-wife who did a TedX talk at the University of Kentucky where she read from her journal entries from the time she was married. “He got mad at me for ignoring him and grabbed me and shook me again.” ... “He also threw me to the ground and got on top of me. He started punching me in the stomach and slapped me across the face. I was shaking so bad.”


**&#34;What are you going to do, cancel me?&#34; - Man who was cancelled**

Weise relayed these quotes to Price, who said he was not comfortable responding when he had no evidence of such an allegation. He called back three hours later to remember to say that the events never happend.

Weise published her article and everyone who loved being in the room with him ran for the exits. Someone had called the emperor naked, and suddenly there were other things to do.

Taking a page from Bill Clinton, Price told his staff that his ex-wife was nuts and needed to be restrained, but admitted he should not have done that. A year later his staff spontaneously gifted him with a new Tesla because they loved him so much, which was another media set up according to his head of marketing, another employee in marketing, and the young woman who had at the time claimed credit for coming up with the idea. Price gives this recitation of facts the Sharper Image  how-dare-you-say-our-product-is-fake-when-this-hurts-the-feelings-of-our-customers-who-did-not-know-that treatment: “the idea that some people are trying to soil this cherished memory is deeply hurtful.” He was quickly forgotten again.

**Just tweet through it**

But Price was determined to get his spotlight back. He set out on a new quest to uncancel himself and hired an ex-Seattle Times reporter to shit out orthodoxy 24/7/365 on all social media channels.

He got back into the spotlight. Nick Kristof&#39;s NYT wrote [a lauditory opinion piece](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/30/opinion/sunday/dan-price-minimum-wage.html) ([archive link for NYT](https://archive.ph/c5WU1)). Did it contain anything negative at all? Yes, it admitted there were &#34;bumps.&#34; Kristof links to the NYT&#39;s old story from when the narrative was that Lucas&#39;s lawsuit was in response to the pay policy. Kristof does not correct that narrative but knows better than to repeat it since it has been proven false by court records.

&amp;gt; There were bumps, no doubt about it. A couple of important employees quit, apparently feeling less valued when new hires were close to them in pay. The publicity forced Gravity, which processes credit card payments for small businesses, to hire additional people to handle a deluge of inquiries. Worst of all, Price’s brother, who owned a stake in the company, sued and alleged that Price hadn’t consulted him on decisions.

Nothing there is literally incorrect! Publish it! We are in the height of #MeToo but no need to publish accusations from his ex-wife TedX talk.

Oh, the ex-wife&#39;s TedX talk? Gravity&#39;s head of marketing called the University of Kentucky about &#34;potential defamation lawsuit&#34; and the university declined to publish it. This was known back in 2016 but no need to bring that up in a 2019 piece. Definitely nothing #MeToo relevant here, nosiree.

**You can count on journalists to do the right thing after they have exhausted all other options and then forgotten the previous narrative and then once again exhausted all other options**

So Karen Weise writes a new article at NYT (the first link). And it turns out that he has been building up his SEO as the standard male feminist to lure in women. Doug Forbesm, a blogger, had been collecting accounts of women accusing Price for years. No one, including the NYT, wanted to run the story so he blogged them himself. Besides his ex-wife we have:

* Serena Jowers filmed them having sex without her knowledge and three other women say he did the same to them.

* Another described Price having sex without her consent in the middle of the night.

* In a car ride, Shelby Hayne said he grabbed her throat and would not let go, and then drove donuts around a parking lot when he realized he was not getting any.

* Danny Askini said he pushed her against a wall when he did not invite her upstairs after a date.

* Kacie Margis did not know there were any warning signs because they did not come up in Google searches, and ended up in Palm Springs with him. She says she got locked out of their room while wearing a bikini, and later he had sex with her while she was asleep after taking an edible.

The Hayne incident ended up being investigated by the cops, which is what broke the dam and let everything else finally come out. 

He resigned as CEO so he could devote his energy full time to fighting the false accusations against him. As Karen Weise is writing this article, you can tell she loves rubbing it in the face of media, including the NYT that she is currently writing the article for. And she fucking loves juxtaposing Price&#39;s orthodox social media posts with his actual behvavior. Particularly his posts about how easy it is for a man to disprove false allegations. (-͡°-͜ʖ-͡°)☞

Current web searches are all about articles of his resignation so there may not be a third act for him.

The assault charge got dropped from the Hayne incident, but the cops had a gem they documented:

&amp;gt; According to the police report, Mr. Price boasted that no one had believed Ms. Colón’s allegations of abuse “because of who he is and that no one would believe her either.”

After all, what use is all that cred as a male feminist if you cannot spend it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilm1fkk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>