<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-20T13:24:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il2bi0i/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Are pity and sympathy a form of power? Rather than a kind of compassion that the</title><updated>2022-08-20T13:24:28Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Are pity and sympathy a form of power? Rather than a kind of compassion that the powerful feel toward the weak, should it be seen as a form of social capital that the powerful use to subjugate the weak?

When you examine how much is needed to create a truly sympathetic account of something today — the domination of a social environment to trap an audience, writers and designers, publications, media, attractive spokesmen, storytellers — it reads like a veritable army. All of these “soldiers” work together to create a sympathetic portrayal of an event in the hopes of influencing opinion. If you can raise an influencer army, are you really weak? And if you are a captured audience to sympathetic messaging, are you really powerful?

We see that enemy powers fight over sympathy. Israel and the Arab world use their influence to fight over dominant sympathy. The truly weak party finds themselves at the disadvantage, lacking the prerequisite capital for strong messaging. 

A documentary is not a documentary[1]. A documentary is never a documentary. It’s more like a special military operation, or espionage behind enemy lines. “The Lobby” encapsulates this idea. State-owned *Al Jazeera* used (expensive) investigative journalists to uncover the lobbying efforts of Israelis in the UK and America, who ostensibly use their power to promote sympathetic portrayals of themselves and unsympathetic portrayals of their enemies. In the first series of the documentary, the Israelis keep a “hit list” of pro-Arab politicians to socially “take down”, using their social capital in the media, and accusations of oppression (anti-semitism) are brought against pro-Palestinians. And the Arabs responded by creating this documentary, a one-sided portrayal of all of the above, which lead to government inquests and the election of a Muslim student leader. In the second series, we learn that a wealthy Israeli businessman runs a website that accuses anti-Israeli activists of oppression (anti-semitism) in an attempt to, well, oppress them (shaming and blackmailing). However, this documentary never officially aired — Israel pressured Qatar to can airings of the documentary; Republican congressmen asked Jeff Sessions to label Al Jazeera a foreign agent, and the Justice Department to investigate Al Jazeera. The *Zionist Organization of America* boasted of lobbying the Qatari government to can the documentary.

This documentary was not small potatoes, as evidenced by the “exaggerated” Israeli response. But their reaction wasn’t exaggerated at all. A documentary is a weapon of sympathy, and Israel and the Arab world are fighting over control of sympathy. I question whether there is any organic sympathy left to be found that is not boosted by powerful sponsors.

[1] https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lobby_(TV_series)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il2bi0i/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticul</title><updated>2022-08-14T14:29:24Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticuline](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reticuline) is for neurons?  I’m trying to figure out whether reticuline is neurotoxic like alcohol or something more serious. There’s some cool herbalism involving it but I don’t want to take chances.

I can only find its toxicity in relation to Annonacin where it’s written “annonacin is a thousand times (1000x) more toxic to cultured neuronal cells than reticuline”. Regarding annonacin, “Studies in rodents indicate that consumption of annonacin (3.8 and 7.6 mg per kg per day for 28 days) caused brain lesions consistent with Parkinson&#39;s disease. An adult who consumes a fruit or can of nectar daily over the course of a year is estimated to ingest the same amount of annonacin that induced brain lesions in the rodents receiving purified annonacin intravenously.”

One study has,

&amp;gt;we exposed mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons in culture to the total extract (totum) of alkaloids from Annona muricata root bark and to two of the most abundant subfractions, corexi- mine and reticuline. After 24 hours, 50% of dopaminergic neu- rons degenerated with 18 􏰀g/ml totum, 4.3 􏰀g/ml (13 􏰀M) coreximine, or 100 􏰀g/ml (304 􏰀M) reticuline.

Now a lancet correspondence from 99 says,

&amp;gt; Although the two studies did conclude that simple 1-benzylated TIQs are “relatively weak neurotoxins” that can cause behavioural signs of parkinsonism in animal models, they did not examine the structurally more complex reticuline, a morphinan precursor (or any of its N-methylated alkaloidal derivatives or metabolites). As with many isoquinoline alkaloids, reticuline has pharmacological activity at diverse neurotransmitter synapses and uptake sites. However, a myriad of studies going back nearly 30 years have never revealed it to be neurotoxic. If anything, with its phenolic groups, reticuline is more likely to be a n t i o x i d a t i v e 4 , 5 a n d , t h u s, n e u r o - protective against the free radical- initiated toxicity that is commonly linked to neurodegenerative mechanisms.

The cell culture study looks pretty bad though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>