<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T11:34:19Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij1hg9v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] As I am continuing my long pursuit to learn all the obscurities of reinforcement</title><updated>2022-08-05T11:34:19Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">As I am continuing my long pursuit to learn all the obscurities of reinforcement and punishment psychology,  here are a couple fun tidbits I’ve come across:

* The stimulus that signals the end of a punishment, or is even *more toward the end* of a punishment, takes on positive valence in flies, mice, and (debated) humans. Not just *within the context of punishment*, but outside the context too. If you zap a mouse for a couple minutes and toward the end of the zap you play a certain sound, the mouse will “like” this sound and approach it outside the context. This is a kind of relief learning, where we begin to desire things that are associated with relief. 

* It’s commonly understood that exposing yourself to a fearful thing will gradually erase the fear, however the duration in which you expose yourself is crucial. In experiments of mice and men, short and sporadic exposures to a conditioned fear without the accompanying fearful thing can actually *increase fear* more than no exposure. And unlike in reinforcement learning, spaced trials are inferior to massed trials (although spaced mass trials are best). This seems extremely under appreciated because it indicates that merely thinking about your fear in short durations will increase it, something that a lot of people do. For the extinction of a fear to occur, a sufficiently prolonged exposure is necessary (for humans 15+min), ideally in massed trails (15min repeatedly).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij1hg9v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especiall</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:26:54Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especially related to reinforcement, learning type stuff, more advanced than basic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>