<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-17T13:27:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

F</title><updated>2022-07-17T13:27:30Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why is it so uncommon to factor for the malleability of value in our beliefs?

For instance, if I am a feminist, it’s important to factor in the fact that people can be reared to value *either* feminist values *or* traditional values. Humans are this malleable, that they can be raised to value particular things according to what they consume and how they model rewards. Men, for instance, can be raised to value the Spartan way of life, the Athenian way of life, or the Puritan way of life. By simply changing some variables we can have people value different things.

This is important, because it means we can just think dispassionately “what is best for the whole of society”, without much care for what people happen to value at this particular point, ourselves included. I have little doubt that if I were born a Spartan I would love war and that if I were born a Puritan I would love prayer. People did not historically deviate from their culture’s values except in times of strong propaganda against the values, eg counterculture 60’s with their strong and vivid media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/igikeu1/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9dgwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Adding to the theme of FFT gaming posts. There’s been talk online about [how vid</title><updated>2022-07-15T13:14:32Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Adding to the theme of FFT gaming posts. There’s been talk online about [how video games aren’t as fun as they used to be](https://youtu.be/j4QKSCushmo). The ascribed reasons vary, from differences in design to superstimuli alternatives like Tik Tok. But there’s an important element that has been missed: the fun of video games is in some sense *charged* from the boredom of everyday life. The more boredom you have habituated to in daily life, the more fun video games will be.

When childhood life around the 00’s and before consisted of boring schoolwork and activities, and you did not have the ability to find anything on YouTube and message your friends 24/7, the fun factor of video games stands out. This fun factor is relative to your default living condition. When you’re at school, simply getting free time to eat lunch and stand outside for recess is fun, or watching a boring documentary on a crappy TV. But over summer vacation this fun factor no longer stands out. Fun is relative to what we are accustomed to. And so back when life was more boring, the fun of a Halo or other game is stronger and more memorable. 

You might remember seeing your first “modern” television, and how captivating the image was. Maybe you remember when YouTube switched from 720p to 1080p. Maybe you remember recording a show on TiVo and being able to skip through commercials (!). The pleasantness and novelty of this is also relative. 

The importance of understanding this dynamic is that it proves to us a certain vanity of pleasure. A fun video game is fun, but it makes real life less intrinsically fun. A colorful dramatic television drama is engaging, but it makes our real life relationships less engaging. “Fun” is our mind being lit up by easy pleasure. Going from boring middle school life to GTA San Andreas is overwhelmingly fun. Going from modern GTA to San Andreas is no fun at all. Waking up on Christmas and playing Oblivion is fun; going from modded Skyrim to Oblivion is less fun. And don’t get me started on Chess. 

This fun differential is most evident in open world games, because the fun of the open world game is charged from real life participation; but open world games sap our pleasure from real life participation, to some degree.

This explanation is the least fun answer to the question of why video games are no longer fun. Because like a Renaissance vanitas painting it shows us clearly the vanity of games. Sum total fun was not increased in your life from your game playing, it was just transferred from real life to an artificial consumer product.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vzgha1/friday_fun_thread_for_july_15_2022/ig9dgwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>