<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-10T13:05:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflb2gs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Did Christianity produce a “domesticating” effect in Europeans?

I was reading a</title><updated>2022-07-10T13:05:50Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Did Christianity produce a “domesticating” effect in Europeans?

I was reading about that [Russian fox experiment](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domesticated_silver_fox). Domesticated traits started to occur only after the second generation. After six generations you had a few hyper-domesticated foxes and by the 20th generation 30% of foxes constituted this hyper-domesticated status. 

The Christian social system appears especially conducive to domestication.  Only those with especially prosocial tendencies will get the most out of services; those with especially “domesticated” qualities will be graded best by peers according to the Christian rubric of grading another’s behavior; greater voluntary activity within the church would draw in the especially prosocial, creating prosocial pairings similar to in the Fox experiment. Those who best internalized the behavioral proscriptions of the Church had the highest status, and this obedience is a kind of domestication. Traits like intelligence, humor, and athleticism have no real value in the historically Christian social system, although a minimum amount of intelligence was probably necessary to secure a mate.

Compare to what (little) we know about Paganism. Paganism had no such fixation on domesticated qualities.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/iflb2gs/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>