<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-14T14:29:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticul</title><updated>2022-08-14T14:29:24Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Could anyone familiar with chemistry and neurobiology tell me how bad [S-Reticuline](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reticuline) is for neurons?  I’m trying to figure out whether reticuline is neurotoxic like alcohol or something more serious. There’s some cool herbalism involving it but I don’t want to take chances.

I can only find its toxicity in relation to Annonacin where it’s written “annonacin is a thousand times (1000x) more toxic to cultured neuronal cells than reticuline”. Regarding annonacin, “Studies in rodents indicate that consumption of annonacin (3.8 and 7.6 mg per kg per day for 28 days) caused brain lesions consistent with Parkinson&#39;s disease. An adult who consumes a fruit or can of nectar daily over the course of a year is estimated to ingest the same amount of annonacin that induced brain lesions in the rodents receiving purified annonacin intravenously.”

One study has,

&amp;gt;we exposed mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons in culture to the total extract (totum) of alkaloids from Annona muricata root bark and to two of the most abundant subfractions, corexi- mine and reticuline. After 24 hours, 50% of dopaminergic neu- rons degenerated with 18 􏰀g/ml totum, 4.3 􏰀g/ml (13 􏰀M) coreximine, or 100 􏰀g/ml (304 􏰀M) reticuline.

Now a lancet correspondence from 99 says,

&amp;gt; Although the two studies did conclude that simple 1-benzylated TIQs are “relatively weak neurotoxins” that can cause behavioural signs of parkinsonism in animal models, they did not examine the structurally more complex reticuline, a morphinan precursor (or any of its N-methylated alkaloidal derivatives or metabolites). As with many isoquinoline alkaloids, reticuline has pharmacological activity at diverse neurotransmitter synapses and uptake sites. However, a myriad of studies going back nearly 30 years have never revealed it to be neurotoxic. If anything, with its phenolic groups, reticuline is more likely to be a n t i o x i d a t i v e 4 , 5 a n d , t h u s, n e u r o - protective against the free radical- initiated toxicity that is commonly linked to neurodegenerative mechanisms.

The cell culture study looks pretty bad though.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wnz8wv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_14_2022/ik995xh/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>