<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-04T19:18:05Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in3azg3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Historians advise the president. The problem? The scholars were all white.](htt</title><updated>2022-09-04T19:18:05Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Historians advise the president. The problem? The scholars were all white.](https://www.npr.org/2022/09/04/1120561788/historians-advise-the-president-the-problem-the-scholars-were-all-white)


&amp;gt;When President Biden spoke on Sept. 1st, to tell the nation that democracy is in danger, his warnings echoed the words of many who have been paying attention. Especially those who study the past. Not a month earlier, the president met with a group of handpicked historians who told him that democracy was teetering, hanging on by a thread.

NPR is running this piece in their history section today. Out of five (!) scholars advising the President, all five are *White*. Not a single person of color. The article links to WaPo, which mentions that’s Biden’s speechwriter Vishy Reddy was at the table when the historians advised Biden a month ago. We can assume that this meeting influenced Biden’s anti white nationalism speech.

I find the NPR analysis superficial and misleading. We are meant to believe that these five white historians insufficiently advised the President on the problem of white supremacism. This appears incorrect, given the substance of Biden’s speech. In fact, out of the five historians, three are Jewish, one being the descendant of a Holocaust survivor. Jewish groups are at the forefront of warning about white nationalism and white identity. Jewish groups have historically been one of the most vocal and critical of all sorts of white identity movements.

If we are to care about the absence of black historians at the meeting, we should probably mention that “legacy white” Americans were surprisingly absent. Despite being more than 60% of America’s over-30 demographic (the lower range of anyone advising Biden), they made up only 40% of historians advising Biden. The plain white Americans, Christian white, gentile white, whatever you want to call them are thus not responsible for the under-representation of PoC historians. 

Instead, the 2% of the population who comprise America’s thriving Jewish community made up 60% of the advisors to Biden on the dangers of America, and influenced his anti white nationalism speech. This is a shocking over-representation on its face, but not too unusual in light of Biden’s cabinet and appointments, which are also disproportionately Jewish. If we are to care about over-representation, it seems we should start here. After all, the plain white community and the Jewish community do have different socioeconomic and historical aspects. It’s not like Jimmy the Italian from long island has access to the wealth of the Jewish community. 

As [the Times of Israel](https://www.timesofisrael.com/did-a-jewish-mafia-once-control-the-us-publishing-industry/amp/) reported recently, the Jewish community maintained a “mafia-like” influence on publishing since the 1940s, so the difference between the Jewish community and say the Italian community are real and substantive. This is to say, it’s true Jews are white, but they have historically comprised a unique and somewhat inclusive community with their own levers of influence. NPR castigating 100% of white people for the over-representation of a small subset of that community is unreasonable. And indeed, once Jewish over-representation is analyzed, we can move on to Irish Catholic over-representation, which is nowhere near as high as Jewish over-representation, but there to some degree.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in3azg3/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their</title><updated>2022-09-03T23:22:23Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their service](https://blog.cloudflare.com/kiwifarms-blocked/)

The Cloudflare argument (which may be an excuse to cover for political pressure behind the scenes) is that because some user made a threat on Kiwifarms, the website ought to be refused service. This is despite Kiwifarms having strict rules regarding threats and always issuing bans soon after violating posts are published. I’m reminded of when the Florida school shooter literally wrote on YouTube that he planned to carry out his attack, in no uncertain terms, weeks before his attack. Obviously, no one would argue that YouTube ought to be denied DDoS protection (effectively deplatformed) for this. importantly, this judgment by Cloudflare allows malicious actors to eradicate any unpopular discussion website they desire by writing threats using a VPN. The rule strikes me as an insane misjudgment, but then, I don’t think this is as simple as Cloudflare making a misjudgment. I think there may be political pressures behind the scenes, which would be even scarier than Cloudflare making a misjudgment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m se</title><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m searching for mellow upbeat music and anything with lyrics is about sex and crushes. It doesn’t *have* to be this way; I used to listen to post-rock and it was not very sexed. Hymns are rarely sexy. But I like the indie genre, I just get tired of music about girls.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>