<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T01:19:00Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He</title><updated>2022-08-28T01:19:00Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Lex Fridman [interviewed](https://youtu.be/0ZO28NtkwwQ) Magnus Carlsen today. He may have used one of my requested questions, but I can’t tell as they were vague. Magnus is the most interesting case study of performance psychology because he’s so beyond his competition, in what amounts to the most competitive cognitive game in the world. 

Some interesting bits from the interview:

* Magnus does not like practicing with puzzles. Neither does he consider himself good at stand-alone puzzles. 

* Magnus hates strict, organized practice. He refused to do this as a child and instead enjoyed exploring interesting parts from books he takes a liking to. When he was younger he “fired” Kasparov as a coach (one of the best players of all time) because Kasparov wanted Magnus to analyze his past mistakes, which he found annoying.

* The above two bits are shocking as it flies in the face of our understanding of deliberate practice. But actually, maybe not! While it’s true that puzzles can be construed as very specific deliberate practice, you come across the scenarios in games anyway, in their “natural habitat” surrounded by other information; so playing difficult games is probably better than specialized puzzles. 

* While focusing on past major mistakes could be seen as optimal deliberate practice, it’s also highly demotivating. Magnus’ practice is odd in that he appears to choose the most motivating path. He reads from books guided by pleasure, and he ignores strict puzzle-based practices. He favors playing games, and if you notice, he very often plays these games with variable strategy in mind. Instead of focusing on one opening, when he plays online he frequently changes openings, tests out things he doesn’t know will work, etc. This is excellent deliberate, variable practice while maintaining motivation.

* While Magnus was the poster child of athletic chess players, in recent years he has fallen out of shape. I find it interesting that he favors sports games over weightlifting or cardio. This has a motivational component, because when he’s playing tennis for an hour or two he’s in a state of competition. I think this extra “competitiveness practice” aids him in chess. 

So I find it interesting that Magnus’ approach to chess prioritizes competition and motivation. I also find it interesting to think that if Magnus were placed in chess school with dry exercises and exams, he probably wouldn’t even make it in the top 200 students. He has a strong aversion to boring practice and is chiefly motivated by real competitive wins, and he’s not good at chess “practice puzzles”. This says a lot about modern schooling: what other talents are we missing out on because we focus on dry, boring practice problems that do not directly translate to real life? Have we missed out on Henry Fords and Da Vinci’s?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/im2p5t2/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more fema</title><updated>2022-08-27T11:00:56Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I’ve noticed from social media that  skinny guys with low body fat get more female attention than those who have a gym body. Think Timothee Chalamet or Ezra Miller, versus buff Chris Pratt. I think this is because such natural thin disposition signals good metabolic health. This sign of effortless good health trumps the gym body because it conveys greater reproductive fitness and gene desirability.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilzle2b/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>