<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-31T14:26:54Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especiall</title><updated>2022-07-31T14:26:54Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone have cool books or youtubes on psychology they would recommend? Especially related to reinforcement, learning type stuff, more advanced than basic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iidvk5l/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii1xays/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] If the rats in San Francisco get monkeypox, how bad will it get? The EU Centre f</title><updated>2022-07-28T22:45:20Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">If the rats in San Francisco get monkeypox, how bad will it get? The EU Centre for Disease Control has a [report](https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C31&amp;amp;q=%E2%80%9CImplementing+actions+to+minimise+the+presence+of+the+virus+in+the+sewage+system%E2%80%9D&amp;amp;btnG=#d=gs_qabs&amp;amp;t=1659048407870&amp;amp;u=%23p%3Dfzr8qRg_B9MJ) that reads —

&amp;gt;Implementing actions to
 minimise the presence of the virus in the sewage system, where numerous rodents are living, should be considered.

A Veterinary research paper on Monkeypox [from 2004](https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.418.2491&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf) speculated that —

&amp;gt; One can envision prairie dogs, perhaps infected with monkeypox, plague, or tularaemia, populating the sewers of Tokyo or Los Angeles, only to emerge to engender some new public health plague, as a sort of horrific life imitates art event, akin to a Grade B horror film

A doctor, though without relevant credential, had [the following tweet](https://mobile.twitter.com/denise_dewald/status/1552226260071366657) go viral —

&amp;gt;Once monkeypox is detectable in the wastewater, it’s game over for eradication; the sewers are swarming with rats. It will become endemic. We will need to resume universal vaccination against smallpox/monkeypox. Monkeypox has been found in the wastewater in San Francisco.

Lastly, San Francisco is going to declare a state of emergency.

I think people who do not know what San Francisco is like might not realize that there is sufficient cross-reservoir contact being rats and humans to cause a crisis. A pizza place on the block where I lived was shuttered because people saw rats on their counter at closing hours. The entryway was later inhabited by a junkie who spread his feces and needles around the sidewalks, where dogs were often walked. Vagrants are frequent flyers at the hospitals, sometimes against their will, meaning police snd EMTs will have to use full PPE. The public library will likely have to close because the homeless of San Francisco congregate there to use the restrooms and open doors (without washing hands) and occasionally picking up a book or using a computer. The restrooms at Starbucks are continually used not just by the homeless but by tourists and busy people.

Implying that a dozen heroin-using homeless individuals acquire monkeypox, my intuition is that it could lead to a sustained public health problem.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii1xays/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvm026/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I’ve been reading some studies on alcohol. I’m pretty sure our culture is drinki</title><updated>2022-07-27T17:29:26Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I’ve been reading some studies on alcohol. I’m pretty sure our culture is drinking incorrectly. Alcohol has a significant *retrograde* enhancement on memory; it especially enhances positive-valence memory and (perhaps) social/language memory, but only post-learning.  I don’t think the mechanism is conclusive but the hypothesis is that it works by reducing memory interference on information presented post-ingestion. There is no benefit to drinking *before* learning on memory acquisition, there is only a benefit *after* learning on memory *consolidation*. Drinking before any learning will negatively influence acquisition and retention. Or so studies suggest.

This would mean that, if we are to drink, we ought to (1) not pre-game; (2) exposure ourselves to a context where we desire to create preferentially happy memories, (3) drink immediately following the context. If we are drinking to bond socially, we want the bonding to be before the drinking starts. If we are drinking with a book, we may want to start reading before we start drinking. It would also seem that if we have to do some annoying negative thing, alcohol will enable it to be done without much negative effect on mood when it is over.

It’s surprising to read historical accounts of writers and thinkers drinking so much. It’s likely that culture used to be oriented toward this more beneficial style of drinking. Think: drinking in ode of some emotionally-charged celebration (wedding, then after-party); drinking the wine *in memory* of Christ; etc.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w9703v/wellness_wednesday_for_july_27_2022/ihvm026/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>