<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-03T23:22:23Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their</title><updated>2022-09-03T23:22:23Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Update to the Kiwifarms Saga: [Cloudflare has blocked Kiwifarms from using their service](https://blog.cloudflare.com/kiwifarms-blocked/)

The Cloudflare argument (which may be an excuse to cover for political pressure behind the scenes) is that because some user made a threat on Kiwifarms, the website ought to be refused service. This is despite Kiwifarms having strict rules regarding threats and always issuing bans soon after violating posts are published. I’m reminded of when the Florida school shooter literally wrote on YouTube that he planned to carry out his attack, in no uncertain terms, weeks before his attack. Obviously, no one would argue that YouTube ought to be denied DDoS protection (effectively deplatformed) for this. importantly, this judgment by Cloudflare allows malicious actors to eradicate any unpopular discussion website they desire by writing threats using a VPN. The rule strikes me as an insane misjudgment, but then, I don’t think this is as simple as Cloudflare making a misjudgment. I think there may be political pressures behind the scenes, which would be even scarier than Cloudflare making a misjudgment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imzlrm8/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m se</title><updated>2022-09-03T01:23:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Why is so much music about sex? I guess I never thought about it before.  I’m searching for mellow upbeat music and anything with lyrics is about sex and crushes. It doesn’t *have* to be this way; I used to listen to post-rock and it was not very sexed. Hymns are rarely sexy. But I like the indie genre, I just get tired of music about girls.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x3t1mp/friday_fun_thread_for_september_02_2022/imvfw48/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>