<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-04T14:59:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib5guzz/</id><title type="text">[CW] 
I came across a [news story](https://www.khou.com/article/news/crime/tomball-is</title><updated>2022-06-04T14:59:35Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">
I came across a [news story](https://www.khou.com/article/news/crime/tomball-isd-family-killed-in-centerville-texas/285-ad1274ed-db15-4c2e-b2d0-54948156479c) that made me more upset than usual. An escaped convict, a cartel member, murdered five members of a family in Texas. Reasoning why this story hit me hard, I concluded that the crime I find significant is not the crime that is measured in graphs and figures. I think we’re measuring crime incorrectly and should be fighting crime differently. 

In terms of the betterment of society, a criminal killing a well-adjusted citizen is worse than a criminal killing another criminal. Much crime in America is criminal-on-criminal. This should be modified a bit, because criminality is a spectrum, not a matter of violating the letter of the law. The person who spends his time hanging out with gang members, boosting their posts on social media, and egging on his friends to commit violence is less innocent than the well-adjusted citizen, and is also more *oriented* toward criminality, despite never violating the letter of the law. 

The moral person endures pain and sacrifice to work towards the betterment of society, and the criminal does the opposite. The moral person feels the sting of long hours at work, the pangs of unfulfilled desire, and love for neighbor as he navigates life to make the world better. The criminal chooses violence and hate. A criminal killing an innocent moral person is worse for society than a criminal killing a criminal. And a criminal killing the criminally-inclined is better for society than a criminal killing the morally-inclined. Criminals are not the kinds of people we want in society to begin with.

And so a criminal killing five members of a moral family is an egregious crime against society that we’re not able to really quantify and measure. We have no idea how prevalent the phenomena of “crime against innocents” is, whether this is increasing or decreasing. And we probably have disagreements over exactly how significant the life of an innocent is relative to that of a criminal. For instance, is a criminal killing an innocent *twice* as bad as criminal-on-criminal? Is it ten times as bad? 100? 

I want to propose a new value scheme for thinking about crime. The scheme is this:

(1) the only crime worth caring about and deterring is criminal-on-innocent crime. The more innocent the victim, the worse the crime.

(2) The criminally-inclined killing the criminally-inclined is not merely *less bad*, it’s actually *good*. We should be increasing the amount of criminals killing each other in society, other things being equally. 

While this last point comes off as edgy, I believe it would make the world better with limited drawback. There are ways to encourage criminals to kill each other without negative consequences. 

The first way is an area of a city cordoned off, where criminals can commit violence with no legal repercussion. We already have de facto areas of cities like this, where police don’t patrol and where the solved homicide rate is perhaps 10%. I simply think this should be a legally-recognized expanded practice.

The second way is a national “battle royale” event for 16+ men with a prize pool of $40,000, something low enough to deter good and intelligent people, but high enough to encourage would-be criminals. In order to deter any accidental reinforcement of criminality in society, the event would be held without recordings. It can be advertised in high crime areas of the country.

Criminality is a natural variation of human biodiversity. We will always have criminals, no matter the policies we instantiate. In the past, the violent-prone would be enjoying a life of killing in war parties, becoming state-sponsored pirates, dueling each other to the death and killing each other outside taverns.

Our greatest hope should be to remove criminals from society as quickly as possible, with the least harm inflicted on innocents. Putting criminals behind bars is needlessly expensive, when we can simply permit them to kill each other in specified contexts. Who are we to say criminals shouldn’t live out their destiny anyway? [Hundreds of species](https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2021/07/mammal-adulticide/619512/) kill each other, from bears and lions to primates and walruses. We would not suppose to hold court over nature, or presume that these animals should be barred from inflicting violence. So it is with violent humans. It makes sense to allow them to commit violence against each other, which cancels out the problem in a cost-efficient and self-selecting way. 

While the above is the most palatable version of my idea, I actually think we should go a step beyond and raise the battle royale prize pool while publicly televising the event. This would have the effect that, over consecutive generations, those who are the most *inherently deterred* from violence will be selected for in society. Those who want to commit violence, and who cannot reason about longterm gain, will be gradually filtered out of society. All of this would occur in a way that respects a person’s freedom and right to self-determination, so I don’t really see anything wrong with it morally.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib5guzz/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib1plfi/</id><title type="text">[FF] I’m fascinated in how gambling is addictive. I watched some Twitch drama videos </title><updated>2022-06-03T15:32:37Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I’m fascinated in how gambling is addictive. I watched some Twitch drama videos because a streamer (XQC) gambled and lost two million dollars. In the era of MMORPGs and MOBAs, which are highly sophisticated reinforcement platforms with gambling mechanisms, people still play slots. 

From my understanding, if you look at slots, the crucial aspect is the *quickly repeated behavior* with clear reward/punishment. The fast repetition and multi-sensory (auditory/visual) focus makes these reward/punishment states very salient, so the mind can strongly distinguish between the two, growing the desire for the reward and dislike of the punishment. Slots use movement, which probably enhances visual focus. The randomness of the reward increases craving by modulating attention; the “near-misses” build anticipation by creating a sense of proximity to reward, staving off discouragement. The flashy lights and sounds add a little bit of reward as well as focus. All this leads to the reward of winning becoming as clear as any possible behavior, and then strengthened with every repetition. I’m surprised they don’t add more reinforcing agents like warming your seat but keeping the air cool, or releasing a scent they increases alertness when you win, or — well, don’t want to give anyone ideas. But I’d wager they can make gambling 20% more addictive.

I think the lynchpin for this all working is that, unlike a video game, money is already imbued with value. A video game has to invest value in certain rewards over time by repeated association, but when you gamble the reward is already maximally invested with value, because everyone knows the value of $100. And so, as you care more about money (looking at your paycheck), the thrill of gambling is *increased*. Finally, the more you gamble, the *less salient* the value of money is, because you’re hyperfocused in a context where the numeral value of a dollar is blurred with the inherently rewarding behavior of engaging in the gamble loop. Someone hyperfocused on slots is not going to be able to immediately call to mind the value of $20 for (say) their kid, because their attentional resources are focused on the association of money with the game they are playing.

Sort of insane that this is legal.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib1plfi/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iasl96i/</id><title type="text">[WW] Any natural depressants more powerful than chamomile but less risky for longterm</title><updated>2022-06-01T15:05:04Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Any natural depressants more powerful than chamomile but less risky for longterm use than alcohol?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iasl96i/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iahrtmb/</id><title type="text">[SQ] Are there any games (of any sort, offline/online) without a clearly delineated w</title><updated>2022-05-30T01:25:01Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Are there any games (of any sort, offline/online) without a clearly delineated win or loss? What is it about our psychology that we need a clear and indisputable boundary for the desired terminal state of behavior? It seems the more visual and “sensationally obvious” win the better: a ball going through a net, shooting a tin can and hearing its sound, touching a person in tag. And we get upset and taken out of the game when any ambiguity is present, eg tagging a person or “merely tagging their clothes”. If the game were just a measure of skill, such a small gap between tagging skin or clothes should not matter. Instead the win needs to be obvious and indisputable. You would think this could be because interpersonal competition is driving it, but that doesn’t explain all games: games against ourselves (reaching a time while running), and “stunt” games like throwing a basketball backwards blindfolded and trying to make it in the net. Getting 99.99% close to a stunt win is not 99.99% as pleasurable as victory, it’s sometimes even *less* pleasant than if you were never close.

So is it just some animalistic relic of satisfaction needing to have some sensory “on/off” switch, because this led to greater evolutionary fitness? In other words, the cat that leaps to catch a bird and is 99% close and feels reward may not have been as fit as the bird that only felt reward when 100% hitting. Because feeling reward when merely close to hitting is not as reinforcing as 100% hitting, in terms of hunting prowess. The cat that was rewarded for coming close may stick to that inferior strategy of hunting; the cat that is only rewarded for a clean catch will be rewarded more accurately than a close catch.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iahrtmb/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaevkuz/</id><title type="text">[SQ] * Could mass shootings be the result of an expanded conformist state, where the </title><updated>2022-05-29T10:34:56Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">* Could mass shootings be the result of an expanded conformist state, where the individual confronts big “S” Society on a daily basis? So whereas in the past, men would commit interpersonal violence against other men in feuds or altercations or gang disputes, men now see an increasingly demanding society personified. This would be due to greater societal demands of conformity and obedience, centralized competition for mates, and reduced small male spaces. Could be, because I noticed China has as many mass school stabbings as we have shootings, relative to their default homicide rate.

* Are we going to see an increase in the commodification of women in the coming decades? I’m noticing a new kind of shameless among young women on social media. Their primary obsession is showing their body in skimpy outfits (since common), but now there’s also complete acceptance of promiscuity, plus Onlyfans culture and reduced wages, and “legitimization” of whoredom (sex work). And then consider the science that will be published in coming decades about immune health and physical attractiveness. All of these combined could lead to a new culture where young women are virtually bought and sold; they advertise their body on social media, bidders pay for escort dates which are a euphemism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaevkuz/"/></entry></feed>