<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Difficult_Ad_3879 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T16:22:19Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Difficult_Ad_3879" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7b6h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] To what extent should we even care about workplace inefficiencies and waste? Isn</title><updated>2022-08-22T16:22:19Z</updated><author><name>Difficult_Ad_3879</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">To what extent should we even care about workplace inefficiencies and waste? Isn’t consumerism and inequity better to focus on, as it wastes more resources more flagrantly? For instance, Jeff Bezos wasting resources on yachts and so on, while squeezing the lowest workers dry; financial sector employees wasting resources on fancy things, while taking over companies to fire the slightly inefficient employees. Our system seems hyperfocused on inefficiencies of the lower class, while almost completely ignoring the inefficiencies of the upper class re: resource utilization. Consider how the upper echelon of Walmart waste exorbitant resources on multiple mansions, needless cars, needless trips, etc. It makes me wonder whether unionization and labor bargaining wouldn’t ultimately be more resource-efficient, as a way to prevent Bezosian wastefulness. 

Like sure, we could fire warehouse Bob because we can force warehouse Joe to do his job, if we cut Joe’s breaks down to 15 minutes and prevent him from talking at the water cooler. And if this existence is unlivable we can replace him with Juan when he dies from a fentanyl overdose. Or Bob and Joe can band together and fire Office Edward, who takes home extra resources akin to 40 Bobs a year, and wastes them buying vodka with gold flakes in it. Which one is really immoral and deserving of efficiency-finding? I refuse to believe Office Edward is actually that valuable in terms of what he brings to the company, having known Office Edward, and MBA programs are a meme. Maybe it’s better for society for Bob and Joe to get some slack versus Edward getting 1000x the slack.

This question is kind of reinventing the wheel, but this is the angle I’m trying to look at.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilc7b6h/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>