<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DinoInNameOnly - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-30T23:42:55Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DinoInNameOnly" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgejsp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **There&#39;s Still a TJ Test, Actually**

The [Thomas Jefferson High School for Sci</title><updated>2022-08-30T23:42:55Z</updated><author><name>DinoInNameOnly</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**There&#39;s Still a TJ Test, Actually**

The [Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Jefferson_High_School_for_Science_and_Technology) is a magnet STEM-focused high school in Northern Virginia established in 1985. The school has special facilities meant to provide opportunities for students who show achievement and passion for STEM and who will eventually pursue careers in science, engineering, or medicine. It has courses in things like artificial intelligence, quantum mechanics, DNA science, and machine learning. It also has several labs where students can do research projects. It was [ranked](https://www.usnews.com/education/best-high-schools/virginia/districts/fairfax-county-public-schools/thomas-jefferson-high-school-for-science-and-technology-20461) as the best school in the country in 2022. 

Until recently, TJ admitted students through a competitive process similar to the college admissions process in which prior academic achievement, teacher recommendations, and an exam similar to the SAT played a major role. The school had a low proportion of black and Hispanic students who were admitted, and this was long a complaint of left-wing activists who advocate reforms to the admissions process so that more non-Asian minorities would be admitted. In particular, they blamed the admissions exam for eliminating most such students from consideration.

In 2020, those activists got their way. The school board voted to eliminate the admissions test in [October 2020](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/education/thomas-jefferson-high-admissions-change/2020/10/07/0a1f8faa-08a7-11eb-9be6-cf25fb429f1a_story.html) and later that year made other reforms to the admissions process, including setting minimum quotas for admission at the middle school level and adding &#34;experience factors&#34; to the process. The [class of students](https://www.fcps.edu/news/tjhsst-offers-admission-550-students-broadens-access-students-who-have-aptitude-stem) admitted the next year went from being 4.52% black and Hispanic to 18.36%. 

An advocacy group opposed to the 2020 changes [sued](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coalition_for_TJ_v._Fairfax_County_School_Board), alleging the changes discriminated against Asian Americans, whose share of admitted students decreased from 73.05% to 54.36%. The case is currently pending before the appeals court.

One thing I realized while I was researching this is that there actually still is a test that influences your probability of admission to TJ. One of the &#34;experience factors&#34; that increases a student&#39;s odds of being admitted in the [new admissions process](https://www.fcps.edu/registration/thomas-jefferson-high-school-science-and-technology-admissions/tjhsst-freshman) is whether they are an English Language Learner (ELL). An [ELL is a student](https://wida.wisc.edu/sites/default/files/resource/explaining-ell-status-english.pdf) who has extra support learning English in school. How do schools identify which students need extra support learning English?

Well, there&#39;s a test. Schools administer an English skills test and students who perform poorly on it are identified as ELL and offered extra instruction in special classes for ELLs. 

What this means for TJ is that a student&#39;s chance of being admitted to an elite school for the academically excellent is *increased* if they perform *poorly* enough on evaluations of their language skills.

The reason the school board added this consideration is obvious: The [large majority (78%)](https://www2.ed.gov/datastory/el-characteristics/index.html#four) of ELLs are Hispanic, so preferring ELLs in the admissions process is a way to increase the proportion of Hispanics admitted without needing to add race to the admissions process explicitly (which would be more easily challenged legally). Asians make up 11% of ELLs too, but it&#39;s notable that Hispanics outnumber Asians among ELLs by 7:1 but only by about 3:1 in the general population ([6.1% vs. 18.9%](https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/fact/table/US/PST045221)). A lot of Asian kids speak two languages but their parents made sure they were good enough with English that they don&#39;t need any special instruction.

This is just... so backwards. I don&#39;t think it would be fair to prefer students who speak more than one language in admission to TJ. But I could see an argument for it: Students who successfully learned a second language and succeeded enough to be equally or almost equally academically impressive as students who speak English natively have done something really impressive, now that they&#39;ve mastered the lingua franca, they&#39;ll probably shine even brighter. In fact, this describes a large proportion of the students admitted to TJ under the old process. But that&#39;s not what they&#39;re doing with this new process. They&#39;re specifically preferring the students who were *least* successful at learning the new language, the ones who struggled the *most* with it. 

On top of that, immigrant families who were responsible and ~~paid off their student loans~~ taught their kids English fluency and saved the taxpayer-funded school system the extra burden of dealing with kids who don&#39;t know English are punished, while the ones who depended on the government for that are rewarded.

Well, expect an increase in enrollment in ELL programs in Fairfax County of kids who seem to be speak pretty good English most of the time.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imgejsp/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>