<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DinoInNameOnly - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-20T18:44:18Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DinoInNameOnly" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy93di/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Merriam-Webster recently updated the definition of the word &#34;female&#34;: The first </title><updated>2022-07-20T18:44:18Z</updated><author><name>DinoInNameOnly</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Merriam-Webster recently updated the definition of the word &#34;female&#34;: The first one:

&amp;gt;of, relating to, or being the sex that typically has the capacity to bear young or produce eggs

The second one is different:

&amp;gt;having a gender identity that is the opposite of male

The definitions for male are similar. First:

&amp;gt;of, relating to, or being the sex that typically has the capacity to produce relatively small, usually motile gametes which fertilize the eggs of a female

Second:

&amp;gt;having a gender identity that is the opposite of female

There are more definitions provided, but all of them use the words &#34;woman,&#34; &#34;girl,&#34; or &#34;female&#34; (or are defining about the word in a different sense, like a female rhyme or a female connector) so they don&#39;t tell us anything about what it actually means to be female, since the definitions of &#34;woman&#34; and &#34;girl&#34; both use the word &#34;female.&#34;

The definition of gender identity is 

&amp;gt;a person&#39;s internal sense of being male, female, some combination of male and female, or neither male nor female

The first definitions are obviously hateful and transphobic, so let&#39;s throw those out. If someone who didn&#39;t know what male, female, and gender identity were wanted to use the definitions to figure out what female meant, they would learn that being female means &#34;having an internal sense of being that is the opposite of the opposite of female.&#34; 

That&#39;s basically a long way to say that &#34;female&#34; means female. We learn from these definitions that male and female are gender identities that are opposed to each other, but we learn nothing about what the difference between them actually is or even what gender identity really means other than that it&#39;s an &#34;internal sense&#34; of some kind. The concepts are connected to each other while floating in the ether, unconnected to physical reality or to any non-gender concepts. This is the form gender ideology always takes when you scratch it even a little bit, circular definitions with no connection to reality. Merriam-Webster avoided the simplest one (&#34;A woman is someone who identifies as someone who identifies...&#34;) by adding more steps but the result, ultimately, is the same.

The only way to give these any kind of meaning is if you sometimes use the second definition and sometimes the first. If you interpret female as meaning &#34;having a gender identity that is the sex that typically has the capacity to bear young or produce eggs&#34;, then you&#39;ve come to something sort of like the understanding of the meaning of the word that progressives actually use. But to get to this definition, female has to mean *both* the second definition *and* the first definition at the *same time*, in the context of the *same statement*, even though these definitions contradict each other (e.g. Lia Thomas is only female by the second definition). 

This contradiction takes other forms, like how trans activists simultaneously insist that having a penis has nothing at all to do with being male at the same time that they insist that surgeries to fabricate a fake penis for someone who doesn&#39;t have a real penis are absolutely vital for some males in order to truly live out their gender identity. Penises are simultaneously completely irrelevant and absolutely vital to male identity. 

To believe in gender identity you have to simultaneously believe two contradictory things (that penises make someone male and that they don&#39;t). It&#39;s trite, but I don&#39;t know what to compare this to other than Orwell&#39;s doublethink.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igy93di/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>