<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Doglatine - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T22:15:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Doglatine" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijx1bm6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Tuesday marked [the death of Raymond Briggs](https://www.theguardian.com/books/2</title><updated>2022-08-11T22:15:32Z</updated><author><name>Doglatine</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Tuesday marked [the death of Raymond Briggs](https://www.theguardian.com/books/2022/aug/10/snowman-author-raymond-briggs-dies-aged-88), one of England&#39;s greatest graphic novelists, most widely known for [The Snowman](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZE9KpobX9J8) and [Father Christmas](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkoejIzlITA).

While his life and death aren&#39;t culture wars material per se, I wanted to mention his passing because his work was *immensely* influential on me as a kid. Specifically, when I was about 7 years old, I read his graphic novel [When The Wind Blows](https://readcomiconline.li/Comic/When-the-Wind-Blows), and accidentally saw [the TV adaptation](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9pJKdTqYijY) a few years later. In a departure from his previous work aimed at children, this was a &#34;comic book&#34; about nuclear war. Even more specifically, it&#39;s about an elderly English couple who follow every bit of government advice, and slowly, painfully die of radiation sickness in the wake of a nuclear attack on the UK.

I cannot emphasise enough how much anxiety and trauma this caused me as a child. I was lucky enough to avoid a religious upbringing, but suddenly, I became aware of civilisational-level threats and the horror of the apocalypse. I literally took weeks off school because I was vomiting from fear of nuclear attack, a condition that only eased when puberty hit and I became worried about much more sensible things like not having a large enough penis.

While at some level I resent Briggs (and my parents!) for exposing me to such existential horror at such a young age, I&#39;m also very grateful. I do think the world is a safer place in virtue of this kind of protest comic. It also set in motion a lifelong coping strategy for me - when faced with something terrifying, I resolved to learn as much as possible about it, so that the emotional was replaced by the intellectual. In my late prepubescent years, I became fascinated by nuclear weapons and prepping, and to this day, I make sure to keep potassium iodide pills in the house. Somehow by turning horrors into intellectual problems, they lose their terror.

In any case, Raymond Briggs&#39;s work helped make me who I am today. May the man rest in peace, and his work continue to (appropriately, within reason) traumatise generations yet to come.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijx1bm6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>