<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Doglatine - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-04T00:59:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Doglatine" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib3mvbv/</id><title type="text">[CW] **Some quick thoughts on value change**

Hi all, apologies for the absence etc.,</title><updated>2022-06-04T00:59:45Z</updated><author><name>Doglatine</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Some quick thoughts on value change**

Hi all, apologies for the absence etc., but just had a quick social observation I wanted to share. This evening I sent out invites to my birthday party to a bunch of friends. One of my friends (the wife of a barrister pal) asked me if we were enjoying the jubilee. I commented that my wife (from the Philippines) had eaten a bunch of scones already, to which my friend&#39;s wife replied &#34;oh, she&#39;s gone native!&#34;

At this point, my cheeks flushed a little. Why? After all, this was a wholly innocuous comment, and was in no way indicative of any colonialist feelings on the part of my friend&#39;s wife. It was entirely a matter of using a figure of speech in its appropriate context. And yet... the fact that my wife is from a South-Eastern Asian country, one that is often seen as &#34;primitive&#34; - this was why my cheeks had flushed. There was absolutely nothing wrong with the comment. However, I realised that ***I would never have said it myself***, lest I be seen as tacitly endorsing a worldview in which people like my wife were more appropriately accorded the label &#34;native&#34;.

I realise that in a certain normative sense, my cheeks \*shouldn&#39;t\* have flushed. But nonetheless they did, in much the same way they flush when I hear a colleague use the word &#34;niggardly&#34;. It&#39;s irrational, but it reflects a realisation that there&#39;s an (unreasonable!) norm that I follow that my friend or colleague is violating. And that in itself is slightly damning for my friend or colleague, like failing to realise that the Port is passed to the Left these days, chum, or that the preferred term for the differently abled is &#34;differently abled&#34; rather than &#34;disabled&#34;.

All of which gave me a clue into how norms-on-the-ground create... well, NORM-norms. Actual norms we feel we&#39;re bound by. I may not have thought there was anything untoward about what my friend&#39;s wife said, but I felt like she should have realised there might be, so shouldn&#39;t have said it; there was a subtle status-test there which she failed.

I *hate* this, and genuinely wish I could choose not to impose on others norms which I repudiate myself, but I increasingly think it&#39;s not so easy or simple. Once we abide by a norm, and recognise that others are abiding or failing to abide by it, judgement inevitably follows. That judgement may initially be of the form &#34;oh, X failed to use the appropriate terminology&#34;, but that quickly turns into &#34;X is low-status in this regard&#34; and in turn to &#34;X *shouldn&#39;t say that at all*.&#34;

This makes me more cautious about adopting norms-on-the-ground for the sake of politeness, insofar as it shows me how they can quickly turn into norms-of-society and thence into Norms full stop. Curious as to other&#39;s thoughts, though!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib3mvbv/"/></entry></feed>