<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DrManhattan16 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T01:32:43Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DrManhattan16" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijsuiyy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] For a blast from the past, [Alex Jones has just finished up with a one of multip</title><updated>2022-08-11T01:32:43Z</updated><author><name>DrManhattan16</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">For a blast from the past, [Alex Jones has just finished up with a one of multiple lawsuits he&#39;s involved in](https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/alex-jones-law-suit-verdict-sandy-hook-case-scare-conspiracy-theorists-rcna41828).

The lawsuits were about his messages calling Sandy Hook a fake school shooting and saying the parents were crisis actors. Jones obviously moved on once the shooting was no longer relevant, but his actions led to his followers harassing the parents in question. Some accounts of that harassment can be found here: [1](https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2016/09/the-sandy-hook-hoax.html), [2](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2017/06/08/sandy-hook-hoaxer-gets-prison-time-for-threatening-6-year-old-victims-father/). It&#39;s difficult to conclusively define his impact, so I can&#39;t really say if he&#39;s the originator of the hoax claim. There are more conspiracy theorists with large followings than Jones, and ideas can occur independently at the same time. But Jones&#39; status makes it likely many people heard the &#34;Sandy Hook was a hoax&#34; line from him in one way or the other and some acted on it.

A big point about this lawsuit and Jones&#39; conduct in general has been the refusal to obey judicial orders or not follow court rules in general. Jones, his lawyers, his company, and whoever was involved in his defense don&#39;t seem to have done a very good job, his lawyer straight up sent Jones&#39; phone records to the plaintiffs&#39; lawyer, who said that Jones basically lied about actually trying to see if he had any records about Sandy Hook.

That said, [he&#39;s admitted under oath that he does think the school shooting actually happened](https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/sandy-hook-parents-alex-jones-claims-created-living-87866827), which seems on brand for Jones as someone who doesn&#39;t actually believe what he&#39;s saying. Of course, he added that he&#39;d apparently love to recant his mistake, but the media won&#39;t let him. He&#39;s also said he apparently wanted to apologize to the parents, but given how many years its been, it&#39;s clear this is throwing anything at the wall to see if something sticks.

The lawsuits are not satisfying for anyone, I think. Jones&#39; defenders can tell themselves that this trial was really only decided by legal technicalities and the actual facts were never put under examination, a similar claim to one that some people here have made regarding 2020 election lawsuits. For those who want to see Jones taken down, the amount of money is basically nothing to him. Some are calling for Jones to see trial for perjury (he lied multiple times under oath in this trial) and his phone records are apparently being sent at request to the Jan 6th committee, so look forward to that in the future.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijsuiyy/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>