<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DuplexFields - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-10T07:03:10Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DuplexFields" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijothr6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] As the resident Albuquerquean, I want to mention that the serial killer of Musli</title><updated>2022-08-10T07:03:10Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">As the resident Albuquerquean, I want to mention that the serial killer of Muslims has been found. At least one tip to the police was from a redditor in the Albuquerque subreddit who methodically searched Google Streetview for the suspect’s Jetta, which had small but significant damage in one place.

The killer targeted local Muslim men, mostly Shia but one Sunni. He lay in wait for his victims, hinting that he knew them personally. The community was devastated by the deaths and was also devastated by the killer’s identity: a Sunni gentleman who was known to be a bit off his rocker, and seems to have been motivated by his son marrying a Shiite girl.

The Albuquerque subreddit, a progressivist haven as most default-named subs tend to be, instantly stopped calling for fire to rain down from Washington DC onto Albuquerque’s red-hatted bigots, and started thoughtfully bemoaning extremism and mental health issues. They did manage to find a few outgroup tags to apply to the suspect, whose shares his first name with his Prophet and a few of his victims.

EDIT: I was just reported for a violent comment in the Albuquerque sub wherein I said (before his religion and race were known) that I hope the suspect gets the death penalty, in the form of a public hanging, after a fair trial and all applicable appeals, instead of life in prison. I got the warning only *after* it became known he’s a non-white Muslim with longstanding mental health issues.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijothr6/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij0qba8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] &#34;The first step in escaping a prison is realizing you&#39;re in a prison.&#34;

&#34;...Why </title><updated>2022-08-05T05:54:14Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">&#34;The first step in escaping a prison is realizing you&#39;re in a prison.&#34;

&#34;...Why would the simulation want me to punch a baby?&#34;

Auralnauts Star Wars: [Existential Stormtroopers episode 1](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gKppwACQ-qk) and [episode 2](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eoU_7Xg3Zzw) - lots of spoilers for The Mandalorian series

&#34;If the consequences of self-awareness are super-powered genocide babies, then maybe it&#39;s not worth it.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij0qba8/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>