<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DuplexFields - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-11T15:49:14Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DuplexFields" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifqh42h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] #My body, my choice

The left and the right have both recently used this slogan,</title><updated>2022-07-11T15:49:14Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">#My body, my choice

The left and the right have both recently used this slogan, and interestingly enough, have argued their points in almost exactly the same way down four levels of argument.

**Abortion**

- Left: When it comes to abortion, my body my choice. The government must respect my bodily autonomy and my right to make choices about my own body.
- Right: But it’s not just about your body. There is a child developing inside of you who also has rights, and the government must respect their bodily autonomy too.
- Left: It&#39;s not a real child, it doesn’t substantially have the ability to experience or think. Even ignoring my right to privacy, I have the right to avoid a life-changing nine month pregnancy which could see me dead or disabled because of it, and I would also be consenting to the onerous duty of having to raise and support the child for at least eighteen years, and in the case of an otherwise healthy child with Down Syndrome, in perpetuity.
- Right: Well, how about adoption instead?

**Vaccine**

- Right: When it comes to the vaccine, my body my choice. The government must respect my bodily autonomy and my right to make choices about my own body.
- Left: But it’s not just about your body. There is a community of people breathing around you who also have rights, and the government must respect their bodily autonomy too.
- Right: It&#39;s not a real vaccine, it doesn’t substantially prevent transmission. Even ignoring my right to privacy, I have the right to avoid a life-changing shot which could see me dead or disabled because of it, and I would be consenting to the onerous duty of having to show the government and private companies my vaccine cards with all required boosters in perpetuity.
- Left: Well, how about lockdowns instead?

EDIT: Well, it looks like I found a nigh-perfect [scissor statement](https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/10/30/sort-by-controversial/). Although I have opinions on both topics, I was inspired to post this simply by how closely the arguments are mirrored.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifqh42h/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/iffvcby/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] [She works in cryonics now](https://www.smbc-comics.com/comic/ageless).

*SMBC i</title><updated>2022-07-09T05:18:44Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">[She works in cryonics now](https://www.smbc-comics.com/comic/ageless).

*SMBC is the rude little brother of XKCD: just as clever, but he&#39;ll kick you in the shins if you don&#39;t laugh.*</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/iffvcby/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>