<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DuplexFields - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-13T04:31:23Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DuplexFields" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik3a798/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] On Wordle, I’ve decided to start playing “yesterday’s” word as my first guess th</title><updated>2022-08-13T04:31:23Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">On Wordle, I’ve decided to start playing “yesterday’s” word as my first guess the following day. It’s a suboptimal strategy when the previous solution has doubles of a given letter (or two), but it gives me a sense of continuity and challenge, and beats starting with “SLATE” or “ARIEL” every day.

What are your favorite Wordle tools?

My primary tool is Notepad, wherein I use the notation of capital letters for certainties, lowercase for possibilities and dashes for impossibilities. Let’s say the word is “&amp;gt;!NIGHT!&amp;lt;” and I’ve guessed “GRAIN”, “SPROG”, and “THERE”, getting no greens, some yellows, and all five letters by the third guess. If I didn’t immediately think of &#34;&amp;gt;!NIGHT!&amp;lt;&#34;, I’d type these in like so:

    G: -ggg-
    I: iii-i
    N: nnnn-
    T: -tttt
    H: h-hhh

I also have an Excel spreadsheet with every word in Wordle’s “guess” dictionary and none from the “solutions” dictionary, so I’ll never accidentally see the real answer. The five letters are each in their own columns, in a filterable List, so in the above example I can eliminate RASPO from all columns after the second guess and E after the third. If I’m still stumped, I can eliminate G from the first and last column, I from the fourth, and so on, and see what’s left to make another guess to eliminate up to five more letters. Of course, in this example I’ve got all five letters by my third guess, so I could just turn off all but those letters, and maybe turn some back on, to eliminate additional positions.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik3a798/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijothr6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] As the resident Albuquerquean, I want to mention that the serial killer of Musli</title><updated>2022-08-10T07:03:10Z</updated><author><name>DuplexFields</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">As the resident Albuquerquean, I want to mention that the serial killer of Muslims has been found. At least one tip to the police was from a redditor in the Albuquerque subreddit who methodically searched Google Streetview for the suspect’s Jetta, which had small but significant damage in one place.

The killer targeted local Muslim men, mostly Shia but one Sunni. He lay in wait for his victims, hinting that he knew them personally. The community was devastated by the deaths and was also devastated by the killer’s identity: a Sunni gentleman who was known to be a bit off his rocker, and seems to have been motivated by his son marrying a Shiite girl.

The Albuquerque subreddit, a progressivist haven as most default-named subs tend to be, instantly stopped calling for fire to rain down from Washington DC onto Albuquerque’s red-hatted bigots, and started thoughtfully bemoaning extremism and mental health issues. They did manage to find a few outgroup tags to apply to the suspect, whose shares his first name with his Prophet and a few of his victims.

EDIT: I was just reported for a violent comment in the Albuquerque sub wherein I said (before his religion and race were known) that I hope the suspect gets the death penalty, in the form of a public hanging, after a fair trial and all applicable appeals, instead of life in prison. I got the warning only *after* it became known he’s a non-white Muslim with longstanding mental health issues.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijothr6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>