<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/DWXXV - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-29T17:24:38Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/DWXXV" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight F</title><updated>2022-07-29T17:24:38Z</updated><author><name>DWXXV</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Ready for a deep dive into something completely random?

Okay: Those Who Fight Further

In 1997 a little game came out called “Final Fantasy 7.” You may have heard of it. The game is wildly influential, often considered one of the best games of all time…and has aged like moderately fine vinegar. If you weren’t active in gaming at the time it’s hard to overstate the influence of the game. It was fantastic, for many people it changed what they thought games were capable of, and one of the spoilers was for decades afterwards (although less so now) was often uttered along with “Vader, father” as one of the top spoilers of all time.

A big part of the game was the music. Nobuo Uematsu and the rest of the sound team had been doing fantastic work with severe technical limitations for ten years at that point, and some of the music from this era transcends videogaming to become some of the best music period (I’d argue Chrono Trigger for this one). Uematsu loved progressive rock, and while he was excellent at classical compositions he loved to inject a flavor that was rare at the time into his music. Compare Dragon Quest with the average Final Fantasy battle theme. 

The music of FF 7 was fantastic. “One Winged Angel” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ce7gVYs7Em0) is still considered one of if not the best compositions in gaming. “Bombing Mission” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VCcSmvGrGx8) can be unironically (and has been) performed by a massive orchestra. 

Excellent battle tracks have always been a tradition in JRPGs, since you’ll be hearing a lot of them, and in the old days you had to stretch one track for almost all the fights in the game.

The battle track for FF 7 is “Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DotavimguEU). Limitations in fan translation resources and official releases resulted in this being generally translated (literally) as “Those Who Fight” if you wanted to pirate a MIDI and listen to it on a Walkman or something like that. Sometimes it would be translated as “Fighting” and later, official releases would land on “Let the Battles Begin!”

It’s fine. Not the best FF has done, but it wouldn’t get that stale for most people. Most encounters are short anyway.

Not so for boss battles. The boss battle theme needs to be a banger, especially in a game that mostly uses one theme for all the bosses.

AND IT FUCKING IS.  

“Sara ni Tatakau Monotachi” (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z_GUWdkJQgw) is still excellent, if limited by the technology of the time. Translated literally as “Those Who Fight Further” and occasionally as “Still More Fighting” the song often appears in top FF battle music lists. Later official translations would label it “Fight On!” which I think is a shame since it loses the character of the initial battle/boss battle names. Listening to it now you can tell that something great is hidden in this track limited by technology.

And we’ll get there.

In the years since the initial release FF 7 has remained influential. The music has been remixed thousands of times, it’s been a fixture in orchestral video game concerts, and Nobuo even made a metal band that plays some of these songs (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NzFh9GuE0rA). Gamers have been clamoring for a remake of the game. In 2020 they got it.

The game is controversial for reasons we won’t get into, but the music is not. With a massive team including the original composer they made a truly next gen sound track for a next gen game. Fans had some trepidation, these songs had been remixed by the community, professional composers, and the man himself tons of times. What were they going to do?

Well the answer was use everything learned about these songs and game composition over the last 20+ years. The soundtrack is absurdly good. From modern takes like an atmospheric exploration theme that turns into a battle theme when a fight starts (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5S49M40hv4) , to taking a one note joke enemy and turning it into an absurd and energetic boss battle (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQgXZ2HDiCQ). The game has everything.

The original battle theme still lives all over the game (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lu-dHQxxv4w), with variations to fit the mood and location of interest. But they hold back on the boss battle music. Yeah it shows up at the end of the first chapter (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AdGOnPsE-Xs). And it’s good. But is this it? Is this the epic remix?

No.

At the end of chapter 7 you fight a boss that was pretty much a joke in the original game. The fight is epic. And this fucking plays (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cQDLBKpbXQU). It has everything. I challenge you to drive the speed limit with this on. They held back, made you think they pretty whiffed on the remix for the boss theme, but they fucking stuck the landing. 

The rest of the soundtrack has some damn good tracks, but nothing injected nostalgia directly into my veins like The Airbuster. 

Never forget how powerful music can be.

Thank you for coming to my Ted Talk.

DW out. 

Anyone who has anything they want to add or correct is welcome!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/ii5i4vr/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>