<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/eBenTrovato - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-03T20:29:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/eBenTrovato" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib2t4nk/</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m a big fan of the anthology series *Inside No. 9*, a BBC show from the brilli</title><updated>2022-06-03T20:29:58Z</updated><author><name>eBenTrovato</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m a big fan of the anthology series *Inside No. 9*, a BBC show from the brilliant Reece Shearsmith and Steve Pemberton. The show is now in its seventh season and has undergone a transformative process that always fascinates me in long-running media: the same &#34;piece&#34; of entertainment essentially becoming a new work inside of itself.

Due to some combination of COVID restrictions around filming and the self-professed burnout/fatigue of its creators, the last two seasons of *Inside No. 9* have taken on a less whimsical, more indecipherable, and far more referential air than the preceding five (clearly paying homage to events or storylines from real life/other series as the creators grasp for ideas). I realized while trying to rank my favorite episodes that the series has evolved to the point where it&#39;s very difficult to compare the most recent episode to those from the opening season.

It&#39;s always interesting when this happens; I&#39;m thinking of things like *The Simpsons* trying to adapt to a world with *South Park* and *Family Guy* and losing its own identity in the process, *Game of Thrones* and its infamous failure to create any original material with the quality and complexity of the book series it could no longer adapt, *Pirates of the Caribbean* and *Star Wars* and *Fantastic Beasts* and many others starting out as action-packed interesting stories that had a need to be told and transforming into episodic serials with nothing at stake (indeed, this basically happened to Disney-Pixar as a company), *Succession* and *It&#39;s Always Sunny* starting out as tight-knit (if insane) character dramas and dissolving into flanderized versions of themselves as the creators burned out. What other works come to mind? Is this always a downward process toward worse material or has an entertainment property ever evolved into something better than its beginning stage over a long period of time?

But this all brings me to my bigger point: I believe that **creative burnout** will be the defining label of entertainment, business, and society as a whole in our current age. If woke, surface-level storylines with all the artistic quality of 1990s Christian family films have come to dominate the streaming menus and theatre marquees, I would argue that it&#39;s only because a total drought of creative energy preceded them. *Star Wars* became a paint-by-numbers corporate convention skit because there was no *creative urgency*; no **need** to innovate and tell a great story in a great way. That concept - **to be creatively great in a great way** - now seems to be a relic of the past (think how pathetic the legitimately great aspirational idealism of Walt Disney or Leonard Bernstein or Steve Jobs would sound in a corporate boardroom today at Disney or the New York Philharmonic or Apple). I don&#39;t see that creative *chutzpah* returning with Generation Z, the most conformist and politically-militant youth generation since children wore [patches depicting bundles of wood](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fasces#/media/File:Fasces.svg) on their jackets, so what&#39;s the outlook? Was this just an American postwar flash-in-the-pan? Are we bound to see the problem get worse or will there be an uptick in aspirational originality without the obsession of &#34;originality,&#34; in so many words?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib2t4nk/"/></entry></feed>