<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/EdenicFaithful - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-21T18:59:05Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/EdenicFaithful" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il85eue/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Kamachi&#39;s *A Certain Magical Index*, b</title><updated>2022-08-21T18:59:05Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m picking up Kamachi&#39;s *A Certain Magical Index*, book 1. The anime was...fascinating in strange ways. Every time the topic was science, it was incredibly compelling. On the other hand, every time the topic was magic, it was horribly dull. This had the unfortunate effect of making the show boring whenever Touma was on-screen, and the very fortunate effect of making the spin-off anime *A Certain Scientific Railgun* excellent. My theory is that the writer has a respectable IQ and excellent writing talent, so whenever there&#39;s some real-world basis (however distant) for his thoughts like the science parts, it&#39;s hard not to be sucked in. But whenever the topic is based on non-empirical things, all we get is a jumble of complex thoughts that can&#39;t be understood unless you&#39;re the author.

On reflection, Academy City is a very dark dream, a place where every citizen is an experiment, everyone is complicit, and criminality is institutionalized. Nevertheless the peace of the everyday lives of the characters is the true focus, together with a desire to hold on to gratitude at having met the people they call friends, despite the nature of the place that they met them in. Hopefully the book will bring out more of the compelling side of this author by giving more breathing room to his thoughts.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/il85eue/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>