<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/EdenicFaithful - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T16:08:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/EdenicFaithful" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of com</title><updated>2022-08-01T16:08:28Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Anyone know any good books on social media design?

The total elimination of compulsive browsing in my life has led me to see clearly how one&#39;s mind adapts to the things he interacts with. Social media seems to be the way things are because I use it, not because it is the way things are. Browsing seems like an effective means of getting information because it&#39;s the most present way that I&#39;m exposed to information, not because it is an effective means of getting information. And it&#39;s the most present way because something went wrong between the human-computer interaction.

I feel the need for something more compatible with this zen state of not hating everything. Even the things I actually care about are slipping away from my life unless I take the effort to hurt myself by reading garbage, so maybe I need something better.

Hopefully there are recognizable classics out there? Looking for anything: theories about interfaces, how to manage users, inside stories like that one about how they designed r/place...especially looking for ones that widely influenced the current industry, however annoyingly mainstream they are, and also any academic tomes that are well put together. The best I&#39;ve found is [this](https://www.researchgate.net/post/Any-good-books-about-designing-social-media) link, but everything else seems to be about marketing on social media.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiith8t/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat </title><updated>2022-07-31T18:49:40Z</updated><author><name>EdenicFaithful</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So, what are you reading?

I&#39;m still on Dreyfus&#39; *Underground*, about black hat hackers in the 90s. It&#39;s nice to read such a close account of something that I&#39;ve only vaguely heard of in news reports. So far Par&#39;s story has been gripping and sympathetic.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iiewoxb/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>