<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Electronic-Ant1533 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T06:24:25Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Electronic-Ant1533" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im85d0q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Why does the fat acceptance movement remind you of anti-trans ideology?** 

Ar</title><updated>2022-08-29T06:24:25Z</updated><author><name>Electronic-Ant1533</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Why does the fat acceptance movement remind you of anti-trans ideology?** 

Are the narrative frameworks of the fat acceptance movement and the anti-transgender movement the same? Both movements posit their respective issues as primarily cultural contagions that are exacerbated by the structure of 21st-century information technology. Additionally, both the fat acceptance movement and the anti-transgender movement imply that the obsession with aesthetics at the heart of American ills has, in the modern era, become the sole arbiter of ethical disagreements. The play-by-play comparison of the typical struggle-session accounts of each movements, I think, is even more revealing of their similarities. I have used scare quotes a lot here, to ensure that no one mistakes either of these opinions for my own.

**The narrative framework of fat acceptance advocates**

* The internet is a **dangerous device**.
* More specifically, the internet promotes the idea that women need to adhere to a specific beauty standard. Before the internet, this beauty standard &#34;didn&#39;t exist,&#34; or at least was not as intensely promoted.
* This beauty standard, of a thin waist, big breasts, etc. is unrealistic and unattainable. **Diets &#34;don&#39;t work&#34; -- that is to say, the media distorts how often people are able to successfully change their &#34;inherent&#34; weight. They are also &#34;dangerous&#34; -- they promote eating disorders**.
* People are brainwashed by the media to accept this aesthetic standard and spread it around their social networks.
* This beauty standard creates socially-derived depression in fat people (that is to say, if this beauty standard were not promoted by the media \[and then spread by people consuming the media\], then this depression would not occur). \*If promotion of this beauty standard did not happen, not only would fat people not be depressed, they would be perfectly happy in their bodies.

As a P.S., such an advocate might claim that there is historical revisionism afoot -- in all of human history, skinny beauty standards are &#34;quite rare.&#34; This is because our ancestors &#34;knew&#34; that skinniness was not a natural state to be in.

**The framework of anti-trans activists**

* The internet is a **dangerous device**.
* More specifically, the internet promotes the idea that people are secretly transgender. Before the internet existed, transgenderism &#34;didn&#39;t exist,&#34; or at least, was not as common.
* Pursuit of a cross-gender beauty standard is unrealistic and unattainable. **HRT and SRS &#34;don&#39;t work,&#34; that is to say, they don&#39;t make people happier, and are &#34;dangerous,&#34; sterilizing people in the pursuit of an aesthetic ideal**.
* People are brainwashed by the media on &#34;transgender ideology&#34; and spread it across their social networks.
* This promotion of &#34;transgender ideology&#34; creates socially-derived depression in people who &#34;think that they are trans&#34; (that is to say, if the &#34;trans ideology&#34; were not promoted by the MSM/social media \[and then spread by people consuming the media\], then this depression would not occur).
* If promotion of this beauty standard did not occur, not only would people who &#34;think that they are trans&#34; not be depressed, they would be perfectly happy in their bodies.

As a P.S., such an advocate might claim that there is historical revisionism afoot -- in all of human history, transgender identities are quite rare. This &#34;shows&#34; that in general, our ancestors &#34;knew&#34; that transgenderism was unnatural.

**What to make of this** 

It seems that ultimately this congruence results from very similar opinions on the average American locus of control. Both movements see people as fundamentally unable to self-evaluate in a media vacuum, and  both groups imply that we should automatically view opinions which mysteriously coincide with those of the MSM with suspicion.

## The radfem-trans activist beef, and its potential relation to the framework of the fat acceptance movement

The MSM (and social media) claims that the clashes between trans activists and radical feminists result from different opinions on gender essentialism. However, considering the overlap of the fat acceptance movement with radical feminist movements (as both question the ways in which women&#39;s bodies are policed), perhaps the origin of the skirmishes between trans and radfem is not even gender itself. Rather, the narratives each movement has woven rely on fundamentally different appraisals of history, culture, and self-determination, making rapprochement impossible.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im85d0q/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>