<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/EngageInFisticuffs - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T14:27:37Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/EngageInFisticuffs" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four differen</title><updated>2022-08-22T14:27:37Z</updated><author><name>EngageInFisticuffs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So reading some substacks has reminded me that there are basically four different kinds of writers on the culture war, or really any kind of commentary on conflict. 

1. Partisan propagandists. These are your Nathan J Robinsons. Their positions are predetermined, so their analyses are rarely anything but hackneyed. &#34;My side is good, the other side is bad,&#34; doesn&#39;t leave much room for nuance *or* actual insight. I used Robinson as an easy example, but there are plenty of weird Trumpists who somehow wanted to say that Russia were the good guys invading Ukraine. Although I&#39;ll totally admit that they&#39;re analyses weren&#39;t stale to start off with, they still quickly became predictable.

2. Cynics/insult analysts. I am struggling to come up with any examples right now, but there are a lot of these in respected editorial positions. These people sometimes have interesting analysis, but so often they resort to content-free insults in order to show their disdain and that they are above the conflict. Never do they ever have actually constructive things to say. They just tear stuff down.These types of analysts had their hey day in the 90s, but plenty of them are still going by inertia in respected legacy media even today. This is actually the group that annoys me the most and got me to write up this analysis because I always forget they exist, and I will be fooled into reading some article because it isn&#39;t just partisan drivel, only to realize that it is the equivalent of socio-political malingering and their delight in being unorthodox is an end-goal in itself.

3. (Un)orthodox ideologues. These are your Rod Drehers and Freddie DeBoers. Although they certainly have a side in the conflict, that side is just a means to an end, not a cause in itself. They have some greater vision that they are loyal to, and this allows them to see and critique &#34;their&#34; side in surprising and effective ways and see value in proposals from their &#34;opponents.&#34; These are the types of editorials that are really interesting to read.

4. Exhaustively fair analysts. These are the Scott Alexanders. This is the rarest type, at least in conflict commentary. Most of the people who do this are probably being paid plenty of money for private analysis. Or, if not private, at least largely wonky topics that most people don&#39;t care about. Still, these are the gold standard when it comes to commentary. Not just because if their analysis, they aren&#39;t necessarily any more insightful than the 3s, but because their attempts to engage with all opinions charitably makes them powerful when it comes to persuasion. 1s are also very powerful when it comes to persuasion with their audience, but only on whatever topics won&#39;t make them considered traitors to their cause/audience. Scott has no such limits, and as a result he has convinced people to change positions on all sorts of issues. He has made people more trans-sympathetic and turned leftists into free-market supporters.  But it is also the hardest to do. People have complained that Scott doesn&#39;t really dig in and engage with a lot of topics like he used to. This style of writing takes the most intellectual and emotional energy. It&#39;s much harder than when you already know everyone on the other side is bad and wrong and your side is good and right. Or everyone is just corrupt and stupid, no matter the side. Especially since it is hard to remain an insightful, charitable person once you have had the eye of sauron upon you. Just look at Jordan Peterson.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbpwre/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>