<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/escherofescher - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-11T15:41:05Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/escherofescher" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifqfwcp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I would appreciate if someone could provide feedback on this line of thinking. I</title><updated>2022-07-11T15:41:05Z</updated><author><name>escherofescher</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I would appreciate if someone could provide feedback on this line of thinking. It&#39;s something that occurred to me during a long evening walk and I can&#39;t decide whether this is a somewhat accurate map of the territory or a complete fabrication of some baser part of my mind.

Collectivism as a different mode of being. I had always assumed that people who lean toward it do so through a conscious choice, that they think through some sort of mini social contract, judge the benefits, and accept/reject it on merit before joining a group. Also, they&#39;re conscious and watchful while part of some group so that if the group breaks the contract, they would leave it.

But what if it&#39;s not a conscious choice? What if, whoever dips their head under the collectivist waterline, surrenders their &#34;self&#34; and their brain becomes a substrate for running the collective&#39;s distributed OS?

Perhaps it will help if I describe what lead me to this train of thought. I imagined a person deeply enmeshed in some collective identity. If you&#39;re in the US, imagine a woman with short blue hair, her face full of piercings, a t-shirt that says &#34;long live Che&#34;, a pair of Doc Marten&#39;s, and NPR blaring on her headphones. Or, to balance things out, imagine an obese man driving a leased pickup truck with one American and one Gadsden flag, listening to a radio version of One America Network&#39;s report about election fraud.

What these two stereotype images have in common is that it seems both of these people have surrendered their minds to a collective. In other words, they outsource their opinion-formation and worldview out to a group of people. Do they still reason? Are they critical of new information? Do they introspect? Or do they merely think what their chosen collective tells them to think?

I&#39;ve met many people that fall somewhere farther or closer to these stereotypes. And one characteristic that always strikes me is that they communicate in the same way: repeating slogans or headlines from their preferred media source (or social media milieu), ie. they&#39;re outputting canned rhetoric someone cooked up for them. Because of that, they can&#39;t actually engage in a discussion because they can&#39;t respond to arguments. They can only shoot back these prepackaged messages.

Going down this slippery slope, talking with people like this doesn&#39;t mean engaging with a reasoning individual, but with a tentacle of a much larger organism. Basically, an alien.

Eh, I know that to some this must sound like an edgy 16 yo&#39;s, &#34;2deep4you&#34; line of thinking. I think I bring it up because it&#39;s dawning on me just how differently different people think and it&#39;s freaking me out. I think one of my core beliefs was that people reason more or less in the same way, but observing people is shaking things up in my mind.

So, is there any merit to this? Any threads in the form of reading I could pull to understand this side of humanity better? Any gross mistakes in this view?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifqfwcp/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>