<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/escherofescher - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-25T12:40:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/escherofescher" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilq5bo5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Why hasn&#39;t American support for Ukraine wavered since February?

Disclaimer: Thi</title><updated>2022-08-25T12:40:27Z</updated><author><name>escherofescher</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Why hasn&#39;t American support for Ukraine wavered since February?

Disclaimer: This is some &#34;armchair general&#34;-level thinking put into words.

When the war began, I was afraid American support would soon disappear, come any newsworthy crisis. But it&#39;s been 6 months and support seems as strong as ever, at least judging by the recent 3bn military transfer along with the number of blue-and-yellow emojis on twitter. For many reasons, I think this war is not only a great chance to beat back Russian expansionism, but also to bring Ukraine closer to the west, hence why this question is important for me.

So--why do Americans seem so eager to help Ukraine?

My take is that it&#39;s mainly because they&#39;re acting out values that we admire.

Zelensky, for one, didn&#39;t run away and has remained deeply engaged throughout the conflict. As have many Ukrainians, both men and women, who chose to either stay behind or go back after the initial exodus. But it&#39;s not just personal courage that&#39;s delivered to us via news reports that we admire--it&#39;s also the example of national unity.

It struck me how low of an opinion Americans have to Afghans and Iraqis. The boots on the ground critique has focused on how cowardly or lazy their soldiers are, but I think the bigger reason for American disdain for them is their complete lack of national allegiance.  Perhaps I&#39;m talking out of my ass, but these two societies don&#39;t exactly fit the definition of society because they&#39;re more like a loose collection of tribes. In that sense, what they did made absolute sense: why risk your life for a different tribe? But from an American, even a Western perspective, this looks like a complete lack of skin in the game, especially in view of the recent news pouring out of the country of what their women are now subject to what with the taliban in power. The unspoken question is: why didn&#39;t they fight to protect their society and their way of life? (Taking into account a handful of individuals who did the needful).

I think Americans will continue to support Ukraine for the near future, at least another year or two because the Ukrainians are behaving in ways that Americans, irrespective of political leanings, can admire.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilq5bo5/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>