<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Evinceo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-30T20:47:19Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Evinceo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imfp7ja/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Is data truth?**

Since I owed a reply to /u/Im_not_JB here: https://www.reddi</title><updated>2022-08-30T20:47:19Z</updated><author><name>Evinceo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Is data truth?**

Since I owed a reply to /u/Im_not_JB here: https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/comment/ilvutba/

I&#39;m gonna try and figure out where we are with WikiLeaks.

Wikileaks has come from the perspective that information wants to be free, that leaks hold people accountable, and that releasing all available data is the best way to do so.

I think that this came from the same place of Aaron Schwartz, Jimbo Whales techno-utopian anti-state idealism that was in the air around the mid to late aughts. Compare the [Declaration Of Independence Of Cyberspace](https://www.eff.org/cyberspace-independence).

We now live in that world, where it&#39;s easy to disseminate vast dumps of data. It&#39;s available to anyone. But now that we have it, I wonder if it&#39;s really the best approach. Because what we end up getting is just data. It doesn&#39;t come with the tools to analyze it, and in the absence of analysts by competent folks, we get The Internet doing its own sleuthing. From misidentifying the Boston Bomber to pizzagate, I can think of examples of information overload harming rather than helping.

And that makes me lean back towards the journalistic approach of combining data with analysis and responsibility. I can think of plenty of hard hitting stories like the Panama papers that _did_ work out.

I think the profession of journalism won. I don&#39;t think it can or should be replaced by blindly dumping any data you can get your hands on and calling it journalism.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imfp7ja/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>