<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/exiledouta - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-15T17:32:53Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/exiledouta" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/igafeex/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **How does someone come to the conclusion that they are transgendered?**

I&#39;m fa</title><updated>2022-07-15T17:32:53Z</updated><author><name>exiledouta</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**How does someone come to the conclusion that they are transgendered?**

I&#39;m fairly liberal in the freedom sense living in a very blue tribe area with very blue tribe loved ones. Most of these loved ones are very on board with the trans movements and I would desperately like to agree with them. I have read much and believe I understand where most of the big differences between conservatives, gender critical feminists, trans medicalists and gender affirming approaches to the broad subject. I do think each of these different contingents have their own kernel of truth but none of them really seems to by itself describe reality as I see it. 

This post is about self identification or how someone answers the self directed form of the infamous question &#34;what is a woman&#34;, that is &#34;Am I a woman?&#34; in their own head and my dissatisfaction with how all of the above factions approach it but mostly the gender affirming camp as they&#39;re the ones I&#39;m most consistently in disharmony with in my day to day life. 

When I truly try to put myself in the shoes of a young person attempting to tackle the question &#34;am I a woman&#34; I am presented with a couple interlocking challenges. 

1. The actual definition of what a woman is

For the conservatives and gender critical crowd this is fairly straightforward. It&#39;s a matter of what set of genitals you were born with and the rare exceptions where there are defects are to be handled on a case by case basis. 

Trans medicalists are defined pretty much exactly by their difference to the gender affirming camp by having a straight forward answer to this question but in doing so excluding some people. A Woman is either a female who does not experience some form of Body Integrity Dysphoria relating to sexual traits or a male who does. 

The gender affirming camp tends to approach this question in a lot of ways but they tend to boil down to a &#34;woman is someone who believes they&#39;re a woman&#34; and my problem with this definition and nearly all other formulations is what inspired this post and 

\2. How can I, with my single point of perspective determine whether I fit in this definition.

For conservatives and gender critical feminists this and the next part are quite easy. You appeal to your physical characteristics and in the very rare edge cases(intersex and similar situations) where this is not obvious you appeal to the community to find the most natural solution expecting grace from those around you on the subject.

For trans medicalists this is also fairly straightforward. If you experience strong dysphoria relating to your sexual characteristics then you are trans.

**Now the big one and the meat of this post.** How can someone armed only with the circular self identification definition actually evaluate if they are a woman? We&#39;re each only endowed with one first person experience and are unable to directly access the experience of a member of the opposite sex to compare and contrast our internal experience. There is no binary light in my head when I close my eyes that glows blue, no proof to myself that I am a man and no proof that I am not a woman. I can&#39;t possibly distinguish between the internal states &#34;I am a man(assigned male at birth) that incorrectly suspects I am actually a woman&#34; and &#34;I am a woman(assigned male at birth) who correctly suspects that I am a woman&#34;. With the total absence of proof, as this imagined child grappling with the question, I&#39;m terrified of the possibility of getting it wrong. 

\3. given that I am or am not a woman what do I do?

This is where the conservatives and gender critical feminists diverge radically. Conservatives expect women to lean into the traditional stereotypes while gender critical feminists consider those stereotypes harmful. And the trans medicalists and gender affirmation camps recombine to strangely enough agree widely with the conservatives on the stereotypes but just not the populations to apply them to. 

------------------------------------------------------

I&#39;d be grateful to anyone who can convince me that there isn&#39;t a huge problem here with the gender affirming approach because it would be far less stressful to be in dissonance with so many around me. I want to be convinced but not at the cost of not strongly believing the solution is correct. Feel free to also correct me if my modeling of how the other groups answer these questions seems wrong to you, in particular I think the conservative camp is probably very low resolution here.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/igafeex/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>