<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/f3zinker - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-07T15:36:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/f3zinker" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijbl7th/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] This is probably suited better for the Wednesday thread but I&#39;ll post anyways be</title><updated>2022-08-07T15:36:30Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">This is probably suited better for the Wednesday thread but I&#39;ll post anyways because its been bothering me a lot lately. 

Lately I have been getting a lot of disturbing imagery in my head. Randomly pop up and ruin my mood. Now the part worth noting here is that its not disturbing in the traditional sense; gore, etc.. But in a more metaphysical/psychological sense. To put it shortly similar to how the main character in Crime and Punishment felt. 

For example. Lets say I didn&#39;t treat a person the most kindly. Or lost my temper, or acted along those lines. The following weeks. I will get imagery of that person mutilated in a car accident. Or withering away in a hospital bed, or something of the sort. 

Now as far as the average person is concerned. I am quite calm and patient. I rarely ever lose my temper, or treat people badly, intentionally. So I really don&#39;t know why would my subconscious feel guilt or whatever else. Because I consciously hold myself to what I consider very high standards of interpersonal behavior. 

I have meditated on this and come to the conclusion that I will take the burden of being the most calm, the most patient and not bring any harm to anyone even if that means going through great discomfort myself. Not bring any further pain to the world. To rid myself of the &#34;evil spirit&#34; or pay any debt *metaphorical* debt I have.

But I really don&#39;t understand what could be the reason for this. I am not too fond on psychoanalysis, but I would be open to some bullshit story that at least explains away some of this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijbl7th/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij1vpdj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Lex Fridman released a [5 hour long podcast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I84</title><updated>2022-08-05T13:35:35Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Lex Fridman released a [5 hour long podcast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I845O57ZSy4) with John Carmack (probably one of the best programmers ever). Definitely a treat for programmers of various stripes.

_______________________________________

On a side-note I want to discuss a potential weakness/strength of rationalist discourse. 

At one point in this podcast Lex says &#34;maybe aliens will visit us sometime in the future and they will see almost everything is running on javascript&#34;. Basically wrapping &#34;at the rate things are going, its probable that everything will run on javascript eventually&#34; with a cute little story. 

I realized I would be much more impulsively skeptical if told the latter than the former. I want to know if anyone else would have this tendency as well. 

I mean wrapping ideas and concepts in stories is quite literally culture, but I think its something that should be done judiciously when the ideas are not as universally agreeable, the rationalists do have a habit of doing this a whole lot. And thinking in stories and wrapping your internal thought process in them might just make you more susceptible to bullshit.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij1vpdj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>