<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/f3zinker - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-31T23:30:11Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/f3zinker" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaq10hk/</id><title type="text">[SQ] Would operating under a negative utilitarian moral framework lock you into econo</title><updated>2022-05-31T23:30:11Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Would operating under a negative utilitarian moral framework lock you into economically left wing positions?

I think so because those on the economic left give greater weight to suffering under economic destitution than negative utility experienced by having to give away large chunks of your income, and that seems to be a well defended motte to be in, its hard to argue for the inverse. 

A truly capitalistic system would also entail tremendous short term suffering for some classes of people, for the &#34;losers&#34;. This does not imply that net utility isn&#39;t greater in the long term. But many might not have the stomach to allow for that deadwood to burn out or let those who are destined to fall through the cracks as they would, even if it means for those who wouldn&#39;t everything would be a lot better.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaq10hk/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iajkoec/</id><title type="text">[CW] **Metastasizing Memes**. 

*Assumptions*: *The phenomenon I am talking about act</title><updated>2022-05-30T13:40:30Z</updated><author><name>f3zinker</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Metastasizing Memes**. 

*Assumptions*: *The phenomenon I am talking about actually exists in sufficient levels and has the potential to materialize into some sort of cultural change.* 

I don&#39;t know if a specific term exists for this phenomenon. The phenomenon I am describing is when some event has some kind of primary meme but there are other supporting ideas/narratives/memes to prop up the primary meme as well. However, when the event is well and done with, sometimes the secondary memes can stay around and have the potential to &#39;metastasize&#39; into malignant cultural notions.

For example the covid restrictions edifying meta-narrative had a lot of novel supportive ideas such as &#39;masks work&#39;,&#39;closing economies is a viable tool when handling disease outbreaks&#39; or &#39;states mandating vaccines is well within the western social contract&#39;. A few orders removed from covid one of them is &#39;***[children are resilient](https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/969604)***&#39;. 

I am writing this because I think that one is one of the more underhanded the ideas that I see sticking around and am surprised that it caught on at all. I have recently seen this sentiment across multiple reddit threads on the topic of children and on top of this phrase being used explicitly, people just seem to have a less protective attitude towards children&#39;s mental health.

I find this phrase especially irritating because its so nonsensical. Children are the least resilient of all classes of humans. They might be resilient on an absolute scale relative to how fragile we think they are, but saying &#39;X is Y&#39; actually implies &#39;X is Y relative to Z&#39; which is absolutely not the case. It seems to be a total 180 from which I see as the more correct analysis which happens to be the opposite of this statement, and was the majority sentiment in modern western culture pre-2020. Why not just say &#34;children are more resilient than we think&#34; if that was the intent?. The fact its a quip three word phrase with maximum ambiguity tells me its that way by design/memetics. 

Now one can argue that the prevalence and potential growth of this sentiment is a positive recorrection given that children are overly coddled in western and in particular American culture. 

However, I don&#39;t think it would pan out in the way most around these parts would want it to unfold. The usage of the phrase is used in cases where the mental health of children worsening is a tradeoff, not their physical health. 

It&#39;s plenty evident that covid is a non physical threat for children but there was still plenty of sentiment to &#39;protect&#39; children from covid, their mental health on the other hand was thrown on the wayside on policy considerations. 

One can say society giving less credence to children&#39;s mental health is still a good thing because [too much of that gave us &#39;snowflakes&#39;](https://www.thecoddling.com/) and there are a thousand other trends showing more care is given to children&#39;s mental health. Firstly I would say I don&#39;t think more care is actually given to mental health, a lot of it is just plain culture warring (hormone blockers, etc). However, that&#39;s a dead horse and popular sentiment around here, I won&#39;t flesh that out any further.

Secondly, it would be amazing that if we could take people at their word for it but I don&#39;t think there is some sort of cultural awakening to the notion that you can over-coddle children, I think its a sign of something much more sinister. That when you need to REALLY engage in the culture war, the wellness of children can be given lesser weight as a potential tradeoff, it&#39;s not sacred, it&#39;s just another tradeoff you have to make or a tradeoff that you can collectively ignore.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iajkoec/"/></entry></feed>