<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/FiveHourMarathon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-15T01:19:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/FiveHourMarathon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig7g4dp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] *New York Magazine* published [this](https://www.thecut.com/2022/07/harvey-weins</title><updated>2022-07-15T01:19:26Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">*New York Magazine* published [this](https://www.thecut.com/2022/07/harvey-weinstein-biography-body-shame.html) tabloid revelation. TLDR: Weinstein had weird deformed genitals, possibly as a result of gangrene[!] which may have lead to amputation of both testicles[!!!]. He also may have been severely impotent, requiring pre-coital injections to maintain an erection. Reportedly the jury saw photos of his genital region during the trial [to confirm testimony], and were visibly disgusted.

I&#39;m torn on the reporting of this and the framing of it as an explanatory factor in his actions. It&#39;s tempting to frame him as a sad man. &#34;Hurt people hurt people.&#34; People reach for these explanations to offer themselves a measure of control. It&#39;s not that rape is a fairly expected outcome of giving men that kind of power and failing to restrain it through social or legal means, or alternatively that we have to cope with the presence of certain evil men in our society, instead it shuffles blame into a nebulous idea that by a series of accidents sometimes there&#39;s a fat guy with a mean mom who loses his genitals in a freak and happens to have a lot of power over a lot of beautiful women. But that series of accidents isn&#39;t really preventable, it&#39;s just the universe, man.

And it has little explanatory power. Ok Weinstein had weird junk, did Lauer, did Epstein, did Prince Andrew, did Deshaun Watson? Or do they all get their own little just-so story that explains their behavior? When do we come around to actually confronting human nature as it exists rather than blaming the dark sides of it on aberrant chances?

I almost find myself wishing this information hadn&#39;t been published, because it retards progress on understanding rape in our society. It is clearly not the action of a psychotic minority of men, but a predilection that lurks within a significant minority of men and must be managed and prevented by policy and personal choices. Our society has this annoying tendency to say that we understand that anyone might be tempted to steal or kill, but only a sick man would think of rape. Then be shocked when so many men engage in pushing the boundaries of consent. 

The piece tries to take that stance, talking about how it is important to see rapists as people not as monsters. I&#39;d say talking about how his balls rotted off renders him more rather than less monstrous and inhuman and unusual. Less relatable, less normal. We need to confront the fact that there is no just-so story and no magic trick to preventing rape, that it is no different than preventing most crimes which people want to commit.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig7g4dp/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>