<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/FiveHourMarathon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-26T13:38:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/FiveHourMarathon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihpow7l/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Has Modern Capitalism Lost Track of the Idea of the Gimmick?**

Wall Street ha</title><updated>2022-07-26T13:38:24Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Has Modern Capitalism Lost Track of the Idea of the Gimmick?**

Wall Street had a day of talking about nothing but [Snapchat](https://finance.yahoo.com/m/054b5080-cb67-3e13-8265-dab2917f384a/snap-stock-tumbles-as.html) as its parent company lost 30% of its value after a bad earnings report. Advertising revenues are down across the board, as Apple and others have instituted better privacy protections for users, and the economy seems headed for a general downturn so ad revenues will likely follow.

[Snap](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snap_Inc.) for those of you that aren&#39;t aware, is a messaging app that send self-destructing picture/video and sometimes text messages. When it launched, it was the first service to really make the disappearing pic/video big, and that made it popular with teenagers/20-somethings who wanted to send pictures that they might be embarrassed by later. Besides the obvious sexting use-case (the privacy was of course much worse than promised), I also recall having a lot of male friends that loved to send me pictures of their giant poops as a gag, and people liked to use it at parties to send drunken videos that wouldn&#39;t last any longer than necessary. Its use was always casual, no one wrote a thesis on Snapchat the way they have on Twitter/Reddit or made art on it the way they have on Instagram/TikTok. Its primary use case was dicking around with your friends, and the professional ecosystem built around that because people were already on snapchat, at core it&#39;s a [Gimmick](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gimmick).

Somehow this got turned into a market cap of over $100,000,000,000; 80% of which has been erased this year. The company has only once turned an actual profit, and while the founders are now immensely wealthy it is as a result of selling equity in the &#34;future&#34; of Snapchat rather than from money actually paid by advertisers or users of Snapchat. Somebody is going to, or already has, lost a lot of money on this.

And it&#39;s summer, so I&#39;m thinking of summer trips to the Jersey Shore as a kid, and the Surf Mall on the boardwalk that was like a big pseudo-department store with every summer fad or gimmick of the year. I think I&#39;ve been inside it most years since about 1998 or so, and every year the majority of their entire stock of stuff is different. One year it&#39;s drug rug hoodies, the next year it is marvel themed sweatshirts, the next everything is in a certain shade of pink. Baseball cards become Pokemon cards become YuGiOh cards become Funko Pops (I think? I&#39;m still not entirely sure what those are beyond hearing them in sneers) comes all the way back around to first edition Holo Charizard Pokemon Cards. 

And I&#39;m thinking about it, the Surf Mall proprietors if you asked them would say they need to make money on whatever they are selling before it goes out of fashion, and run their business each year at a profit on that item. And their suppliers would say, we&#39;re selling these sweatshirts at a price where we can make money this year before they go out of fashion next year and then we&#39;ll make something else, whether they are manufactured in NJ or in Sichuan they are able to figure out what their customer will move to. I feel like that&#39;s what we&#39;ve lost in this business environment, you get a gimmick you and recognize it and you cash in while you can, then move on. Snapchat was a gimmick, it was always a gimmick, and anyone who knew teenagers using it would have said &#34;Yeah, this is a gimmick.&#34; A business like that should have been trying to actually make money off its business while the going was good. What is it that leads to this attitude:

1) Is it that everyone is trying to get the next Amazon or Google? Are all these investors just foolishly playing the lottery? Are they all lemmings following a few leaders on CNBC or whatever who fell for the lottery approach?

2) On a related note, cult of the founder? Snapchat&#39;s founding pair will always control 98% of voting shares, much like WeWork before them, were investors snookered by a few charismatic guys?

3) Generation gap expanding? Maybe middle aged businessmen get physical fads like Pokemon cards because they saw similar things when they were teens, but digital fads confuse them because they didn&#39;t experience them. This should become less true over time, as digital generations age, but it does not seem to be. It would have been obvious, in my mind, to any 19 year old sexting on Snap that Snap was not a $100bn company for the future, it was a fun thing you would stop doing soon enough. There&#39;s a disconnect between the customer and the investor somewhere.

4) Cult of the future? I&#39;m probably more plugged into fashion than most Motte-izens, and you see this as well in fashion companies where brands are constantly decried for not keeping up with the times, or alternatively for selling out when they get big, when the reasonable explanation for the vast majority of brands is that they&#39;re big for a while and then they disappear. Most apps are the same, they&#39;re a fad for a bit, then they fail. Why are we so consistently expecting top 1% scenarios from every business, rather than looking for 50th percentile performance?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihpow7l/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>