<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/FiveHourMarathon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-03T15:40:33Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/FiveHourMarathon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib1qp8g/</id><title type="text">[FF] So stuck at home with Covid, I watched the entire [first season of *Love Island </title><updated>2022-06-03T15:40:33Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">So stuck at home with Covid, I watched the entire [first season of *Love Island Australia*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Island_Australia) with my wife across the last week. **Never has there been a more perfect demonstration of how male confidence functions than this show.**

For those of you unaware, Love Island is a dating game show, where you find a bunch of female and male tanned sluts who want to get on tv and aren&#39;t peculiarly bright, and you lock 12 of them at a time in a vacation villa. Everyone has to form a couple, and the producers add and subtract people as they go, with new people having to find a partner and the odd-men-out getting booted (or sometimes getting booted by contestant/public votes). The last couple left wins the cash prize. So everyone is always trying to either strengthen the relationship they have, or seek out a new one if they don&#39;t think the current one is going anywhere.

For whatever reason, on this particular season of Love Island, there was very little love. Connections were not made by the majority of contestants, and by halfway through it was obvious who would win because there were only like two couples and the girls had formed this weird culture of rejecting every new guy that came in. But what was still interesting was the way the process impacted the contestants. One after another, you had these jacked and tan Aussie gigachads coming into the Villa full of piss and vinegar and confidence, dead certain they would get any girl they wanted, probably because that&#39;s their experience in the real world. You had [tall jacked techno DJs](https://loveisland.fandom.com/wiki/John_James_Parton), [literal Harley riding male strippers](https://loveisland.fandom.com/wiki/Jaxon_Human), and [mutiple](https://loveisland.fandom.com/wiki/Elias_Chigros) [Male Models](https://loveisland.fandom.com/wiki/Justin_Lacko). One after another they all strike out completely, and you could just watch their confidence drain out of them as they stayed week after week. A lot of these guys either self-eliminated and went home on their own, or just gave up and stopped trying to hit on anyone, because they had gotten rejected so many times so harshly. You could watch as their approaches went from &#34;Hey babe, want to oil my muscles&#34; to fawning and overeager, and listen to the girls talk about how the desperation was a turnoff.

I feel like there&#39;s a valuable lesson for single men trying to figure out dating somewhere in there. Something like, confidence is situational, and nothing will provide you with objective confidence in all situations, you just need to maintain your self-worth and play your part. Josh, who ultimately finished third despite not getting any romantic connections until late in the season, stayed within himself and adapted to his part, so when a new girl came in he didn&#39;t fuck it up. Jaxon let it get to him, and became so desperate he started second guessing himself, and didn&#39;t stand a chance. So maybe you can find some wisdom in odd places.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v3s27m/friday_fun_thread_for_june_03_2022/ib1qp8g/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iamdvj4/</id><title type="text">[CW] In honor of Memorial Day, and because I just finished Tooze&#39;s *The Deluge*, let&#39;</title><updated>2022-05-31T03:16:23Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In honor of Memorial Day, and because I just finished Tooze&#39;s *The Deluge*, let&#39;s jump back to one of the great moments of &#34;Donald Trump get&#39;s in trouble for telling the truth.&#34;

[Trump Faces Fallout From Report He Calls Military &#39;Suckers&#39;](https://www.npr.org/2020/09/04/909599762/trump-faces-fallout-from-report-he-calls-military-losers-and-suckers)

Merriam Webster defines a Sucker as (among other irrelevant things):

&amp;gt;: a person easily cheated or deceived

But there&#39;s an absent actor in the definition, who was the one who cheated them, who took advantage of their gullibility?

The reason the usual neoliberal suspects were offended by WWI war dead being called suckers wasn&#39;t the implication that the soldiers were stupid, it was the implication that their man Woodrow Wilson was the Con-Man in the exchange.  Which is just, objectively true. Woodrow Wilson really did con the country into a bad war, which lead to a worse peace, and an even worse war after that.

[Wilson&#39;s slogan for the November 1916 Election was &#34;He Kept Us Out of War&#34;](https://www.whitehouse.gov/about-the-white-house/presidents/woodrow-wilson/). Wilson would lead the country *into* the war just five months later. If you assume that soldiers have a sacred duty to serve in a democracy because their actions represent the will of the people, well the people voted as close to a referendum against the war as we&#39;d ever get, and we still got the war. Sounds like they got sold a bill of goods.

But ok, it was necessary for Wilson to go to war to &#34;make the world safe for Democracy.&#34; Well, just to look at some particular cases, [400,000 Black soldiers served in WWI](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/retropolis/wp/2017/09/22/african-american-world-war-i-soldiers-served-at-a-time-racism-was-rampant-in-the-u-s/), and [225,000 Jewish Soldiers including 4 Medal of Honor recipients](https://nmajmh.org/stories/over-there-profiles-of-american-jews-in-world-wwi/) served as well. Well, after the war, when the League of Nations was being hammered out, [Japan proposed a Racial Equality Clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racial_Equality_Proposal), which the USA shot down for even *implying* that the races might be equal. It&#39;s not clear that Japan meant *all* the races, but the USA blanched at language that might even hint that they would need to treat Blacks as equal citizens. Black Americans would continue to be denied their right to vote in the democracy of their birth for years to come. Jews would face formal and informal discrimination throughout American society, and it wouldn&#39;t go so hot for them in Europe either. Sure seems like that&#39;s 600,000 soldiers who didn&#39;t get what they paid (some, the ultimate price) for.

But even giving him credit for what he was trying to do, Wilson lied to the American people, especially to those soldiers, because he never had the power to deliver a victory that would be worth the effort. [One of the great fifth grade English class works of American literature, *Where the Red Fern Grows*](https://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;amp;pid=sites&amp;amp;srcid=Z3JlZW52aWxsZXNjaG9vbHMudXN8bXItZXxneDo3ZTQ2YWQyZDFhZDBmYjUw) has a great scene where the protagonist&#39;s young hunting dogs get a raccoon up an enormous tree, and he despairs of being able to cut it down, and the dogs look at him as if to say:

&amp;gt;&#34;You told us to put one in a tree and you would do the rest.&#34;

Even though his hands bleed from the ax, he cuts that enormous tree down and they get the raccoon. That&#39;s the bond between leader and follower: you do your part and I&#39;ll do mine. You put in the effort and make the sacrifices, and trust that I have a plan that will work.

Well, the American Marines laying in Belleau Wood treed the German raccoon, and Wilson very much failed to do the rest. I&#39;m sure we all know the sad story of Wilson being outmaneuvered by Clemenceau and George at Versailles, and winding up with a punitive treaty that destroyed the German state. Then with that pathetic treaty in hand, he couldn&#39;t get that obvious bad idea ratified by the Senate, leaving America with nothing. The net result of WWI, of the immense sacrifices made by thousands of American soldiers, was to set the stage for their sons to go back and fight an even more destructive war so they could hand half of Europe to Stalin. Because Wilson couldn&#39;t follow through, he couldn&#39;t do his part after the soldiers had secured victory and secure a durable, workable peace. That was the promise he made, implicitly, to American soldiers, and he didn&#39;t deliver; he defrauded them.

So this Memorial Day, let&#39;s recognize that so many of the brave men who thought they were dying for America were being fleeced out of their sacrifice, and let&#39;s recognize who the people doing the fleecing were, and let&#39;s recognize when their intellectual descendants are trying to fleece us again.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iamdvj4/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iak805z/</id><title type="text">[SQ] When exactly did Purses become a feminine concept in American culture? It seems </title><updated>2022-05-30T16:41:16Z</updated><author><name>FiveHourMarathon</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">When exactly did Purses become a feminine concept in American culture? It seems like one of the most arbitrary ideas of gender we have in our culture, yet it is one of the most rigid cultural points. A man carrying anything smaller than a backpack or a briefcase is near universally (if lightly) mocked, and I can&#39;t think of any good reasoning behind it. I recall this even being formalized at airports and ballgames when I was a kid, where my mom and sister could carry a purse, but my father and I were not, as a matter of policy. What&#39;s the history there?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iak805z/"/></entry></feed>