<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/fkakenNfjakx629 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-28T12:56:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/fkakenNfjakx629" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihzgukn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Is &#34;cultural genocide&#34; actually bad? I think it&#39;s non controversial that actual </title><updated>2022-07-28T12:56:40Z</updated><author><name>fkakenNfjakx629</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Is &#34;cultural genocide&#34; actually bad? I think it&#39;s non controversial that actual genocide, ala murdering/ driving people out of the area and taking their land is not good. However I&#39;ve been thinking about forced assimilation lately and how it gets a super bad wrap in progressive and even moderate circles. 

Things like taking indigenous children and forcing them to learn in  missionary schools are nowadays treated as a moral outrage. Whereas back in the day these works would be celebrated as a civilizing mission of the white man&#39;s burden. Yet I feel like for technologically &#34;backwards&#34; populations that would otherwise be outcompeted in the labor market, this type of cultural assimilation gives their generations children the best hope of succeeding in a competitive world.

One main point where I differ from my friends is believing that the Uyghur re-education camps in western China are probably the least-bad policy choice the Chinese government has to pacify the region. Yes it&#39;s heavy handed, and the implementation has likely been highly flawed, but fundamentally when you have a separatist minority that visibly practices different cultural customs AND every now and then commits domestic terrorism acts, either you lock everyone up ala manzanar or you do your best to use a carrot and stick approach to get them to conform to the same value systems as your majority population. Why is jobs  training and de-radicalization bad? I&#39;m sure as with any large scale government program there are abuses and corruption at all levels, but fundamentally teaching people the majoritarian language is something every state needs for state capacity.

 In China&#39;s case, the Hui are another Muslim minority but wholly integrated with the Han through the work of their leaders during the warlord era and even earlier. Would that not be preferred than having a separatist community with worse living standards?


The Europeans for example should do the same to their various underclasses (obviously less hamfisted since either don&#39;t have authoritarian control) like the Romani, and hope that in the future more Romani become lawyers or doctors to where the stigma of ethnic differentiation and prejudices goes away. 

When immigrants migrate to a new country most of them actively seek to conform because they chose the country they moved to. They will syncretize and being bubble tea and chicken biryani to our restaurants but still adopt our individualistic morals and watch game of thrones.

Any time where borders move over people, this is much more challenging because the people didn&#39;t choose to be conquered/absorbed. So if there is a risk of unrest, especially when a significant number of the conquering empires population has already moved in, the least bad option is assimilation and coexistenve as opposed to extermination.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihzgukn/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>