<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/gamedori3 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-31T15:13:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/gamedori3" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iao602x/</id><title type="text">[CW] Our Korean medical institution just posted an announcement informing staff of pr</title><updated>2022-05-31T15:13:34Z</updated><author><name>gamedori3</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Our Korean medical institution just posted an announcement informing staff of precautions to take (and symptoms to look for) related to monkeypox infection, and I would like to reflect on it here as it brought back very strong memories of the early days of Covid. 

First, about monkeypox. Monkeypox is a poxvirus (same family as smallpox, chickenpox) which is known to be transmissible by contact with bodily fluids and by contact with contaminated fabrics. The memorandum sent by my institution says that it is *suspected* to be transmissible by droplets. In this context, droplets are airborne particles larger than aerosols. While an N95 mask is generally required to control airborne infections, a paper surgical mask is generally sufficient when handling droplet infections. So, what does our institution recommend? 

The official policy of our institution in the case of a verified case of monkeypox is patients who test positive for monkeypox to be kept in a negative-pressure room *with full airborne disease precautions*, and requires the attending medical staff to wear a **Level D suit with PAPR** (red underlined text in the original memo): a big white balloon suit, complete with air tank.

Meanwhile, the CDC (in the US) has some recommendations of its own. The CDC&#39;s guide for [&#34;Infection Control: Healthcare Settings | Monkeypox&#34;](https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/monkeypox/clinicians/infection-control-healthcare.html) reads 

&amp;gt; Activities that could resuspend dried material from lesions, e.g., use of portable fans, dry dusting, sweeping, or vacuuming should be avoided. ... A patient with suspected or confirmed monkeypox infection should be placed in a single-person room; special air handling is not required. The door should be kept closed (if safe to do so). The patient should have a dedicated bathroom. Transport and movement of the patient outside of the room should be limited to medically essential purposes. If the patient is transported outside of their room, they should use well-fitting source control  (e.g., medical mask) and have any exposed skin lesions covered with a sheet or gown.

So we have a tale of two responses. The US CDC gives an &#34;evidence-based&#34; response: poxviruses are not known to be transmissible in the air, and are known to be transmissible by bodily fluids. The US CDC would have us worry about contamination from skin lesions. Meanwhile, the Korean response is to apply the precautionary principle: droplet transmission has not been ruled out, so patients go in the negative pressure ward and doctors wear full biohazard suits.

I think there&#39;s a cultural difference in this response to monkeypox. Part of this is that I remember the exact same dynamics in the our response to Covid: while public health professionals in the US were wringing their hands over how medical professionals wearing masks would cause patients to be irrationally afraid, our institution was sending out memos recommending that *all* staff wear N95 masks, even non-medical staff, and mandating Level D precautions for treatment of Covid patients (white paper biohazard suit with facemask and N95 but without the PAPR). I think this culture of precaution regarding emerging diseases was probably a major part of the reason that Seoul was able to control spread early in the Covid outbreak. The hospital response probably bought time to organize the testing-and-tracing program which was so successful (until Omicron and full vaccination shifted the cost/benefit ratio. The tracing program has now been wound down.)

The origin of this cultural difference was probably the [2015 outbreak of Middle East respiratory syndrome](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2015_Middle_East_respiratory_syndrome_outbreak_in_South_Korea). During that outbreak 186 patients were infected, mostly via transmission within a few Seoul hospitals which were sloppy with infection control. Of these patients, 38 died. The response was a public outcry and renewed procedures for early outbreak response.

I guess the moral of the story is that from 2015 to 2019, South Korea was able to form a rigorous epidemic response policy, whereas from 2019 to 2022 the US CDC seems to be sticking to strategies which cover their ass (&#34;evidence-based&#34;), but which are taking a gamble in the case that the disease is actually airborne.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iao602x/"/></entry></feed>