<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/gattsuru - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T18:55:59Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/gattsuru" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijh79rt/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Minecraft&#39;s 1.19 patch has released, and among the normal fun of programmer hell</title><updated>2022-08-08T18:55:59Z</updated><author><name>gattsuru</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Minecraft&#39;s 1.19 patch has released, and among the normal fun of programmer hell that is the Forge/Fabric/Quilt updates, there&#39;s also been a more [conventional culture war aspect](https://www.pcgamer.com/minecraft-players-are-in-an-uproar-over-its-new-reporting-system-but-mojang-wont-back-down/): 

&amp;gt; Minecraft players have been up in arms about the new player reporting system since it was announced a month ago, but it was finally implemented as part of yesterday&#39;s 1.19.1 update. It allows players on both private and Mojang-hosted multiplayer servers to flag inappropriate messages in chat for review by Mojang investigators, potentially resulting in suspensions and bans for players that violate Minecraft&#39;s community guidelines even on self-hosted servers. Fans are worried that the system will result in player bans for messages taken out of context, and more broadly that it gives Microsoft too much power to dictate the content of discussions on its platform.

More details from Mojang (aka Microsoft) [here](https://help.minecraft.net/hc/en-us/articles/7317376541197), or a more technical breakdown of an earlier implementation from the weekly builds [here](http://web.archive.org/web/20220630085634/https://blog.bithole.dev/mc-report.html).

For those unfamiliar with the game&#39;s online mode, Minecraft (way back in 2009) originally focused on privately-run servers, and while there&#39;s a subscription service for company-run Realms servers (starting in 2013, before the Microsoft buyout), and a small industry of third-party management tools, some [better](https://chs.gg/) and some worse, but either way, the majority of servers are effectively managed by non-Mojang and non-Microsoft employees.  People playing on such machines only interface directly with Microsoft services to login and to download updates (and, uh, for everything in Windows).

Most of these servers are _small_.  It&#39;s theoretically possible to run a &#39;large&#39; server or server cluster -- [HyPixel&#39;s count is famously high](https://hypixel.krashnz.com/) -- but this usually involves some combination of throwing obscene amounts of RAM at the problem, using an extremely customized version of the server, and/or [clustering approaches](https://velocitypowered.com/wiki).  For a single dedicated server machine or even mid-end cloud instance, it&#39;s very hard to scale past ~200 simultaneous users: modded environments tend to struggle badly in the [~100](https://twitter.com/CuriousCalamari/status/1535364691488395266) users range, and the most recent BlanketCon (a modder convention server focused on a higher-performance culture war split called Quilt that derived from the high-performance internal-frustration split called Fabric) [managed to get a workable server to 170 concurrent players](https://hackmd.io/@LemmaEOF/blanketcon-22-postmortem#Performance-Performance-Performance) by live-patching out stuff like Achievements.  Most servers more likely run 5-40 concurrent players, usually favoring the low end.

Running a server is balancing act beyond the technical aspects.  Even without mods or PvP, it&#39;s trivially easy for a bad actor to grief other players at least some of the time, and even well-meaning players can unintentionally create lag bombs or overflow NBT.  And people are people, for better or worse.  In turn, server operators are dictators by nature; there is little appeal past whoever controls the electrical bill or the file system, and it&#39;s historically be constrained to the sort of thing that involve the FBI.

Which runs into some complications, when you&#39;re talking about a game a) is at least somewhat marketed toward kids, b) [that supports chat and a nearly-unfettered voxel sandbox](https://twitter.com/glassbottommeg/status/604411327583375361), c) has or had prominent cultural trends toward [anti-censorship](https://www.uncensoredlibrary.com/en).  Not _new_ problems -- kids wandering unobserved into the wrong IRC channel, PHPbb or USENET/BBC are stories nearly as old as the internet themselves, and [inspirations behind federal legislation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act) older than Java 1.2 -- but ones somewhat more prominent when the majority of the children in the country play the game.So there&#39;s [definitely](https://twitter.com/politicalmath/status/1391282599046238208) a [problem](https://twitter.com/mattcarriere/status/1391290583486922757) that this is [pointed](https://twitter.com/gigaherz/status/1553076537179660288) at solving, or at least helping solve.

But there are some tradeoffs.  There are some technical efforts built into the system to avoid or at least reduce manipulation, but ultimately this is a field where not just one client, but also the server and the other client may be in the hands of the enemy -- early attempts to manipulate it are [allegedly failed](https://twitter.com/Minecraft/status/1553077938639085568), but I&#39;m somewhat skeptical that it&#39;s totally bulletproof and the rapid release of a couple patches hasn&#39;t encouraged people.  Even with the system working perfectly at a mechanical and code level, there&#39;s also just a more fundamental problem when moderation runs into culture: &#34;&#34;Is Queer A Slur&#34; - the greatest thread in the history of forums, locked by a moderator after 12,239 pages of heated debate,&#34;.    There&#39;s also not a lot of trust of Microsoft, here.  The migration from Mojang to Microsoft accounts famously, in the modded community, [booted one Forge dev out for over four months](https://twitter.com/voxcpw/status/1489695958925463555).  Xbox&#39;s general moderation capabilities are not exactly held in high regard, either, and it&#39;s pretty easy to imagine that the typical server maintainer does a better job.

Worse, there&#39;s reason to think it may not stop at this particular limit.  The [ADL](https://www.adl.org/resources/report/breaking-building-blocks-hate-case-study-minecraft-servers) has a oft-linked study on Minecraft moderation on the largest server clusters, and somewhat interestingly there&#39;s not very much overlap between what it&#39;s worried about, and what the new reporting system focuses on.  That [glassbottommeg](https://twitter.com/glassbottommeg/status/604411327583375361) thread wondering how Minecraft hasn&#39;t resulted in a bunch of lawsuits?  It&#39;s also about content that isn&#39;t reportable, here.  The central example where a server op might be an abuser?  Possibly handled... if the victim realizes it, and reports something that&#39;s obvious enough.  It&#39;s not clear how well this fixes or even seriously slows the underlying motivations and concerns, in the long run, in short.

Worse, this handles the _difficult_ technical problems: while not a perfect solution to the questions of authenticity of messages only viewed by three untrusted parties, it&#39;s a good enough one for Microsoft to have shipped it.  Expanding this system to upload different data, or without user intervention, isn&#39;t as simple as a boolean tweak, but it&#39;s not deeply complicated.

That&#39;s not to say it _will_ go wrong, or go further.  I&#39;m hope I&#39;m just being paranoid, and outside a small number of cases for stuff that would otherwise end up involving the FBI we never hear about it again.  But that&#39;s a hope.

There&#39;s a temptation to label this by the normal Culture War assumptions, where _obviously_ Red Tribers would oppose the new system, and Blue Tribers would support it.  And you can find _some_ of that, whether genuine or primed by the coverage, and whether pogger-faced unverifiable claims on YouTube or hyperbolic comparisons to Gamergate (yes, really) on Discord.

But there&#39;s also people on the Quilt Discord, a place defined in no small part by its Culture War split from a different modloader, pondering about the ramifications when someone reports certain feelings about the international status of Hong Kong.  Or that, given the weaponization of concerns about child abuse applied to even the most of LGBT-related topics, that perhaps this is not a great tool to be passing to the XBox Live Moderation Staff.  Which isn&#39;t a _huge_ surprise; I&#39;ve posted before about tech censorship [aimed at VioletBlue](https://www.reddit.com/r/CultureWarRoundup/comments/b7ycv5/offtopic_and_loweffort_cw_thread_for_the_week_of/ejwyhxf/?context=999) who then used that [as examples of what should be aimed at her _opponents_](https://twitter.com/violetblue/status/1112878491588939776), but it&#39;s worth pointing out none-the-less.((And, on the other side, it&#39;s not like PoliticalMath is going to share VioletBlue&#39;s perspective on what is acceptable discussion matter [when young adults are in the room](https://twitter.com/politicalmath/status/1523840050122870789).  There are people with principles, but you&#39;d give Diogenes a run for his money looking for &#39;em.))

So... I dunno.

The deeper melancholy is more about the general case.  Minecraft hits particularly had because it&#39;s Microsoft&#39;s Mojang (2 billion served!) on one side and Your Personal Server (2/10 active players) on the other, but that isn&#39;t exactly unique.  Everyone knows that anything happening on Discord is between you, everyone else on the server, Discord Inc, and [the inevitable leaks](https://twitter.com/hradzka/status/1116502891689172993), but it&#39;s not like the motivations for Minecraft here will care that you&#39;re running your own RocketChat or Matrix instance; they&#39;re just smaller and haven&#39;t gotten the same attention.

For now.

It&#39;s not like this is new grounds in a framework where private or small-community utterances can end up sliced and diced by faceless team of reviewers by metrics you can&#39;t understand or contest.  It&#39;s not even particularly extreme as such goes.  But now it feels increasingly like the result people want, rather than some accidental end-point.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijh79rt/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>