<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/GavinSkulldrinker - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-04T04:15:48Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/GavinSkulldrinker" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iivid1j/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Call this a self-effacing journal entry.

My phone recently suffered some minor </title><updated>2022-08-04T04:15:48Z</updated><author><name>GavinSkulldrinker</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Call this a self-effacing journal entry.

My phone recently suffered some minor water damage, and I was easily able to get a replacement for $100.  Thank you insurance, you did your part, will be removing you now.  I&#39;d be kinda happy to have a new device with zero miles on it, except...

My previous phone was a Oneplus 7 Pro, the dumb orange one with the 5g.  I got it for half off on a desperation promo, I loved it to death, with it&#39;s pop-up camera and notification slider, and the fact that no one has heard of the thing.

The insurance guys sent me a Note 10 Plus.  Apparently they were out of that model.  Because there weren&#39;t that many.  Because no one had heard of it.

It says a lot about my character that I experience so much internal strife at the prospect of having to, however briefly, use a Normie Phone.  I could turn around and sell it for $300 tops, and use that money to buy...nothing that excites me, at the moment.  Some overpriced Sony midranger?  The Nothing Phone?  Eh.  Nokia hasn&#39;t made anything good, 

I used to sell phones.  I have strong opinions about them (I have legit sherlock-scanned people based on their phones).  It&#39;s a personal accessory, it doesn&#39;t say nothing about it&#39;s owner.  I made a lot of money matching up the Note series with the right people; I got so many grumpy boomers to upgrade to the things.  They&#39;re good devices, the pen is nice for the tactical games I play, I like scrolling around with it.  This thing will last me two more years easily.  I really do care less and less about phone crap; I hate the world they&#39;ve created, and feel somehow implicated.  Twitter is on phones man, and I knew that, and I was selling the things anyways.

And I&#39;m still pissy that someone might see the phone I have and mistake me for a Normie.

Urge to buy Xperia 10 IV, rising.  It&#39;s got a side-mounted fingerprint scanner, and a really long aspect ratio.  Visually striking, and people do recognize Sony, so Sony making phones will blow their mind.  There&#39;s a green one...

Yes, I choose the phone I use based on the opportunities it gives me to indicate to people that I am different, in whatever small, inconsequential way.  I once used the Razer phone, the monolith with the RGB shit on the back.  Before that, the Moto Z, the phone with magnetic modular doodads.  Before that, the Essential phone, a titanium brick from 2016 that looked exactly like the latest iphones somehow.

I have a disorder: &amp;gt;!I can&#39;t like popular things!&amp;lt;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/waw03g/friday_fun_thread_for_july_29_2022/iivid1j/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>