<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/gearofnett - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-20T04:28:31Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/gearofnett" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driv</title><updated>2022-08-20T04:28:31Z</updated><author><name>gearofnett</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">How do I get back the will to improve myself and live healthy? I was always driven by some goal that I would set for myself, but I&#39;ve managed to achieve everything I wanted in the past few years, and the new goals I try to set for myself are not motivating enough for me to change my behavior. My regular day consists of waking up at 12-3pm, browsing the internet/reading a book/watching youtube or movie + 1 hour of work (if needed) + cook food, then going to bed at 3-6am. It&#39;s not all bad, on the weekends I go out with friends, and I also travel 3-4 times a year, but I understand that my regular day schedule is extremely unhealthy. If I keep living like that I won&#39;t be well physically or mentally. Even though I understand the consequences, it&#39;s still not motivating enough to change my ways. I try to fix my sleep, but after 2-3 days I&#39;m back to that degen schedule because I literally don&#39;t have a reason to be awake early. I work for myself, so I don&#39;t need to be up early. All my friends and family work regular jobs, so I can&#39;t interact with them at that time either. I&#39;m physically fit (as much as one can be when not working out consistently) and don&#39;t eat junk food, so I don&#39;t have an urgent need or want to go to the gym. I used to work out in the past and I know how much of an impact it has on your mental, but again, for some reason me knowing all that is not enough to push me to change. 

I&#39;m very tempted to get a regular 9-5 job or join the military just for the sake of having responsibilities that would force me to have a normal human schedule and hope that the habits I learn during that time stick with me for the rest of my life.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/il1270m/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>