<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/georgioz - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-19T14:54:03Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/georgioz" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxwcd1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Recently,  the Senator Thorpe who identifies as Australian Aboriginal from *Aust</title><updated>2022-08-19T14:54:03Z</updated><author><name>georgioz</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Recently,  the Senator Thorpe who identifies as Australian Aboriginal from *Australian Greens* party made an oath in Australian Senate. Here [is the video](https://youtu.be/HAJQ_K_CzCE) and what follows is a rough transcript.

Senator Thorpe goes down to read the oath with [Raised fist](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raised_fist) salute and declares that:

&amp;gt; I, sovereign Lidia Thorpe do solemnly and sincerely affirm and declare that I will be faithful and I bear true allegiance to the **colonizing** Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth, the second ....

At  that point she had to be reminded that this is not what was written in the oath presented, and she had to repeat the original transcript. Thorpe&#39;s whole body language as well as tone of voice expressed that she does not think of this oath as genuine.

And this is an interesting point here, should government officials who make oaths to &#34;protect the constitution&#34; or other oaths be given a pass obviously demeaning it and signaling that they do not agree with their oath? I think this is an interesting &#34;foreshadowing&#34; of the things to come, where the legitimacy of the government and its institutions is obviously and explicitly ignored. I am not an Aussie so I can be educated on the ramification of this act by Thorpe, but to me this seems like an interesting case of how will the institutions react to such a blatant disrespect of the spirit of law although the letter of law was adhered to in the end.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikxwcd1/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>