<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/gimmickless - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T14:59:06Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/gimmickless" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikiyxbg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Front Lines in Culture War: Diversity in Policing

I attend town hall meetings i</title><updated>2022-08-16T14:59:06Z</updated><author><name>gimmickless</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Front Lines in Culture War: Diversity in Policing

I attend town hall meetings in my neighborhood pretty regularly. There&#39;s a new guy who started showing up, and most of his input is focused around &#34;why aren&#39;t you hiring enough minority police?&#34; Because identity matters, he&#39;s a white male in his 30s.

I notice a distinct lack of charity on my end towards his position. The jumping to conclusions are arguments you might have seen before: &#34;He probably doesn&#39;t know any himself, who is he to talk?&#34;, &#34;He&#39;s probably not helping any apply, why isn&#39;t he doing the work to solve this?&#34;, &#34;Who is this White Knight, and why is he expecting other people to do the heavy lifting?&#34; &#34;He probably doesn&#39;t want any people he knows to be police anyway. Does he want to make mental room to be secretly racist, but have plausible deniability because they&#39;re cops?&#34;

The last one, of course, is a terrible conclusion. But it&#39;s still a thought I had, and TBH is also a comment I&#39;d expect someone else to post here. I&#39;m not happy about assuming the worst of him. That he is a sneaky fucker, Literally Hitler In Sheep&#39;s Clothing.

The obvious solution is to find time to take him aside &amp;amp; ask him the questions I&#39;ve had in my head. What steps to take after then, though?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikiyxbg/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>