<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/gimmickless - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T17:07:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/gimmickless" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilm8ko6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Good news: my work on the neighborhood newsletter has opened enough doors to sta</title><updated>2022-08-24T17:07:34Z</updated><author><name>gimmickless</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Good news: my work on the neighborhood newsletter has opened enough doors to start hosting business networking meetings in my neighborhood. I&#39;ve done one in July &amp;amp; August so far. I charge a small fee for coffee &amp;amp; pastries ($10), and a local nonprofit is shouldering most of the financial load in paying for advertising. (mailing postcards to registered businesses within the ZIP code) Tonight, I&#39;ll be working with a local marketer to start scriptwriting for online video content.

Results are mixed. Less than 10 people are showing up right now, but 3 are returning ticket buyers. Also, I&#39;ve had people on city council show up. An acquaintance also wants to shadow me next month to set up a similar service across the other side of the city.

So now I&#39;ve got to figure out how to keep pushing through the growth stage.  Current marketing (I&#39;m told) costs $500/mo, which is not sustainable. The 501c3 has told me I cannot operate as a business if I&#39;m to continue enjoying their support. It is possible to set up as a nonprofit with various designations (501c3, 501c4, 501c6) but I have to educate myself on the pros and cons of each of these. 

The biggest con for now: I am used to making executive decisions by myself, and I don&#39;t feel get warm fuzzies about forming a board. I don&#39;t trust the talent pool available, given what I know.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilm8ko6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>