<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Gorf__ - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-17T20:45:16Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Gorf__" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition</title><updated>2022-08-17T20:45:16Z</updated><author><name>Gorf__</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">So I&#39;m switching to a mostly plant-based diet. I&#39;ve been interested in nutrition for a long time, and for a while I&#39;ve been circling this as probably the best approach to food long-term for health and longevity. The ethics side of it is nice too, but I&#39;m not super interested in discussing that. This is mostly an experiment to see how I feel, and how my weight and blood markers look after a while. I&#39;m trying to take a 90/10 approach, eating as plant-based as possible for all of my staple meals at home, but allowing some meat and dairy in when necessary, mostly when eating out. I haven&#39;t eaten any red meat or poultry in a few weeks, but I&#39;ve had fish here and then when out at restaurants, as well as some dairy stuff - some cheese here and there and ranch dressing.

Generally I&#39;ve been a hardcore meat-eater, so up until about 3 weeks ago, every dish was very focused around meat, and any vegetables were there as condiments or just because I felt like I &#34;should&#34; make myself eat some broccoli. It seems to me that this is an extremely common approach to food in the US. Everyone I know eats this way. Most of us have this idea that if you take away meat and dairy then you&#39;re stuck just eating salads all the time, but that&#39;s not the case at all. I&#39;ve been eating oatmeal + fruit + some agave for breakfast; a smoothie and usually some sort of leftovers for lunch; and the formula for dinner is roughly: some a carb (whole grain pasta, brown rice, quinoa, etc) with a few vegetables mixed in and some kind of sauce for flavoring. The other night I made whole grain spaghetti with homemade tomato sauce (just cook down canned diced tomatoes and throw in some garlic and spices), sautéed mushrooms, roasted asparagus, and then topped with sautéed spinach, and then I ate that for lunch yesterday and today, and it was delicious.

So it&#39;s been a big change, but I&#39;m loving it. When you&#39;re eating a wide variety of fruits and vegetables, there&#39;s just a lot more variation in flavor and texture going around. I&#39;m finding out that meat itself is kind of boring: it&#39;s mostly texture, salt, and fat flavor. It&#39;s all of the stuff surrounding it that makes it good. Really, meat is already losing its allure to me altogether.

I also feel less full and bloated after a meal. I&#39;ll be full because of the bulk of all the vegetables I just ate, but that goes away pretty quickly; otherwise I feel much better than I would after pounding a burger and fries.

Why am I using the term &#34;plant-based&#34; and not vegan? To me, vegan has a connotation of doing it more for ethical concerns, and plant-based has a connotation of being based more on nutrition. But that&#39;s just my own perception. A whole food plant based diet is one where you focus on eating plants that came from the ground more or less directly, maybe heating, chopping, and/or seasoning them first, but not much alteration beyond that. Ie, avoiding as many processed foods as possible - so while it&#39;s probably ok to have an Impossible Burger every now and then, it shouldn&#39;t be a staple. Folks who eat vegan for ethical reasons are probably more likely to eat processed foods like tofurkey or whatever, which isn&#39;t really any healthier than just eating meat all the time.

So the inevitable question is: _so where are you getting all of your protein?_ First of all, the whole &#34;incomplete protein&#34; thing isn&#39;t true - all plants have all amino acids. Yes, the amounts of each vary, but if you&#39;re eating a variety of plants then it&#39;s nothing to worry about. Incomplete proteins were written about in this popular vegetarian book in the 70s, and the author later realized her mistake and backed off of it, but it was too late - the idea had already been solidified in public consciousness.

Second, the actual amount of protein we need is probably majorly inflated for most people. Sure, bodybuilders might need more, but even they are probably majorly overdoing it. There&#39;s some good discussion about this in the book _Proteinaholic_ by Garth Davis.

In any case, it&#39;s pretty easy to hit solid protein numbers from eating plants, especially if you&#39;re getting lots of legumes. And protein shakes are still a thing if you need even more.

The only issue I&#39;ve had so far is that I&#39;m farting a lot, and the farts are pretty bad. I think I went overboard in going from eating like 10-15g of fiber a day to like 50g. I&#39;m going to try dial that back and then ramp it back up more slowly. So maybe more white rice and pasta for a bit as I give my GI tract more time to adjust to the massive amounts of fiber.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikpgcyx/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>