<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/GrapeGrater - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-17T00:04:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/GrapeGrater" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iklaeru/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So while we seem to have managed to add to the record every political hot take o</title><updated>2022-08-17T00:04:58Z</updated><author><name>GrapeGrater</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So while we seem to have managed to add to the record every political hot take of the last week, we somehow completely missed the arrest of the Tornado Cash developer, Alexey Pertsev in Amsterdam. This is a fairly interesting omission from the forum in its own right as this forum has at least traditionally had a strong SF Tech overlap. 

But for those who didn&#39;t get the story, Tornado cash is a new Smart Contract that is intended to obscure the block-chain addresses used in transactions by bundling them together to obfuscate any single transaction. The US Treasury blacklisted the coin blacklisted and declared it illegal for Americans to own or use following it being used to funnel money to North Korea [see: https://nitter.net/RyanSAdams/status/1558129960140816384#m, https://www.pcmag.com/news/tornado-cash-developer-arrested-as-blacklisted-crypto-site-goes-down, https://www.foxbusiness.com/financials/dutch-authorities-arrest-suspected-developer-tornado-cash-platform-launder-billions]. 

Dutch authorities (Pertsev is Dutch) have claimed to have an independent investigation and the arrest was for concealing criminal financial flows and money laundering on behalf of the Dutch prosecutor&#39;s office. [https://nitter.net/sccanavos/status/1559530518043148290#m]

This obviously has many developers in arms. Tornado Cash was VC backed and worked to follow the law [https://nitter.net/jonst0kes/status/1558196851169452034#m, https://nitter.net/dystopiabreaker/status/1558196263190876161#m]

Fight For the Future (remember them?) and The EFF have weighed in favor of the developer [https://nitter.net/fightfortheftr/status/1559297577694429184#m, https://nitter.net/EFF/status/1559224086491934720#m] With the EFF taking the long-standing stance that code is free speech (remember that argument)? Coin Center has promised a lawsuit, likely in conjunction with the EFF and FFTF.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iklaeru/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>