<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/grendel-khan - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T21:02:11Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/grendel-khan" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij3s6v8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Jerusalem Demsas for *The Atlantic*, [&#34;The Billionaire&#39;s Dilemma](https://www.th</title><updated>2022-08-05T21:02:11Z</updated><author><name>grendel-khan</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Jerusalem Demsas for *The Atlantic*, [&#34;The Billionaire&#39;s Dilemma](https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/08/marc-andreessens-opposition-housing-project-nimby/671061/). (Part of [a series on housing](https://old.reddit.com/r/neoliberal/comments/8a9o5i/on_the_nimby_subject/), mostly in California.) I was waiting on this year&#39;s legislative session to conclude to post another update ([the local AARP endorsed parking reform!](https://twitter.com/AARPCA/status/1554502644177182722)), but this seemed extra relevant.

Marc Andreessen, co-founder of Netscape and of Andreessen Horowitz, techie luminary and Bay Area presence, is most recently known for his 2020 essay [&#34;It&#39;s Time to Build&#34;](https://a16z.com/2020/04/18/its-time-to-build/) ([previously discussed here](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/g0ck7p/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_april_13_2020/fnw1l2q/)). Among other notes about how our civilization does not *build* things, it cited housing as a problem:

&amp;gt; You see it in housing and the physical footprint of our cities. We can’t build nearly enough housing in our cities with surging economic potential — which results in crazily skyrocketing housing prices in places like San Francisco, making it nearly impossible for regular people to move in and take the jobs of the future. We also can’t build the cities themselves anymore. When the producers of HBO’s “Westworld” wanted to portray the American city of the future, they didn’t film in Seattle or Los Angeles or Austin — they went to Singapore. We should have gleaming skyscrapers and spectacular living environments in all our best cities at levels way beyond what we have now; where are they?

This is [Housing Element](https://www.hcd.ca.gov/housing-elements-hcd) season in the Bay Area, a once-every-eight-years process by which every city must update part of their General Plan to accommodate a share of regional housing need, address governmental constraints to housing, affirmatively further fair housing, and so on. The process has been going on since 1969, but it&#39;s much more meaningful now; the numbers are higher, the sites inventories have to be plausible, the consequences of noncompliance are unknown but potentially [severe](https://www.lewis.ucla.edu/research/a-primer-on-californias-builders-remedy-for-housing-element-noncompliance/), and so on.

Andreessen lives in Atherton, a small city of about seven thousand (down from eight thousand in 1970) primarily known for its [hilariously low-intensity police blotter](https://www.mercurynews.com/2011/08/27/the-best-of-atherton-police-blotter/). Atherton must [plan for 348 new homes](https://abag.ca.gov/sites/default/files/documents/2021-12/Final_RHNA_Allocation_Report_2023-2031-approved_0.pdf#page=29), about three-fifths of which must be below market rate. Currently, the city has two kinds of zones which accommodate homes: one with a 13,500 square foot minimum lot size, and one with a one-acre minimum lot size; as a result, [cops and dispatchers can&#39;t live anywhere near the city](https://www.almanacnews.com/news/2018/05/04/atherton-looking-for-place-for-officers-dispatchers-to-sleep-between-shifts). The city&#39;s [draft Housing Element](https://www.ci.atherton.ca.us/DocumentCenter/View/10417/Atherton-Draft-Housing-Element_Complete_6_9_2022#page=41) plans to allow six, occasionally eight, and in one instance sixteen homes per acre on land totaling 16.64 acres, or one two-hundredth of the city.

Andreessen and his wife wrote the following letter to the city:

&amp;gt; Dear Mayor DeGolia and Members of the Atherton Town Council,  
&amp;gt; I am writing this letter to communicate our IMMENSE objection to the creation of multifamily overlay zones in Atherton. Multifamily development is prohibited in the Atherton General Plan and any change in zoning and land use rules should only be considered after a thoughtful General Plan amendment process, that includes significant community outreach, participation and comment. Please IMMEDIATELY REMOVE all multifamily overlay zoning projects from the Housing Element which will
be submitted to the state in July. They will MASSIVELY decrease our home values, the quality of life of ourselves and our neighbors and IMMENSELY increase the noise pollution and traffic.

There are some mistakes in here; the Housing Element update is *part* of the General Plan amendment process; [a thorough community engagement process](https://www.ci.atherton.ca.us/DocumentCenter/View/10417/Atherton-Draft-Housing-Element_Complete_6_9_2022#page=90) is mandated by law and described in the draft (among other things, &#34;A special edition of the Town newsletter was prepared and physically mailed to every address in Town&#34;). But more to the point, I&#39;m reminded of [Robert Reich&#39;s yard-sign hypocrisy](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/i2r8qo/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_03_2020/g0eu6dh/) in the same way. It&#39;s Time To Build... Somewhere Else.

[All of the public comments are here](https://www.ci.atherton.ca.us/DocumentCenter/View/10529/Public-Comments-and-Summary-Info), all 270 of them, of which the vast majority (85%, according to city staff) were of a similar nature. Notable participants included Tim Draper of Draper Fisher Jurvetson, arguing that &#34;If we stall, I suspect the mandate will go away with a new political wind&#34;. He seems to be right; [all of the multifamily overlay zones have been removed from the city&#39;s plan](https://www.ci.atherton.ca.us/627/Housing-Element-Update) as of this week.

While it&#39;s fun to point out hypocrisy, the *real* lesson here is that while it would be reasonable for individuals to have lots of power over the use of their own land, or regional/state governments to have that power, the weird middle we&#39;re in, where land-use power is wielded in practice by whoever can make life hardest for their city councilmembers, has led to the current mess in California. Atherton isn&#39;t where the housing crisis is worst; it&#39;s just a particularly sharply drawn example. This is, in part, [why the local YIMBYs are focusing so much on removing local governments&#39; power to say no](https://old.reddit.com/r/TrueReddit/comments/v5hvir/twilight_of_the_nimby/ibaz5br/?context=3), even while doing everything they can to preserve their authority.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij3s6v8/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>