<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/grendel-khan - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-09T20:54:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/grendel-khan" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijmqb7h/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Jordan Weissmann for *Slate*, [&#34;Why Internet Leftists Are So Pissed About Democr</title><updated>2022-08-09T20:54:46Z</updated><author><name>grendel-khan</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Jordan Weissmann for *Slate*, [&#34;Why Internet Leftists Are So Pissed About Democrats’ Historic Climate Bill&#34;](https://slate.com/business/2022/08/inflation-reduction-act-climate-change-criticism-adam-mckay-david-sirota.html). (See also [this episode of *Volts*](https://www.volts.wtf/p/volts-podcast-what-to-make-of-the).)

This is inside-baseball among climate activists, but I thought it was interesting enough to lay out here.

The [Inflation Reduction Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inflation_Reduction_Act_of_2022) is, [as Michael Sweeney predicted](https://nitter.it/mtsw/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=inflation+reduction&amp;amp;since=&amp;amp;until=2022-01-31&amp;amp;near=), part of Build Back Better wearing a different hat, but adjusted significantly to appeal to Joe Manchin and Kyrsten Sinema. Some Mottians [are doing a collaborative analysis here](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wc7x7s/collaborative_analysis_of_the_inflation_reduction/).

A central tradeoff is in [section 50625](https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/22122281/inflation_reduction_act_of_2022.pdf#page=644), which requires that for wind and solar to be developed on federal lands, two million acres of land and sixty million offshore acres of federal land must be offered for lease for oil and gas development. (Note that private and public lands are somewhat fungible, all offers are not leased, and all leases are not developed.)

Adam McKay and David Sirota are the screenwriters of *Don&#39;t Look Up* (previously [reviewed on ACX here](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/movie-review-dont-look-up)), with 1.3 million Twitter followers between them. They&#39;ve been *very angry* about this deal. ([Example from Sirota](https://twitter.com/davidsirota/status/1556487558510821376), [from McKay](https://twitter.com/GhostPanther/status/1556745117838430208).) This has led to some [moderately funny beclownening](https://twitter.com/Wertwhile/status/1556278768674566145), and [is the same line being pushed by some Republicans](https://popular.info/p/the-people-behind-the-bizarre-non) attempting to derail the bill.

But I think there&#39;s something more interesting here. This reads to me as a very clean deontology/consequentialism split. If it hadn&#39;t been the leases, it would have been the [supports for keeping nuclear plants open](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-08-03/machin-deal-tosses-30-billion-lifeline-to-us-nuclear-reactors). From one perspective, anything that helps fossil fuels in any way is absolutely forbidden, therefore, this is a bad idea; from the other, we [see that the policy bundle reduces 24 tons of emissions for every ton it adds](https://energyinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Modeling-the-Inflation-Reduction-Act-with-the-US-Energy-Policy-Simulator_August.pdf), so it&#39;s net good, period.

There&#39;s a persistent belief on the left that there&#39;s a vast disaffected left-wing mass of voters who would show up for a sufficiently inspiring candidate. This was shown to be false when Sanders ran in 2016 and again in 2020, but it&#39;s *sticky* because it&#39;s nice to believe that everyone&#39;s silently on your side. Similarly, this portion of the left has been very keen to believe that [we can crush fossil-fuel supply, and it&#39;ll only affect billionaires](https://twitter.com/KateAronoff/status/1089327906139054080). The political reality is, of course, different, in that people [*really hate* high energy prices](https://pprg.stanford.edu/wp-content/uploads/Presidential-Approval-and-Gas-Prices.pdf), which is how supply restrictions manifest themselves.

I want to emphasize, not everyone on the climate-hawk left is taking the deontological approach. But it&#39;s certainly *interesting* to see this split.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijmqb7h/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>