<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-14T17:41:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig5l4s9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] It&#39;s on now: [Twitter sues Elon Musk to enforce original merger agreement](https</title><updated>2022-07-14T17:41:36Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">It&#39;s on now: [Twitter sues Elon Musk to enforce original merger agreement](https://www.cnbc.com/2022/07/12/twitter-sues-elon-musk-to-enforce-original-merger-agreement.html)

&amp;gt;The outcome of the dispute could be unpredictable, legal experts say, and could involve a judge forcing Musk to complete the deal or forcing him to pay a $1 billion breakup fee, or other scenarios including a settlement, renegotiation of the purchase price, or even Musk walking away without paying anything.

&amp;gt;Twitter is seeking a four-day trial in September, according to a court filing.

&amp;gt;In the suit filed Tuesday, Twitter argued that Musk’s conduct during his pursuit of the social network was in “bad faith” and accused the Tesla CEO of acting against the deal since “the market started turning.”

Elon seems completely unfazed by the whole thing. His followers do not seem to care either and agree with Elon on the bot excuse/problem.

I have observed that many of the people who opposed the deal 2 month ago at $44 billion on the grounds of Elon being bad for Twitter, now want Elon to be forced to buy Twitter, which strikes me as odd. 

https://twitter.com/memecoinist/status/1547291548726882305 

https://twitter.com/Scuttlepunk/status/1545541867634319362

As mentioned last week, I think it&#39;s unlikely he will be forced to pay the $44 billion. Either a large fine or buying twitter a discount. If Elon is fined, twitter is goin to have a hell of  a time collecting on it, and likely it will be stalled out.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig5l4s9/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>