<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-08T03:36:38Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifase74/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Japan former Prime minister Abe has been shot , likely dead

[Shinzo Abe, former</title><updated>2022-07-08T03:36:38Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Japan former Prime minister Abe has been shot , likely dead

[Shinzo Abe, former Japan prime minister, shot during speech – report](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jul/08/shinzo-abe-former-japan-prime-minister-shot-during-speech-reports)

&amp;gt;Japan’s former prime minister Shinzo Abe is in a “state of cardiopulmonary arrest” after collapsing while making a speech, with initial reports saying gunshots had been heard shortly before he fell to the ground.

&amp;gt;NHK, Japan’s public broadcaster, said Abe – the country’s longest-serving prime minister until he resigned in 2020 – appeared to be bleeding from the chest after being shot from behind with a shotgun on Friday morning.

&amp;gt;NHK said a man had been taken into custody but provided no further details. Abe had been in the city of Nara to make a campaign speech ahead of this Sunday’s upper house elections.

The shooter has been detained but the motive is unknown. Given that he&#39;s not longer the PM, he does not seem like an important target, so it&#39;s hard to understand what the motive could possibly be. From the video on twitter , it would seem as if he had no security and the shooter simply rushed him and shot him in the back.

Japan is held up by the media as a gun control success story, yet stuff like this still happens.  it shows how the problem is not necessarily the guns but people.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifase74/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>