<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-07T22:59:48Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ijddqzs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] What is the deal with the Red Scare Pod? I have seen some people mention it and </title><updated>2022-08-07T22:59:48Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">What is the deal with the Red Scare Pod? I have seen some people mention it and posted on the subreddit. It have seen here some people mention it or on its associated subreddit. I listened to an episode and it seems like another Breaking Points or other generic,  alt-edge &#34;both sides are bad and let&#39;s blame elites&#34; podcast, but I agree with them about AOC. This genre seem so saturated but it endures.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ijddqzs/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij99tf2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] China&#39;s response or retaliation to Pelosi&#39;s Taiwan visit is pretty weak and not </title><updated>2022-08-07T01:25:27Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">China&#39;s response or retaliation to Pelosi&#39;s Taiwan visit is pretty weak and not nearly as bad as feared a week ago . 

[China fires missiles near Taiwan in live-fire drills as PLA encircles island](https://www.cnn.com/2022/08/04/asia/china-taiwan-military-exercises-intl-hnk-ml/index.html)

&amp;gt;The Chinese missiles flew over Taiwan Island for the first time, a Chinese military expert said on state television channel CCTV on Thursday, representing a major escalation of China&#39;s military intimidation against Taiwan.

&amp;gt;The military posturing was a deliberate show of force after Pelosi left the island on Wednesday evening, bound for South Korea, one of the final stops on an Asia tour that ends in Japan this weekend.

&amp;gt;Within hours of her departure from Taipei on Wednesday, the island&#39;s Defense Ministry said China sent more than 20 fighter jets across the median line in the Taiwan Strait, the midway point between the mainland and Taiwan that Beijing says it does not recognize but usually respects.

&amp;gt;In addition, the ministry said that 22 Chinese warplanes had entered its air defense identification zone (ADIZ) on Thursday, and that all of them crossed the strait median line.


[China sanctions House Speaker Nancy Pelosi over &#39;egregious provocation&#39; in visit to Taiwan](https://www.foxnews.com/world/china-sanctions-house-speaker-nancy-pelosi-over-egregious-provocation-visit-taiwan)

How does one sanction a person? Not even sanctions against the US but against her. 

&amp;gt;&#34;In disregard of China’s grave concerns and firm opposition, Speaker of the US House of Representatives Nancy Pelosi insisted on visiting China’s Taiwan region. This constitutes a gross interference in China’s internal affairs,&#34; the spokesperson said. &#34;It gravely undermines China’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, seriously tramples on the one-China principle, and severely threatens peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij99tf2/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>