<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T20:25:12Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imau220/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Why is it so hard to invent a good sugar substitute?

All the economic incentive</title><updated>2022-08-29T20:25:12Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Why is it so hard to invent a good sugar substitute?

All the economic incentives are  in place, you got many companies that stand to make probably  hundreds of billions of dollars. Yet a century later, despite collective billions of R&amp;amp;D and some of the smartest chemists,   nothing even comes close. We&#39;re talking imitating sugar, not trying to cure cancer. The policy implications of this are huge: helping to fix global obesity, for example. Yet why can&#39;t it be done?

Trying to lose weight and this would be a godsend.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imau220/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9smmz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ~~[Voters are split in support of Biden&#39;s $500 billion student loan handout, Bid</title><updated>2022-08-29T16:12:12Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">~~[Voters are split in support of Biden&#39;s $500 billion student loan handout, Biden approval up in new poll](https://www.foxnews.com/politics/voters-split-support-bidens-500b-student-loan-handout-biden-approval-poll)~~

&amp;gt;Registered voters are nearly tied in support of President Joe Biden&#39;s recent $500 billion student loan handout initiative, as the economy remains the most important issue to registered voters, according to new poll.

&amp;gt;A new Emerson College Polling national survey suggests that Americans are almost evenly split in favor and opposition to President Joe Biden&#39;s recent student loan handout, with 36% believing the loan handout is too much and 35% thinking it is just the right amount of action. Thirty percent think it is not enough action.

&amp;gt;The majority of registered voters, 51%, believe the executive action will result in colleges raising tuition, whereas 49% think that it will allow students to have more access to education.

538 shows Biden at 42% approval, a little higher than a week ago

https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/

This is the sort of partisan split we would expect for something as polarizing or politicized as his student forgiveness plan. There does not seem to be any evidence yet that Biden is seeing a net-loss of support. 

It&#39;s still possible that SCOTUS will try to block it. RBG not retiring was the ultimate gift for the right that keeps giving, whether it&#39;s Roe v. Wade or this....it shows how important the courts are.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9smmz/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>