<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-19T19:40:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikz4q8q/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] 
This is sorta old, but the NFL is [no longer](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/0</title><updated>2022-08-19T19:40:40Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">
This is sorta old, but the NFL is [no longer](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/02/sports/football/nfl-wonderlic-test.html#:~:text=Wonderlic%2C%20the%20N.F.L.-,Finds%20Other%20Ways%20to%20Test%20Football%20I.Q.,other%20assessments%20of%20football%20acumen.) (archive version https://archive.ph/WPfD0) requiring the Wonderlic  test (although it&#39;s still being administered by teams on request)

A Google search shows it&#39;s inconclusive if the Wonderlic  is predictive of NFL success. I think it&#39;s possibly more predictive at the low-end, meaning that low-scorers are more likely the be unsuccessful, in the aggregate, than high scorers are super-successful. Football is a pretty technical game compared to other major sports (such as the use of playbooks, and having to make quick decisions in chaotic environments) so it&#39;s not surprising that the test is of some value.  

It&#39;s popular these day to downplay the predictiveness of standardized testing  and IQ scores...if you want to be a wedding photographer, then, yeah, the SATs do not matter or predict much, but for technical jobs, in which preciseness is important, then they are predictive. Second, the correlation between SATs and GPAs/grades is strong at all score ranges, which counters the narrative that standardized tests undersell the abilities of low-scorers.  If these tests didn&#39;t mean anything then we should see employers not value credentials highly correlated with them. In lieu of degrees, thousands of employers use something called the Wonderlic test, for this reason, which is like an IQ test; for example the following question:

https://preview.redd.it/rh16krsjufe81.jpg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=33844a6352f34597934e52a905764a33adff6bb7

The fact that cognitive screening is so important and prevalent despite the political backlash to them, suggests that in spite of the unpopularity of such teats that companies still value productivity more than political correctness, which I think is obvious.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikz4q8q/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>