<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/greyenlightenment - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-28T00:29:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/greyenlightenment" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihxe7kh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I saw this [Exclusive: Former Republicans and Democrats to form new third U.S. p</title><updated>2022-07-28T00:29:46Z</updated><author><name>greyenlightenment</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I saw this [Exclusive: Former Republicans and Democrats to form new third U.S. political party](https://archive.ph/hCiRX#selection-435.0-442.0)

It&#39;s called the &#34;Forward party&#34; 

&amp;gt;The new party, called Forward, will initially be co-chaired by former Democratic presidential candidate Andrew Yang and Christine Todd Whitman, the former Republican governor of New Jersey. They hope the party will become a viable alternative to the Republican and Democratic parties that dominate U.S. politics, founding members told Reuters.

&amp;gt;The new party is being formed by a merger of three political groups that have emerged in recent years as a reaction to America&#39;s increasingly polarized and gridlocked political system. The leaders cited a Gallup poll last year showing a record two-thirds of Americans believe a third party is needed.

&amp;gt;The merger involves the Renew America Movement, formed in 2021 by dozens of former officials in the Republican administrations of Ronald Reagan, George H.W. Bush, George W. Bush and Donald Trump; the Forward Party, founded by Yang, who left the Democratic Party in 2021 and became an independent; and the Serve America Movement, a group of Democrats, Republicans and independents founded by former Republican congressman David Jolly.

It looks like it&#39;s composed of disaffected democrats and never-Trump Bush-era holdouts and Trump turncoats. Does not seem promising.  

Regarding spoilers, this will hurt democrats more than republicans. From what I have gleaned on reddit and social media like Twitter, Yang has sorta become today&#39;s Ralph Nader...a leftist that democrats love to hate and who is perceived as being unhelpful despite his good intentions. It&#39;s like &#34;go away Yang..your moment is over&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihxe7kh/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>