<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Hacef_ - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-04T16:54:31Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Hacef_" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iixrh4y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Today, Florida Governor Ron Desantis [suspended a State Attorney](https://www.ta</title><updated>2022-08-04T16:54:31Z</updated><author><name>Hacef_</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Today, Florida Governor Ron Desantis [suspended a State Attorney](https://www.tampabay.com/news/florida-politics/2022/08/04/desantis-suspends-hillsborough-county-state-attorney-andrew-warren/) for signing a pledge indicating that he would refuse to prosecute cases brought under the state&#39;s new laws restricting/criminalizing abortion after 15 weeks. Likewise, said State Attorney signed a pledge against enforcing laws that would restrict/criminalize gender-transition treatments for minors, although no such law currently exists on the books in Florida. 

Andrew Warren, the State Attorney in question, was the only Florida Attorney who had signed such a pledge, but he joined a number of other state attorneys from around the country.

Official order explaining and enacting the suspension [here.](https://www.flgov.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Executive-Order-22-176.pdf) (PDF warning)

Hillsborough County is one of the more populous and economically important areas of the state, although usually overshadowed by Miami and Orlando, and also leans more Democrat than the rest of the state (not counting Broward and Palm Beach). 

A few initial points:

* It is clear that the [Florida Constitution grants the Governor the authority](https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/ExecutiveSuspensions/2023) to do this, although the Senate is in charge of either fully removing or reinstating the suspended official.

* Noteworthy, however, is that State Attorney is an *elected* position and the position is a regional one rather than statewide, in this case it applies only to the counties in a particular legal district. You can thus argue that the people who voted Warren in largely agree with his stance.

* It doesn&#39;t appear that there have been any *actual* cases where the State declined prosecution, so this appears to be a pre-emptive move by DeSantis. Although they allege that there is a non-prosecution policy for crimes where the initial encounter with police was due to non-criminal violations.

* Prosecutorial discretion is indeed a recognized legal concept which is usually given broad deference. I know of no mechanism by which anyone can *force* a State Attorney to bring charges against a given suspect/Defendant. This is a powerful tool because of double jeopardy protections, which means if given charges are officially dropped by the State Attorney, they can never be brought again, even if a *different* State Attorney argues that they were dropped for &#39;improper&#39; reasons. The whole point is that the prosecutor doesn&#39;t have to explain themselves.

* With that in mind, I actually wonder if Mr. Warren hadn&#39;t signed the public pledge, and instead had just quietly ordered his prosecutors to decline to prosecute any abortion cases that weren&#39;t, shall we say, &#39;egregious,&#39; he might not have been noticed and the case for removing him might be much weaker.

* There is a yet-untested argument that [Florida&#39;s Constitution actually *does* protect abortion](https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2022/06/florida-15-week-abortion-ban-state-constitution-privacy-rights.html) because Florida&#39;s &#39;right to privacy&#39; amendment was added after *Roe* was decided and thus could, even after the recent SCOTUS decision, be determined to have intended to codify abortion as part of the right to privacy.


My own thoughts: 

Desantis continues to show willingness to flex his authority as Governor in very targeted ways. This action is probably less objectionable than his moves targeting Disney since the subject is a government official who is directly employed by the State.

At a basic level, I have to agree with the action. Whatever your thoughts on the validity or morality of a given law, it is the very *definition* of dereliction of duty for a state attorney to decline to enforce laws that the legislature has passed and the governor has signed and thus nominally represent the will of the state&#39;s electorate. Their whole job, prosecutorial discretion or no, is to enact the will of the people of the state as expressed in its laws by prosecuting violations of said laws. It would be outrageous if a state attorney were to refuse to prosecute a given law in exchange for monetary gain, it is only somewhat less outrageous to refuse to prosecute for purely political reasons. 

So even if people take this as yet *another* sign of DeSantis&#39; fascistic ambitions to rule Florida, and later the Country, with an iron fist, this is still an utterly justifiable exercise of executive authority, and is well *within* the limits of the authority delegated to the Governor, so you cannot truly argue that this is a troubling expansion of executive authority by a power-mad wannabe Despot. 

Leaving aside the extant problems of enforcing abortion restrictions when it is simple to travel to a different state to get one, having a &#39;sanctuary city&#39; for abortions *within* the state would render the entire law almost moot since  Hillsborough County is at most a 4 hour drive from anywhere in the state except the deepest part of the panhandle.

And end of the day, it is a savvy move by Desantis as it will of course garner support from his base, it should also cause many possible opponents to keep their heads down, and the ones who will be emboldened to fight back pretty much already despise him, so net result is he has simply shored up his already strong position with minimal effort or political capital expended.

I see a few likely effects intended by this action. 

The First order effect is removing a rebellious official who might have grown into a bigger problem down the line. Whatever other steps Warren takes from here, he won&#39;t be able to use his position as a government official to legitimize his actions.

Second order is a warning to other state government officials, and not just state attorneys, that if they publicly assume a stance in defiance of the State Government, they will be summarily removed without prior warning and no waiting until they actually *do* something objectionable. This one action will probably force many other officials who quietly agreed with Warren to dutifully stay in line during Desantis&#39; tenure. 

Third-ish order is probably to prevent any sort of camel&#39;s nose from entering in the tent which could possibly lead to an avowed leftist like [Chesa Boudin](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chesa_Boudin) getting elected and declaring amnesty for other classes of crimes. 


It is also possible that this is aimed at being a direct response to [George Soros&#39;](https://www.wsj.com/articles/why-i-support-reform-prosecutors-law-enforces-jail-prison-crime-rate-justice-police-funding-11659277441) recent piece declaring his intent to continue to support/fund &#39;reform-minded prosecutors.&#39; This action would basically close that off as an avenue for social agitation in Florida.

The primary way this backfires is if Warren runs for office again and is elected again and thus a clear message is sent to Desantis that the constituents are rejecting Desantis&#39; influence and defying the laws he has championed. I&#39;m not sure how it shakes out, ultimately, if a given district &#39;goes rogue&#39; in electing someone *because* he promises to defy the state&#39;s authority. Desantis and the GOP-controlled legislature could absolutely escalate by taking actions that target the city/county/people more directly, but that would probably draw more ire than its worth.

Maybe he&#39;ll find some use for that [newly reformed state guard](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Florida_State_Guard) after all.

It&#39;s probably similar to how many [County Sheriffs will state their refusal to enforce gun control laws](https://www.npr.org/2019/02/21/696400737/when-sheriffs-wont-enforce-the-law). Arguably as long as their jurisdiction doesn&#39;t turn into a zone of open rebellion/insurrection necessitating intervention by state-level authorities you just leave things be and govern &#39;around&#39; the problem.

**EDIT:** and just so I cannot be accused of strawmanning, [here](https://twitter.com/NikkiFried/status/1555197696608182272) is a Democratic hopeful for the Florida Governorship in this year&#39;s election calling Desantis a &#34;wannabe dictator&#34; and this action &#34;outrageous and dangerous&#34; without elaborating. [Here&#39;s](https://twitter.com/CharlieCrist/status/1555227810326880256) the other hopeful echoing the &#39;wannabe dictator&#39; language and calling it an &#39;attack on women&#39; (but making the reasonable point that the State Attorney was elected twice so maybe his constituents like him.)

So this is in fact what the mainstream Democrats are willing to say about a Governor exercising lawful authority to ensure the enforcement of a (presently) valid law of the state.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iixrh4y/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>