<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Hailanathema - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T23:53:17Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Hailanathema" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij4fsrm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How about some more Twitter/Musk drama to round out the week? Last Friday Musk f</title><updated>2022-08-05T23:53:17Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How about some more Twitter/Musk drama to round out the week? Last Friday Musk filed (under seal) his reply to Twitter&#39;s complaint and his own counterclaims. There was a minor dustup between [Twitter](https://www.plainsite.org/dockets/download.html?id=308452085&amp;amp;z=9dde261e) and [Musk](https://www.plainsite.org/dockets/download.html?id=308462636&amp;amp;z=7b23ae73) about *when* the redacted copy of his reply could be made public. Court rules require that it be published five *business* days after it&#39;s filed under seal (so today) while Musk wanted to publish it on Wednesday (after five *calendar* days). Ultimately each side&#39;s lawyers had a meeting with the judge who ruled in favor of Twitter that Musk couldn&#39;t file it until today.

In any case we now have the redacted copy of [Musk&#39;s reply and counterclaims](https://www.plainsite.org/dockets/download.html?id=308502776&amp;amp;z=225aeced) as well as [Twitter&#39;s reply](https://s22.q4cdn.com/826641620/files/doc_news/2022/08/Twitters-Reply-to-Verified-Counterclaims.pdf) to Musk&#39;s counterclaims. If you can only read one document I recommend Twitter&#39;s, since it basically goes paragraph by paragraph through Musk&#39;s document and offers Twitter&#39;s response. Mostly this response is not very informative (&#34;Denied&#34;) but sometimes it is.

There are five counterclaims Musk asserts against Twitter.

The first counterclaim is for fraud, specifically with respect to Twitter&#39;s SEC filings and the fraction of its monetizable daily active users (mDAU) that are bots or spam accounts. I don&#39;t think this count is particularly likely to succeed. Twitter&#39;s statements in its SEC filings are extremely hedged and basically come out to &#34;We did process X, which involved significant judgment, to estimate the number of bots and got result Y. This result could be wrong.&#34; Musk&#39;s assertion that this is fraud seems to rest on (1) his own belief that Twitter&#39;s process is not very good and (2) an analysis his team did (that did not mimic Twitter&#39;s) on a different data set (that Twitter says does not include most mDAUs) which found a much higher number. I don&#39;t think either of those are fraud, so I don&#39;t think this is going anywhere.

The second counterclaim is for violations of the Texas Securities Act. Now, I&#39;m not a lawyer and definitely not a lawyer practicing in the Delaware Court of Chancery, but is that even a thing? Does the Delaware Court of Chancery have jurisdiction to enforce Texas&#39; state securities law? I actually have no idea here but it stuck out to me.

The third counterclaim is for breach of contract surrounding Twitter&#39;s refusal to provide Musk&#39;s team with certain information they requested. I suspect the outcome of this count turns a lot on how the judge interprets the language of the agreement. Musk seems to construe it pretty broadly as requiring Twitter to give him basically info he wants but I don&#39;t think the court is going to agree.

The fourth counterclaim is another breach of contract claim predicated on the departure or firing of certain Twitter employees after the announcement of Musk&#39;s purchase offer and Twitter&#39;s acceptance. This again seems like it comes down to a determination about the specific language of the contract, what Twitter did and did not need Musk&#39;s consent to do. I suppose my benefit of the doubt is with Twitter but again, I am not a lawyer.

The fifth and last counterclaim is seeking a declaratory judgement that a material adverse event (MAE) exists and is ongoing due to the number of mDAUs being much lower than Twitter has represented. If there were an existing and ongoing MAE that would be a basis for Musk to terminate the agreement. Given what it has taken for a Delaware court to find an MAE [in the past](https://www.jonesday.com/en/insights/2018/10/delaware-chancery-court-finally-finds-an-mae) I think this is unlikely to succeed.

Overall I remain pretty confident the court is going to find for Twitter and order specific performance. Twitter&#39;s stock price is up almost 4% today which makes me think the market agrees.

ETA:

As regards claim four Twitter asserts in its 14th affirmative defense that Musk&#39;s claim under Texas law is barred by the agreement&#39;s specification that Delaware law controls:

&amp;gt; Defendants’ Counterclaim under the Texas Securities Act is barred, in whole
or in part, because Delaware law governs all claims arising out of or relating to the
Merger Agreement.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/ij4fsrm/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article2</title><updated>2022-08-03T03:21:34Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article263823143.html) (as of the time of this writing) of votes being counted it seems the attempt to amend Kansas&#39; constitution to clarify that it *does not* protect a fundamental right to abortion has **failed** 60-40. The amendment was a reaction to a [Kansas Supreme Court ruling](https://www.kscourts.org/KSCourts/media/KsCourts/Opinions/114153_2.pdf?ext=.pdf) from 2019 that found the Kansas constitution protected a fundamental right to abortion. This ruling required state regulations on abortion to overcome strict scrutiny to be constitutional. The [full text](https://sos.ks.gov/elections/22elec/2022-Primary-Election-Constitutional-Amendment-HCR-5003.pdf) of the amendment:

&amp;gt;Because Kansans value both women and children, the constitution of the state of Kansas does not require government funding of abortion and does not create or secure a right to abortion. To the extent permitted by the constitution of the United States, the people, through their elected state representatives and state senators, may pass laws regarding abortion, including, but not limited to, laws that account for circumstances of pregnancy resulting from rape or incest, or circumstances necessary to save the life of the mother.

As someone whose pro-choice I&#39;m encouraged by this result. The people of Kansas apparently prefer a constitutional right to abortion to having legislative control of it. I don&#39;t want to generalize this too far outside of this one race but it seems to indicate abortion may be a winning issue for Democrats.

ETA:

I didn&#39;t know about this when I wrote the above but something similar happened in Mississippi in [2011](https://ballotpedia.org/Mississippi_Initiative_26,_Definition_of_Person_Amendment_\(2011\)). Mississippi had a ballot initiative trying to amend their state constitution so that the definition of &#34;person&#34; would include &#34;every human being from the moment of fertilization.&#34; That amendment was defeated by a pretty similar margin (58-42).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>