<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Hailanathema - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-20T20:50:15Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Hailanathema" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igyr7zl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How about a post on some recent Congressional legislation?

---

The House of Re</title><updated>2022-07-20T20:50:15Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How about a post on some recent Congressional legislation?

---

The House of Representatives has now passed two bills aimed at protecting abortion rights. 

The first is the [Women&#39;s Health Protection Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/3755/text). This bill basically sets out a list of reasons why abortions may not be restricted and creates a test for what future reasons will be prohibited by the law. It targets pretty directly laws various Republican states passed when *Roe* was still in effect to limit abortion. It empowers both the US Attorney General and private parties (including those seeking abortions and those providing them) to sue to enforce the law.

The second of these is the [Ensuring Women’s Right to Reproductive Freedom Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/8297/text?r=1&amp;amp;s=1). This law creates liability (enforced by either the Attorney General or private citizens) for anyone acting under color of State law who tries to prevent someone from traveling interstate for the purpose of getting an abortion that would be legal in the state they are going to have it done in.

Both bills passed the House with all but one Democrat in favor and all Republicans against.

Both bills are most likely dead on arrival in the Senate.

---

On Tuesday the House of Representatives also passed the [Respect For Marriage Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/8404/text) which enshrines, not [*Obergefell v. Hodges*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obergefell_v._Hodges) but rather [*United States v. Windsor*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_v._Windsor) into federal law. The law does not require that states perform either same sex or interracial marriages but it does require they recognize those marriages if performed in other states where they are legal. It is also enforceable by either the Attorney General or a private right of action. The law also clarifies that the federal definition of marriage includes both interracial and same sex marriages.

Interestingly 47 Republicans (~one-fourth of the caucus) joined the Democrats in passing the bill. If a similar fraction of Senate Republicans support the bill that would be sufficient to invoke cloture and pass it.

---

Finally, introduced today by a bipartisan group of Senators (but not passed anywhere) is the [Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022](https://www.democracydocket.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/electoral_count_reform_and_presidential_transition_improvement_act_of_2022.pdf). Exploitation of some ambiguity in the 12th amendment and Electoral Count Act (USC 3) were key to John Eastman&#39;s plan for Trump to retain the presidency even after losing the 2020 election. This act is an attempt to remove that ambiguity. The Act does so first by clarifying that state electors are determined by the laws of the state *prior to election day*. This is to prevent state legislatures from changing who the electors are after the vote has happened (unless they delegated themselves that power in advance). The Act also raises the threshold necessary to trigger a vote on an objection from one Senator and one Representative to one-fifth of Senators and Representatives. It also clarifies the grounds on which electors may be objected to. Finally it clarifies that the role of the President of the Senate is ministerial only and sets up an expedited legal process (three judge panel, then SCOTUS) for hearing challenges to election certification.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/igyr7zl/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>