<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Hailanathema - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T03:21:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Hailanathema" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article2</title><updated>2022-08-03T03:21:34Z</updated><author><name>Hailanathema</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">With [80%](https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article263823143.html) (as of the time of this writing) of votes being counted it seems the attempt to amend Kansas&#39; constitution to clarify that it *does not* protect a fundamental right to abortion has **failed** 60-40. The amendment was a reaction to a [Kansas Supreme Court ruling](https://www.kscourts.org/KSCourts/media/KsCourts/Opinions/114153_2.pdf?ext=.pdf) from 2019 that found the Kansas constitution protected a fundamental right to abortion. This ruling required state regulations on abortion to overcome strict scrutiny to be constitutional. The [full text](https://sos.ks.gov/elections/22elec/2022-Primary-Election-Constitutional-Amendment-HCR-5003.pdf) of the amendment:

&amp;gt;Because Kansans value both women and children, the constitution of the state of Kansas does not require government funding of abortion and does not create or secure a right to abortion. To the extent permitted by the constitution of the United States, the people, through their elected state representatives and state senators, may pass laws regarding abortion, including, but not limited to, laws that account for circumstances of pregnancy resulting from rape or incest, or circumstances necessary to save the life of the mother.

As someone whose pro-choice I&#39;m encouraged by this result. The people of Kansas apparently prefer a constitutional right to abortion to having legislative control of it. I don&#39;t want to generalize this too far outside of this one race but it seems to indicate abortion may be a winning issue for Democrats.

ETA:

I didn&#39;t know about this when I wrote the above but something similar happened in Mississippi in [2011](https://ballotpedia.org/Mississippi_Initiative_26,_Definition_of_Person_Amendment_\(2011\)). Mississippi had a ballot initiative trying to amend their state constitution so that the definition of &#34;person&#34; would include &#34;every human being from the moment of fertilization.&#34; That amendment was defeated by a pretty similar margin (58-42).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqifuk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>