<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/HalloweenSnarry - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T09:47:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/HalloweenSnarry" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikhznez/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] To springboard off of Ilforte&#39;s post about AI-generated art below, I wanted to f</title><updated>2022-08-16T09:47:35Z</updated><author><name>HalloweenSnarry</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">To springboard off of Ilforte&#39;s post about AI-generated art below, I wanted to find an old ratsphere Tumblr post about &#34;living in the last era of great art,&#34; but I couldn&#39;t find it (thanks to Tumblr&#39;s jank search feature). I did, however, find [this post](https://the-grey-tribe.tumblr.com/post/676558263243997184/there-are-too-many-video-games) arguing about a [Jeff Vogel article](https://bottomfeeder.substack.com/p/there-are-too-many-video-games) about there being too many indie video games.

Leaving aside the...very debateable mertits of said article, this reinforced something that I&#39;ve been thinking about today: is there too much *everything?*

To lay out the life of a modern Western person: there is practically-infinite entertainment to be found, and little worthy work to apply oneself to. Decades ago, supposedly, there were jobs that one could take pride in or even enjoy, and you had to take what you could get for entertainment. Today, there&#39;s so many video games, YouTube videos, TV shows, movies, Twitch livestreams, books, music, and so on to consume. Hundreds of thousands of people are constantly adding onto this pile of information, not to mention a lot the good stuff that came before is still accessible today. This sounds like the end part of Metal Gear Solid 2, which outlines a vision of informational overload, civilizational senesence brought on from the halting of traditional informational eugenics. MGS2 was said to have predicted the Internet&#39;s impact and social media, but I feel that this issue of [monumentality](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bwGKqiOyIAM), of living in a world with vastly more information than you could ever hope to consume in your lifetime, would not have been forestalled in a world without social media or internet forums.

There&#39;s also the dismal material aspects to consider. The world&#39;s population is somewhere just north of 8 billion, every grocery store is stocked with food products engineered for mass-producibility and cheapness at the cost of other desirable factors, and every person&#39;s estimated impact on politics or productivity is likely so infitesimal as to not matter at all. It seems like getting any job more complex or higher-paying than a burger-flipper or Amazon warehouse worker is a competition where luck is as much of a factor as merit or credentials. On one hand, there are going to be a lot of people who are going to be eliminated from the job market by automation. On the other hand, there may not be enough money to support so many people with welfare. On the third hand, however, the US is no stranger to playing funny games with the nominal numbers of dollar bills that are sent into &#34;the wild.&#34;

Maybe this is just the painful transition period, the growing pains. Perhaps in the future, we will deftly handle these problems brought about by the monumentality of civilization: every job that is too competitive or unrewarding now will be automated, every person will be provided for, and maybe, just maybe, we can still forage *meaning* out of life. Maybe some catastrophe will burn through the forest of human civilization and free up slack in the system (but that&#39;s a big maybe, assuming said catastrophe doesn&#39;t make things so bad that we can never recover). Or maybe things just continue onwards and the human race blindly enters into the biggest rat race of all.

Maybe this is all just my own particular anxieties. I&#39;m more of an artist, I don&#39;t code, and while I&#39;m no stranger to lifting a finger for a job, a fair bit of that was sweeping floors and washing dishes at college. Vogel complains about potholes in his article, but what is there to do when you have no hope of making it as neither an artist nor a road worker?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikhznez/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>