<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/HalloweenSnarry - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T04:36:10Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/HalloweenSnarry" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijtgwi4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] EDIT: [My apologies, this may have all been bullshit.](https://twitter.com/Ashle</title><updated>2022-08-11T04:36:10Z</updated><author><name>HalloweenSnarry</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">EDIT: [My apologies, this may have all been bullshit.](https://twitter.com/AshleyLatke/status/1557430756267511808) Original post follows below.

----

Dispatches from the War on Horny, per Dexerto: [OnlyFans bribed Meta into suppressing competitor sites by having models on said sites labeled as &#34;terrorists&#34; on FB and Instagram.](https://twitter.com/Dexerto/status/1557491228232622081)

I&#39;m reminded of the recent story about PredictIt losing the legal cover it had, along with the allegation that rival site Kalshi basically engaged in [regulatory capture](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulatory_capture) to get the CFTC to not only approve them, but de-approve PredictIt.

This is a story not merely about how society treats sex work, but more about how sex work is the canary in the coal mine that often exposes the ways in which our economic system fails. First there was deplatforming and the impossibilities of &#34;building your own&#34; (a story that also involved OnlyFans), now there is the reminder that sufficiently-large actors can wield enough clout to just *ask* platform-holders to essentially put their competitors out of business. Now, if you&#39;re reading this, chances are you&#39;re likely about to respond about how government regulation actually enforces monopolies, but this story is about Facebook (granted, maybe this isn&#39;t much different depending on how much you believe that FB is essentially an arm of the US Government), who effectively controls a large chunk of the modern surface internet.

It&#39;s one thing for there to be rules and regulations in place, but much of our legal landscape is in effect very malleable and prone to change on the say-so of ultimately-human agents. Of course, I know that money and words have always been weaknesses in our democratic institutions, but this is just more grist for the mill of &#34;the real power is not just in Washington.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijtgwi4/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>