<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Haroldbkny - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-31T16:09:55Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Haroldbkny" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaodwqd/</id><title type="text">[CW] I was looking back at this old SSC article titled [Why Are Transgender People Im</title><updated>2022-05-31T16:09:55Z</updated><author><name>Haroldbkny</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I was looking back at this old SSC article titled [Why Are Transgender People Immune To Optical Illusions](https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/06/28/why-are-transgender-people-immune-to-optical-illusions/), and I want to make sure I understand it. Is Scott saying that hormone therapy is a treatment for any disorder involving feelings of disassociation, or just those caused by gender dysphoria? Or is it simply not known?

I&#39;m wondering if the implication is that trans people have feelings of disassociation, and getting hormone injections help them feel better about that, simply because hormones help anyone have less feelings of disassociation. And then some people in the medical establishment took that and ran with it and said &#34;this proves that the trans person was really in the wrong body!&#34;, even if it really just proves that hormones are a good treatment for feelings of disassociation. 

I think that Scott&#39;s article could read as indicating that (at least some) trans people simply have weird bodily feelings more often than other people, and then they get suggested or they come to the conclusion that it&#39;s because they&#39;re really born into the wrong sex, and they latch onto that idea, and then it just so happens that hormones also help cure that, so that reaffirms their conclusion. Am I reading that correctly, or are my own biases coming into play to draw certain conclusions?

My knowledge on this subject is next to zero. Could someone with better medical knowledge help me understand?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaodwqd/"/></entry></feed>