<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Haroldbkny - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T20:41:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Haroldbkny" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilx1wqg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] When I was in middle school, there were boys in my school that everyone just pos</title><updated>2022-08-26T20:41:46Z</updated><author><name>Haroldbkny</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">When I was in middle school, there were boys in my school that everyone just positively knew were gay. Some acted effeminate, some had a strange sense of humor, some were quirky, some walked funny or had certain affectations in their voice. Basically in all the standard gay stereotypes that we have as a society (or maybe in general? Do those stereotypes hold cross-culturally?). I maintained, as I was taught at the time, that just because someone acts that way, it has no bearing on their sexual orientation. They could be effeminate, but still like women. And as we grew up, guess what? Those boys all came out of the closet as gay, some in high school, some afterward.

I could see 3 possibilities:

1. The stereotypes are stereotypes for a reason. They acted that way because having those behaviors were highly correlated with being gay. Basically, liking men goes hand in hand with gay behavior, for most cases
2. Because everyone in their lives &#34;knew&#34; they were gay due to the way that they acted, they absorbed it into their own sense of self, and thus, essentially became gay. Basically, gay behavior leads to liking men.
3. Because they were gay, they saw the signals that you&#39;re supposed to produce in the culture, and subsequently acted them out. Basically, liking men leads to gay behavior

I&#39;m not sure which makes the most sense as an explanation.

I&#39;m still disturbed that I was the &#34;good&#34; kid, who did as I was told, and did not judge anyone or make assumptions about anyone based on their signals, just as I was taught to, and ended up being 100% wrong because of it. I also wonder if the popular perception in culture has changed, these days. With so much emphasis on identity, are people still taught that anyone could be anything, and that their behavior is uncorrelated to their sexual identity? Or does being gay go beyond just liking men, and it&#39;s more about performance than ever?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilx1wqg/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>