<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/herzenslied - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-12T20:37:25Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/herzenslied" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifwjyxh/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Does anybody have experience with, and/or can recommend, apps for forming online</title><updated>2022-07-12T20:37:25Z</updated><author><name>herzenslied</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Does anybody have experience with, and/or can recommend, apps for forming online friendships with people nearby-ish?

I&#39;ve had some decent amount of success with language learning apps like HelloTalk and Tandem, but seeing as these are gained primarily towards language *learning*, I don&#39;t really meet people in *my own* country/region via them - only foreigners. This kinda bums me out as every single one of my friends is too far away to visit comfortably, and I don&#39;t currently see the need to increase that number further.

This is something I&#39;d like to change, but I can&#39;t really think of any apps that suit the bill. Unfortunately, the app market is of the &#34;95% shit, 5% decent&#34; variety, so any tips that could speed up my process of going through the seemingly inexhaustible list of garbage-quality &#34;friend finding apps&#34; on the play store would be greatly appreciated.

Specifically, I&#39;m looking for something that *isn&#39;t* just another dating app clone Tinder-wannabe (like the top search results for &#34;friends&#34; on the play store all seem to be). But something more like the apps I mentioned above, where you can actually send messages to people, reach out, and form friendships based on common interests.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifwjyxh/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>