<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/huadpe - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-31T15:00:11Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/huadpe" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/iie038y/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Democrats in... Array?

Against all expectations, the Democratic party seems to </title><updated>2022-07-31T15:00:11Z</updated><author><name>huadpe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Democrats in... Array?

Against all expectations, the Democratic party seems to suddenly be having a pretty good summer.  

First, Joe Manchin and Chuck Schumer seem to have snookered Mitch McConnell, with Manchin loudly ditching any version of Build Back Better a few weeks ago, which lulled McConnell into allowing a vote on the CHIPS bill that had been his main leverage point against a reconciliation bill.  

As soon as that vote was done, Schumer and Manchin announced that the deal was back on, with the bill being renamed the &#34;Inflation Reduction Act&#34; and having a tax hike on corporate income plus more IRS enforcement money, to pay for a bunch of green energy spending and expansions to Obamacare, plus some deficit reduction.

Republicans have decided as retaliation to self-immolate themselves by filibustering burn pit legislation, which regardless of the merits of their complaints, is complete political malpractice.  &#34;Veterans who got sick/injured serving in war&#34; is about the hardest group to pit yourself against in American politics.

Prior to that, the Jan 6 committee hearings have gone roughly as well as possible for Democrats, with [the DoJ now taking investigative steps fairly openly against Trump himself](https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2022/07/26/trump-justice-investigation-january-6/) and Republicans fractured around defending Trump, and mostly trying to avoid the subject.

Republicans are additionally fractured now on abortion politics, with the reality of abortion bans not being especially popular, and with Democrats armed to the teeth with sympathetic stories, such as a [10 year old rape victim,](https://www.dispatch.com/story/news/2022/07/13/columbus-man-charged-rape-10-year-old-led-abortion-in-indiana/10046625002/) or miscarrying women who have been [left in limbo while their condition degrades enough that an abortion to save their life becomes permitted.](https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2022/07/26/1111280165/because-of-texas-abortion-law-her-wanted-pregnancy-became-a-medical-nightmare)

The biggest weight around Democrats&#39; neck, inflation and the economy, also seems to be mildly improving.  Gas prices at least have dropped from their peaks, though are still quite historically high.  And employment remains quite robust.  

This is reflected in the polling, with [Democrats chances as forecast by FiveThirtyEight meaningfully improving in the past month](https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-political-environment-might-be-improving-for-democrats/) despite the fact that usually very little changes in the midterm campaign in July.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/iie038y/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>