<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/huadpe - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-31T05:07:43Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/huadpe" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imhhqa5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The DoJ has filed [their response](https://int.nyt.com/data/documenttools/doj-re</title><updated>2022-08-31T05:07:43Z</updated><author><name>huadpe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The DoJ has filed [their response](https://int.nyt.com/data/documenttools/doj-response-to-trump-request-for-special-master/1b30feb331082a68/full.pdf) to Trump&#39;s request to appoint a special master.  It is quite long, has a number of attachments, and gives us a lot more insight into the investigation so far.

My highlights:

1.  The filing includes a partially redacted photo of some of the documents seized during the search. *(Attachment F, last page of the pdf)*

 This photo will be the front page of basically every paper tomorrow, and was certainly a conscious choice to include as it looks extremely damning.  There are a bunch of documents with really blatant cover sheets and TOP SECRET // SCI printed in 36 point red font multiple times.

2.  The filing also gives us a copy of the subpoena that was issued on May 11 of this year, and the response provided on June 3. *(attachments C and E)*

 The subpoena demanded:

 &amp;gt;Any and all documents or writings in the custody or control of Donald J. Trump and/or the Office of
Donald J. Trump bearing classification markings, including but not limited to the following: Top Secret,
Secret , Confidential, Top Secret/ SI- G/NOFORN/ ORCON , Top Secret/ SI-G/NOFORN, Top Secret/HCS
O /NOFORN/ ORCON, Top Secret/ HCS- /NOFORN, Top Secret/HCS- P/NOFORN/ ORCON,
Secret/ HCS- P/NOFORN, Top Secret/ TK/ NOFORN/ ORCON, Top Secret/ TK/ NOFORN,
Secret NOFORN, Confidential/ NOFORN, TS , TS / SAP , TS / SI-G/NF/OC , TS / SI- G/ NF, TS/ HCS
O/ NF/ OC, TS/ HCS- O/NF, TS/ HCS- P/NF/ OC , TS / HCS-P/ NF, TS/ HCS- P/ SI- G, TS / HCS- P/ SI/ TK ,
TS/ TK/NF/ OC , TS/ TK/NF, S/ NF, S / FRD , S /NATO, S / SI, C , and C /NF

 The response said:

 &amp;gt;Based upon the information that has been provided to me ,I am authorized to certify , on
behalf of the Office of Donald J. Trump , the following :

 &amp;gt;a. A diligent search was conducted of the boxes that were moved from the White
House to Florida;

 &amp;gt;b. This search was conducted after receipt of the subpoena, in order to locate any
and all documents that are responsive to the subpoena;

 &amp;gt;c. Any and all responsive documents accompany this certification; and

 &amp;gt; d. No copy, written notation, or reproduction of any kind was retained as to any
responsive document.

 &amp;gt;I swear or affirm that the above statements are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

 The response to the subpoena was to produce a single envelope, double wrapped in tape, which contained 38 documents with different classification markings.

3.  DoJ says they found classified documents in Trump&#39;s office desk in the drawer which contained his passports, *(p. 12)* which was the reason his passports were seized.  The warrant told them to seize all contents of any containers that have classified information.

4. DoJ says multiple times *(p. 4 and 8)* that at no point prior to the execution of the search warrant execution did Trump claim he had declassified any of these documents despite numerous opportunities to do so.

5. DoJ hints at some specific evidence about documents being moved around Mar-A-Lago beyond what&#39;s known so far.  In particular they say *(p. 10)*:

 &amp;gt;Through further investigation, the FBI uncovered multiple sources of evidence
indicating that the response to the May 11 grand jury subpoena was incomplete and that
classified documents remained at the Premises, notwithstanding the sworn certification made
to the government on June 3. In particular, the government developed evidence that a search
limited to the Storage Room would not have uncovered all the classified documents at the
Premises. The government also developed evidence that government records were likely
concealed and removed from the Storage Room and that efforts were likely taken to obstruct
the government’s investigation. ... This included evidence indicating that boxes formerly in the Storage Room
were not returned prior to counsel’s review.

6. DoJ says they have finished their privilege review for attorney/client privilege already, and do not think executive privilege can possibly apply, and did not filter for it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imhhqa5/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>