<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/huadpe - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T17:47:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/huadpe" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilwbtis/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A fairly heavily redacted copy of [the search warrant affidavit for Mar-A-Lago](</title><updated>2022-08-26T17:47:50Z</updated><author><name>huadpe</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A fairly heavily redacted copy of [the search warrant affidavit for Mar-A-Lago](https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.617854/gov.uscourts.flsd.617854.102.1.pdf) has been unsealed by the court, as well as a redacted [govt legal memo regarding those redactions](https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.617854/gov.uscourts.flsd.617854.98.0_4.pdf) 

Biggest new things in the documents that we can see:

1.  The 15 boxes of documents provided by Trump to NARA in Feb 2022 contained:
 
 184 unique documents bearing classification markings, of which 67 were marked Confidential, 92 were marked Secret, and 25 were marked Top Secret.  An unspecified number of them also contained HCS, FISA, NOFORN, and SI markings. *(warrant affadavit, para 47)*

2. The DoJ investigation seems to be specifically centered around section (e) of the Espionage Act, which says:

 &amp;gt;Whoever having unauthorized possession of, access to, or control over any document, writing, code book, signal book, sketch, photograph, photographic negative, blueprint, plan, map, model, instrument, appliance, or note relating to the national defense, or information relating to the national defense which information the possessor has reason to believe could be used to the injury of the United States or to the advantage of any foreign nation, willfully communicates, delivers, transmits or causes to be communicated, delivered, or transmitted, or attempts to communicate, deliver, transmit or cause to be communicated, delivered, or transmitted the same to any person not entitled to receive it, or willfully retains the same and fails to deliver it to the officer or employee of the United States entitled to receive it ... Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both. *(warrant affadavit, para 8)*

3.  DoJ is saying that the warrant was in part based on evidence from &#34;multiple civilian witnesses.&#34; *(memo of law, pg 4)* 

4. DoJ presented Trump&#39;s claims about declassification authority to the judge before the warrant was issued, and released as an attachment to the affidavit [a May 25, 2022 letter from Trump&#39;s attorneys they provided to the court.](https://www.politico.com/f/?id=00000182-daec-dfd1-adef-dafe79d30000) *(p. 34-36 of that link)*</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilwbtis/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>