<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/I_Dream_of_Outremer - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-04T07:10:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/I_Dream_of_Outremer" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iivy7kw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some things just seem to &#39;maximize&#39; and only grow in one direction. 

When I was</title><updated>2022-08-04T07:10:26Z</updated><author><name>I_Dream_of_Outremer</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some things just seem to &#39;maximize&#39; and only grow in one direction. 

When I was a kid the only commercials in baseball were on static billboards and in between innings, which was bad enough, to be sure. But they slowly started having &#39;sponsors&#39; for big events (the World Series brought to you by Ford), which morphed into &#39;sponsors&#39; for tiny events (the GameDay StatCast powered by Intel), which grew into &#39;sponsors&#39; for absolutely anything (if your team hits a homerun today you get a free burger tomorrow). Then moving, active billboards, all game long. Then sponsors on the mound, etc, and now they even have mini-ads in between pitches.

&#39;More of this is better&#39; seems to sometimes be the active principle, and (*here&#39;s my point*) I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s terminally so with &#39;liberalism.&#39; I used to like what it had to offer, but now I&#39;ve been pushed far enough that I want my baseball advertisement-free and don&#39;t particularly care how that comes about.

[Somewhere around 94% of abortion is elective](https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6874-13-29/tables/2) - maybe it&#39;s a good idea to not make people forcefully adopt cats and dogs - but if your &#39;pet shelters&#39; are killing ~94% of their &#39;patients&#39; for no morally defensible reason maybe you&#39;re more akin to the Aztecs then a healthcare provider.

More vs less abortion. More vs less immigration, especially illegal. More vs less income taxed away. More vs less kids being sexualized and taught about sex stuff. More vs less affirmative action. More vs less war in far off places. More vs less regulation. More vs less corporate consolidation. More vs less &#39;gun control.&#39; 

&amp;gt;The mother of excess is not joy but joylessness.

-Nietzsche</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iivy7kw/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>