<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/i_like_big_mottes - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-31T20:47:18Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/i_like_big_mottes" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iapfnja/</id><title type="text">[CW] One subject that comes up frequently is the philosophy of r/fuckcars. This is a </title><updated>2022-05-31T20:47:18Z</updated><author><name>i_like_big_mottes</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">One subject that comes up frequently is the philosophy of r/fuckcars. This is a facet of the culture war that I find fascinating, and that also hits close to home. 

I have some unique insight, as I’ve spent the last four years traveling full-time with my family of six, essentially as a family of digital nomads. I&#39;ve had the chance to experience everything from giant cities to tiny rural towns, and just about everything in between. I’ve lived in both the United States and Europe, and  I’ve spent a decent amount of time in each place we’ve experienced - meaning a month or more, beyond just living as a tourist for a week. We’ve had to buy groceries, do laundry, and get around using either a car or public transportation, just like we would if we lived there permanently.

We’re not going to be nomadic forever, so I’ve spent a lot of time thinking about what I’d like my future lifestyle to look like. Here are some things I think are important:

* I’d like to get groceries for my family once or twice a week.
* I’d like my kids to be able to go outside to play on their own terms, not when mom or dad can take the time away from their obligations to give them specially supervised outdoor time.
* I’d like to visit my out-of-state siblings once or twice a year.
* I’d like to get into nature 4-5 times per year, whether that’s hiking or camping or both. Some of these trips will involve bringing my kids.

These don’t come off to me as unreasonable or excessive, but they seem to be totally impossible in the ideal r/fuckcars world. Grocery shopping becomes wildly inconvenient, taking several times as long. Kids can’t go outside as they please. Long travel becomes extremely difficult, and long travel into nature becomes nearly impossible. 

I understand that having kids meant taking on extra work, and I made that trade willingly (and would do it again). I don’t expect society to bend over backwards to make my life easier, but any society that goes out of its way to make life more difficult for parents is only hurting itself in the long run.

There are a lot of use cases that fit cleanly into an ideal r/fuckcars world. If you’re a young white collar worker in a big city with lots of nightlife, or if you’re visiting one of those temporarily, that world would be amazing. But there are other use cases beyond parenting that don’t seem to have much of a place. What about people with physical disabilities? First responders? Ambulances? Fire trucks? Delivery trucks? Do those not exist in the r/fuckcars world? 

I think they do exist in that world, which means we’ll still need the exact same amount of infrastructure to support them. Maybe we can take a four line highway down to two lanes, or maybe we can get rid of a few parking lots (and granted, there&#39;s a lot of r/fuckcars hate for parking lots). But we’ll still need just as many miles of road, with every house accessible by car. And at that point, aren’t we really just determining who is and isn’t allowed to use that infrastructure?

The whole thing feels very much like a motte-and-bailey, with the motte being “Cars are loud and dirty and dangerous, fuck them” and the bailey being “Cars are loud and dirty and dangerous, fuck them, also everyone who has a different lifestyle than me.”</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iapfnja/"/></entry></feed>