<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Iconochasm - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T01:42:15Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Iconochasm" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizy0yn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I caught [this campaign ad tonight](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RHxQFqbdFUk)</title><updated>2022-08-05T01:42:15Z</updated><author><name>Iconochasm</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I caught [this campaign ad tonight](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RHxQFqbdFUk).  Watch that.  It&#39;s only a minute. 

What party do you think John is in?  There is actually a reference, but it&#39;s quick.  I missed it when I saw it live.

I feel like there&#39;s a lot to unpack here.  Fetterman is going to fight Washington?  Where his party has the White House, the House and the Senate???  Because people feel forgotten, like their best time was a generation ago?  A decade of left-leaning media has taught me that that&#39;s a blatant racist dog-whistle, appealing to aggrieved white entitlement.  Maybe it&#39;s just smart, faux-flag campaigning in a red wave year with a very unpopular president.

Here is Fetterman&#39;s [spot on gun violence](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Krqv8O4ENQ).  This one&#39;s 2.5 minutes; that&#39;s how I getcha.  So, a couple of things to note.  First, in the story he tells in that bit, the person he went after was, in fact, not any kind of a shooter.  It was, according to [The Root](https://www.theroot.com/john-fetterman-has-had-eight-years-to-apologize-for-pul-1846249115) literally some unarmed black jogger that Fetterman pulled a shotgun on.  Second, the town of Braddock has a population of [1,721](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Braddock,_Pennsylvania).  Managing to go *a whole five years* without a *fatal* shooting seems like the kind of low bar you describe as damning with faint praise.  But maybe Fetterman was the magic ingredient - they had another murder in [2018](https://www.city-data.com/crime/crime-Braddock-Pennsylvania.html), in [2020](https://www.wpxi.com/news/top-stories/he-was-one-most-loyal-people-loved-ones-remember-man-shot-killed-north-braddock/3KVFBCDYPZG3FEISI5DCJK2Y5Q/), and another just a [few weeks ago.](https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/man-dead-after-overnight-shooting-braddock/C6JVNFDK3NDXXPJMGO5HLN3PO4/)

Fetterman is, belying appearances, a Harvard School of Government grad who has been called a [&#34;carpetbagger&#34;](https://whyy.org/articles/braddock-made-john-fetterman-a-politician-its-also-home-to-some-of-his-biggest-critics/).  This is kind of funny because the opponent he is leading by [11 points](https://www.forbes.com/sites/nicholasreimann/2022/07/28/fetterman-takes-double-digit-lead-over-oz-in-new-pennsylvania-poll/?sh=5fe0b07d6227) is absurd TV clown doctor/carpetbagger, [Dr. Mehmet Oz](https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2022/jul/18/john-fetterman-knocks-mehmet-oz-carpetbagger-attac/), who was last seen getting rolled by [Joe Rogan](https://twitter.com/joerogan/status/546471534768828417?lang=en).  Fetterman has been blasting out attack ads while he recovers from his stroke - yes, that&#39;s right, he had a minor stroke a few months ago, because he was diagnosed with a heart condition, and then didn&#39;t go to a doctor for 5 years.

You know, single-payer stuff aside, I think he&#39;s my new favorite Democrat.

All of which is to say that I hate campaign season, I hate seeing these ads, and whatever the outcome is, yes, actually, but more stupider.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizy0yn/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>