<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/IdkWhatToSay01 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T21:01:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/IdkWhatToSay01" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/iln9sr0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] a theory for why violent crime might be going up.

I&#39;m sure there are a variety </title><updated>2022-08-24T21:01:27Z</updated><author><name>IdkWhatToSay01</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">a theory for why violent crime might be going up.

I&#39;m sure there are a variety of factors contributing here, but one that I think is probably a relevant is that violent crime is [disproportionately](https://bjs.ojp.gov/content/pub/pdf/revcoa18.pdf) committed by black people, so focusing on arresting violent offenders would necessarily result in disproportionately arresting black people. Or perhaps that black people received longer sentences under the current government 
 in the event that violent offenders tend to get longer sentences.  No one lobbying for the progressive, or perhaps even black, vote wants to be the focus of a headline saying that arrests of black people increased under their leadership. Conversations surrounding equity are simply not nuanced enough for the politician to be able to counter that there&#39;s more to it than those statistics, that it&#39;s just because they focused more on violent crime so people who commit violent crime were arrested at higher rates. And this could also explain why violent crime rates have gone up more in blue cities on a per capita basis. 

I just wanna say, I hate to be the guy to bring this point up. I&#39;m not just out here looking to take jabs like this, so if there is anything I&#39;m missing, definitely let me know.

My ultimate point is that I have to imagine politicians on the left looking for votes are not unaware of this reasoning.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/iln9sr0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>