<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ikeepfalling2 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-21T12:38:42Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ikeepfalling2" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il6p8nd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Hopefully this has enough effort in it to be a top-level.

Sunday morning musing</title><updated>2022-08-21T12:38:42Z</updated><author><name>ikeepfalling2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Hopefully this has enough effort in it to be a top-level.

Sunday morning musings: equality is *good*! &#34;All men are created equal&#34; and other cultures&#39; versions thereof, is a great idea. Why, you ask, in light of all the talk about sorting meritocracy and the like elsewhere in the thread? Because it makes elections and government possible. Obviously that has its ups and downs, but as we&#39;ve seen so far, governmental transitions aren&#39;t usually punctuated by revolutions.

I posit that this is only possible when you take &#34;all men are created equal&#34; (before the law) as an axiom. If you don&#39;t, that means that we need to have some sort of measure to see who is more equal or less equal - and who would consent to (i.e. vote for) being governed by a state that can decide one&#39;s standing before the law on a whim? That&#39;s just totalitarianism but without even bothering to declare someone an enemy of the state. Peaceful transition? Maybe lots of people involved in opposition political campaigns wind up ... less equal.

So it seems like in order to actually have a government that has a mandate from the governed (or at least doesn&#39;t involve a coup), it&#39;s necessary to say &#34;all men are created equal&#34;.

It occurs to me that it&#39;s a little worrisome that both sides in the USA are turning up the &#34;the other is EVIL and needs to be DESTROYED&#34; knob to 11, because all of a sudden it&#39;s people are equal, _but_...</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il6p8nd/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>