<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ikeepfalling2 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T11:55:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ikeepfalling2" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/im497t8/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So the USA is supposed to be this semi-libertarian, cutthroat, winner-take-all a</title><updated>2022-08-28T11:55:45Z</updated><author><name>ikeepfalling2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So the USA is supposed to be this semi-libertarian, cutthroat, winner-take-all and fuck the rest place, if you ever hear a non-American speak of the country. But it sure isn&#39;t! Somehow every big blue city managed to vote its way into high taxes and low law enforcement, individual states (RI, I forget about any others) tried to turn travel into &#34;papers, please&#34;, and the president forced every gov&#39;t employee to either take a shot (not discussing efficacy, just the coercion) or quit their jobs. 

So I&#39;m very curious - why do Americans suddenly care about their neighbors? How did the country go from &#34;fuck you, I&#39;m gonna do what I want&#34; to &#34;Heaven forbid I misgender you&#34;? What happened to the people that conquered every frontier they could find? I&#39;m not asking rhetorically, I&#39;m genuinely puzzled as to how the culture has completely changed, because it can&#39;t be as simple as a top-down change - after all, the USSR fell apart, and the state controlled the entirety of the educational pipeline. 

Here&#39;s the real question, finally: what made the general person in America suddenly in favor of redistribution? What got everyone to stop feeling like a temporarily embarrassed millionaire? And why did it work in the USA? It can&#39;t be as simple as a top-down edict, because if that actually worked, the USSR would still be around. And yet, country that was the antithesis of communism seems to be leaning in to the nanny state thing pretty hard. Is it just because the USSR fell apart and there&#39;s no longer any counterexample to warn away from? What happened to the nine scariest words in the English language? 

I just can&#39;t put together a model for the type of American that defines the Overton window. How on earth did the people of the most prosperous, most capitalist country change their minds?

My current working theory is that the Purutanisn that runs through the very core of the USA was suppressed for a generation or two (60s-10s or so) and is now reasserting itself. What is happening now is very much in line with Salem. Maybe everyone was just lucky to catch the industrial revolution and then the technological revolution and reap the benefits of the increased productivity to keep themselves occupied with their own prosperity, but now that technological progress has stalled (in the sense that there is nothing new being made, just incremental improvements) everything is back to how it was - segregation (look at all the skin color-specific affinity groups, both at work and at school), policing male/female interactions, etc.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/im497t8/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>