<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ilforte - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-11T00:16:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ilforte" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnth1f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What happens to thinking people who are clearly wrong but [whose heads haven&#39;t e</title><updated>2022-07-11T00:16:45Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What happens to thinking people who are clearly wrong but [whose heads haven&#39;t exploded](https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_dennett_the_illusion_of_consciousness?language=en)? 

The (imo) stupid adage that science advances one funeral at a time is so old that I think it has finally [overstayed its welcome](https://rootsofprogress.org/how-curing-aging-could-help-progress) and, with any luck, we&#39;ll bid it final goodbyes soon enough. 

Yes sometimes, often even, it is right on the money. There are walking scholarly zombies all around: people who&#39;ve bet it all on a hypothesis, have been publicly and convincingly proven wrong (or had the ground move under them to the point their entire map became obsolete) and have not recanted. Indeed, some double down or just begin to ignore all criticism. 

What do we know about such cases and such people? Are they just cognitively rigid and emotionally invested? Bound like slaves to a cottage factory that has been built around their assumptions, perhaps? Does the stress of debunking alter their reasoning somehow, degrade it maybe? How does it feel from the inside? I&#39;ve seen some curious patterns, but don&#39;t want to bias you. 

The easy recent example: Hofstadter and GPT-3, see [Scott&#39;s 53rd point](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/links-for-june-1e7) and [my comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vp23id/quality_contributions_report_for_june_2022/iej8xel/).  

What are your examples? And if you know any more systematic sources: I&#39;d be much obliged. Sounds like something Lesswrong ought to have done a lot of work on.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vvl5yv/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_10_2022/ifnth1f/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>