<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ilforte - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-24T19:30:22Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ilforte" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihhgrry/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In the waning hours of this thread, I feel like remarking on what makes The Mott</title><updated>2022-07-24T19:30:22Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In the waning hours of this thread, I feel like remarking on what makes The Motte special and keeps me here, in part by being so alien to my natural inclinations.  
It’s the enforced culture of speaking plainly.

A friend has asked me today: what&#39;s the deal with Dugin’s Noomahia? Isn&#39;t it just a bunch of evocative chapter titles pointing at literal emptiness hidden under the shallow plaiting of made-up words?  

It&#39;s probably not. Unwieldy and meandering though it is, it remains clearly more interpretable to me than the sort of pseudo-profound Lakanian bullshit Alan Sokal has revealed in his book; and it&#39;s interpretable in the specific way intended by the author. But I can see how it can be hard to parse. The same is true for much of the stuff I&#39;m translating, and triply true for stuff that gets left out.  

It seems to be more prevalent in the modern Russian right-wing culture (where Galkovsky has had the effect akin to Yarvin&#39;s in the Anglosphere), but is a natural feature of certain domains. People speaking *like this* can be sarcastic, or sincerely conveying their thoughts, or speaking for the other side charitably *or* uncharitably, – and it&#39;s all delivered in the same deadpan or unnaturally jovial manner. Mockery, hostile misrepresentation, speculation, steelmanning, actual knowledge are shared in a single stream, and you need a key to decompose it, else you risk seeing mad gibberish. 

It is annoyingly adaptive. Communication aside, speech is a medium for status competition, and one way to increase your status is to trip your opponent up, to trigger Poe&#39;s law with every second turn of phrase, even bait with passable strawmen of your own side and «prove» that the enemy is beneath you because you can anticipate their models and invectives (but how does it prove anything?)  
And so on. The impenetrability of the end product is a feature, not a bug, and says little about the quality or content of understanding underneath.  
This also grants undue opportunities to grifters and frauds trying to look smart and novel, to people who avoid committing to a position, and to witches seeking plausible deniability. 

In the past, plausible arguments have been made to the effect that every advantage of this community is a consequence of seed population, and /u/ZorbaTHut is deluding himself about the value of ruleset. That the same pool of smart or at least loquacious, predominantly anti-woke people would have resulted in mostly the same outcome, rules be damned. Finally, that these rules are instead stifling us, removing some opportunity for creative play and evolution. (On this note, why have we shut down /u/Kind-Trust-780&#39;s amazing test instead of making it, say, into a topic for discussion about the level of numeracy and general knowledge needed to opine on toxic stuff? Just because he wasn&#39;t «speaking in good faith»?)

But one can also see where unrestricted loquacity leads. The state of neoreactionaries and «dark enlighteners», the absolute state of sneerers who, despite occasionally being very smart, cannot figure their way out of their own snark. 

No smart-ass punchline.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ihhgrry/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>