<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ilforte - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T02:17:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ilforte" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgubw7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How do you think the industry, culture of art and art itself will change in the </title><updated>2022-08-16T02:17:04Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How do you think the industry, culture of art and art itself will change in the era of easily achievable post-scarcity for custom content?

*A few jumbled thoughts, rearranged into Linear Ilfortese B on the advice of /u/f3zinker.*  

With the beta rollout of Stable Diffusion (previously [shilled here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij9ge8b/)), digital artists [have finally taken notice](https://mobile.twitter.com/arvalis/status/1558623545374023680) of text-to-image models, and particularly their ability to imitate individual, modern stylesˆ1 . It seems artists have abruptly phase-transitioned en masse from naysaying to fear and rage, and have promptly shut down @StableDiffusion acc with malicious reporting, in what may eventually be recorded in history books as one of the opening shots in the inevitable Neo-Luddite backlash transcending industries and political tribes. (Additionally: fresh HN discussion of [copyright infringement in AI art](https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32436203), of [Stable Diffusion](https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32471199).) 

The gnashing of teeth, gloating, motivated reasoning, [politruk-level understanding of art itself](https://mobile.twitter.com/senfflasche/status/1559311057310580736), [political allies](https://twitter.com/AmandaTNStevens/status/1557766146920783873/retweets/with_comments) and amusing narcissism ([«The tiniest cock I draw has more soul than what an AI could spit out»](https://twitter.com/Rattfood/status/1559007094598246402)) are all exactly what I&#39;ve had in mind when saying that I don&#39;t like artists as a class of people and welcome their impending professional decimation by AI (a take [which invited some opposition](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijoupt6/)). Of course they&#39;ll fight back. Going beyond Twitter antics, they voice a somewhat reasonable hope for class action lawsuits and encouragement of broader regulation. Artists naturally can have power in excess of their SES, and they love to flex it. Probably it can work, if the powers that be see utility to facilitating their crusade. And maybe (returning to my constant concerns) we&#39;ll see this used as a *casus belli* for a huge push for prohibition of general-purpose compute in private hands (embraced by Lesswrongian AI alarmists and EAs, and Bostrom-WEF technocratic goons). And AI art will be reduced to some gimped alternatives like cloud-only Adobe Photoshop with $5.99 monthly fee for «in the style of James Gurney» meta-brush, with royalties to James or his publisher or estate.ˆ2   

Then again, maybe it&#39;ll fall through. Torrents are still here. And good luck regulating away secure comms like Matrix or Briar or, hell, PGP emails. And Stable Diffusion checkpoints are already being spread around, and a rig with four second-hand 3090s from bankrupt Ethereum miners will be enough for *a great deal* of inference. Most importantly, there&#39;s enough interestˆ3 . Like [Emad says](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YQ2QtKcK2dA) in the recent excellent interviewˆ4, billions of people are *creatively constipated* and they want to let it all out. This may not be singularity yet, but it&#39;s a classical [revolutionary situation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolutionary_situation). To wit, the case where preservation of status quo would require drastic changes tearing away at its other aspects, introducing unsustainable runaway processes.ˆ5  

The question is, *how* does this continue? Images are of course the least of our problems. Emad can&#39;t wait to automate all forms of media production, and the market will do the rest for «normal» jobs. Savvier artists are, predictably given their socialist leanings but IMO very rationally, advocating [for basic income](https://twitter.com/basicincomecdn/status/1557374154478964737). Alas, it&#39;s not that good, and it may not be the lowest-effort adaptation of our society as it grapples with runaway optimization processes.ˆ6 And beyond that, there are direct AI risks, both existential due to alignment failure (which I&#39;m skeptical about) and ones obvious from human history. But even for art alone, consider these asinine outcomes: 

- Neuralink-powered DRM: content-as-a-service streamed directly into the brain, with per-qualia billing, data interpretable only on this individual human connectome (connectome «keys» owned by Neuralink Corporation, accessed by streaming services through an API), with extreme financial and medical ramifications of tinkering. Episodic memory wiping for extra [dystopian flavor](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IFe9wiDfb0E) (but you keep your ratings, reviews and habits!). For extra [Cheems mindset](https://normielisation.substack.com/p/cheems-mindset): ID-locked screens/output devices with always-online perceptive hash tracking of all consoomable content.  
- Actual anarchy wiping out incentives for professional artistic work. The culture up to 2022 compressed into language to summon combinations, endless Age of the Feuilleton that Hesse adumbrated in his *The Glass Bead Game*. No more innovative one-upmanship of starving artists who sink decades into grokking the craft and exploring its rabbit holes, just «X trending on artstation 8K» forever.

It&#39;s a failure of imagination to go for those. But the status quo can&#39;t continue. [The defaults don&#39;t work.](https://moultano.wordpress.com/2020/06/21/the-defaults-dont-work/) We need to up the learning rate to guess at the future. 

Importantly, what will happen with ideology inherent in contemporary art? Emad promises to train custom models for companies like Sony and Nintendo, and I suppose those will be very good (and if Stability.ai fails, eventually Sony will do it on their own or buy something from a startup or FAANG). But there probably are diminishing returns to the effect of raw quality and quantity on how compelling art feels.  
If you can crank out CalArts style cartoons (assuming people like that style *per se*) with right-wing talking points, and Disney or Netflix animators will do the same but 3x better with their stale propaganda of [embracing monsters](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Sea_Beast_(2022_film)), will it matter a lot? Memes with crudely drawn pepes and chads are viral enough; indie games and Minecraft are insanely successful. The Last Of Us II was, I think, [a vessel for Druckmann&#39;s politics](https://collider.com/last-of-us-2-joel-death-neil-druckmann/), and it didn&#39;t persuade people a great deal (on the other hand, people still cite the sophomoric critique of libertarianism in Bioshock, brought to you by Ken Levine, so that depends on specifics). if Druckmann and Levine have the equivalent of Unreal Engine 6 with [automatic generation of arbitrary assets and most code](https://www.theverge.com/2022/8/2/23287173/ai-image-generation-art-midjourney-multiverse-interview-david-holz), and Zorba and his friend have the equivalent of mere UE 4 with the same properties, downgraded – will it matter that the former duo has access to AAA tier promotion and the latter just go on Steam and get word-of-mouth fame? 

Finally, will artistry, «style», *stylization* itself survive when it&#39;s not scarce? Will it advance to its llimits?ˆ7 Or will the people, surfeited with it, cast away gimmicks and choose simple, beautiful, ecologically valid naturalism with well-told archetypal stories? Or on the contrary, decide that Apple was right and legible schematics that are easy on the mind are the best – art fading away much like the adolescent Android modding and ricing of desktops?  Will it shard into tiny niche superstimuli, or will generic ones be quickly discovered? How will this play together with VR, Metaverse and its private equivalents, and generational churn? 

I honestly have no idea. 

Footnotes in two posts below are not 100% pertinent to the topic and can be ignored.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikgubw7/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>