<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ilforte - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-17T02:30:25Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ilforte" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/iggzthc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] ## Two theories of extremism

A belated meditation on Slatestarcodex CW gems (Mo</title><updated>2022-07-17T02:30:25Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">## Two theories of extremism

A belated meditation on Slatestarcodex CW gems (Moloch, Toxoplasma, Outgroup...) and some topics I&#39;m thinking of lately: pet causes, post-rats, reputation, and steelmanning «deradicalization». Well-trodden and [even mathematically modeled](https://ncase.me/crowds/). Anyway, let&#39;s think of it as an [artists practice](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwvr5c/grayed_out_options/).

How many extremists are consciously exaggerating their case to move the needle of public opinion?  
How many could be persuaded to stop if they were exposed to the actual distribution of opinions?

Instead of a definition, here are diverse cases of «extremism»:  

1. Eliezer Yudkowsky [says that](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/uMQ3cqWDPHhjtiesc/agi-ruin-a-list-of-lethalities) we&#39;re getting wiped out by an evil AGI with probability **«roughly 1»** and nobody sans him and his frens worries enough about preventing it.  
2. Scott Aaronson used to insist on [Donald Trump&#39;s delicate skin](https://scottaaronson.blog/?p=2777) posing lethal threat to his family, eclipsing even the threat of feminist trolls and sneerclub. As for the AGI: he thinks we&#39;ve got it (probably).  
3. Richard Hanania [explains](https://richardhanania.substack.com/p/why-do-i-hate-pronouns-more-than) that he doesn&#39;t *really* find pronouns to be worse than genocide, nor does he think wokism is a larger threat than, like, an unaligned AGI, but he&#39;s way more driven to tilt at pronouns and hey, someone&#39;s gotta do it.  
4. Dynomight [suggests](https://dynomight.net/plans/) climate activists believe that geoengineering is a viable solution, but scorn it to keep everyone focused on cutting down CO2.  
5. Paul Erlich is [still not admitting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Ehrlich) that he was wrong about the population bomb.  
6. A sagely intellectual who&#39;s devoted his life to checking the influence of the American Empire carries water [for every anti-Western faction](https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/09/11/book-review-manufacturing-consent/) from Palestinians and Hamas to Putin to Pol Pot.  
7. Some people are very concerned about the Russian grip on the GOP. Others [are imploring of them](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Israel_Lobby_and_U.S._Foreign_Policy) to pay more attention to the Israel lobby instead.  
8. There&#39;s a guy who&#39;s dunking on *everything* I say and calls me an illiterate schizophrenic douchebag nazi or permutations thereof. He digs deep enough into references I provide in random chats to find an unsourced number in a book-length supplement; he&#39;s my personal stalker cum fact checker active 24/7/365 (it&#39;s flattering). He never breaks kayfabe with me around, but has confessed elsewhere that my ideology (the way he understands it) justifies libel.  
9. [My friend](https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/16464119/ernest-khalimov-chad-meme/) rates every anime he watches with 1 of 2 numbers, giving either 1 if it&#39;s overrated and 10 if it&#39;s not.  
10. Survey designers recommend leaving out or discouraging the use of midpoints on rating scales when you need to decrease [satisficing behavior](https://www.surveymonkey.com/curiosity/satisficing-learn-to-defeat-the-subtle-menace-in-your-survey-data/). 

See? 

This can be shoehorned into Motte and Bailey, but I think here lies an important special case. 
Many advocate for the Bailey and insist it&#39;s a certainty; the former is in good faith, the latter is not. When pressed to quantify or bet, they don&#39;t retreat to some Motte but admit the Bailey is only *possibly true* – but the thing is, their estimation of the probability is higher than (what they take to be) the public average. In effect, they are **feigning** extremist beliefs to bring the median public signal about the issue closer to truth. «M&amp;amp;B» is when a boy cries wolf after noticing a fox in the grass; «Moderating Extremism» (suggest a better name?) is when a boy thinks not enough boys are on wolf patrol, because he has once heard a noise that *maaybe* was a howl.

Taken as such, this is strictly incompatible with the core premise of the «Bayesian» rationalist mindset, with its ethos of Tetlockian supeforecasting, calibrating, betting and taxing bullshit and becoming... well, less wrong. Not quite so if you put it in the social context: people who act like this are not intellectual objects, passively updating on evidence, but active subjects of the quasi-Bayesian conversation forming the consensus reality; symmetry breakers, hair-trigger neurons with an agenda in the indecisive collective brain.  

I am not saying that orthodox Bayesians are socially inactive: but they are prosecuting a different strategy of influence, tailored to another way of life. A boy who cried wolf lived in a small tight-knit village, and after two false positives everyone has learned to discard him; the moral of the story is he should have been humbly building credibility with verified truths and admissions of uncertainty, like [Toby Ord](https://slatestarcodex.com/2020/04/01/book-review-the-precipice/) does. These people try to live in the world like that village – one of high-agency individuals, high trust and high value of reputation, where sources can be (and are!) discretely tracked and evaluated over their lifetimes. It can be said that in their information ecosystem, they encourage K-selection and slow life strategy on all levels: for memes, for expert voices, for attitudes.  
Whereas Moderating Extremists are creatures or the big city, the bazaar, the newspaper, the advocacy group, the social media feed, the parasocial relationship. They are willing to burn their credibility a la PETA because they see little use to it. A cautious, credible voice is not updating the consensus, it being a muddy stream where chief differentiators are salience and raw volume. More than that, moderation doesn&#39;t contribute to building a platform on fame. Some would uncharitably say they&#39;re chasing attention for profit, and their organizations may do so; but I think they&#39;re somewhat selflessly propagating a meaningful signal in the only way they know.

M-Extremists can baffle Bayesian Villagers simply by living day-to-day peacefully – or indeed, doing credible science and rising up that hierarchy too! – while insisting that the sky&#39;s about to fall. But, in village-speak, they&#39;re just saying you should look up. 

---

There also exist true believers. 

The  problem began when everyone moved into Mcluhan&#39;s Global Village, which is neither a village nor a city. I believe there&#39;s a failure mode revealed by social networks. It&#39;s more nuanced than the basic groupthink, and probably warrants an evo psych story.  
**Here&#39;s the simplest hypothesis in three parts:**   
1. People like hanging together with those who think the same on various issues.  
2. Our confidence about a given issue decays a little on meeting disagreement, but *gets reinforced more* on finding *a close match*. 2.1: This *applies to meta-beliefs* as well.   
3. There are metaparameters, constants governing this dynamic, and I suspect they&#39;re not a good fit for a big networked world.

A single cowardly boy who thinks there *might be* a wolf and insists on there being one will bounce around the village, get laughed at by everyone he bumps into, and chill. In the meantime he&#39;s spreading public knowledge that there&#39;s a Wolf Hypothesis. If someone else reports hearing a (probabilistic) wolf – then its plausibility skyrockets; and crucially, now they both feel that those not yet enlightened ought to be brought up to speed. It&#39;s almost as if they&#39;ve associated by [Hebbian learning](https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aao4159). Should they find a third one...  
This is trivial to stabilize in a small well-connected network: the wilder the claim, the harder to find corroboration, the greater the decay. But in a planetary web that&#39;s a *small-world network*, and with search to boot, you need almost-constant effort to discover not only multiple reports about wolves but [a deluge of murderous cardiologists](https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/09/16/cardiologists-and-chinese-robbers/). And in Web 2.0, *the very same* exploration process leads you to people who are similar mentally, validate you and who confirm that forests must be teeming with ravenous howling wolves. And, topping it all, you can share stories about your local «villages» where everyone is blind and deaf to the horror and [must be beaten over the head with Truth](https://youtu.be/_n7iIYhjiSQ?t=1574). Soon that&#39;s your company: spiritual brethren, and ghosts of the ignorant.

In the limit, this causes gnosticism, the sense of chosenness and radical decisions. In the «normal» case, this stays limited to extremist advocacy in the vein of provided examples. 

Now I don&#39;t really want to demonize social networks – God knows this is popular enough. Not only do they connect people, but help some get their heads out of their own asses, and reveal naked kings. Consider that 11 years ago [this dumb, artless banality](https://www.wired.co.uk/article/human-plus-science-gallery) could be called «exploring the future of the human species», received funds and accolades. I feel like there used to be more of this pre-Twitter, and creepy, out-of-touch «high art» has been decimated when social networks flattened the social landscape and allowed sharp-witted plebs to laugh in the faces of wannabe sophisticates. Consider that 15 years ago some [«Yale Professor»](https://twitter.com/jasonintrator/status/1547513558782681090) or [«Public Intellectual»](https://twitter.com/nntaleb) (has blocked you) could ride much further on the accumulated glory of his class or glowing reviews in press before his follies turned memes.

I also don&#39;t want to equivocate between all causes of concern. After all, I also am such an extremist on a few topics, and I think I **am** right (if not 100%). 

Still, this model may be worth keeping in mind when you tell someone afraid of wolves to go touch grass.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/iggzthc/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>