<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Ilforte - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-30T02:47:08Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Ilforte" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii7nojw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Have you stocked up on microchips yet? 

Many believe now that the war over Taiw</title><updated>2022-07-30T02:47:08Z</updated><author><name>Ilforte</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Have you stocked up on microchips yet? 

Many believe now that the war over Taiwan will start in 2022 and the casus belli will be Nancy Pelosi.  

- “Chinese state media just suggested the PLA should shoot down Pelosi’s plane if she travels to Taiwan. This would be a direct act of war. The U.S. does not take foreign policy demands from Communist China or any other belligerent bully”,  says [U.S. Senator Marsha Blackburn](https://twitter.com/MarshaBlackburn/status/1553077081633873920).   

- A post appeared on Jul 29 on the official account of China&#39;s 80th group of People&#39;s Liberation Army, saying [«Get ready for war!»](https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202207/1271742.shtml). 

- During Nancy Pelosi&#39;s supposed visit to Taiwan, a U.S. Navy strike group led by the aircraft carrier Ronald Reagan [will move into the South China Sea](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-07-28/us-aircraft-carrier-enters-south-china-sea-amid-taiwan-tensions).

- The Chinese army, on the other hand, is actively [relocating armored vehicles to Fujian](https://twitter.com/gusten777/status/1553107420054016003), the nearest province to Taiwan from mainland China. Unscheduled exercises will start tomorrow.

- [Another word to the staff of Global Times](https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202207/1271745.shtml): 

&amp;gt; &#34;Don&#39;t say we didn&#39;t warn you!&#34; - a phrase that was used by the People&#39;s Daily in 1962 before China was forced to fight the border war with India and ahead of the 1979 China-Vietnam War, was frequently mentioned during a forum held Friday by a high-level Chinese think tank, as analysts warned that open military options and comprehensive countermeasures ranging from the economy to diplomacy from China await if US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi gambles with a visit to the Taiwan island during her Asia tour.
&amp;gt; Sending fighter jets to intercept Pelosi&#39;s plane, declaring air and maritime zones around the island of Taiwan as restriction zones for military exercises … China&#39;s responses will be systematical and not limited to small scale given the severity of Pelosi&#39;s move and the damage to the political trust of China-US relations, Yang Mingjie, head of the Institute of Taiwan Studies in Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, told the Global Times.  
&amp;gt; [...]  
&amp;gt; The 80th Group Army posted a comment saying, &#34;we must bear in mind the fundamental responsibility of preparing for war and charge on the journey of a strong army.&#34; The comment has received 8,000 thumbs-up.

Well if Marsha Blackburn on Twitter and 300000 Chinese people on Sina Weibo agree, I guess this is it. Should I buy USD, gold, Bitcoin, RTX 3090, or buckwheat? This is the question...

----

It&#39;s possible to frame this in a number of ways. Old clueless women and frenzied nationalists stumbling into abyss, pulling their country along; something something our rights, freedom, liberty, Communism vs. Capitalism, Tyranny vs. Democracy; Thucydides Trap... You all follow big brain bloggers who can pontificate on that (or *are* such bloggers) and I don&#39;t have the energy to go though it all. (Frankly I&#39;m sick and someone else should write a proper post). 

My hypothesis, of course, is that the US is actually ran by hypercompetent people, and they will crush China without breaking a sweat – or, more likely, force it to back down in humiliation, although they would accept sacrificing not just Pelosi but the majority of the world&#39;s population including most Americans to achieve their goal of total hegemony if that were the cost. How those competent people have paved the road to the provocation with Pelosi is the content of a bona fide **conspiracy**, and we&#39;ll never learn of it. 

The war was generally pegged to happen in 2025-2026 or later, as implied by Chinese-American power differential and rates of military buildup – at the schedule most convenient to PLA. (Alternatively, the «declining power» model [is purported to yield much the same result](https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/09/24/china-great-power-united-states/)). Just like with AI forecasts, it was naive and didn&#39;t account for the trivial notion that interested parties are aware of this basic scenario and thus anticipate its turns. Google *can* in fact keep scaling transformers; USA can in fact accelerate the schedule of the conflict to settle it on preferred terms. 

And right now the terms are excellent. 

Taiwan is very defensible. According to (picked at random) the *Naval War College Review* issue from 2001, titled [«How China Might Invade Taiwan»](https://digital-commons.usnwc.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2535&amp;amp;context=nwc-review), “Just to get ashore, the landing force commanders would have to improvise extensively to deal with the inhospitable Taiwanese west coast, which is mostly mud flats, with significant tidal ranges. **The Chinese would also have to contend with two monsoon seasons, from August to September and from November to April**; it would be restricted to two “windows” of attack, from May to July and the month of October.” 

Moreover, they&#39;re just strait up not ready. For example, according to the *Southern China Morning Post*, [China’s Fujian aircraft carrier doesn’t have radar and weapon systems yet, photos show](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3185845/chinas-fujian-aircraft-carrier-doesnt-have-radar-and-weapon). «The Fujian was [launched a month ago](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3182032/china-launches-fujian-pla-navys-3rd-aircraft-carrier?module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=article), and military analysts say the process to get the warship ready for active service could take several years – from the fit-out to testing and sea trials». They didn&#39;t rush it enough. What does this say for their chances to attain air superiority?

Can they fight the US in their present state? Their main ally is in no shape to help or even lend them arms, battered and discredited in Ukraine. Their economy is buckling under the strain of Zero-Covidiocy and bursting housing bubble. Their military still is half-baked, their industrial capacity – wasted on high-speed rail, other infrastructural grift and gimmicks for Westerners instead of leapfrogging the US by mass-producing autonomous weapons which are [only now reaching proof-of-concept stage](https://interestingengineering.com/china-drone-swarm-forest). It doesn&#39;t look good.  

On this note, back in the December of 2021 Telegram military analyst Atomic Cherry (known here through his coverage of Ukrainian conflict) has said: 

&amp;gt; In 2018, China was not just deprived of access to advanced chip production technology - Beijing was literally kicked to the curb on the eve of a new round of microelectronic evolution. The mainstay of this trend in recent years has been the 7nm chip process (China still has not received the technology to manufacture such chips). A few days ago, however, TSMC began test production of 3nm chips. IBM unveiled a prototype 2nm chip back in May, and is now working with Samsung on a unique VTFET (vertical transistor arrangement) technology which will eventually break the 1nm (!) barrier.   
A special zest to the appearance of these technologies is that they will be launched into mass production at about the same time as the U.S. will finish and start up new plants in the microelectronics industry - that is roughly 2024-2025.  
Probably not all readers understand what the evolution of chips is all about. So as not to bore you with nerdy theory, I will explain the difference in simple and understandable categories.   
▪️ 100-nm technology makes it possible to produce, for example, cruise missiles similar to the American Tomahawk of old modifications;   
▪️ 40-nm technology makes it possible to make missile launchers similar to the older versions of the Javelin or, for example, the Predator UAV;  
▪️ 7-nm technology is your ticket into the world of multi-platform kamikaze drones and compact reconnaissance drones.   
Not to say that the PRC had any chance at all of changing the current strategic environment - but now there is none at all. 

And a few days ago we&#39;ve learned that they are in fact producing 7nm class chips... for Bitcoin mining ASICs. In a year or two, perhaps...

It&#39;s like watching [AlphaZero clobber Stockfish](https://youtu.be/lFXJWPhDsSY). 

I am not sure how it&#39;ll go, but I think they&#39;ll blink, like they always do when this issue is raised and the US clears its metaphorical throat. If they don&#39;t... it&#39;ll be even worse for them.

Xi is – or [was](https://www.cnbc.com/2022/07/29/chinas-xi-faces-major-economic-challenges-says-investor-david-roche.html) – expected to secure his third term [this November](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/20th_National_Congress_of_the_Chinese_Communist_Party) on the 20th National Congress of the CCP. His entire schtick by this points amounts to pandering to nationalists, «little pinks». Can he survive disappointing them – by giving Taiwan up symbolically or losing it in an open conflict? *Probably.* If his grasp on power is comparable to Putin&#39;s, he can. It will necessitate turning the country into a comparable one-man show, with crippling brain drain from leading corporations  (sanctions will follow, of course), economic collapse and irrelevance.  
It won&#39;t be *that* bad. USA-developed AGI will take care of manufacturing – the fraction we&#39;ll still need after degrowth explained away by Putin&#39;s aggression and COVID-caused (actually it was lockdowns) recession. 

Meanwhile, if he can&#39;t stat on top, his faction gets replaced by a more pro-Western one, and the next GenSec is probably [someone like this guy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wang_Yang_(politician)#Political_positions_and_public_image). 

I&#39;m not AlphaZero of politics nor Von Neumann of Machiavellism and I can&#39;t tell how it&#39;ll play out. But they, too, have deal with uncertainty. What matters is that I don&#39;t see any winning moves for China. 

Do you?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii7nojw/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>