<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/it_is_so_weird_to_be - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-10T06:05:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/it_is_so_weird_to_be" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkeby3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] My parent is dying and in one of the moments we have had, my parent shared that </title><updated>2022-07-10T06:05:27Z</updated><author><name>it_is_so_weird_to_be</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">My parent is dying and in one of the moments we have had, my parent shared that my estrangement from my sibling “is killing” them. 

They’ve always hated that I cut the sibling off and have continually pressured me to reconnect for years. The estrangement has gone on since 2010.

The sibling was physically abusive toward me, as well as very emotionally abusive. I have other siblings and they maintain a relationship with this one. When the estranged sibling comes up in conversation with the other siblings, it is almost always complaints about their abusive behavior. Which leads me to believe I made the right decision for my own sanity, and that the behavior that precipitated the estrangement is ongoing. 

This situation with our parent has led the abusive sibling to reach out to me, but the thought of talking to them or even being in the same room as them gives me a great deal of anxiety. I did not respond. 

But I’m getting even more pressure than usual - parent is dying. My estrangement of the sibling is “killing” them. Why can’t I just let bygones be bygones. 

They won’t listen to me when I describe being abused by this sibling, or when I point out the hypocrisy that the dying parent didn’t talk to their siblings for decades because of shitty behavior. They have a history of ignoring abuse, like with another family member who is an accused child molester (I have personal experience that this accusation is 100% true) and is still invited to gatherings. 

I guess I just don’t know how to navigate this. I live in a different state, visiting theirs, and I am trying to spend time with my dying parent but every time we talk, it’s brought up how I need to put aside my differences with the sibling and make amends. 

It makes me doubt my own experiences and makes me feel intense guilt. Part of me wants to placate them. Part of me wants to go home and never contact my parents again. How would you deal with this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifkeby3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>