<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/JarJarJedi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-30T04:48:55Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/JarJarJedi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ii80sem/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;ve read many times the advice that if you are in some (especially non-friendly</title><updated>2022-07-30T04:48:55Z</updated><author><name>JarJarJedi</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;ve read many times the advice that if you are in some (especially non-friendly, e.g. being arrested) encounter with the police, you should not talk to them beyond the required minimum and contact your lawyer. The thing is, I don&#39;t have &#34;my lawyer&#34;. I have no idea how to contact one. I never needed one. I could probably make a web search and find one if I needed one, but I doubt the police would let me if it comes to that. Also, what if that random person I found on the net tell me they don&#39;t want to go just now and sit with me for police interview (which they would probably do)? How many attempts would the police allow me? 

So, what is it that people *actually* do in such situations? I know there&#39;s an institute of public defenders, but I&#39;m probably not poor enough to be awarded a lawyer for free. OTOH, I am not rich enough to regularly need services of an attorney (or be able to afford them if I can help it). Do other people actually somehow find a lawyer for that scenario in advance and keep their phone number somewhere accessible at all times? Or memorize it? Does the police has some lawyers on call for smartasses that refuse to talk without one? Am I missing some vital part of adult experience here and should have had &#34;my lawyer&#34; years ago as all the normal people do? 

NB: Just to be clear, I am not asking for legal advice or anything, I don&#39;t need a lawyer right now, and the police so far has zero interest in me. I am just curious - when reading this advice for the 1000th time I suddenly realized I have no idea what that actually *means* if I ever needed to follow this advice. 
Also, all this is in the US-based context, if it wasn&#39;t clear.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ii80sem/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>