<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/JosephinesOtherMan - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T11:52:31Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/JosephinesOtherMan" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a b</title><updated>2022-07-13T11:52:31Z</updated><author><name>JosephinesOtherMan</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Does anyone have any advice on making new and close friends as an adult with a baby?  Almost all of our friends moved away from our city during or after COVID.  

My wife and I traveled for a friend&#39;s engagement party (one of those friends who moved away)--it was fine.  The day after, we met up with an old friend of mine and an old college friend of hers who live there, and we had a much better time with them than we&#39;ve had with any of our friends at home in a really long time.  

... I&#39;m finding myself feeling a little sad after that for two reasons:

1. Most of our friends at home have moved away, and while it&#39;s not too hard to make little acquaintances or Jane Jacobs-esq &#34;public friendships&#34; around (especially with a baby), it seems very hard to find or develop close friendships at this point in our lives.
2. Meeting up with those old friends made me realize how distanced a lot of my friendships at home were--we were a large crew of folks who met up to have fun together, but ultimately we weren&#39;t very close (the contrast between the friends at the engagement party and the old friends the day after felt fairly extreme)

I have a handful of close friends who mean a lot to me, but almost all of them are distributed around, and we keep in touch when we can, though a lot of formerly close friendships have gotten a little less close over COVID for whatever reason too.  I vaguely worry that the only person who I can rely on is my wife (my family isn&#39;t reliable), and it scares me a little.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzau68/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>