<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/jspsfx - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T13:57:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/jspsfx" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums </title><updated>2022-08-22T13:57:32Z</updated><author><name>jspsfx</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Anyone else here trawl through chaotic, conspiracy/politically incorrect forums looking for interesting nuggets of information? It’s rather like panning for gold. There’s a steady stream of dirt but almost on a daily basis you will find the seed of a worthwhile idea or some information that’s being suppressed/ignored in mainstream circles.
     
I suspect this is something most curious people do, even “intelligent presenting” people who keep their rhetoric straight and opinions inoffensive. I wonder if it’s an unspoken secret, some habit we engage with after dark.
    
During covid this became a daily activity for me. I hated it though. I hated that information and idea exchange were as locked down as we were physically. I knew any given /r/lockdownskepticism post or idea could be just as valuable as a post made in any mainstream subreddit - I could sort through the bullshit. But I also knew any information outside the establishment view was going to be tainted and treated as false purely by association being stuck in the conspiracy bin.
   
Many dissenting views and/or information which contradicted the dogma of the day regarding covid were relegated to the corners of the internet which the establishment media and institutions label as crazy and dangerous.
  
Essentially, in tandem with the government, social media companies helped create a rhetorical landscape where the only information the public would consume and digest through free discourse was information they deemed acceptable.
  
You could talk about lab leak theory but it would have to be next to the tweaker claiming *they* are transmitting covid via 5G Wi-Fi signals. You could talk about potential or active side effects of the vaccine but it would have to be lumped in with people claiming everyone who got it would die within a year.
   
This seems like the playbook for how “misinformation” is going to be handled online and it’s rather concerning to me. With that in mind I’m actually drawn to check in on these forums even more. Covid information control made me wonder what else am I going to miss if I just stick to mainstream sources… And where else am I to find this information but the black market of ideas?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilbllbf/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>