<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/JTarrou - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T11:59:00Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/JTarrou" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ill027f/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In the wake of Bruen (henceforth Bruen1), a suit has again been filed (Antonyuk </title><updated>2022-08-24T11:59:00Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In the wake of Bruen (henceforth Bruen1), a suit has again been filed (Antonyuk v. Bruen) to challenge New York&#39;s tweaked concealed carry license regime.

A primer for the case is [here](https://firearmslaw.duke.edu/2022/08/litigation-highlight-antonyuk-v-bruen/).

Plaintiff has moved for a preliminary injunction, and the state&#39;s response is [here](https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nynd.133602/gov.uscourts.nynd.133602.19.0.pdf).

Time will tell how the court case is going, but this is culture war! From the primer:

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;New York’s reliance on Founding-era laws that sought to disarm disfavored groups such as Native Americans and religious minorities is sure to garner attention. But, of course, this isn’t a novel idea.  In a dissent from the Seventh Circuit’s 2019 decision in Kanter v. Barr, then-Judge Amy Coney Barrett posited that the U.S. historical tradition of gun regulation—including laws disarming “\[s\]laves and Native Americans,” although obviously unconstitutional today—supports laws “based on present-day judgments about categories of people whose possession of guns would endanger the public safety” (such as, potentially, those who have posted online about a desire to commit violent acts).

So what is this referring to? In the response, the state leans on this argument:

&amp;gt;2. New York’s Good Moral Character Requirement Is Relevantly Similar To A Long Tradition Of Anglo-American History And Doctrine  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;New York’s good moral character requirement is consistent with the long history in both England and America of disarming those whose *associations, reputation,* or conduct suggested they posed a danger to others or to the public order...

Italics mine

&amp;gt;From the early days of English settlement in America, the colonies sought to prevent Native American tribes from acquiring firearms, passing laws forbidding the sale and trading of arms to Indigenous people....  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;even after the English Bill of Rights established a right of the people to arm themselves, the right was only given to Protestants, based on a continued belief that Catholics were likely to engage in conduct that would harm themselves or others and upset the peace...  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Virginia followed this example, passing an act in 1756 that ordered the disarmament of all Catholics or “reputed Papists” who refused to take an oath of loyalty to the colonial government. An Act for Disarming Papists, and Reputed Papisits \[sic\], Refusing to Take the Oaths to the Government (1756)

While all of this may be good law practice, it&#39;s red meat for the war. The memes practically [wrote themselves](https://i.redd.it/bh55uyi2mbj91.png).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ill027f/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>