<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/JTarrou - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T12:40:52Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/JTarrou" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iirwh5v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In this moment, when I believe we&#39;ve seen peak-Woke, it may be interesting to lo</title><updated>2022-08-03T12:40:52Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In this moment, when I believe we&#39;ve seen peak-Woke, it may be interesting to log some pre-mortems.

In that vein, I ran across an [interesting article](https://mattgoodwin.substack.com/p/the-great-awokening-of-british-media) about the correlation of US and UK journalists in this process.

&amp;gt;it becomes clear that Britain’s media —once known for being much less moralistic and divisive than its American counterpart— is now undergoing the same Great Awokening.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In fact, if we compare America and Britain, as we do below, then we see that despite the two countries having entirely different histories of racism and discrimination, the trends now closely track one another. If anything, remarkably, British media now appears to devote more attention to these issues than their American counterparts.

This provides some support for the concept that the UK is a cultural colony of the US. Cultural hegemony is a hell of a drug.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;As concepts have become much looser, our national debate has become more divisive —ironically just as the country is becoming a much more tolerant, accepting, and welcoming place.

Guided by the beauty of our memetic superweapons....

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;The end result is a media that is simply socially constructing a very warped picture of the country we live in, which is playing an active role in driving the division.

This brings us back to my old hobbyhorse, which is that bigotry is essentially a conspiracy theory about the world that justifies (in the mind of the bigot) their insane hatreds and tactics. The parallels between things like anti-semitism and anti-white-supremacy pretty much write themselves. The construct that the world is rigged against \[decent people\] by the evil racist \[Other\] who is implacably hateful and infinitely destructive, and thus all extremism is \[self-defense\] is as old as group hatreds.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;This has also almost certainly been exacerbated by how media today has also become far more dependent on degree-holding journalists who have usually passed through elite private schools and universities (about 44% of Britain’s columnists went to one of only two universities —I will let you guess which)

This is directly another point of mine, which is that this whole woke thing has been primarily a revolt of the upper-class and the upwardly-mobile against the proles. The word games, the holier-than-thou moralizing, the vicious anger over the most minor of slights. This has been the attempt of the aspiring aristocracy to enact something very close to sumptuary laws. Instead of an appeal to their natural superiority or divine right, these neo-aristocrats claim immunity from criticism and a slate of special privileges based on their supposed disenfranchisement, poverty and victimization. Which is a bit rich coming from graduates of the most rarified schools in the world. Part of the ineradicable conflict of social justice was always that it was a top-down movement of and for the rich, connected and famous. A lot of other people jumped on the bandwagon, and even more just kept their heads down, but this is and has always been a movement driven intellectually by the upper classes.

&amp;gt;our new victimhood culture —which is especially strong in the elite institutions— instead incentivizes people to define themselves first and foremost as members of a victimised group, to derive their sense of social esteem, social status, and recognition from this status, and to punish, aggressively, perceived oppressors.

This is, for instance, why I think the obsession of the left over the last decade has been to ram the concept of &#34;self-identification&#34; through, and shut down any criticism. They need the concept because a pack of mostly-white, mostly-rich, mostly-straight and very well connected posh twats are running their mouths about &#34;social justice&#34;, and their identities don&#39;t give them enough protection in the progressive stack. Self-ID gives them an easy out! Anyone can be &#34;genderqueer&#34; or a &#34;nonpassing trans lesbian&#34;(also known as straight dudes). The profusion of sexual identities feeds a fundamental need for validation in the stack.

The movement was only viable so long as they could keep anyone from pointing out the Emperor&#39;s dick. That fundamental phenomenon may be coming to a close.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iirwh5v/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>