<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/JTarrou - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T12:26:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/JTarrou" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifzejpk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In what could become a regular sort of analysis given the CJ policy trends curre</title><updated>2022-07-13T12:26:50Z</updated><author><name>JTarrou</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In what could become a regular sort of analysis given the CJ policy trends currently, let us turn our attention to the policy shitshow exemplified by [this story](https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2022/jul/8/new-york-bodega-clerk-jose-alba-makes-bail-after-s/). A quick synopsis of the facts as we know them currently (subject to additional information and corrections, of course). 

1: Female subject with small daughter in tow attempts to purchase a number of items at a bodega, but her EBT card is declined. The clerk (M/61)runs the card a couple times, then declines the sale. When he gathers the items, the woman begins shouting that he assaulted her daughter, that he &#34;snatched&#34; a bag of chips from her etc. Unclear from video angle. 

2: Female subject threatens bodega clerk that she will go get her &#34;N\*\*ger&#34; and &#34;fuck you \[him\] up&#34;. 

3: Female subject retrieves her boyfriend, a 35-yo ex con with north of 25 arrests, including multiple arrests for assault and reportedly on parole from an assaulting-a-cop beef.

4: Female and male subjects return to the bodega and initiate first a verbal confrontation, followed by the boyfriend coming behind the counter and assaulting the clerk. The clerk stabs the boyfriend several times, and the girlfriend follows them behind the counter and stabs the clerk three times (exact timeline unclear). Boyfriend dies, clerk&#39;s wounds are superficial. 

5: NY prosecutors charge the clerk with second degree murder, do not charge the woman at all. They ask for $500,000 bond, the judge gives them a quarter mil bond. Later, under public pressure, the bond is reduced to $50k and enough money is raised to get the wounded clerk out of Rikers. 

6: Current status is the clerk has become a local [cause celebre](https://edition.cnn.com/2022/07/11/us/new-york-bodega-stabbing-murder-charges/index.html), but is still facing a second-degree murder rap. The woman who initiated every stage of the conflict and stabbed the clerk remains free of arrest and charges entirely. 

As I&#39;ve said many times before, I&#39;ve lived through this news cycle before. The swing in criminal justice public policy exemplified by BLM and the sort of reforms pushed by the rationalist community (among many others) very quickly started resulting in these sorts of issues. It&#39;s a sort of microcosm of systemic failure of the justice system. It combines outrageous social behavior, aggressive violence, the intentional policy of keeping violent criminals free, and swift punishment for the victims of violent crime who dare to defend themselves. 

This is, in my view, the inevitable result of the reheated 1970&#39;s policies we are currently implementing in many major cities. When criminals are considered the victims, it is citizens who are the &#34;perpetrators&#34;. Basic anarcho-tyranny. This is the criminal justice system currently being adopted, and if allowed to fully mature, we will probably see the same sort of crime wave we did in the &#39;70s and &#39;80s, complete with the economic hollowing-out of major cities, a civilian population that will get scared and start arming itself, and a criminal population that will explode when they fully realize that the only people doing time are the ones resisting them.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifzejpk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>