<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Karibil_Watar - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T20:32:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Karibil_Watar" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror </title><updated>2022-08-26T20:32:28Z</updated><author><name>Karibil_Watar</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I&#39;m making a stupid parody game that I&#39;m planning to have devolve into a horror scenario with humor elements, before circling the entire thing around to be a jab at a certain politician in another country with whom I have no beef. Anyway, via the game [Space Funeral](https://thecatamites.itch.io/space-funeral), which is a free and excellent two to three hour experience that feels like you&#39;re traversing a slightly humorous nightmare, I&#39;ve become more interested in older experimental music as a means of communicating an atmosphere of horror so that I can bundle it up with my already growing pile of copyright infringement. This has led me down the rabbit hole of early synthesizer music, starting with [Delia Derbyshire](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XVsqxNy8kkg) with the BBC Radiophonic Workshop. Most recently, I&#39;ve been delving into Japanese Synthesizer stuff, which is frequently very pretty...

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRZch8wSeII)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lj9CARDiBj8)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIqrqqKt12Q)

And then, there&#39;s 70s-80s French experimental music, which is good at stoking a sense of terror and sometimes downright miserable to listen to (as also is Derbyshire)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQL8GHzkcwM)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHudu1Am6oQ)

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ay2yxt08Ed0)

Not all the music I&#39;ve posted is good. A lot of it is discordant. But Space Funeral is pretty fun and if you know any other cool early synthesizer stuff that&#39;s good at creating an ambience, please shoot it over. Anyways, I am complete newb to this stuff and am not sure of how much interest it would be to anyone else. At very least, it you need to terrorize trick or treaters or your significant other during Halloween, some of these tracks will do a good job.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wy0c32/friday_fun_thread_for_august_26_2022/ilx0jd2/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>