<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/LacklustreFriend - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-02T14:34:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/LacklustreFriend" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinbqkq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A minor (major?) culture war story from here in Australia.

---

Lidia Thorpe, a</title><updated>2022-08-02T14:34:47Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A minor (major?) culture war story from here in Australia.

---

Lidia Thorpe, an Australian Greens (Australia&#39;s progressive party) Senator representing Victoria in Federal Parliament, made [headlines during her swearing in ceremony by describing the Queen as a &#39;colonising Queen&#39; and raising a black power fist](https://www.smh.com.au/politics/federal/thorpe-s-coloniser-queen-oath-out-of-order-as-former-leaders-find-backbench-20220801-p5b6an.html) (apologies for the source, but basically no apolitical coverage exists). Eventually, she was told to retake the oath as written, which she did, but strongly protested. This incident became prominent in not just domestic Australian news, but made it into international news.

Lidia Thorpe is a Indigenous woman and activist, is no stranger to these kinds of controversy has been involved with various culture war issues in the past. She&#39;s a major provocateur, and a model progressive culture warrior.

---

Some debate has emerged over the truthfulness and validity of Thorpe&#39;s statement. Thorpe herself stated: &#34;It&#39;s a fact, it&#39;s truth. It&#39;s not something to get upset about... If people are hurt by truth, then we need to keep talking truth so we can get people on board and educate people.&#34;

On one hand, you can argue that her statement that the Queen is a coloniser isn&#39;t true because the Queen herself has personally done very little to actually colonise anyone. This is seems to be the form most mainstream pushback against Thorpe&#39;s statement is taking.

However, looking at Thorpe&#39;s statement in context of what else she said, she has a point. The Queen is the head of Australia, and Australia *is* a colonial state (or maybe post-colonial state), at least in the sense that Australia as a state is result of British settler colonialism, and it forms the foundational basis of our culture to this day.

I think the real issue is that Thorpe is breaking, probably intentionally, a unspoken agreement in Australian society, and Western liberal post-colonial society more broadly. I think the agreement goes something like this: don&#39;t call any of us individually, specifically colonists, racists, or other bad term, and we&#39;ll agree with you that those things are bad.

What Thorpe is doing is essentially putting her ideological opponents (which include mainstream politicians) in a double bind, and I believe she is very aware of what she is doing. Everyone has agreed that colonialism is a bad thing that we oppose. So when she accuses a prominent, respected and essential figure like the Queen of being a colonist, her opponents can either:

- Just deny any association between the Queen and colonialism. This is weak because it doesn&#39;t actually refute the arguments made by Thorpe and other progressives, which do have some legitimacy to them.

- Admit the Queen is a coloniser or otherwise concede to her point, which is basically agreeing the Queen (and Australia) is bad and illegitimate. Which no non-progressive politician actually wants to do, least of all because it delegitimises the very political system the politicians operate under.

What politicians *can&#39;t* do is say, &#39;yes we admit the Queen is a coloniser and Australia a colonial state, but *that&#39;s a good thing*&#39;. Well, outside of some far-right political pariahs like Pauline Hanson. But the more that Thorpe and other progressives pushes and prods and tries to break the unspoken post-colonial &#39;liberal agreement&#39; on topics like race and colonialism, the more I think people will eventually just say &#39;fuck it, you know what, I like Australia, colonialism is good, actually.&#39;

This story has a strong similarity to the issue of white identity and white racial consciousness in the US and the Western world. The unspoken liberal agreement for the last 50 or so years has been for whites to supress any white consciousness or identity, which has seemed to work reasonably successfully, as white rarely do think about themselves in racial terms compared to other ethnic groups. But this is changing as progressives are deliberately trying break the status quo and stoke white racial consciousness, albeit only in self-flagellating and guilt ridden form. But this runs the risk of white eventually saying &#39;enough, if you want me to be racially conscious, I will do it on my terms, I don&#39;t want feel guilty&#39; and becoming actual racists. I suppose the progressives would still see this as a win.

There was a similar story to this one a couple years ago in Canada where [NDP leader Jagmeet Singh called a Bloc Québécois MP racist in Canadian Parliament](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/ndp-jagmeet-singh-rota-racist-therrien-1.5616661). Singh was also breaking that unspoken agreement, I believe.

--- 

To conclude, one interesting thing I noticed about this news story is that there was no coverage of it by the ABC, our national public news broadcaster. At least, I can&#39;t find any articles about it on their website. The only national Australian public news [coverage I could find of it was from NITV](https://www.sbs.com.au/nitv/article/2022/08/02/senator-lidia-thorpe-makes-international-headlines-after-colonising-queen-oath), a publicly-funded Indigenous news and broadcaster, which was unsurprisingly strongly favourable to Thorpe. If you think the ABC&#39;s lack of coverage might be due them not wanting to report on &#39;culture war&#39; type topics, they were more than happy to [run a story a few days ago when Pauline Hanson, a far-right Federal Senator walked out during the acknowledgement of country](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-07-27/pauline-hanson-walkout-acknowledgement-of-country/101275080) (those statements which acknowledge land is stolen from Indigenous/First Nations/Native peoples).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iinbqkq/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies </title><updated>2022-07-31T13:27:10Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">So I want to ramble out some thoughts about behaviour game theory as it applies to society or morality, or at least that&#39;s the best way I can think to describe it. I realise I&#39;m treading philosophical old ground here but it is something I&#39;ve been thinking about recently.

In the Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma, and the Tragedy of the Commons etc, we have the general case of rational individual actions leading to negative outcomes for everyone.

What this really reminds me of egoist, classical realist, amoral (individualist, even) philosophy, perhaps best exemplified by Machiavelli&#39;s *The Prince*. That is generally a purely self interested individual with no concern for the common good. But there is a glaring issue with Machiavellian philosophy. No one would ever want to work under the Prince, over him or with him, because he would betray you in a heartbeat, and would be constantly looking for opportunities to undermine you for his own benefit. If everyone took Machiavelli&#39;s advice and acted like the perfect Prince, there could be no society. Everyone would just be continuously trying to screw each other over, there can be no true cooperation or common good.

This has kind of given me the idea of a kind of &#39;social parasitism&#39; (yes I am aware of the association of the term with Soviet political prisoners - I using it in an different sense. It&#39;s an apt label here). Machiavelli&#39;s Prince is basically a &#39;social parasite&#39;, in the sense benefiting himself while harming society and others generally. Just like an actual biological parasite, the social parasite needs the host (&#39;society&#39;) to thrive, yet if there are too many social parasite, it will leech too much off the host and kill society and itself (metaphorically), causing society to devolve into chaos and bloody anarchy. The Prince can only exist by exploiting the system he is ultimately undermining by his actions.

If I can think of any benefit that the Prince might provide to society, it might be if there is only one who gains supreme power and thus could theoretically rule competently (after all, this was the original intent for the Prince. But that requires there to only ever be one and only one Prince or would-be Prince. (Maybe you could use this as justification for some kind of elitism)

Sociopaths are essentially naturally this, amoral and a callous disregard for others, only concerned with their own benefit, abusing others trust. But too many sociopaths would cause everyone to become distrustful and thus collapsing the whole system that sociopaths love to exploit.

In some sense, I think this also applies to the constantly debated mistake vs conflict theory around here, with conflict theory obviously representing social parasitism. Conflict theorists can make easy gains by exploiting unassuming mistake theorists, but too much conflict results in dysfunction and collapse of social institutions which the conflict theorists are trying to overtake in the first place. The mistake theorists are the ones actually trying to solve issues, after all. I also wonder if there&#39;s a conflict theorist Schelling point, where the number of conflict theorists reaches critical mass, they create more problems than mistake theorists can solve, so mistake theorists are left with a choice, to either: become a conflict theorists and try to grab whatever resources are around before the collapse, or &#34;die&#34; a mistake theorist. (e.g. a previously principled scientist becoming politicized to secure his job even if it undermines the integrity and value of said job).

This is obviously not a new observation, but then moral systems (historically religions) primarily exist as enforcement mechanism, as a means to dissuade people from becoming social parasites. It&#39;s the Mafia don in the Prison&#39;s Dilemma who threatens the prisoners to keep their mouths shut.

I guess another question is, does social parasitism exist in mostly stable or unstable equilibrium? Does the system tend towards a sustainable number of social parasites, only forced out of balance by extreme external events? Or is there a natural, cyclical boom-bust pattern, where increasing social parasitism will ultimately destroy institutions, and mistake theorists will have to build new institutions from scratch before the cycle repeats.

Maybe I&#39;m looking at it backwards. Maybe the conflict theorists surge *after* the collapse of an institution, rushing to pick at the scraps like a vulture collecting carrion. Attempting to carve out a little niche for themselves, while stunting the ability for mistake theorists to rebuild. Maybe this is what we are seeing with the death of God, decaying social cohesion, and the attempt to establish some new common morality again.

Yeah I don&#39;t really know where I&#39;m going with this. I would like to hear everyone else&#39;s thoughts on this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wchwo3/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_31_2022/iido1sq/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>