<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/LacklustreFriend - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-07T15:40:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/LacklustreFriend" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijblsnk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] To engage in a not-serious thought experiment (please don&#39;t take this too seriou</title><updated>2022-08-07T15:40:36Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">To engage in a not-serious thought experiment (please don&#39;t take this too seriously, it&#39;s only for fun, not an actual proposal):

**What if we just banned advertising?**

With obvious certain exemptions for public service announcements and the like, but no advertising generally for commercial products was allowed. People would be able to seek out information on products and services (via catalogues, websites etc), but this cannot be integrated into media not explicitly meant for that purpose.

The US advertising industry alone is worth almost US$300 billion. That $300 billion has an opportunity cost - that is theoretically $300 billion of labor, resources etc that could be spent something else to benefit society as a whole. While advertising may generate economic value to an individual or a company competing against others, it doesn&#39;t generate *wealth* for the economy as a whole. Advertising isn&#39;t producing a good or service that materially benefits society. It may be the case that the advertising industry is a leech on the economy as a whole, sucking away productivity that could be better spent elsewhere.


Advertising has often been described as a Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma. Companies constantly spend more and more on marketing and advertising to keep ahead of their competition, and there maybe be a tipping point where the money spent on advertising exceeds gains and all parties would have been better off if no one spend money on advertising in the first place. Of course, one of the ways to solve the Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma is to have an external agent force compliance and avoid defection. In this case, the government. 

Of course, there are some counter arguments:

1. While advertising doesn&#39;t generate wealth itself, it can assist in generating wealth by making people want things (consumerism). When people want things, they will engage in economic activity to acquire said things. This extra economic activity is a net good, and (arguably) leads to innovation and invention. There is a quote I can&#39;t quite remember that exactly - &#34;Advertising is the lifeblood of the economy&#34;. The counter-counter argument to this is a consumerist economy is not a good thing in the first place, and people should be driven by their &#39;organic&#39; needs and wants rather than what advertising has told them they should want or need. i.e. standard anti-consumerism argument. Additionally, advertising might cause people to engaging in behavior that causes actual harm, with the most poignant example that pharmaceutical advertising may play significant role in the opioid crisis, overmedication of kids etc. The obesity epidemic being fueled by junk/fast food advertising might be another example.

2. Advertising provides a source of funding for industries and institutions that couldn&#39;t otherwise exist without it. Journalism, entertainment media, some forms of art, sports might be some examples of this, where a significant part of there revenue is generated from advertising that they couldn&#39;t exist without, and we think these things are a net good. The counter-counter argument is that many of those things can exist via alternative (or original!) revenue models (e.g. charging more for a newspaper, ticket sales), and in fact advertising has resulted in perverse incentives that have corrupted those industries and institutions, e.g. advertising in journalism has incentivized clickbait and outrage rather than investigative, &#39;real&#39; journalism, which causes harm to society, which is a net negative.

3. The advertising industry does provide a benefit by providing insights into human psychology and communication that has benefits for society elsewhere (the same way NASA/the space race provided inventions and innovations that could be adapted to benefit the public, but on a psychological level). The counter-counter argument is that this is hard to quantify, doesn&#39;t fully address the issue of opportunity cost, only lessens its impact, and it might actually be a net moral negative as it allows the powers that be to engage in social manipulation and engineering we don&#39;t like.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wi8rc4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_07_2022/ijblsnk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>