<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/LacklustreFriend - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-05T17:49:38Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/LacklustreFriend" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieywk50/</id><title type="text">[CW] ####Illiteracy of Christianity

Apologies for the rambling tone.

I recently sta</title><updated>2022-07-05T17:49:38Z</updated><author><name>LacklustreFriend</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">####Illiteracy of Christianity

Apologies for the rambling tone.

I recently started playing *Wasteland 3* and been having a lot of fun. Early on in the game, there is [a cover](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXeHwhLPKz8) of the Christian hymn [*Are You Washed in the Blood?*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Are_You_Washed_in_the_Blood) that plays as part of a dramatic setpiece battle. I found the cover really quite catchy, and went to listen to it outside the game and find the original hymn (I hadn&#39;t heard it before). Apparently I wasn&#39;t the only one who enjoyed the song and many other Wasteland 3 players did the same. However, I found their comments on the &#39;genuine&#39; renditions by actual Christian artists to be very strange to me. They frequently describing the tone and lyrics (and the Youtube comments of Christians) on the song as &#39;creepy&#39; or &#39;cultish&#39;.

It&#39;s obvious why people find the Wasteland 3 version creepy. It&#39;s a pretty sinister sounding rendition and you hear it when you the player are fighting a post-apocalyptic inbred redneck cult family while destruction and blood surround you. The &#39;genuine&#39; versions are more tricky. Clearly [many Christians listening to the hymn](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJWgpljckbA) don&#39;t feel it&#39;s creepy, but fulfilling and positive.

Maybe the non-Christians finding it creepy have a point. Lyrics like &#34;washed in the Blood of the Lamb&#34; and &#34;are your garments spotless&#34; do sound very strange or creepy devoid of any context. But these lyrics *aren&#39;t* devoid of context, it&#39;s clearly a Christian hymn. Rather, non-Christians (secularized Americans) don&#39;t *understand* the context. They don&#39;t know what the &#39;Blood&#39; or &#39;Lamb&#39; means or represents. They are illiterate of the language of Christianity. As a cultural/lapsed Catholic, I wouldn&#39;t consider myself *fluent* in &#39;Christian&#39;, but I&#39;m certainly literate enough that I don&#39;t find the lyrics of the song creepy and can easily understand their meaning.

It&#39;s like hearing an idiom literally translated from another language. e.g. the Swedish idiom &#39;*to shit in a blue cupboard*&#39;. Removed from its linguistic and cultural home makes it sound like the Swedes are crazy. There was an image that reached the front page of reddit recently of [an ethnic group in Indonesia that exhumes their ancestors&#39; bodies to dress them up and spend time with them](https://old.reddit.com/r/interestingasfuck/comments/vqeptq/the_toraja_people_in_indonesia_periodically_dig/), something that would seem absolutely ghastly and creepy to many Westerners despite being a positive and joyous event for this ethnic group.

This is not really a brand new thought for me, but rather this was just a crystalizing event. I recall a [public lecture from Camile Paglia](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nvmTHQviAHM) where she describes teaching a class 15 years ago on the art of song lyrics where she was playing the hymn &#39;Go Down Moses&#39;. After a lack of engagement from the students, she came to the shocking revelation that virtually none of the students knew who Moses was. Seemingly the only engagement contemporary secular America has with Christian themes is negative, cynical and superficial portrayals in media. Typically some evil redneck evangelical doomsday cult that serves as than antagonist who is more that happy to use Christian symbols in their evil plans. Obviously *Wasteland 3*, but media like *Farcry 5* or the Netflix movie *The Devil All The Time* and many others. Sure, Americans might know some superficial details, like Christmas being the celebration of Jesus&#39; birth, but they have no real understanding of Christianity.

The reason I think this is important for the US (and its cultural sphere) is it renders secular Americans unable to communicate, understand and ultimately find common ground with American Christians, who still make up a sizable portion of the US population. I don&#39;t believe this was the case in the past (though I have no strong evidence), where secular individuals or even atheists understood Christianity in the broad sense, being an important part of American life. It also breeds hostility, as there is a tendency to view people one cannot understand with suspicion (exacerbated with the negative portrayals of Christianity in media). I also suspect this illiteracy is largely unidirectional too, as most Christians are exposed to the glut of secular/liberal media that exists.

Edit: Just to add an addendum, I do wonder what the consequences of this are. A lack of understanding of the cultural history of the West, a lack of understanding of the most influential moral system in the word, is this a void that secular religions are rushing to fill? Is America truly culturally secular now?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieywk50/"/></entry></feed>