<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/LastNightLonely - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T23:18:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/LastNightLonely" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheM</title><updated>2022-07-13T23:18:46Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Thanks everyone who replied to [my post last week](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/?context=3). I did indeed start swiping on other guys on Tinder. I somehow got four matches in a couple days, and two of them didn&#39;t even ghost me immediately! We switched to Snapchat texts and everything.

...which was *absolutely exhausting*. I don&#39;t understand how people chat over text with near-strangers they&#39;re trying to possibly date. The notification sound now produces not so much butterflies as the panic response.

One guy gave me kind of pushy/weird vibes after a bit, so I blocked him, solving one problem. The other guy seems pretty cool so far. I followed TracingWoodgrains&#39; advice of suggesting an in-person meeting soon, which seemed to go over well, but he&#39;s not going to be free until the weekend, dooming me to several days of awkward texting. We might do a call soon at least.

On one hand, I hope it goes well, but on the other, I wouldn&#39;t be too upset if this connection disintegrated. Perhaps I should hold out for meeting people in-person or as friends of friends. The board game group this week involved a guy who I&#39;m pretty sure is gay; he&#39;s well outside my age range, but there being any gay guys there is progress.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ig22xn5/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>