<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/LastNightLonely - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-06T18:04:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/LastNightLonely.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/</id><title type="text">[WW] Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white,</title><updated>2022-07-06T18:04:36Z</updated><author><name>LastNightLonely</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww.html" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Another awkward guy who could use some dating advice here.

I&#39;m 23, male, white, just finished a master&#39;s degree, starting a career in software engineering, normal-looking (though skinny; I&#39;m working on that), and shy in large groups of new people (but alright one on one). The main problem is that I&#39;m gay in a moderate-size city in the US South, population 150,000, whose main university was recently ranked the least LGBT-friendly public university in the nation.

Due to general awkwardness and being busy during college and grad school, I&#39;ve never kissed a guy or been on a date, but girls have definitely liked me, so I think I would do alright if I could just meet some gay guys that are at least slightly nerdy. My question is then how to do that.

There are gay bars in town, but bars aren&#39;t at all my scene, I personally don&#39;t drink for genetic reasons, I&#39;m not looking for a hookup (I could just use Grindr if I was), and it just seems like my kind of guy is unlikely to be at a bar. But maybe I should try anyway?

I tried Tinder and Bumble, but the pools are so small (I exhausted them in just a couple hours) and a large proportion of guys smoke (a deal-breaker for me) or are just looking for a hookup. I got a couple matches, but they almost immediately stopped responding, which I suppose is to be expected on the apps.

To make some regular friends in town, I&#39;ve started going to a board game club. There used to be a pretty active programmers community in town, which apparently kind of collapsed during the pandemic, but I&#39;ll keep an eye on it. For some physical activity I&#39;m thinking about joining a recreational soccer league this fall.

Thoughts on any of this would be appreciated, thanks!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if3qh70/"/></entry></feed>