<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-23T20:16:49Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ili33i1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Following up my “equality” post from the other day, I will talk about abortion a</title><updated>2022-08-23T20:16:49Z</updated><author><name>Lorelei_On_The_Rocks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Following up my “equality” post from the other day, I will talk about abortion and the way in which I strongly disagree with the framing on both sides of the issue. I think abortion is a similar issue because, like &#34;equality,&#34; people on &#34;both sides of the issue&#34; today share much more common ground than they think, and are thoroughly blinkered as a result. 

The “anti-abortion” side is pretty straightforward, at least ostensibly. “Human life is sacred, fetus is human life, therefore no kill.” 

The “pro-abortion” side cannot dispute the idea that human life qua human life, that is, individual members of the biological species *homo sapiens*, is sacred and inherently worthy protecting. So they must marshal different sorts of arguments, appealing to bodily autonomy or the inhumanity of the fetus. 

Intuitively, to me, it’s obvious that abortion is not equal to murder. It also seems to have been obvious to most people through most of history, since abortion has rarely ever been considered equal to murder, by law or custom. Even when it has been considered unsavory and even criminal, it was not considered equivalent to stabbing a man in the street or dashing out an infant’s brains. 

Why is this? I think it is the same the reason that, in the classical world, infanticide was not considered equal to murder, either. Exposure was a common practice in the ancient world. Anti-abortion activists today are very fond of pointing out that the vast majority of abortion is not in cases of rape or incest, but simply in cases of a mother who does not feel she is “ready” or “capable” of taking care of a child. Likewise, in the ancient world, countless babies were exposed with the rationale, “just another mouth to feed,” or even, “don’t wanna take care of this thing,&#34; and thus left to die on rubbish heaps. 

Again, this was a practice that was sometimes frowned upon, sometimes condemned, though never outlawed as far as I know, but never considered equal to actual murder. 

This is because to be a full-fledged “human” it is not enough to be a biological member of the species *homo sapiens*. Humanity is contextual as much, or more so, as it is biological. To be a human means having a place in a social structure, obligations and rights. You have parents, children, brothers, sisters, friends, patrons, clients. You understand religion, history, civic duty. 

If a member of the species *homo sapiens* was raised by wolves in the forest, and grew up without language, human parents, friends, religion, ethics, or socialization of any kind, he would be morally equal to a wild beast and could be killed with the same impunity as a wolf. A fetus, or an infant for that matter, is in the same position. This is what makes abortion unequal to murder, if it is a crime at all. 

Modern anti-abortion activists cannot make this argument because they are, like their enemies, wedded to the idea that being homo sapiens makes one inherently sacred.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ili33i1/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>