<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T19:25:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imalmyd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **&#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34;** 

Did it? What does this actually </title><updated>2022-08-29T19:25:46Z</updated><author><name>Lorelei_On_The_Rocks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**&#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34;** 

Did it? What does this actually mean? It is a sentiment I encounter often. Including on this subreddit in the course of a discussion a few days/weeks ago (most articulately elucidated by /u/FCfromSSC). 

It usually comes up in arguments between Christian and non-Christian right-wingers. e.g:

&#34;Christianity is a cringe cuck Asiatic soy religion&#34; 

&#34;Actually Christianity is heckin based and redpilled and built western civilization.&#34; 

I disagree with the proposition, or at least, I am pretty sure I do. 

I think &#34;Christianity built western civilization&#34; can be interpreted a number of ways. 

First, and least charitably, it could be taken to mean that Christianity has had a very great influence on western civilization over the course of the past, say, fifteen centuries. This is undeniable. There would be no Gothic cathedrals, no *Divine Comedy* without Christianity. Sure. But I don&#39;t think this is what is meant by &#34;Christianity built western civilization.&#34; Because this is a very tautological and uninteresting interpretation of the proposition. If not for Christianity, European civilization would not bear a Christian stamp. Sure. So what?

There is a stronger interpretation, which is that Christianity added something (or some*things*) to European civilization which, while not explicitly Christian, it would not have had without Christianity. For example, it sometimes said that the scientific method is rooted in a Christian worldview (I happen to think this is absurd). However, I could still probably agree with this. European civilization would certainly have been very different without Christianity. Fun as counterfactuals are, we will never know precisely *how* it would have been different, but it certainly would have been, and many of these differences would probably have been subtle and not immediately tied to the absence of Christianity. 

The strongest interpretation of the proposition, and the one I believe its defenders are adhering to, is something like, &#34;European civilization is/was *great* and its *greatness* is entirely or largely owed to Christianity.&#34; This is the interpretation I strongly *disagree* with. 

It depends on what you think is (or was) *great* about European civilization. If you are a Christian, and you say, &#34;Christianity is true, and therefore a civilization that exemplifies Christian morals and virtue is great,&#34; then we have a very deep disagreement, because I *don&#39;t* think Christianity is true. The argument will have to be suspended while we dig down to a deeper level and argue about the truth of Christianity. 

But most defenders of the proposition don&#39;t tend to argue so bluntly. In my experience, they attempt to find common ground with the non-Christian RWer by which they can persuade them that the greatness of European civilization, agreed upon by both parties, can be credited to Christianity. 

So what made European civilization great? In my view it is obvious. 

First and foremost, strength and power. Various nations of Europe subjected a greater portion of the world than any before them. All of the Americas, all of Africa (save a few stubborn states), great swathes of Asia. It was a feat unequalled in world history, and &#34;great&#34; by any reasonable measure. 

Secondly, artistic and cultural achievement. It is obvious that Europe has been the world center for great art for the past several centuries. I confess I am no connoisseur, but *The Ecstasy of Saint Teresa* has left me in awe since high school. To say nothing of architecture, literature, etc. 

Thirdly, scientific achievement. Again, it is quite indisputable that Europe has been the center of scientific and technological excellence for the past several centuries. Northwestern Europe, in particular. No industrial revolution without England. 

So the question is, to what extent was Christianity responsible for any of these three?

I believe the answer is &#34;barely,&#34; or &#34;not at all,&#34; since Europe was leading in all three even before Christianization. If anything there was something of a backslide on all three metrics in the early middle ages. I&#39;m not trying to resurrect &#34;hole left by the Christian dark ages,&#34; but if Christianity had a stimulating effect on European greatness you would not expect its proliferation to coincide with the political, cultural, economic, and artistic decay that characterized late antiquity and the early medieval period. 

This argument is usually capped off with something along the lines of, &#34;well, you&#39;re just a LARPer, western civilization has been Christian for centuries so trying to resurrect pagan Greece or Rome is just dumb and pointless.&#34; Which may be true, but is also a huge self-own considering how many online Christian RWers are trad monarchist LARPer types. One might as easily say, &#34;well, the west has been liberal democratic for two centuries, now. Trying to resurrect catholic monarchy is just dumb and pointless.&#34; Or bring it even further down to date. &#34;Trying to resurrect the 1950s is dumb and pointless, that was more than half a century ago. Move on, stop LARPing.&#34; You get the point. 

I am aware that today, the great majority of western conservatives are Christian or at least Christian adjacent. In real life, I don&#39;t call Christian conservatives cringe and tell them they should be worshipping the Olympians. That would, indeed, be silly and pointless. I am happy to make common cause with Christian RWers IRL. But this is an argument I get into regularly in niche internet spaces, and I happen to think I have the better part of it. I am curious what the users of this subreddit think, since this is after all one of the niche internet spaces in which I have had this and related arguments. 

SIDENOTE: the also-common argument that &#34;Christianity united Europe&#34; is not addressed above because it is almost too stupid for words. After the dissolution of pagan Rome, Europe was never so united again until the 20th century. Christian Europeans spent centuries warring with their fellow Christian Europeans. And of course during the Based Crusades™ another set of Based Crusaders was up north slaughtering Baltic pagans. Not that any of this matters because pan-European nationalism is dumb in most contexts anyways.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imalmyd/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>