<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-19T21:46:43Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Lorelei_On_The_Rocks" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikznn5w/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Humans are not equal**. 

I expect most people here would probably agree with </title><updated>2022-08-19T21:46:43Z</updated><author><name>Lorelei_On_The_Rocks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Humans are not equal**. 

I expect most people here would probably agree with that statement reflexively, insofar as most people here probably agree that all people do not have equal capabilities, whether we’re talking about physical capabilities or the more controversial mental capabilities. 

However even most people who are quick to admit to this are just as quick to follow it up with the caveat that practical inequality does not imply *moral* inequality, and that all persons regardless of ability are worth equal moral consideration. 

I think this is self-evidently false. Leftists, the paladins of “equality,” understand this, which is why inegalitarian thought frightens them so much. If, in fact, humans are not practically equal, then it is self-evident that they are not morally equal, either. A dullard is worth less than a genius. It is obvious. 

IMO the right can never really win against the left until it defends the proposition, yes, some people are inherently better than others on all relevant metrics. 

It is difficult to argue against economic redistribution, to give one example unless you accept this. To make an argument that people should not have their wealth expropriated for the sake of others, you cannot make purely practical arguments (i.e it won’t have the desired results, it’s inefficient, etc.) because this leaves one open to all sorts of moralistic sophistry. One must make the point that the intended recipients of the redistribution simply are not worthy of the goods of better people. 

Likewise, with the axiom of human moral equality taken for granted, right-wingers will flounder to explain why an intelligent, respected, sober, successful man deserves more consideration than a stupid, habitual drunken layabout. Sure, the former might make better decisions, but if the two share some fundamental moral equality, shouldn’t their desires, interests, and well-being merit equal consideration?

To argue for “equality of opportunity” instead of “equality of outcome” is an equally (ha) silly thing to do. What does it even mean, when one gets down to it? We haven’t sprung fully formed from the aether. We are all products of our ancestors, and the environments produced by our ancestors. There was “equality of opportunity” at the beginning of time, and we are living with its results. It’s possible someone whose ancestors are all imbecilic failures, and who lives in a community of imbecilic failures, will prove as capable (in whatever respect) as someone whose ancestors are all intelligent, competent persons, but it is unlikely enough that no resources or energy should be expended on giving that former someone “his shot.” 

I suspect this line of thinking viscerally would disgust and upset even a lot of people who consider themselves “right-wing.” I submit that this merely shows the extent to which even self-considered conservatives or reactionaries have been mind-colonized by leftism in the present day. For the past sixteen plus centuries of human civilization, no one ever dreamed that the life of a slave was worth the life of a free man. 

I would amend the first statement to, **humans are not equal in *any* sense.** Except perhaps the most banal and uninteresting sense in which two humans are equally humans, in the same sense that a boulder and a pebble are equally rocks. Conceding “equality” in any sense other than this plants the seed of a thousand errors.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikznn5w/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>