<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Lost_Martian_Expat - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-02T17:10:52Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Lost_Martian_Expat" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxlpgm/</id><title type="text">[CW] The Modern Transgender Phenomenon and its Function

Many people ask themselves h</title><updated>2022-06-02T17:10:52Z</updated><author><name>Lost_Martian_Expat</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The Modern Transgender Phenomenon and its Function

Many people ask themselves how and why has a castration cult managed to gain so much power in the last decade?

After gay marriage was legalized in the States, in the mid 2010s, all the progressive machinery needed a new cause to champion or the money, and purpose, dried up and they found a replacement for gays with transgenders and moved all the cultural infrastructure accordingly. 

That&#39;s the how, but I believe the why is more important and interesting.

I see the trans-debate as a way for power to differentiate between loyalists and dissenters: [&#34;Calling a deer a horse.&#34;](https://laowai-dawei.com/calling-a-deer-a-horse-%E6%8C%87%E9%B9%BF%E4%B8%BA%E9%A9%AC/)

&amp;gt;The second Qin emperor, Qin Er Shi who reigned from 221 to 206 B.C., had a prime minister named Zhao Gao.   

&amp;gt;Zhao Gao was very ambitious and had treasonous ambitions.   He wanted to attempt a coup of Qin Er Shi but didn’t know who in the Emperor’s court would go along with his plans.

&amp;gt;One day Zhao Gao presented the Emperor with a deer, but said it was a swift horse.

&amp;gt;“Prime Minister, you are clearly mistaken.  That is a deer.’

&amp;gt;Zhao Gao, prepared for this response replied, “If that is the case, Your Majesty, ask the member of your court what it is.”

&amp;gt;Some of the court remained quiet.   Some, knowing how treacherous Zhao Gao was, went along with his claim.   Others, called a spade a spade and told the Emperor it was a deer.

&amp;gt;Knowing who his allies were, those royal courtiers who said the animal was a deer were executed.  The cunning Zhao Gao knew who his allies were.

The idiom is used to describe a situation where “black” is called “white” and vice versa for the purpose of manipulating people to advance one’s evil agenda. 

The greater [plain-faced lie](https://imgur.com/a/XUAJkGe) you repeat show just how willing you are to toe the party line.

Doesn&#39;t the above all sound familiar? 

Anyone remember when Twitch elevated some insane troon named FerociouslySteph into a censorship csar position? Not only did he think he was a woman, he also [LARP as a deer](https://youtu.be/FVzE6ulTtck?t=83). 

Time is a flat fucking circle.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxlpgm/"/></entry></feed>