<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MacaqueOfTheNorth - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-16T04:13:21Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MacaqueOfTheNorth" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/igcsc8z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Our Problems Aren’t Procedural](https://www.city-journal.org/our-problems-arent</title><updated>2022-07-16T04:13:21Z</updated><author><name>MacaqueOfTheNorth</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Our Problems Aren’t Procedural](https://www.city-journal.org/our-problems-arent-procedural)

&amp;gt;Alexis de Tocqueville previewed this theme a century earlier by declaring that he did not “know any country where, in general, less independence of mind and genuine freedom of discussion reign than in America.” Among Americans, “the majority draws a formidable circle around thought,” he wrote. “Inside those limits, the writer is free; but unhappiness awaits him if he dares to leave them.” Those that so dare are “the butt of mortifications of all kinds of persecutions every day . . . everything is refused him, even glory.” As with the cancelled of today, stepping outside this circle of approved thought means that “those who blame him [will] express themselves openly, and those who think like him, without having his courage, keep silent and move away.” The American dissident is left no choice but to “bend under the effort of each day and return to silence as if he felt remorse for having spoken the truth.”

&amp;gt;Tocqueville blamed the narrow range of acceptable speech on the social conditions of democracy. Aristocrats were protected from the force of social judgment by their rank and the economic security of their landed inheritance. With literacy rates high enough to guarantee mass participation in politics, social ranks level enough to preclude aristocratic deference, and wealth spread widely enough to instill an anxious spirit of bourgeoisie striving, America would never favor the heterodox. It never has.

&amp;gt;If cancel culture has always been with us, what has changed over time is what an American can be cancelled for. Twenty years ago, country music bands were being cancelled for opposing the Iraq War and writers were being cancelled for refusing to put American flags on their doorstep. Today, a different set of offenses leads to ostracization, but the forms and consequences of ostracization are largely the same. The current moment feels so fraught not because cancellation has emerged as a new feature in American life but because of the sudden and dramatic shift in the range of views deemed cancel-worthy. For the first time in their lives, many Americans find themselves on the wrong side of Tocqueville’s circle. This shift is especially disorienting for centrists whose views had—for most of their lives—constituted the very definition of acceptable opinion.

The essay is making a broader point, but I thought this part was particularly relevant to this subreddit for hopefully obvious reasons.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/igcsc8z/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>