<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MelodicBerries - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-03T19:07:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MelodicBerries" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imym8n3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] One thing about Biden&#39;s speech that surprised me was his desperation to get back</title><updated>2022-09-03T19:07:28Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">One thing about Biden&#39;s speech that surprised me was his desperation to get back to &#34;moderate Republicans&#34;. If these MAGA people are so extreme as he claims, wouldn&#39;t he want to encourage their antics so as to continually win general elections?

In places like Philippines or Hungary, the ruling party relishes putting their opposition to the margins, whereas Biden bizarrely wants to *help* the establishment of his opponent.

This is something that seems strangely and uniquely American. I can&#39;t think of any other country where the elite of one party tries desperately to help out the other party&#39;s establishment. In most other democracies, the ruling party just tries to consolidate its gains. 

And lest I be accused of only promoting right-wing populists (e.g. Orban or Duterte), you could look at Scandinavia from the 1950s-1970s for a left-wing equivalent. Those government had no compunction about stacking the odds as much as possible in their own favour.

The generous reading is that Biden&#39;s speech wasn&#39;t about winning but about &#34;saving democracy&#34; even if it means helping the GOP elite, because Biden is such a selfless patriot.

A less generous reading would be that Biden is part of the same &#34;uniparty&#34; as Mitch McConnell and other GOP leaders who are terrified of being swallowed up alive by the forces that Trump ultimately represents however inperfectly. In this reading, Biden trying to bring down a rival faction to the GOP establishment isn&#39;t a selfless act of patriotism as much as naked self-interest.

Whichever reading you prefer, it still remains notable that this type of behaviour is uncommon in other countries. Certainly, the US system seems to produce a unified political class much more unified than other countries.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imym8n3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>