<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MelodicBerries - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-06T21:25:57Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MelodicBerries.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4jc0o/</id><title type="text">[CW] **The death of the American Middle-Class**.

Much has been written about this to</title><updated>2022-07-06T21:25:57Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**The death of the American Middle-Class**.

Much has been written about this topic in terms of outsourcing or trade, but the NYT has a decent [data-rich article](https://archive.ph/m93RC) showing how US cities are increasingly bifurcated onto &#34;poor&#34; or &#34;rich&#34; areas with a disappearing middle. 

A few excerpts:

&amp;gt; And in Orlando, nearly 70 percent of area residents lived in “average” neighborhoods back in 1990, according to census data. In 2020, the same was true for just 46 percent.

&amp;gt;That leaves a lot of people feeling like they are on the outside looking in.
Michael Street is a union electrician who moved from Nashville to Goodlettsville about 25 minutes away. 

&amp;gt;He said he spent his days driving around Nashville, working on houses that have all been rehabbed, rebuilt or rendered unrecognizable in neighborhoods he can no longer afford.
“Either you’re poor, or you’re rich,” he said. “Middle class is kind of phasing out. Either you have a lot of money, or you’re just barely getting by.”

This raises a few questions. First, should we aim for a more evenly balanced income distribution in residential areas? If not, should we at least try to mix people socio-economically even if they don&#39;t live in the same neighbourhoods? This seems to be the underlying premise of the article. 

Second, is it even possible to achieve? The forces of self-segregation appear to be structural. It&#39;s an important reminder that while the US remains obsessed about race, class is often just a salient issue, if not more so.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if4jc0o/"/></entry></feed>