<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MelodicBerries - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T18:45:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MelodicBerries" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but</title><updated>2022-08-22T18:45:28Z</updated><author><name>MelodicBerries</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Has &#39;wokism&#39; peaked? It&#39;s hard to say without looking in the rearview mirror but from my vantage point while opposition may have slowed its ascent, it hasn&#39;t managed to reverse the gains.

Case in point: https://www.aier.org/article/the-suicide-of-the-american-historical-association/

Basically, the AHA President dared to offer the mildest of critiques of the &#39;1619&#39; project and now his own members are baying for his blood in the form of a career defenestration. He has hardly any defenders within his organisation and he&#39;s the top guy, so what hope is there for someone with less status within the history profession?

DeSantis&#39; so-called &#34;anti-woke laws&#34; were all stopped by a federal judge. He hopes his voters don&#39;t pay attention and he gives no indications of trying to fight hard to overrule  any of these setbacks.

University of Tennessee - supposedly in a red state where the GOP has political control - has [massively ramped](https://twitter.com/JohnDSailer/status/1559605619857956864) up the DIE (Diversity, Inclusion, Equity) policies.

The GOP appears content in complaining but doing little to combat any of this by using state power. As long as this is the case, my prediction is that &#39;wokism&#39;, for a lack of a better term, is here to stay.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilctpsy/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>