<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MihowZa - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T16:44:15Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MihowZa" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9xi04/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] How many people here can hold an emotion for 10 minutes?

Sam Harris had a quote</title><updated>2022-08-29T16:44:15Z</updated><author><name>MihowZa</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">How many people here can hold an emotion for 10 minutes?

Sam Harris had a quote recently where he said &#39; 10 minutes of anger can really fuck up your life &#39; and I understood it to be obviously true. But how many people can actually hold an emotion that long? I&#39;ve held sadness twice for a longer period of time: once when a long term gf and I broke up, and once when my best friend killed themselves. I also get angry in spurts - browsing Reddit sometimes does it or hearing peoples various political opinions I disagree with or know that are incorrect - but it&#39;s just a spur of the moment issue. Another example is sports. I love sports but I really never get too up or too down about my teams performance; there&#39;s always next year + being a Marlins and Dolphins fan that would just be an outlet to constant anger. Otherwise, pretty much every other emotion is just done after what seems like several seconds. 

This leads me to question if otherwise I am emotionally comatose the majority of my life? 

Now Sam was talking about it in relation (I believe) of criminality and, as always, of free will and I&#39;m talking about it more on a personal level, and that&#39;s what I&#39;d like to hear feedback on: how long do you hold onto emotions? And how does this impact your life daily and in general?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im9xi04/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>