<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/mirror_truth - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-01T20:34:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/mirror_truth" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iatwl2r/</id><title type="text">[CW] We&#39;ve all heard of shadow-banning, but have you heard of Reddit&#39;s new policy cal</title><updated>2022-06-01T20:34:26Z</updated><author><name>mirror_truth</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">We&#39;ve all heard of shadow-banning, but have you heard of Reddit&#39;s new policy called &#34;Heaven Banning&#34;? Here&#39;s a screenshot of an article from the [NYT](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FUMHLLxWYAM6xLe?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=900x900) with some details. I hadn&#39;t heard about it till today.

That&#39;s unsurprising though, since if you look at the article&#39;s publication date, it won&#39;t be written for another 2 years. Here&#39;s the [source](https://twitter.com/nearcyan/status/1532076277947330561) for the image - a tweet with some more context.

In the current context of the recent mass-shootings in the US, this concept of &#39;heaven-banning&#39; felt especially relevant. It&#39;s been noted by many people that one of the ways that young men are radicalized to the point they shoot up a school, or a church, or a shop it through online discussion forums. These forums offer young men a community of like-minded people that reinforce and enforce a cycle of despair and hate that can take root in some young men. Any voices that argue against it get drowned out and either leave the toxic community or get subsumed by it, until only the worst most toxic men remain to wallow in each other&#39;s pity. Until one decided to take out their rage on innocents. Then, if the community is located on a site with strong moderation, it gets sent to the shadowrealm, its constituent members presumably separated from each other. Until they, or others like them, gather somewhere else to begin the cycle again.

But what if instead of simply dispersing them, there were a way to quarantine them - without them even realizing it? Each member presented with their own slice of reality, filled with helpful &#39;friends&#39; that could steer them back onto the straight and narrow? And without having to subject any real people to the toxicity inherent in those communities to do it.

A few years ago, there was much handwringing over internet bubbles - the fragmentation of communities that could span a nation into fractal subgroups facilitated by the internet, where every time you looked closer, the more subdivisions you found. At least those bubbles were all filled with humans, however twisted they might be. The coming internet bubbles will come preloaded with zombies, ready to trap their unwitting victims into a fantasy in which they are the star.

Then it&#39;s just a hop, skip and a jump to get to Samantha from Her and Joi from Blade Runner 2049. Made to order, a new pacifier for the next generation of male incels and losers - and maybe a solution to mass shootings. The zombies won&#39;t feel a thing, but their companions will.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iatwl2r/"/></entry></feed>