<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/mustardEconomics - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-03T12:03:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/mustardEconomics.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/</id><title type="text">[SQ] TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and ma</title><updated>2022-07-03T12:03:27Z</updated><author><name>mustardEconomics</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq.html" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">TL;DR: I&#39;m introverted and companionship tires me out, should I still try and marry someone?

---

For most of my adult life, I wasn&#39;t really interested in romance, relationships, or women in general. This has recently changed. I&#39;ve grown increasingly interested about the idea of falling in love and marrying someone. There are a number of reasons for this. Lately, more and more frequently I&#39;ve been feeling unhappy about being alone and lacking connections, and I like the idea of someone genuinely feeling attracted to me. I sometimes feel like my current life is pointless overall; creating a family and fathering children feels like a good way of making myself feel that I&#39;ve amounted to something. And, to be honest, I want to actually share my sexuality with another living person. 

On the other hand... I&#39;m pretty introverted. Social interaction exhausts me quickly. There are days where, after having to endure others&#39; company for many hours, I just want to spend an entire evening without hearing another person&#39;s voice. Now, I&#39;m not *bad* at social interaction: When I need to, I&#39;m good at talking with people, acting smooth, suave, and confident. But it tires me out fast. And, to me, it always feels like I&#39;m putting on an act, pretending to be someone I&#39;m not. 

This makes me worry if marriage is really a good idea for me. Social interactions wears me out, but if I got married, I suppose I&#39;d need to socially interact with my wife (and later children) all the time. Getting to be alone would become the exception rather than a daily occurrence. It might make me miserable rather than happy. 
Also, while I&#39;m confident that I can get a woman interested in me by charming and intelligent conversation, I&#39;m scared of accidentally deceiving her. She might get the false idea that I&#39;m *always* a smooth-talking charmer, and will be disappointed to find out I&#39;m an introvert who doesn&#39;t really like talking much. 

So my question is, are these desires compatible? Should I aim for marriage if I find social interaction to be tiresome work? Perhaps some of you have experience with being married (or otherwise in a permanent relationship) while introverted?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vqb0xe/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_03_2022/ieos5yp/"/></entry></feed>