<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/MustPavloveDogs - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-04T20:10:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/MustPavloveDogs.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieuxana/</id><title type="text">[CW] I love reading and thinking about the future of robotics and artificial intellig</title><updated>2022-07-04T20:10:04Z</updated><author><name>MustPavloveDogs</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I love reading and thinking about the future of robotics and artificial intelligence, and am a fan of works such as Blade Runner/Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?, iRobot, and other media that explores the possibilities of artificial intelligence. I don&#39;t have the most sophisticated understanding of them, but I enjoy discussing them with others.

Assuming that 1) We develop androids that can pass the Turing Test and 2) Humanity doesn&#39;t destroy itself before we reach this point, how do you imagine the fight for android rights, the possible &#34;final frontier of civil rights&#34; playing out?

It occurred to me that future discussions on android rights could mirror current discussions on transgender rights.

(NOTE: I am NOT at all trying to compare trans people to robots or imply that trans people aren&#39;t human. I&#39;m only comparing the discourse around their treatment in society.

Also NOTE: I&#39;m using the term &#34;androids&#34; mostly, but if you&#39;d prefer to focus on AI as a separate thing, that&#39;s fine with me)

I imagine one argument against androids being given the same rights as humans would boil down to:

*&#34;They&#39;re not really humans, they&#39;re only acting how they think humans behave.&#34;*

Replace &#34;humans&#34; with &#34;men&#34; or &#34;women&#34; and you&#39;ve got one of the most common complaints in the current &#34;trans rights&#34; discourse.

Assuming we can get through the [Uncanny\_Valley](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncanny_valley) and create androids that look identical to humans in addition to sounding like them--in other words, &#34;passing&#34; as human--how does that affect the discussion? Would it be better to have androids that don&#39;t look too human, or would that negatively impact their chance for greater rights?

A few other questions to consider:

\- Will &#34;robosexual&#34; and &#34;robophobia&#34; become mainstream terms?

\- Will the robots destroy us all before we even get to that point...or perhaps will the debate lead to them destroying us?

\- Would you be a human ally to android activists?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I thought this would be a good place to have an intelligent, honest discussion. I hope it&#39;s enjoyable for everyone.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieuxana/"/></entry></feed>