<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Navalgazer420XX - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-23T17:52:35Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Navalgazer420XX" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series. I&#39;m already getting half</title><updated>2022-07-23T17:52:35Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I take back everything I said about the LOTR TV series. I&#39;m already getting half a billion dollars worth of [entertainment](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FYS5d_YUEAAPl2D?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=orig) from it, and I&#39;m not even gonna watch.

Also my deeply closeted white trash middle school boyfriend turning out to be Sauron is an acceptable twist, if a lazy and obvious one.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w524ad/friday_fun_thread_for_july_22_2022/ihcj6ub/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recomme</title><updated>2022-07-21T13:25:21Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Are salt intake guidelines too low? (Am I getting enough salt?)

The FDA recommends eating less than a teaspoon of salt per day, while animals our size generally eat a quarter to a third of an oz per day.  
I don&#39;t eat any processed food, so the only salt I get is on meat and fried eggs. Have been developing salt cravings this summer to the point that livestock mineral salt looks really delicious, which is a pretty reliable sign I&#39;m missing _something_.   
Everything out there is just yelling at people not to eat salt, but maybe someone here has done some proper research?

Bonus question: other than a costco multivitamin, what&#39;s a good extra source of zinc and other useful minerals?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ih1pz9v/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing some</title><updated>2022-07-18T05:02:13Z</updated><author><name>Navalgazer420XX</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I finally finished a year-long project, need suggestions on buying or doing something to celebrate. 

Started air-layering a couple hundred laurel starts last summer, planted them in a composted trench along the most exposed section of my frontage this spring, and only just got [the last of the weed barrier and wood chips down](https://files.catbox.moe/9hohcv.jpg).  
Total cost was about $20 for some rooting hormone and a lot of grunt work, and while it feels really good to be finished, I can&#39;t think of anything to treat myself to.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/iglux6n/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>