<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/netstack_ - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-04T14:55:41Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/netstack_.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ietouha/</id><title type="text">[CW] The other week, I enjoyed lunch with my grandmother in her retirement home.
One </title><updated>2022-07-04T14:55:41Z</updated><author><name>netstack_</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The other week, I enjoyed lunch with my grandmother in her retirement home.
One of the other residents was a sweet old lady with, apparently, quite the variety of life experiences.
And as I listened to her stories of Saudi Arabia, I felt what can only be described as national pride.
So in the spirit of the 4th, I&#39;d like to share a few examples of American cultural imperialism.

___

The year is 1981.
In Iran, 52 American hostages were only just released to the newly inaugurated Reagan administration.
Soviet forces occupy Afghanistan; three offensives have so far failed to drive the mujahideen from the Panjshir valley.
Saudi Arabia&#39;s King Khalid is in ill health and delegates ever more administrative duties to Crown Prince Fahd.
His response to the 1979 Grand Mosque Seizure has increased the power of Islamic traditionalists.

This woman is not terribly concerned with such developments, even though the American embassy has warned her: 
&#34;If there&#39;s trouble, don&#39;t come here.&#34;
She has already resolved to ignore that directive in case of danger.

Her new job is administrative work at a major Riyadh hospital employing citizens of 52 different countries.
She speaks only English.
Later she will tell me that the trick is careful listening, not the half-awareness we do when we are familiar with a language.
You can get a lot from paying attention to tone.

As she becomes more familiar with employee records, she notices that no one celebrates birthdays in the office.
(She told me that the records don&#39;t emphasize birth date like they do here;
I haven&#39;t been able to corroborate that, but the lack of celebrations still holds true today.
It is considered a risk of excess.)
Naturally, she decides to correct this oversight.
This means assigning each of her fellow employees to a week.
When that date comes around, she bakes a cake for the office and throws a little party.
She really enjoys having this as a regular occurrence.

Payroll is managed entirely with paper money.
Each month bags are brought into the hospital to be divided by department.
Then each department head distributes the cash to their employees.
During her stay, she is part of the rollout of a new and exotic technology known as the &#34;check.&#34;
This takes some getting used to; many employees are not familiar with the concept at all, and may even lack a bank account, treating the check like it&#39;s cash.
She observes that the number of uncashed checks is very high.
Not that she&#39;s particularly surprised, as management has done next to nothing to prepare training for the rollout.
Again, she takes it upon herself to set up workshops explaining the basics.

Saudi Arabia was and is incredibly gender-segregated.
Its buses allocate the front half to men and the back half to women.
Not in the Rosa Parks sense--there are two separate entrances with a divider.
All the bus drivers are Filipino, apparently because they are more likely to speak English.
But the passengers are largely young Saudi men.

She makes a habit of walking up to the front entrance.
Not to *actually* board the men&#39;s section, but to holler at the driver for directions before heading to the back.
&#34;The men would get outraged as you walked up, shouting &#39;You have to go to the back!&#39; and waving me away,&#34; she tells me.
&#34;It was the *funniest* thing.&#34;

There&#39;s an older man running a cafe that she frequents.
They regularly chat over lunch, and on occasion, he tries to matchmake her with locals.
She doesn&#39;t hold it against him.
After several months, he says it&#39;s a shame she&#39;s still unmarried, and makes the offer himself.
She says yes--on two conditions.
First, he&#39;d have to convert, as she&#39;s a Baptist with no intention of taking up Islam.
Second, she doesn&#39;t share.
But if he divorces his first wife, she&#39;d marry him.
He reconsiders.

A week before she is due to fly back to the States, she is walking downtown and notices one of the *mutaween* evaluating her outfit.
These are the religious police, tasked with identifying and punishing noncompliance with Sharia law.
They&#39;re equipped with switches to slap any uncovered ankles passing by.
As a consequence of population statistics, they also tend to be at least six inches shorter than her.
She fixes this man with a Look and tells him, and I quote:
&#34;Hit me with that and I&#39;ll kill you.&#34;
It&#39;s not clear whether or not he speaks English, but he certainly lets her pass.

___

I still don&#39;t know exactly why this woman chose to spend a year or two in Saudi Arabia.
She didn&#39;t know the language, was a stranger to the culture, and left the U.S.A. for a country actively sliding towards Islamic fundamentalism.
And she did so with *confidence*.
Her self-assurance in our customs, paired with the willingness to go out there and export it to the rest of the world--
That&#39;s cultural imperialism in action, and I&#39;m proud of it.

Here&#39;s to another 250 years.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ietouha/"/></entry></feed>