<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Nightmode444444 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-08T13:38:22Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Nightmode444444" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I re</title><updated>2022-07-08T13:38:22Z</updated><author><name>Nightmode444444</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">I don’t know if observing other niche communities is frowned upon here, but I recently ran across an external forum that is totally fascinating. It’s a fairly large and active community of Christian polygamists. They’re not associated with a denomination (definitely not Mormon) and seems to be legitimate biblical scholars. They have reasoned their way into polygamy with carful reading of scripture. If you liked watching Big Love and want to really see how modern polygamists live. Here’s your shot. 

Some observations:

* They seems to be quite persecuted within mainstream Christiandom. As you would expect.
* They also seem to be quite intelligent and know the Bible inside and out. They can support their position quite well and it seems difficult find a flaw in their logic. As a Catholic, I can’t say that I’m an expert on scripture and the only argument I have against their logic is that The Church has taken a very diffierent view on sex and marriage. Without having The Church as an authority, I don’t know how evangelicals who stick to the Bible as ultimate authority can pin these people down. 
* There does seem to be some motivated reasoning going on here. Some posters are clearly looking to justify their lust and build a harem, but most seem to be quite sincere. 
* The community is surprisingly healthy with lots of activity and very collegial users. Reminds me of themotte in some ways. 

I find the whole thing fascinating. Besides the whole intellectual discussion of polygamy and the Bible there are quite of few gems in here. Ever want to see a bunch of Christian men painstakingly discuss whether or not lesbiansism between sister wives is a sin (spoiler: it’s not)? Ever want to see full throated defense and encorgament of patriarchy? I’ve always loved to observe these types of communities that I would otherwise not know about. Reminds me of early internet days. 

I won’t link to the the forum, but you can google christian polygamy forum and find it quite easily. 

Enjoy.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vu2vu3/friday_fun_thread_for_july_08_2022/ifcc5sj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>