<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/NotATleilaxuGhola - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-22T00:41:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/NotATleilaxuGhola" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4l4i1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] TW: Navel gazing and red-tribe/blue-tribe palm reading 

Yarvin has a new piece </title><updated>2022-07-22T00:41:46Z</updated><author><name>NotATleilaxuGhola</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">TW: Navel gazing and red-tribe/blue-tribe palm reading 

Yarvin has a new piece in typical Yarvin style (long on flourishes, short on substance) call [&#34;You Can Only Lose the Culture War.&#34;](https://graymirror.substack.com/p/you-can-only-lose-the-culture-war)  In it, he makes a (muddled) Tolkein analogy, casting the blue tribe as &#34;elves&#34; and the red tribe as &#34;hobbits&#34;:  
  
&amp;gt;We know who are the hobbits and who are the elves. We know who is on top and who is on the bottom. (Of dwarves and orcs, we shall not speak.) We know what the elves want: they want to live beautiful lives. We know what the hobbits want: they want to grill and raise kids.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Dear hobbits: you can only lose the culture war. Even when elves use political power to impose elf culture on you, you cannot use political power to impose hobbit culture on elves.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;I mean, sometimes (rarely) you can. It never works out well. I suppose that in theory you could massacre all the elves. You don’t seem up for that in practice. As an elf… I have to regard that as a good thing. But it leaves you, dear hobbits, in a real bind.  
  
And then he adds a third group, the &#34;dark elves&#34;:

&amp;gt;Moreover, when hobbits try to take revenge on elves at large, or even worse when they actually succeed, they are damaging a resource they do not even know they have. There may even be some elves—the dark elves—who are actually on the hobbits’ side.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Naturally, being traitors and all, these dark elves keep a low profile. But culturally, they are still totally elves and into, like, “art films” and stuff. Any attack on elves in general weakens and demoralizes this important fifth column. What are they useful for, these dark elves? See below.  
  
This sounds like shorthand for dissident blue tribers, maybe more specifically dissident blue tribe PMC members.  
  
At first, when I read this, I thought of myself as a hobbit.  The hobbits (peasants), according to Yarvin, are hopeless at political action and have to stake their hopes of living satisfying, hobbity lives on a hobbit-friendly group of elves taking power (aristocracy).  So much for having an impact on events.  Maybe I should just tend my garden.  
  
But I thought about it more, and realized that I&#39;m solidly in the blue tribe.  Despite holding reactionary, anti-enlightenment political views and being a practicing Catholic, I&#39;ve lived in blue cities and around blue tribers most of my adult life.  It&#39;s where the money is, the power is, the cultural ferment, the dynamism.  Even after having kids and moving to a red area, my social circle is blue/purple and the industry I work in is dark blue, and I have trouble connecting with my red tribe neighbors on a deep level.  
  
What to do when your fellow tribe members are ideological opponents and your ideological allies are culturally alien?  I want to move to a clandestine dark elven community deep in the red state of Mirkwood where I can join a reactionary book club, go to weekly Mass, go to a climbing gym, and enjoy craft beer.  I want the blue tribe, right-wing cultural and intellectual ferment diffused to near-insubstantiality across the online right to be concentrated into one place so that it can start to do things and develop ideas and put them into practice.  I know I&#39;m not the only one out there, and that hobbits would love to be ruled by this sort of dark elven elite (at least compared to the current elite), so this seems like a huge market failure.
  
Why is this?  There seems to be a lot of dissident right wing energy out there -- why are no centers of intellectual activity forming?  Leftist movements seemed quite good at condensing political energy, historically. Certain cities or regions became centers of union/socialist/communist activity, and from that power base these movements were able to exert political pressure and score victories.  Red tribe right-wingers, hobbits, just want to grill -- they&#39;re not about to get politically active unless their families are threatened.  But blue tribe right-wing dark elves have much in common with blue tribe leftists.  So why is there no organizing impulse amongst the dark elves?  Fear of retaliation from the elven elite?  Perhaps it&#39;s all just a LARP? Something else?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih4l4i1/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>