<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Nwallins - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-14T00:02:07Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Nwallins" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ik6xioi/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, WFH (work from home).  There are upsides and downsides for both employers an</title><updated>2022-08-14T00:02:07Z</updated><author><name>Nwallins</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, WFH (work from home).  There are upsides and downsides for both employers and employees.  I have long lamented (pre Covid) in my own career that it&#39;s not more acceptable to take advantage of modern telecom and click the buttons at home instead of HQ.

I&#39;m thankful for Covid upsetting the old equilibrium.  As such, I&#39;ve come up with a new source of tax revenue, to of course be offset by a tax reduction somewhere else.

For every employee required to commute to work more than 3 days per week, the employer pays a *commute tax*, possibly scaling with commute distance, time, or congestion, in order to offset the economic and ecological harms of unnecessary commutes.  Harms include time away from family, stress, physical accidents, danger to self and others, air pollution, road wear, congestion impacts on others, etc.

I feel like there will be huge corporate pushback on such a policy.  What do employees think?

EDIT: multiple posters have pointed out a giant oversight -- much if not most work is necessarily on-premises.  e.g. a retail cashier.

I am super ok with wide exemptions here, but I haven&#39;t thought through exactly how to carve it out.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ik6xioi/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>