<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/OracleOutlook - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-14T17:01:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/OracleOutlook" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig5etui/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I want to understand people who honestly believe that a human fetus is not a hum</title><updated>2022-07-14T17:01:34Z</updated><author><name>OracleOutlook</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I want to understand people who honestly believe that a human fetus is not a human person of moral weight.  From previous discussions I take that this is most of the people on this forum, and in fact most people on this forum have a hard time understanding someone like me, who believes that all living human organisms have 100% equal moral weight.  

I don&#39;t want to talk about abortion per se, because that gets into bodily autonomy and other moral considerations that muddy the water.  I want to investigate what gives humans moral weight, in the minds of Mottizens.  I devised the following thought experiment and questions to really get into the fine details:

Imagine a mad scientist who created a memory wiping chamber.  An orphaned, friendless adolescent wanders into the chamber and has their mind wiped.  As part of this process, they will be in a helpless coma for a few weeks, followed by a long period of relearning how to eat, walk, and talk.  As I mentioned, no one has a sentimental attachment to the person they were and they will have 0 memories of their previous life.  

1. While they are in the coma, is it morally acceptable to stab them?  Poison them?  Otherwise seek their death?
- If not, would it be ok for the mad scientist to starve them or otherwise not seek to provide medical treatment to keep them alive through their coma?  
- Does this answer change if the coma period extends from a few weeks to a few years?  When is the cutoff period at which it is acceptable to actively kill them or passively refuse aid?  

2. If you say that it&#39;s not ok to kill them and/or it is necessary to render aid given their helpless state, what is it that makes them a human person to you? 
- Is it that they resemble you physically in some respect?
- Is it that they will soon regain the abilities that you think define personhood?
- Is it that they once experienced the abilities that you think define personhood even if there&#39;s no conscious continuity?  
- Something else?

Edit:

A recurring question is what the coma process is like, so to clarify:

The brain is reformatting itself, this is a process that is uninterruptible and will take a long period of time. During this time the brain is not having what we would consider thoughts or experiences, though there is some sort of electrical activity. Electrical activity closer to 8 weeks of gestation than 40 weeks of gestation.  The subject is not light sensitive and not forming memories, for instance.  This process is happening on its own and is certain to complete itself in two weeks as long as the body is kept hydrated.

I also really don&#39;t want to talk about abortion.  Even talking about zygotes/embryos has been getting off topic.  I want to identify what a human person is and how that is different from a living human organism for most Motte people.

So far, the answer I&#39;m getting is a certain amount of gray matter, though it doesn&#39;t depend on if it&#39;s forming a thought.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig5etui/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>