<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/OracleOutlook - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T17:24:44Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/OracleOutlook" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijvrw9p/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Are we seeing a correction in practice for transgender issues?  I&#39;ve seen severa</title><updated>2022-08-11T17:24:44Z</updated><author><name>OracleOutlook</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Are we seeing a correction in practice for transgender issues?  I&#39;ve seen several signals this year that indicate the tide is shifting away from the affirmative care model.

[The Tavistock clinic](https://archive.ph/TM9LO#selection-295.52-299.145) has been shut down.  The NYT makes it sound like long waitlists are the main reason the UK is ditching this model, but another very strong reason is because the clinic ignored mental health issues in favor of beginning medical transition.  The clinic faces a [class action lawsuit](https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/4e7fc538-18dc-11ed-b1f4-627a202c7457?shareToken=8c10508fb9e9acdd02579f7a5207924c) from families who believe their child was negligently misdiagnosed by the clinic.  

An independent review of the Gender Identity Development Service by [Dr Hilary Cass](https://cass.independent-review.uk/publications/interim-report/) appears to be a significant catalyst.  The key points from an interim report are:

&amp;gt;The rapid increase in the number of children requiring support and the complex case-mix means that the current clinical model, with a single national provider, is not sustainable in the longer term. 

&amp;gt;We need to know more about the population being referred and outcomes. There has not been routine and consistent data collection, which means it is not possible to accurately track the outcomes and pathways that children and young people take through the service.  

&amp;gt;There is lack of consensus and open discussion about the nature of gender dysphoria and therefore about the appropriate clinical response. 

&amp;gt;Because the specialist service has evolved rapidly and organically in response to demand, the clinical approach and overall service design has not been subjected to some of the normal quality controls that are typically applied when new or innovative treatments are introduced.   

Finland and Sweden have likewise changed their guidelines on how to treat gender dysphoria in children.  The Swedish National Board of Health and Welfare has released a [new set of guidelines](https://www.socialstyrelsen.se/globalassets/sharepoint-dokument/artikelkatalog/kunskapsstod/2022-3-7799.pdf):

&amp;gt;For adolescents with gender incongruence, the NBHW deems that
the risks of puberty suppressing treatment with GnRH-analogues
and gender-affirming hormonal treatment currently outweigh the
possible benefits, and that the treatments should be offered only in
exceptional cases. This judgement is based mainly on three factors:
the continued lack of reliable scientific evidence concerning the
efficacy and the safety of both treatments [2], the new knowledge
that detransition occurs among young adults [3], and the uncertainty that follows from the yet unexplained increase in the number
of care seekers, an increase particularly large among adolescents
registered as females at birth [4]

[Finland released a report with similar guidelines.](https://segm.org/sites/default/files/Finnish_Guidelines_2020_Minors_Unofficial%20Translation.pdf)  

Overall it seems to me that parts of Europe are moving more towards the *actual* Dutch protocol and becoming more cautious about providing medical interventions to gender non-conforming youth.  I have not seen any evidence that this shift might happen in America or Canada though.  Is America lagging behind Europe or is the affirmative care and informed consent model here to stay?  

Lastly, the reason this post came together today is because of a thread in the SeattleWA subreddit.   There are a few Seattle subreddits, SeattleWA is the more right-leaning.  It&#39;s still pretty left leaning, earlier this week there were people arguing against voting for an independent candidate in case they were a secret Republican.  (They were not, they are actually further left of the Democratic candidate.)  So it&#39;s &#34;right for Seattle&#34; which is still pretty left for much of America.  

Someone posted a link to a news article about a YMCA transwoman employee being harassed by an 80 year old woman who felt there shouldn&#39;t be a male helping little girls pull down their swimsuits to go potty.  The old woman was banned from the Y due to the incident.   I would expect the comments to be supportive of the trans employee and less supportive of the old lady.  However, that is not what happened.  [See here](https://archive.ph/bdp2r), but most people felt like they wouldn&#39;t want a transwoman helping their small daughters use the toilet.  

Other recent events like Lia Thomas&#39; infamy seems to indicate that people don&#39;t really mean &#34;Trans women are woman&#34; in all situations.  I&#39;m wondering if we&#39;ll see an ideological shift happen in America before we see a medical care model shift.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijvrw9p/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>