<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/orthoxerox - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-24T12:45:42Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/orthoxerox" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfxd76/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] What&#39;s the most right-wing quote from a work of fiction you can think of?

Mine </title><updated>2022-07-24T12:45:42Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">What&#39;s the most right-wing quote from a work of fiction you can think of?

Mine is from *No Country for Old Men*:

&amp;gt; &#34;Dope. They sell that shit to schoolkids.&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;It&#39;s worse than that.&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;How&#39;s that?&#34;
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &#34;Schoolkids buy it.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ihfxd76/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih0wtcs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] South China Morning Post [writes](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/articl</title><updated>2022-07-21T08:14:51Z</updated><author><name>orthoxerox</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">South China Morning Post [writes](https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3185140/chinas-court-ai-reaches-every-corner-justice-system-advising) that PRC has made legal AI a mandatory part of the judicial process. &#34;As required by the supreme court, a judge must consult AI on every case. If the judge rejects the machine’s recommendation, the machine demands a written explanation for records and auditing.&#34;

As I understand, Chinese judicial system is more similar to the Russian system: weak cases are dropped by the prosecution before the trial and the trial is more about the sentencing severity than the determination of guilt: the defense submits every extenuating circumstance, the prosecution submits every aggravating circumstance, the judge finds the person guilty and comes up with an appropriate sentence. If this is the case, then pattern-matching the punishment to similar cases from across the country might actually not be a bad band-aid, it will prevent judges from passing sentences that are too lenient or too harsh due to some bias.

For example, an AI like this could ensure that no implicit racial bias affects the sentencing. But there&#39;s always the risk the knobs of the AI can be fiddled with. What if, in the name of equity, the AI will insist on more lenient sentences if the person is BIPoC? Even if a principled judge keeps writing written explanations of why he agreed with Billy Bob&#39;s and Libby Mae&#39;s sentences, but increased Tyrone&#39;s and Shaneequa&#39;s, she or he will sooner or later be crucified in the media as a &#34;racist judge&#34;.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih0wtcs/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>