<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/pmmecutepones - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-21T13:49:14Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/pmmecutepones" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il6x8o7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **In which I lose faith in my rulers**

Singapore, formerly well-known in these </title><updated>2022-08-21T13:49:14Z</updated><author><name>pmmecutepones</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**In which I lose faith in my rulers**

Singapore, formerly well-known in these circles as [the poster child of NRx](https://i.would.put.a.neoreactionary.link.here/but_i_dont_know_if_reddit_will_ban_them), is about to [repeal its ban on gay sex](https://www.channelnewsasia.com/singapore/section-377a-repeal-law-sex-gay-men-marriage-constitution-pm-lee-ndr2022-2891381). This is not Singapore&#39;s first taste of modern progressivism -- we had the [Year of Celebrating Women](https://www.herworld.com/women/women-now/year-celebrating-sg-women-2021/), [Chinese Privilege](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/pecd0o/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_30_2021/hbjq403/), [anti-ableism](https://www.purpleparade.sg/), and trans people walking freely (I&#39;ve met them! Worked with them!) because the constitution never anticipated we&#39;d ever get this far.

There&#39;s, of course, no political outrage to speak of from what few conservatives exist here. Rear-guard movements like Wear White are pathetic, to put it politely: they&#39;re barely enough of a threat to justify news time, let alone actual outrage. The older generations are devoid of political agency, owing to the authoritarianism that ran pre-2000s Singapore, so that just leaves us with the youth. The ones who were raised to read and internalise the lessons of English-written cultural exports -- Rights, Equality, Change, and the whole nine miles. I (think I) linked polls to demonstrate this in my last post, but at this point I&#39;d rather not see what the numbers look like.

Each and every time the government made a step leftwards, I tried to justify it -- to &#34;cope&#34;, if you will. Anti-ableism -- obviously needed for national stability, considering where our age demographics are going. Feminism? Can&#39;t be due to foreign influence; it [hit the peak half a decade ago](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/the-rise-and-fall-of-online-culture), and they didn&#39;t crack then. Trans rights? _Well, they never [explicitly endorsed](https://youtu.be/2ZWoHU2Cfuw) it, so I&#39;m sure it&#39;ll be temporary._

Today, as I watch another cornerstone of conservatism fall, **I no longer cope**. I have no explanations, no rationalisation, no armchair _realpolitik_ perspective to sooth my rejection of what my nation is becoming.

No, I have nothing. I&#39;ve been abandoned by a Party I should&#39;ve never held hopes for.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il6x8o7/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>