<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/pmmecutepones - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T10:48:12Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/pmmecutepones" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilkt0k3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] As a short follow-up to my [wisdom teeth removal](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMo</title><updated>2022-08-24T10:48:12Z</updated><author><name>pmmecutepones</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">As a short follow-up to my [wisdom teeth removal](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vn8roc/wellness_wednesday_for_june_29_2022/ie60a3u/) post: got them removed. Awaiting future pain.

While I was there, I overhead a not-really private discussion between the nurses about the [removal of 377A](https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-62545577). Some of them defended the decision to protect the definition of marriage (&#34;the religious feel threatened&#34;), others decried the move as useless because of it. But overall, none of them were interested in actually defending 377A directly. 

I&#39;m reminded of this passage from [_Neutral vs. Conservative_](https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/05/01/neutral-vs-conservative-the-eternal-struggle/)

&amp;gt; In the hospital where I work, there’s a RESIST TRUMP poster on the bulletin board in our break room. I don’t know who put it there, but I know that anybody who demanded that it be taken down would be tarred as a troublemaker, and anyone who tried to put a SUPPORT TRUMP poster up next to it would be lectured about how politics are inappropriate at work. This is true even though I think at least a third of my colleagues are Trump supporters.

Why do I post this in the Wellness Wednesday thread? Well...

A few months back, I was really bummed out by observations like these. Like the Communist that seethes at perceived edifices to captialism all around him, I could not help but observe the prevailing attitude of mild cultural liberalism around me, and it brought me a significant amount of distress to think about my observations (which is to say, I upset myself daily). 

Today, I realise I&#39;m no longer upset by the observations I make, even though I still believe in the baseline conclusion that society is fundamentally biased. Above all else, I no longer despair, I no longer feel blackpilled, and I think this is because I plan to actually **do things** to change the world. An obvious lesson for the depressed among us: Make plans, get organised, and above all else -- try. The work of struggle, whether consequentially productive or not, will make you happier for the moment.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilkt0k3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>