<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/practical_romantic - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-06T07:20:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/practical_romantic.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week a</title><updated>2022-07-06T07:20:30Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww.html" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m able to get 2 hours of work done every other day and work out twice a week as the gym is 45 minutes away.

Not great progress but programming is quite fun although taxing. My aim for this week is to workout 3 days a week and work 4-6 hours daily while ensuring I get plenty of sleep at the right time.

It&#39;s genuinely bad but still honest progress and with achievable goals.

Here&#39;s also a text exchange between me and a friend of mine that describes an event which will be the last part of my post. 

So I met my classmate who got into IIT Kanpur today for breakfast
He was here with two other dudes from his uni, one was from CS and the other from materials.
My classmate and the CS dude hadn&#39;t taken a year off like I had and they went from being wierdo nerds who were prentious to well adjusted people who&#39;d indulge in hedonism and doing well in life.
Good to get periodical reminders like today.
I don&#39;t have any girls I text for now and will keep it that way.
You&#39;re right about time man.
I can have all the fun in the world but for now, back to work.

IIT Kanpur is the best uni in the country and is above the one I go to. Both these people have gotten selected by different grad schools (UIUC and CMU respectively) with a bare minium research profile since the recommendation of faculty there matters a lot. 

My point is that there&#39;s a time and place to have fun and there&#39;s a time and place to just study, my current situation is the latter. 

I was genuinely surprised when I was able to solve programming questions and got a sense of joy doing that so shall continue. Working out is a tad hectic and people mock me for even trying since I&#39;ve been doing it on and off for the past year but would go for a week and not go again for a month due to the pajeet exam schedule. 

Anyway, have a fun week ahead.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/if1ptbl/"/></entry></feed>