<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/practical_romantic - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-01T09:43:16Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/practical_romantic" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iarntb1/</id><title type="text">[WW] End of my hellish exam cycle, preparing for software jobs and research. plus phy</title><updated>2022-06-01T09:43:16Z</updated><author><name>practical_romantic</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">End of my hellish exam cycle, preparing for software jobs and research. plus physical culture.

My hellish exam cycle that began in August last year ends tomorrow. I have had somewhere from 50 to 60 exams in 240 days and tanked my cgpa from 8.5 to 7 and it&#39;ll likely dip below 7 (out of 10 that is). more on that later.

Software Dev jobs prep(placements) and Research.

I&#39;ll be free till August first week and will do algoexpert plus my research in NLP. Placements is the term used to describe the annual hiring season where firms visit big reputed unis (like mine) and conduct tests to hire final year students. So it last from August to December and is the sole reason why pajeets even go to cram schools. I will be using algoexpert to prepare for mine and after the 180 questions on it are through, I will switch to leetcode. I want to get a good paying job so that my purpose of uni is fulfilled. Ideally I woould want to get a remote one and then move to the west as India is a decaying country due to unfortunate circumstances.

The prof is in an IIT that&#39;s far away and the entire project is remote. I&#39;m a failure as a person at most levels so hope I can change now. I will finally get to work with a decent ML researcher and if this goes well, I will then get to work with an even better researcher. India sucks when it comes to research of any kind anywhere at all.

Physical Culture.

I finally now have two uninterrupted months with literally zero uni so will work out daily and hopefully try to join the local freestyle wrestling practise. I hope they take me in and I can do well, not get injured. I have wanted to work out for the longest amount of time but being really really really lazy and terrible with time management meant that I would simply end up not studying what was taught in my classes and have to skip gym sessions to study for my exams, not anymore thankfully.

I will also watch the new top gun in theatres and visit places in my city with my family.

**End of my hellish exam cycle.**

I hated every single second of it. My uni has this power couple that were the first PhD in the department and 18 of the 25 full time faculty here are their PhD students or rather who got a PhD from them. I know I&#39;ve not done well but mmthe syllabi here I genuinely outdated as most people are not smart enough to teach. 18 out of 25 is not a normal number given that India has significantly better research institutes.

Regardless, you cannot complain officially as then they&#39;d just fail me in exams. Regardless I&#39;m happy that it&#39;s over but sad that it happened. Going from 24 in 360 days to 60 in 240 is just fucking stupid and I&#39;ll forever hate my uni for it. I missed everything, extra curricular, research, friends, night outs, internships, girls, fucking everything over exams about subjects that are taught in the worst way. Most of not all of them are useless as the teachers would come to class after stealing slides from Stanford. They&#39;d skip over them and copy papers too. The entire point isn&#39;t to learn anything but to conduct exams and then bully kids as that&#39;s how they feel important.

This isn&#39;t just because I did poorly but also because my uni is beyond repair. A central university gig is highly prestigious and offers people lifetime benefits and numerous perks so everyone who&#39;s here exists just to milk it.

I&#39;m happy that my exams are over. I genuinely fucking hate everyone and everything. After years of cram school I got the same treatment again. College is supposed to be magical man, not be an exam fest where you literally learn nothing, absolutely nothing of use. I was in the 99.9xx percentile in the country and despite that this is the kinda trash I have to deal with.

Overall

What has happened has happened, I just am happy that I will finally have some time off. Wish me luck and please drop some other Software engineering job interview or test tips if you have any. Thanks and I am super grateful about life too, as fucked as my uni is (the faculty is too stupid to have passed the exams the undergrad did, this is a fact as Indian higher education has tremendous status decay so most masters or PhDs in tech are not worth the paper they are printed on PhD means that only the scums in tech get faculty jobs, humanities is infinitely better quality wise) I still have decent amount of prestige in society and will get a decent paying job. I have a good life that I fuck up due to my own laziness and I aim to fix that.

Will get my wisdom tooth removed, get finasteride prescription, get my acne scars treated and a bunch of personal grooming done. Cannot wait!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iarntb1/"/></entry></feed>