<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Primaprimaprima - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-15T13:27:49Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Primaprimaprima" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig9f6v6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Abortions and Vaccines: Why the Correlation?**

If you&#39;re in favor of legal ab</title><updated>2022-07-15T13:27:49Z</updated><author><name>Primaprimaprima</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Abortions and Vaccines: Why the Correlation?**

If you&#39;re in favor of legal abortion, you tend to be in favor of covid vaccines.  If you&#39;re against legal abortion, you tend to be against covid vaccines.  Why?  I don&#39;t know.  I&#39;m asking you.

I will use &#34;pro-abortion&#34; to refer to the position that abortion should be legal and &#34;anti-abortion&#34; to refer to the position that abortion should not be legal.  I will use &#34;pro-vaccine&#34; and &#34;anti-vaccine&#34; a little more vaguely, but hopefully not too vaguely.  &#34;Pro-vaccine&#34; will refer to a spectrum of pro-vaccine attitudes, from &#34;it&#39;s really important that everyone get vaccinated and boosted&#34; up to and including legal mandates requiring vaccines to enter public businesses, the workplace, etc.  &#34;Anti-vaccine&#34; is the negation of this position.

If you tend to be pro- one of these things, you tend to be pro- the other.  Likewise if you are anti- one of these things, you tend to be anti- the other.  I find this to be curious, since it&#39;s hard to find a single unifying moral principle that entails both positions.

Frequently, debates over both abortions and vaccines are cast in terms of bodily autonomy.  &#34;You can&#39;t (force me to get a vaccine || force me to carry a fetus I don&#39;t want) because it violates my bodily autonomy&#34;.  If this was actually the key underlying principle at stake, then you would expect that people who are persuaded by the argument from autonomy in one case would be persuaded by it in the other, and we would see a significant contingent of people lining up in support of the pro-abortion-anti-vaccine position.  But this actually turns out to be a relatively rare combination of positions.

Full disclosure: I am both pro-abortion and anti-vaccine, because I take the argument from autonomy seriously in both cases.  However, I also feel that abortion is a more ethically complicated issue than vaccine mandates, which fits with the general observation that there is some underlying shared assumption or psychological trait that tends to pull anti-vaccine people towards being anti-abortion, and vice versa.

I don&#39;t feel like I need to provide much evidence in support of the thesis that there is a correlation between the pro-abortion and pro-vaccine positions.  It&#39;s pretty obvious to me.  Check any leftist discussion forum or news source and see what they have to say about both abortions and covid vaccines.

The correlation between the anti-abortion and anti-vaccine positions may not be quite as obvious, but I&#39;m still confident it exists.  Consider, for example, that of the [seven states which brought a lawsuit](https://www.dispatch.com/story/news/politics/courts/2021/11/05/ohio-ag-sues-again-try-stopping-bidens-vaccine-mandate-osha-coronavirus-covid-19-white-house-yost/6301706001/) against OSHA&#39;s covid vaccine mandate (Ohio, Idaho, Kansas, Kentucky, Oklahoma, Tennessee and West Virginia), six of them (all but Kansas) are planning to [introduce significant abortion restrictions or outright bans](https://reproductiverights.org/maps/abortion-laws-by-state/) in the wake of the Roe decision.  I take this fact to be reflective of the general anti-abortion, anti-vaccine attitudes of the people who live in those states.

So.  Why do we observe a correlation between these particular positions?  Like I said at the outset, I don&#39;t know.  I&#39;m mainly just opening the floor for discussion.  I&#39;d like to get input from others here and hear what your ideas are.  However, I can briefly outline what *forms* a potential answer might take:

**Shared underlying moral principle** - perhaps I&#39;ve simply overlooked something, and there is in fact an underlying abstract principle that allows one to reason to both the anti-abortion and anti-vaccine position simultaneously, or vice versa.  I don&#39;t think it&#39;s going to be &#34;autonomy&#34;.  Even though everyone will acknowledge that autonomy is ultimately defeasible, and I acknowledge that someone could support a very strong principle of autonomy while also being anti-abortion and anti-vaccine (&#34;I support your right do you what you want, but the fetus is a person with moral worth, and you simply don&#39;t have the right to kill another person&#34;), I simply don&#39;t think that autonomy is actually what&#39;s at stake for most people, based on listening to public discourse.  This is particularly evident in the pro-abortion-pro-vaccine camp, where arguments from autonomy against covid vaccines are given essentially no weight at all.

One idea I&#39;ve been toying with is the idea of, not exactly an underlying formal principle, but the idea of an underlying &#34;aesthetic&#34; that could motivate the set of one&#39;s positions.  Perhaps rightists think that both abortions and covid vaccines represent the intrusion of the medical establishment into a natural, potentially even sacred domain that should instead be allowed to take its natural course, and it is opposition to this intrusion that motivates the anti-abortion-anti-vaccine position above all else.  Leftists could be motivated by an opposite impulse where they are fundamentally more sympathetic to humanity&#39;s attempts to control its own biology and environment through technological intervention.

**Shared underlying interest**: Of course, not all political beliefs are arrived at through abstract reasoning, or even adherence to deeper unconscious principles.  Sometimes they&#39;re simply opportunistic.  The type of person who supports abortion, for example, might see vaccine mandates as a convenient way to penalize the class of people who is unlikely to support their broader social agenda.  &#34;If you wouldn&#39;t get a vaccine then you&#39;re probably a shitty person anyway, and now your shittiness is recorded for all the world to see in your digital vaccine passport&#34;.

**Group psychology**: Maybe people on the right are anti-abortion-anti-vaccine because That&#39;s Just What People On The Right Do, and vice versa.  On this model of political psychology, people join a team, they see what their team believes, and then they go believe that.  I think there&#39;s *something* to this idea, but I certainly don&#39;t think it can tell the full story.  There are too many observable patterns in how people think and reason, and it&#39;s not plausible to think that all political reasoning is nothing more than a meaningless epiphenomenon of group identity.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig9f6v6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>