<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Primaprimaprima - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-05T22:03:21Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Primaprimaprima.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezyfh8/</id><title type="text">[CW] **On The Concept of Male Entitlement**

As an example to get the ball rolling: [</title><updated>2022-07-05T22:03:21Z</updated><author><name>Primaprimaprima</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**On The Concept of Male Entitlement**

As an example to get the ball rolling: [Feminism and the Question of Theory](https://ravenmagazine.org/magazine/feminist-critical-consciousness-and-the-question-of-theory/)

&amp;gt;The men who engage in sexual assault are not, as the narrative goes, hapless victims of changing sexual mores. They are, at worst, pretending they don’t know that what they are doing is wrong; or, what is almost as bad, they are utterly clueless: they are unable or unwilling to listen to women because their own sense of entitlement drowns out everything else.

The concept of &#34;entitlement&#34; is frequently used in feminist discourse to explain male sexual behavior, particularly in cases of rape and sexual assault.  I am skeptical of this concept and its explanatory power, and I&#39;ll attempt to outline why.

My own personal theory is that male sexual behavior, good and bad, is largely explained by the fact that men simply desire to engage in the sexual acts that they carry out, in the same way that the fact that people eat food is largely explained by the fact that people get hungry and food tastes good.  My intention in this post is not to defend the desire theory though - it&#39;s just to critique the entitlement theory.

Actually, I&#39;m skeptical that the idea of &#34;acting out of a sense of entitlement&#34; is even coherent.  Entitlement seems to me, first and foremost, to be an objective relation that obtains between you and something else, not a psychological attitude that you take towards something else.  To be entitled to X is to be in a legal or social relation with X that grants you control over or access to X.  Your attitudes and motivations don&#39;t enter into the picture.  

Indeed, when I try to imagine thought experiments where I or someone else is primarily motivated to act by a &#34;sense of entitlement&#34;, I&#39;m not sure if I can do it.  It always seems more appropriate to use other concepts to explain the motivations instead - raw desire, or protecting one&#39;s wounded pride, or maintaining the coherence of one&#39;s self-image, or any number of things.  But it&#39;s hard to think of a scenario where &#34;entitlement&#34; seems like an appropriate psychological concept to explain someone&#39;s motivations.  Ultimately, it seems that it&#39;s just a sneer-like word, too pre-loaded with moral judgment to be explanatorily useful.

It seems more plausible to defend the idea that someone could act out of a *mistaken belief* that they are entitled to something, rather than acting out of raw entitlement itself.  These sorts of scenarios are much easier to imagine.  But is this what men actually do?  I think not.  What man actually believes that he&#39;s entitled to sexual access to women in today&#39;s Western society?  I&#39;ve seen no evidence that any sizable number of men actually believe this, but I&#39;ve seen plenty of evidence to the contrary.

Consider the discourse that circulates in &#34;manosphere&#34;, &#34;The Red Pill&#34;, and &#34;pick-up artist&#34; forums.  I don&#39;t know how you can walk away with any belief other than that these men are *acutely* aware that they are *not* entitled to sexual access to women in any way.  They become completely obsessed with the idea of self-improvement, because the only alternative in their view is dying bitter and alone.  Every day is a constant Darwinian struggle against other men for access to extremely scarce reproductive resources.  Even if they are able to secure a long-term relationship or even marriage with a woman, they are never allowed a moment&#39;s rest.  They constantly have to be on top of their game, always striving to assert dominance, otherwise their woman will leave them for Chad Thundercock at the drop of a hat.  How could anyone think that this paints a psychological portrait of an entitled individual?

Given the flaws with the entitlement theory, why are feminists so attracted to it?  I have two hypotheses:

One is a simple failure of imagination on the part of women.  In the female experience, there is no analogue of male sexual desire.  (Probably there are many feminists who reject the idea that men and women experience sexual desire differently at all).  Women have a hard time believing that men could really just want sex *that fucking much*, to the point that it drives men to do the sorts of insane and violent things that men are known for.

The second is that feminism demands a theory of male sexual desire that renders it socially mutable.  If men do what they do because of biological drives, then that means we just have to live with it, which is horrifying.  But if men do what they do because they&#39;ve been instilled with a false sense of entitlement, then we can just educate them on the appropriate way to have relations with women and everything will be fine.  So the thinking goes.  I make no judgments here - I&#39;m just outlining my thinking on why feminism is structurally predisposed to adopt certain theories over others.

Of course, I don&#39;t think that male sexual behavior *entirely* reduces to basic biological desires.  Certainly sexual behavior can be rooted in other motives as well, like social validation.  But I&#39;m skeptical that entitlement has a role to play in the overall picture.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezyfh8/"/></entry></feed>