<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/puntifex - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-31T16:31:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/puntifex" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imjh3kz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I am kinda surprised that we haven&#39;t done the Duke/BYU volleyball yet.

A few da</title><updated>2022-08-31T16:31:29Z</updated><author><name>puntifex</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I am kinda surprised that we haven&#39;t done the Duke/BYU volleyball yet.

A few days ago, the Duke volleyball played a game at BYU.  The game was overshadowed by allegations of ugly racism when Duke&#39;s black starter, Rachel Richardson (I think there are several black women on the team, but only she is a starter) said that she heard someone racially abuse her throughout the match.  The player&#39;s ~~grandmother~~ godmother also took to twitter to say that the player was called the n-word &#34;every time she served&#34;.

This story hit the national papers with the predictable headlines - strong denunciation against racism, praise for Rachel as a strong person standing up to adversity, denunciation of coaches and officials, athleticndepartments, the crowd at the game, and all Mormons.

BYU&#39;s AD apologized profusely, and the school indefinitely banned a fan identified by Duke as the racist abuser. Rachel herself appeared on several national news stories, with the expected taking points and responses. 

A few days later, though, people stated asking questions.  Several students who were at the game came forward on the record to say that the racial slurs nevered happened.  Officials reviewed video of the crowd from the game, including when people claimed slurs were used - and AFAIK they&#39;ve found... nothing. 

There are other questions.  People started wondering why her teammates - whom one assumes both at least kinda like her (she certainly hasn&#39;t denounced any of her teammates as evil racists) , and, being 20 year old female athletes at an elite US institution are probably among the wokest people on the whole planet - haven&#39;t said anything,  as far as I&#39;ve seen?

Disclaimer - it&#39;s not like I&#39;ve done extensive research.  But I&#39;ve deen no articles writing anyone other than her or her family.   The Duke captain has an instagram that was updated two weeks ago - nothing.  All the quotes are from Richardson or her immediate family. 

And by the way - that ~~grandmother~~ godmother?  She happens to be a politician running for some office. 

I guess it would be hard for this story to be more unbelievable than the Duke lacrosse case (where the prosecutor was literally explicitly trying to frame some innocent kids of the right demographic, and was later disbarred),  and that was ~10 years ago, so I guess I shouldn&#39;t be surprised.

Edit - someone asked for links.  Disclaimer - I have a day job.  I am not claiming to be an expert or to have done extensive research as honestly, is not worth it.  But I am being honest in saying what I haven&#39;t seen.  If someone can post links that credibly contradict what I said (for examples, her teammates reacting strongly on the night of the event), I will gladly reconsider.  It&#39;s also hard to prove a negative,  and I&#39;m certainly not going to trawl through 30 college students&#39; instagrams.  All my links were from google or twitter, so nothing hard to find.

Duke volleyball captains instagrams are easily google-able, so I&#39;m not linking them.

The original face-value sucks are also very easy to find (abc, espn, usatoday, etc etc etc)

Here are some links calling the account into question

https://www.sltrib.com/sports/2022/08/30/fan-who-was-banned-by-byu-does/

I&#39;d *really* rather not link turtleboy sports given their culrure war angle but if nobody else is gonna cover it (and tweets are now deleted), whatcha gonna do?

https://tbdailynews.com/video-shows-that-duke-volleyball-player-and-her-politician-godmother-are-lying-about-being-called-n-word-during-byu-game/</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imjh3kz/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>