<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/PutAHelmetOn - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T17:57:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/PutAHelmetOn" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The </title><updated>2022-08-01T17:57:40Z</updated><author><name>PutAHelmetOn</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Is gender identity like a [fursona](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fursona)? The comparison isn&#39;t motivated by &#34;haha look at how ridiculous these people are,&#34; it&#39;s specifically around reframing the following:

&amp;gt;Everyone has a gender identity, but most people are [cis by default](https://thingofthings.wordpress.com/2015/01/28/cis-by-default/)

To something more like:

&amp;gt;The genderqueer community is comprised of people who have gender identities, which may involve wearing clothing of their preferred gender... A small minority of them express a desire to become, or already see themselves as, their gender

Since I&#39;ve just committed analogy in the first degree, I expect the low-decouplers to be out in full force, so here are a few objections I foresee:

Possible counter: &#34;Well, most people don&#39;t have a fursona but most people do have a gender identity&#34;. Reply: I think both parts (before &amp;amp; after the &#39;but&#39;) are potentially wrong:

* Don&#39;t most people have a &#34;human by default&#34; fursona?
* Do most people *actually* have a gender identity?

To expand on (2): the language around gender identity is maximally confusing. 

As an example, I posed the question &#34;do you have a gender identity? what is it?&#34; to my dad and he said &#34;of course I&#39;m a male.&#34; despite not knowing what LGBTQ activists really think about gender identity. If two people say &#34;my gender identity is man&#34; that **does not mean they are really saying the same thing.** A less confusing language would be to call gender identity a &#34;fnord&#34; and then my dad would realize that he has no idea what a &#34;fnord&#34; is, just that it is something controversial.

Possible counter: &#34;this is not how people use the words &#39;fursona&#39; and &#39;gender identity&#39;&#34; to which I reply: this is missing the point. I am engaging in prescriptivism here, and I&#39;m claiming that speaking as if normal people have gender identity \[the way activists mean it\] is misleading. That activists enthusiastically say it&#39;s OK that gender identity means different things to different people makes me think this confusing language is intentional.

How should I react to a furry telling me my fursona was a human? I would probably tell him I&#39;m not a furry, sorry, not for me, but good for you. Should my reaction to activists asking me about my gender identity be any different? &#34;Sorry, not for me.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iijankv/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>