<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/QuantumFreakonomics - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-03T02:41:13Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/QuantumFreakonomics" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iazpa56/</id><title type="text">[CW] The long-awaited verdict in the Johnny Depp - Amber Heard defamation trial is in</title><updated>2022-06-03T02:41:13Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The long-awaited verdict in the Johnny Depp - Amber Heard defamation trial is in. Depp nets [8.3 million dollars](https://www.cnn.com/2022/06/01/entertainment/johnny-depp-amber-heard-verdict/index.html) in the final verdict.

Here are the 3 statements from Amber Heard&#39;s [2018 Washington Post op-ed](https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/ive-seen-how-institutions-protect-men-accused-of-abuse-heres-what-we-can-do/2018/12/18/71fd876a-02ed-11e9-b5df-5d3874f1ac36_story.html) found to be defamatory:

* *&#34;I spoke up against sexual violence – and faced our culture&#39;s wrath. That has to change.&#34;*

* *“Then two years ago, I became a public figure representing domestic abuse, and I felt the full force of our culture’s wrath for women who speak out.”* (for context, [Heard first accused Depp of domestic violence in 2016](https://www.usatoday.com/story/life/people/2016/05/27/amber-heard-files-restraining-order-against-johnny-depp/85037132/))

* *“I had the rare vantage point of seeing, in real time, how institutions protect men accused of abuse.”*

Notice anything peculiar about these statements? They&#39;re all true. In fact, they&#39;re true even if Johnny Depp never abused Amber Heard at all. She did in fact &#34;speak out&#34; against sexual violence; she accused Depp of abuse in a court of law and got a restraining order. She was in fact a [&#34;public figure representing domestic abuse&#34;](https://www.tmz.com/2016/05/27/amber-heard-domestic-violence-johnny-depp-restraining-order/); there were tabloids with her [bruised face plastered on the cover.](https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/719QfQuWVSL.jpg) She did in fact &#34;see how institutions protect men accused of abuse&#34;; Depp wasn&#39;t removed from the Fantastic Beasts series until [2020](https://variety.com/2020/film/news/johnny-depp-exhits-fantastic-beasts-franchise-1234824564/). Its as if the op-ed was written by a lawyer specifically to avoid making any false claims that could be considered defamatory if the allegations against Depp don&#39;t hold up, (probably because [it was](https://www.abajournal.com/news/article/aclu-lawyers-reviewed-op-ed-that-led-to-johnny-depp-defamation-claim-its-gc-testifies)). Its fascinating then that a judge let this case go to trial and a jury found Heard liable. 

A lot of this comes down to just how terribly Amber Heard came off on the stand. Frankly I would have expected a professional actress to do better. She lied about things like donating her divorce settlement to charity and leaking info to TMZ that don&#39;t actually matter much to the material facts of the case, but do make her seem like a pathological liar. I think the lesson to be learned from all this is that in the legal system, it matters a great deal how much the general public hates you. Precedent can not be relied upon across large changes in public opinion. You best start believing in kangaroo courts, [you&#39;re in one.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4iOGeCLpAY0)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iazpa56/"/></entry></feed>