<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/QuantumFreakonomics - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T13:52:37Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/QuantumFreakonomics" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] 
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble match</title><updated>2022-07-13T13:52:37Z</updated><author><name>QuantumFreakonomics</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">
Thanks to the wonders of the Poisson distribution I actually had 2 Bumble matches message me in the last week, despite typically getting less than one a month. I’ve been incelposting a bit more than usual lately, so maybe writing this up will provide some context for my point of view as well as allowing  others to offer perspective and point out errors in places where I may be blind.

Match number 1 was a thin blonde who opened with “How are you doing handsome?” Yellow flag. That is not something that women say to me, especially not as an opening. I’m not grotesque or repulsive(I don’t think), but I’m certainly not “handsome”, otherwise I wouldn’t be a mid 20s kv. As we continue chatting it immediately becomes clear that this person is both horny and forward with said horniness to an extent that I find very suspicious. This isn’t how I’ve known girls to act, but she doesn’t talk like a scammer or bot and her pictures seem real. It’s a work day so I try to stall until the weekend with some playful flirting. At some point she drops “I’m male but very feminine”. Mystery solved. I don’t see a “report as wrong sex” button on the app, so I just unmatch and move on. 

Match number 2 was more what I would consider “my type”. She’s a good bit overweight but has a cute face. She’s from the exurbs not the suburbs, has no visible tattoos or piercings, and overall seems to have a more conservative view of gender roles than the median woman on these apps. She sends me a “heyy” and I say hey back. No response. A few days later, after the debacle with match number 1 has played out, I admit I get desperate. I ask me friends if she’s out of my league, just to check if I’m being delusional. I get a “definitely not, go for it”. She has her Snapchat name on her Bumble profile, so I add her. We start texting on Snap. She replies very slowly, sometimes not at all, but there are a few moments where it feels like things are going well and there might be something there. 

I’ve had dating apps since my first year of college, but for most of that time I never really used them. This is the furthest I’ve ever gotten with a woman from these apps, and the furthest I’ve gotten with a woman since my not-really-a-gf gf in 8th grade that never got past holding hands. In the long breaks waiting for her replies, I notice my mental state deteriorating. It’s all I can really think about. I’ve never met her in person, but for the first time since early college I have a plausible path towards getting a girlfriend (or at least some kind of intimacy). I haven’t gotten the same butterflies when someone texts me since high school. I start checking my phone obsessively even though I have notifications on. When she leaves me on read I start to panic. I keep texting her. She never says stop, but I’m not a complete moron. I know what the most likely outcome is. At this point I almost want it just to have my sanity back. Finally she blocks me. I hate myself, but I’m free. No more obsession. It’s over. 

After writing this all out I am reminded of Scott Aaronson wanting to chemically castrate himself over fears he might harm a woman if he did not. I am not and have never considered going that far, but I do have to ask the question: Is it ethical for me to continue looking for a partner? Every woman who has ever swiped right on me either wishes she hadn’t or is indifferent. 

I’m 6’3 and make 70k a year if that’s relevant. Something is wrong with me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/ifzpff2/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>