<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/QuarkweightGOAT - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-25T00:20:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/QuarkweightGOAT" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ihiks18/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wedne</title><updated>2022-07-25T00:20:47Z</updated><author><name>QuarkweightGOAT</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/)

Week 4/60 is behind me. Easily the most difficult week. A lot of fatigue, cravings, low mood, etc. Still feeling that right now even though I would have been overjoyed to be in this position at my fattest.  

As I had planned, I fasted the first two days of the week and then final four days as well with Wednesday off. Feeling very lethargic but fortunately I am all done with trying to lose fat. Going to bed hungry tonight but I get to eat tomorrow. No alcohol and I finished the last pack in my carton of cigarettes yesterday. Won&#39;t be buying more. I started doing calisthenics this week to get an early start on delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS) which results from beginning a new exercise regimen particularly rigorous resistance training. 

I lost less than I expected this week given that I fasted for 6 days total. I guess my body revolted and slowed my metabolism way down. Or maybe a touch of dysmorphia. Have a bit of fat left around my lower stomach and lower back but it&#39;s not a lot. I didn&#39;t weigh myself throughout the 4 weeks of fasting. If I had to guess, after I get some food in me and muscle glycogen is restored,  I weigh around how much I weighed when I ran cross country in high school (145ish) at 6&#39;1. I got up to a little over 230 because of the medication situation I briefly mentioned I think in my first post. Will post before and after pictures next week. 

Will do calisthenics for the first half of the week and get a gym membership late next week. Going to use an online total daily energy expenditure (TDEE) calculator and probably subtract a couple hundred calories since my metabolism probably needs time to bounce back. 

Will provide a more detailed account of my plan going forward next week. Thank you.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w3f00s/wellness_wednesday_for_july_20_2022/ihiks18/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>