<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/QuarkweightGOAT - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-18T06:14:39Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/QuarkweightGOAT" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] [Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wedne</title><updated>2022-07-18T06:14:39Z</updated><author><name>QuarkweightGOAT</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">[Following up.](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifofoo2/)

Week 3/60 is now behind me.

I fasted Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday and most of Saturday. 

Unfortunately, I had a drinking lapse. Either Thursday or Friday I justified to myself, in usual alcoholic fashion, to drink “just one last time.” The plan was to grab a “mickey” of rum (contains 8 standard drinks) for my last eating day of the week (Sunday) and factor that into total calories. I grabbed it on Saturday since liquor stores open late on Sundays which would prevent me from beginning to drink right away on the Sunday (yes, I know). Couldn’t resist the urge to have a few drinks that same day and ended up drinking the whole thing. Was very surprised by the effect. Tolerance went way down partly because I didn’t drink for a few weeks but also the fasting did a number. I grabbed another mickey earlier today. I finished drinking around 2pm EDT so pretty much sober now. I know I said I would abstain throughout this at the outset but am more committed to doing that now than before. I have derailed myself many times through drinking and won&#39;t do it for this. I will abstain 100% until the end of the 60 weeks. Words are cheap and I can&#39;t time travel but am confident in my ability to stay sober while I finish this transformation at the minimum.

Positive news. I continue to lose fat at a rapid rate. As mentioned last week, I am increasingly noticing loose skin around lower stomach in certain light. Hard to make a firm distinction between between stretch marks and sagging skin. Remaining fat around stomach also feels squishier than usual - do not know if this is a function of the density of adipose tissue itself or a loose skin issue. I unexpectedly caught the least flattering view possible of aforementioned skin a couple of days ago and was pleasantly surprised by how unbothered I was by its unsightliness.  Must say that I did not at all expect it to look that bad since I hardly notice it in most other settings yet I felt mostly indifferent. I was fixated on this concern previously because the bulk of my considerable weight gain went to my torso, the appearance of stretch marks,rapidity of weight gain, and the fact that I have an unusually slender build. 

After this leaning out phase is done I think I am going to see what can be done over the remainder of the 60 weeks about loose skin and be satisfied with the effort regardless of result. I initially undertook fasting specifically to address this concern but not sure if it helped at all. I am pretty confident in stating that it didn&#39;t hurt despite rapid fat loss. Conventional wisdom is that slow weight loss mitigates loose skin but that’s based on little more than intuition. Logic of fasting was autophagy and the body relying on excess skin as a protein source. Still mostly conjecture but whatever. Anyway, not to bothered by it so far. Maybe it will bug me more once I lose a bit more fat. We’ll see. 
Will likely apply some or all of the following measures which are purported to help with loose skin pending more research: topical vitamin c, hyaluronic acid, dry brushing, high fluid intake, moisturizing, microneedling, collagen supplementation, and of course resistance training to maybe help fill in volume. Time seems to be the most important factor but also important to temper expectations. 

Final week of fasting lies ahead. I will fast Monday, Tuesday, eat maintenance on Wednesday, and then fast for the remaining 4 days of the week. Will slowly work to maintenance the following week. I will post pictures in 2 weeks after I have eaten roughly at maintenance am a few days removed from a calorie-deprived, depleted physical state. 

Will provide update next week. Thanks.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vxw6lz/wellness_wednesday_for_july_13_2022/igm16xj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>