<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/QuinoaHawkDude - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-30T00:18:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/QuinoaHawkDude" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imbozoj/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m not sure this question is small-scale...well, the question is, since I&#39;m not</title><updated>2022-08-30T00:18:30Z</updated><author><name>QuinoaHawkDude</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not sure this question is small-scale...well, the question is, since I&#39;m not willing to put a lot of effort into asking the question.  The scale of the answer(s) might be pretty expansive.

Why does the Left hate Ronald Reagan so damn much?

Or, more specifically, what did Reagan do, exactly, to earn so much opprobrium from progressives?

I see it all the time online, people who are on the left/progressive side of politics casually dropping a &#34;Reagan started the destruction of the American middle class&#34; into a conversation with no explanation or context.

I was was born in the late 70&#39;s so I don&#39;t have any memory of what times were like before the Reagan Era.  I&#39;d ask my parents, but their perspectives are probably skewed by the fact that they were only just growing up and starting their adult lives before 1980, plus they came from pretty poor backgrounds and bootstrapped their way into the upper-middle-class by way of being smart (smart enough to work in computer programming in my dad&#39;s case, and smart enough to marry a computer programmer and get the hell away from her white trash family in my mom&#39;s case).  My grandparents are dead so I can&#39;t ask them.

That caveat aside, an admittedly naive reading of American history from the end of WW2 through today seems like: 1950s, we&#39;re doing great, mostly because we&#39;re the only major power that didn&#39;t get bombed to smithereens during the war; 1960s still okay but slowing down, Vietnam is a real drag and blow to our egos; 1970&#39;s things start looking genuinely crappy, the oil crisis, inflation, urban decay, crime waves, etc.  Lots of people around the world genuinely thinking that the USSR might be the better place to live.  Then Reagan comes along in the 1980s and America gets its groove back, and within ten years the Berlin wall is falling and the Soviet Union is collapsing and living standards are getting way better.

I&#39;m not naive enough to think that everything good that happened between 1980 and 1988 was because of Reagan, but this general story is more or less accepted among cultural conservatives of what I guess I&#39;ll call the &#34;Tom Clancy set&#34;.

The main knocks on Reagan (in terms of actual economic policy, ignoring things like D.A.R.E and his handling of the AIDS crisis and the Iran-Contra affair) I&#39;m vaguely aware of are:  


1. Tax cuts on the top margin, the so-called &#34;trickle-down economics&#34;.
2. Certain anti-union actions, e.g. the air traffic controllers

That&#39;s it.  So, the economic left&#39;s sacred cows are high taxes on the rich and unions?  I guess it wasn&#39;t that hard to answer my own question.  But is there more to it than that?  How has this &#34;destroyed the American middle class&#34;?  My mom&#39;s aforementioned relatives are all solidly middle class (none of them went to college and they work retail or manual labor jobs) and they all, in 2022, live in decent houses with newish cars and wear name-brand clothing and get to go out to dinner multiple times a year.  They wouldn&#39;t have been doing that in the 1970s!  Not working the same kinds of jobs they do now.  What am I missing?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/imbozoj/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>