<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/RadicalizeMeCaptain - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-29T21:30:57Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/RadicalizeMeCaptain" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ii6itww/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I can&#39;t draw. I never learned to draw because the act of drawing is not fun for </title><updated>2022-07-29T21:30:57Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I can&#39;t draw. I never learned to draw because the act of drawing is not fun for me. It&#39;s just stressful. I do often wonder if I could git gud if I applied myself, though, because then I could make my own comics.

Is there research on this? If someone is moderately intelligent, does it necessarily follow that they can learn to create images on paper? I&#39;m not asking for the usual &#34;practice makes perfect&#34; folk wisdom, I&#39;m just asking how true it is in regards to this specific skill.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w6otlm/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_24_2022/ii6itww/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0uqkg/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Kamala Harris recently did an event where, after disclosing their name and prono</title><updated>2022-07-28T18:31:08Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Kamala Harris recently did an event where, after disclosing their name and pronouns, [people announced what they were wearing](https://twitter.com/greg_price11/status/1551986134535884800). This boggles my mind. The only explanation I can think of is that they&#39;re trying to be sensitive to the visually impaired, but even that makes no sense. A person who was born blind has no idea what color is and will never be able to comprehend it. A person who lost their vision later in life probably wouldn&#39;t care what anyone at the table looks like, because they&#39;re there to exchange ideas. Moreover, if the goal is to tell people what you look like, then why focus on clothing? Do the people responsible for this custom have such limited visual imagination that they think a person&#39;s appearance can be compressed down to a handful of assumptions based on gender and color of clothing? (Come to think of it, that sounds like [Corporate Memphis](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporate_Memphis). Maybe there&#39;s a connection there)

Any explanation or steelman would be appreciated.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0uqkg/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>