<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/RadicalizeMeCaptain - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-18T11:22:10Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/RadicalizeMeCaptain" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iks5awc/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] What is empathy? Does it exist? Are there multiple types? Is it several differen</title><updated>2022-08-18T11:22:10Z</updated><author><name>RadicalizeMeCaptain</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">What is empathy? Does it exist? Are there multiple types? Is it several different concepts that are conflated? Can people have different amounts of empathy? Can empathy be turned off on purpose? These are but a small sampling of the questions I&#39;ve asked myself, and I don&#39;t have answers. I don&#39;t know what empathy is, but I know 1. I have less of it than most people do, if I even have it at all and 2. a lot of people have empathy only when it&#39;s convenient. I waffle on whether people in my outgroup/people whose outgroup includes me are particularly unempathetic, or whether my cognitive bias just makes me think that they are.

I&#39;ve tried to understand this concept of empathy not because I think it&#39;s important to understand, but because the word &#34;empathy&#34; gets tossed around a lot and I&#39;d like to know how to interpret it. Maybe it&#39;s one of those words like &#34;racism&#34; or &#34;woke&#34; that has no precise definition and is, at best, a direction.

As a rule, I don&#39;t like seeing people suffer. However, when someone is suffering, I cannot say I feel their pain, because I&#39;m not them. I only know what it&#39;s like to be me and have the particular experiences that I&#39;ve had. The closest I can get to putting myself in the place of another person is thinking back to an experience I&#39;ve had that made me feel a certain way and acting as though that&#39;s exactly how my interlocutor feels. That&#39;s not empathy, but an approximation. The way people describe empathy makes it sound like a superpower, like mind reading. But people often act as though they can read minds (hence the concept of dog whistles), so maybe this is all one big LARP too?

I was lurking on r/ThePurplePill and I saw [this comment ](https://www.reddit.com/r/PurplePillDebate/comments/wr2ls0/people_need_to_stop_saying_men_are_lonely_because/ikrjnql?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share&amp;amp;context=3) that approximates my feelings on humanity and the phony concept of empathy.

Sorry if this comes off as rambly. Basically, I&#39;m asking for a &#34;CMV: empathy isn&#39;t real&#34; or &#34;ELI5: What is empathy?&#34; I&#39;m not going to those subs, though, because I trust The Motte more than either of them. (Huh, I sound kinda close-minded when I put it like that.)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iks5awc/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>