<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/rokosbasilica - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T02:43:31Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/rokosbasilica" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqxcae/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Biden gave [a speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wygovCnX8Uw) tonight.  The</title><updated>2022-09-02T02:43:31Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Biden gave [a speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wygovCnX8Uw) tonight.  There was some [interesting imagery](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Fbnb-x5XwAA1LB2?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=medium) from it, although I&#39;m not really a fan of these sorts of photos.  Also somewhat hilariously CNN tried [edit the hue of the stream](https://twitter.com/MiaCathell/status/1565533698795208704) in the middle of the speech, apparently to make it look less sinister.

My thoughts on the speech: I like the *surface version* of some parts of what biden is saying here.  Or maybe a better way to say that is: I like the character he is pretending to play.

Where this goes off the rails for me is: he&#39;s basically saying that almost half of the country is a threat to not just his power, but to democracy *itself*.  He goes on and on about how incredible our nation is (something I agree with), how important our ideals of democracy and free speech are (something I also agree with), but then goes on to say that &#34;MAGA&#34; is a threat to all of this.  Of course this is probably a performance for his followers, and of course this likely isn&#39;t going to move anybody in the direction of supporting him.  Maybe this will rile up his base?

My frustration with everything is: where does this supposedly lead?  If Biden loses power in November, and is removed from office either on or before january 2025, will he &#34;go peacefully&#34;?  Will there be riots?  Will more cities burn?  What happens when he loses an election in 2024?  I certainly don&#39;t think any of his followers will simply accept it and congratulate Trump or Desantis or anybody else.

My other frustration is: what biden is pretending to say here is actually really important.  We actually, truly, need somebody to unite the nation.  Here is what I wish he would do, and think this would make him go down as one of the best presidents in our nations history:

* Blanket pardon for anybody involved in January 6th

* Blanket pardon for anybody involved in summer 2020 rioting

* Blanket pardon for Donald Trump, his family, and anybody related to his campaign WRT anything tax or document related, or anything else that the democratic machine has been running for the last 5 years.

* Support a &#34;MAGA republican&#34; led committee to spend as much time as they want chasing down every conspiracy theory related to election fraud that they want, and encourage the courts to cooperate.  Televise it.

If Biden did this, it would take most of the wind out of the sails of these MAGA republicans, and it would solidify his win in 2024.  The thing fueling those MAGA republicans *is* them feeling like they have absolutely no voice in government right now, and seeing a president that they feel is invalid get in front of a scary red brick background and give an angry speech about how they aren&#39;t really valid as Americans certainly doesn&#39;t make them feel any better.

Just saying: &#34;okay, I&#39;ll listen to you.&#34; would go a long, long, long way to reestablishing some trust *and* I think it would give him what he wants.

Unfortunately I doubt this will happen.  That scares me.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imqxcae/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>