<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/rokosbasilica - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-25T16:37:27Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/rokosbasilica" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub. </title><updated>2022-07-25T16:37:27Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There&#39;s a trend I&#39;ve noticed more on reddit lately, including here on this sub.  I thought I&#39;d share some thoughts on it.

There is a technique that old SysAdmins will recognize called tarpitting: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarpit_(networking)#SMTP_tarpits

The technique is to prevent spammers from being able to abuse a mail server (send too many messages) by simply wasting their time.  If the mail system detects something it believes is a spammer, it will simply make everything take a really long (relatively) time.

Instead of being able to send 1000 messages/second, it might limit you to one message ever 5 seconds (this is exaggerated).  The idea is that a normal user won&#39;t notice this, but a spammer trying to send thousands of messages will.  It&#39;s a very clever, and also effective strategy.  I like it.

There is something that I&#39;ve noticed especially on reddit, which feels like an evolution of Gish Galloping: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gish_gallop

The way it might go is that an uncharitable discussion partner will write long posts with very little substance in which they repeatedly ask the same questions, or sortof &#34;play dumb&#34; and ask for explanations for things which have been discussed *extensively* in the past.

I notice it here, but I notice it on other subreddits as well.  To put on a tinfoil hat for a short second: a lot of times the accounts which engage in this behavior seem to spend an almost *unbelievable* amount of time posting things on reddit, and often only on one subreddit.  So my tinfoil hat question is: are these really good GPT bots?  GPT-3 is *quite* good, and it seems within the realm of possibility that there are conversational-tarpitting bots that exist.

My question is: has anybody else noticed this behavior and charted it at all?  If so how do you identify it and what framework do you use for thinking about it?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihlhqm0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>