<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/rokosbasilica - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-18T18:14:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/rokosbasilica" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktra5n/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Sam Harris finally just says the quiet part out loud with respect to how it appe</title><updated>2022-08-18T18:14:04Z</updated><author><name>rokosbasilica</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Sam Harris finally just says the quiet part out loud with respect to how it appears a lot of democrats feel about Trump and the importance of the democratic process: https://twitter.com/JackPosobiec/status/1560257627237539845

&#34;It doesn&#39;t answer the people who say it&#39;s completely unfair to have not looked at the laptop in a timely way and to have shut down, you know, the NYpost&#39;s twitter account.  Like that&#39;s just a left wing conspiracy to deny the presidency to Donald Trump.  Absolutely it is, and I think it was warranted.&#34;

The podcast hosts press him on this, and he does admit that actually, yes, it is completely fine to suspend the idea of democracy simply to prevent Trump from getting the presidency, because he believes that Trump is a big enough threat that this is warranted.  The comparison he makes is to an asteroid heading for earth that will destroy all life on this planet, and that in that case you would do *anything* to stop it.

I think to anybody who has been paying attention to politics for the last two years, and especially to anybody who has spent much time looking at the 2020 election, this sort of thing won&#39;t be surprising.  My question to people who are still of the mind that the left isn&#39;t pushing us towards a less democratic society is: do you agree with what Sam is saying here?  Like for instance: would it be okay to cheat, or to suspend democratic norms to prevent Trump from winning again?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/iktra5n/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>