<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Rov_Scam - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T19:20:09Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Rov_Scam" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitjna5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **A Few Takeaways from the Kansas Abortion Referendum**

Kansas holds a place in</title><updated>2022-08-03T19:20:09Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**A Few Takeaways from the Kansas Abortion Referendum**

Kansas holds a place in American discourse as the prototypical &#34;Red State&#34;; it a Democratic presidential candidate hasn&#39;t won the state since 1964, and a Democratic Senator hasn&#39;t represented the state since 1939. They have had Democratic governors (including the incumbent, Laura Kelly) but hey, nobody&#39;s perfect. More importantly, the state was the subject of the book &#34;What&#39;s the Matter with Kansas?&#34;—which was later turned in to a documentary film—which tried to explain why relatively poor rural people tended to vote &#34;against their interest&#34; for conservative Republican politicians. (I use scare quotes because I think it&#39;s rather presumptuous that someone decide someone else&#39;s interests for them, especially if they don&#39;t actually know that person and are relying on broad demographic information.) 

Of course, the truth is more complicated than that. I&#39;m friends with a couple who lived in the state for several years after they both got postdocs at Kansas State University, and their initial trepidation of moving to the prairie after living in one of the hippest parts of Pittsburgh for a decade turned into an unexpected adoration. While the people there were definitely Trump-supporting conservatives, there was none of the bitterness that one would see in Appalachia. My friends reckoned that this was because there was no deindustrialization that left people longing for a glorified past America; these were simply people whose families ranched cattle for generations and always made a decent living from it and had six kids and always voted Republican because they always voted Republican. It probably also didn&#39;t hurt that practically any farmer would let the husband hunt deer on their property, in contrast to Pennsylvania, where people pay good money for private hunting leases and most people are stuck with overcrowded public game lands and state parks. And the Democratic governor? My friends said that she won simply because her campaign focused on solving the state&#39;s budget crisis while GOP opponent Kris Kobach focused his campaign on illegal immigration. In a state with few immigrants period, let alone illegal ones. Apparently, Kobach had become a punchline within a few weeks of nomination, even among people who ended up voting for him.

Against this backdrop, the citizens of Kansas voted yesterday on an Amendment to the state&#39;s constitution that would remove limits on the legislature&#39;s ability to regulate abortion. The average observer who bought into the &#34;What&#39;s the Matter with Kansas?&#34; rhetoric assumed the measure would pass handily. Professional journalists and others who were actually paying attention saw the issue as a tossup. So when the measure failed, the surprising thing wasn&#39;t that it failed, but that it failed by a 20 point margin. It&#39;s as of yet unclear what such an outcome means, whether for the midterms or abortion politics generally, so here are my initial thoughts:

**1. This won&#39;t help Democrats in the midterms**

To be fair, it won&#39;t *hurt* them either, but I wouldn&#39;t expect a ton of pro-choice Republicans to start voting Democrat. The referendum focused on a single issue, but actual candidates have to deal with as many issues as are necessary. Additionally, now that abortion is primarily a state issue, I would expect that most GOP voters would prefer to have it addressed in state houses rather than Congress. This may also have an effect on the Kansas gubernatorial election. The race is currently a tossup, but Republican challenger Derek Schmidt was on record as supporting the measure and argued the losing position on behalf of the state in 2019. He did, however, temper his position by claiming that termination of nonviable pregnancies did not meet the definition of abortion under Kansas law and would thus not be affected by a constitutional change, though his opponents pointed out that any abortion legislation could define terms however lawmakers wanted. This is a moot point now, but it remains to be seen how Schmidt handles the issue going forward (my guess is that he says the people have spoken and moves on to other things) and whether this tips the scales in favor of Laura Kelly. But I&#39;m no expert in Kansas politics so this is all speculation.

**2. This may have a huge effect on Republican abortion rhetoric**

In recent years, it&#39;s been rare for any Republican running for office to say anything that could remotely be conceived as pro-choice, and the Republicans that did were almost all in New England or the Mid-Atlantic. A quick perusal this morning of comments on the Fox News website and r/conservative shows that the attitude in these places seems to be &#34;This is what we wanted—leave it up to the states, and let the people decide. The people of Kansas have spoken.&#34; While I agree that this is a reasonable position to take and I don&#39;t doubt the sincerity of those taking it, this isn&#39;t exactly what was advertised when it came to overturning *Roe*. Pro-life advocates in states like California didn&#39;t want to see *Roe* overturned out of abstract support for Mississippians&#39; right of self-determination; they wanted it overturned because they wanted people in Mississippi to stop killing babies and hoped that one day California would pass such legislation as well. Certainly, some Republicans in Congress have been advocating for some sort of national ban, despite the knowledge that such a ban would likely be opposed by a majority of voters overall. And while I haven&#39;t looked into it that closely, it would appear that very few Republicans at the state level have voted against trigger laws and other restrictions in states that have enacted them.

If the vote proves anything, it&#39;s that Republican opinion on abortion isn&#39;t as uniform as Republican politicians seem to have assumed. I don&#39;t expect a wave of pro-choice Republicans getting elected on a platform of expanding abortion access in states that have restricted it. I do, however, expect a lot of Republican politicians to ditch the anti-abortion rhetoric that they assumed was getting them votes. Sure, some will know that their base is heavily Evangelical and will have no good reason to stop, but for others who rely on a broader base and need to expand their support they may realize that the issue alienates as many as it attracts and will stop hammering on it. At the Federal level in particular, it may be more politically expedient to defer the issue to the states and leave it at that. At the very least, I would expect the constant barrage of pro-life rhetoric coming from the Right to ebb at least somewhat and no longer be at the point where every Republican running for office has to trot out his pro-life credentials.

**3. Expect more ballot measures**

Some states allow for direct ballot measures and a number are already scheduled, as one would expect. What&#39;s been left out of the conversation thus far is what happens in states that don&#39;t allow for direct ballot measures; some states require voter approval for constitutional amendments, but these measures have to be proposed by the legislature before they go to the ballot. If the national GOP shifts its rhetoric from &#34;Abortion is wrong and should be banned&#34; to &#34;Abortion is an issue that should be decided by the states&#34;, then state legislatures are going to be under pressure to actually allow the people to decide. Pro-life state legislators might not be vulnerable on their votes for abortion restrictions directly, but they may be vulnerable if they steadfastly refuse to submit the question to the people. Some may argue that it&#39;s impractical to turn every matter of state law into a constitutional issue and that elected bodies are the best way of enacting the will of the public, but this argument isn&#39;t particularly effective when it involves what was clearly a national constitutional issue for fifty years and is one of the most controversial issues of the past two generations. If one looks at the referenda most of these states have put on the ballot in the past, the vast majority of it is stuff that most voters wouldn&#39;t find particularly interesting or controversial. In Pennsylvania in particular, the legislature has a tendency to submit items for constitutional amendment as a means of passing a sort of &#34;Super Law&#34; that&#39;s really hard to get rid of.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iitjna5/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>