<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Rov_Scam - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-15T17:08:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Rov_Scam" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikelhsn/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Yesterday I watched a documentary about the Pruitt–Igoe housing project, *The Pr</title><updated>2022-08-15T17:08:29Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Yesterday I watched a documentary about the Pruitt–Igoe housing project, *The Pruitt–Igoe Myth*. For those who aren&#39;t familiar, here&#39;s a rundown: Prior to WWII, most urban poor (minorities in particular) lived in overcrowded tenement housing. This was privately-owned, market-rate housing, but conditions were considered substandard at the time and are unthinkable now. A lot of the apartments lacked windows or any kind of ventilation, most units had shared bathrooms, and some still relied on outhouses (in the city) into the 1950s. A lot of the stuff that would easily fail a code inspection now was par for the course. Conditions were crowded to the point that, as one woman recalls, her mother had to sleep in the kitchen as they had to fit 12 people into a 3 room apartment. 

Following the War, there was an increased drive to move tenement-dwellers into modern apartments. This drive had actually started prior to the War, but gained increased impetus when the Housing Act of 1949 made Federal money available to construct housing projects. Throughout the &#39;20s and &#39;30s, the modernist architecture movement had provided a blueprint of how the ideal city should look, and city planners took full advantage of these architects when money became available to put their plans into action. (A detailed description of modern architectural principles is beyond the scope of this post, but if you&#39;re unfamiliar, look up Corbusier to get an idea of what we&#39;re dealing with). 

At first, the project was deemed a smashing success. The design won awards. Early residents talked about how, for the first time in their lives, they were living somewhere where everything was new, and clean, and there was adequate space. On woman said she felt like she was moving into a high-end resort. Another, who was a child at the time, talked about moving in around Christmas, with the moon shining off the snow and lights in every window, and how it felt magical, like they&#39;d finally escaped the slums.

Needless to say, this feeling didn&#39;t last. Within a few years, the place was in noticeable decline, and within ten, it was practically hell on earth. Maintenance issues, exacerbated by vandalism, added danger and seediness. Vacancy rates were high, leading entire buildings to eventually be abandoned, some of which were taken over by drug gangs. Robbery and rape were common in the now unlit stairwells and in the vast expanses between buildings residents entering to complex from the outside had to negotiate to get to their apartments. Security was lax, and police and other emergency personnel were reluctant to respond to calls for fear of their own safety. While an activist organization was able to form to seek redress for these issues, social cohesion was otherwise low, as most law-abiding residents felt unsafe outside their apartments. Throughout the city and nationwide, Pruitt-Igoe in St. Louis became a metaphor for everything that was wrong with the inner-city.

In 1968, the activist group staged a rent strike to force the housing authority to address the maintenance and safety issues. The authority, who had for years blamed these issues on lack of funding, asked how they could address any of them if they were starved of the one funding source they could rely on. But the residents had only seen things worsen over the years and wondered what they were paying for. Eventually, the city caved, and rent was capped at 25% of income and there was a commitment to address the maintenance issues. This victory was short-lived, however, as cold air getting in through broken windows that had not been fixed caused water lines to freeze and flood the remaining occupied buildings. At this point, just 15 years after opening, the project was deemed a lost cause, and the remaining residents were slowly relocated elsewhere. In 1972, the project was closed permanently, and all the buildings were demolished by 1976. 

Art critics and historians often point to the day in 1972 that the first set of buildings were imploded as &#34;the day modernism died&#34;. The contention is that the high-minded principles espoused by Le Corbusier and others had been proven empirically incorrect by what Pruitt–Igoe and other, similar high-rise projects had become. This new generation of critics could cite a laundry list of fallacious assumptions that the modernists had made, and, after all, you could tell just by looking at places like Brasilia and Le Corbusier&#39;s designs for a new Paris that these weren&#39;t places anyone would want to live. The modernists were designing for an idealized version of man, and accordingly ended up disregarding basic human needs. Thus we get living space that is too small, outdoor promenades and piazzas that nobody really uses for anything, etc. On a more straightforward note, social scientists argue that it&#39;s simply a bad idea to put large numbers of struggling people all in one large building, as these projects end up breeding all kinds of horrible pathologies. 

As you may have guessed, *The Pruitt–Igoe Myth* fights back against these assumptions. The main thrust of their argument is that complaining about the architecture completely ignores the socioeconomic and demographic factors that led to the most immediate problems. The Federal Housing Act provided money for construction, but not for maintenance; it was assumed that maintenance costs would be paid for out of rents. However, the project had been built based on projections that the population of St. Louis would rise over the coming decades. The population of the city itself ended up decreasing from a high of 850,000 in 1950 to only about 620,000 in 1970, fueled by increasing suburbanization. Accordingly, the project had a high vacancy rate from day one, and the money the housing authority was relying on for maintenance never materialized. As the maintenance backlog increased and the city population decreased, the budget went into a death spiral from which it couldn&#39;t recover. Meanwhile, a declining population meant that housing in more desirable areas was becoming available at low prices, so the project, which was originally intended to be a mix of low and middle income residents, ended up only attracting those who had nowhere else to go. It also touches on ancillary issues like racism, lack of policing, Federal housing policy, etc., but it doesn&#39;t go into them in too great of detail. 

Does it succeed in making its thesis? Sort of. The theory is plausible on its face, and it certainly explains why the project failed so soon. The problem is that similar projects were tried in practically every major American city, and there isn&#39;t one anyone can point to as a success. Some of these places did last well into the 2000s, but the film doesn&#39;t examine any of them to see if their problems were due to similar factors. Anecdotally speaking, Pittsburgh&#39;s housing projects supposedly didn&#39;t get bad until the mid-&#39;80s, but this is coming from residents and not statistics. Again, these problems were also supposedly exacerbated by lack of maintenance, so it&#39;s hard to say whether the producers of the film are on to something. One crucial distinction here, though, is that most of Pittsburgh&#39;s housing projects are and were low rises, and there doesn&#39;t seem to be any correlation between how bad a project is and how big the building is. This is in contrast to the complaints of the art critics and some of the social scientists, who argued that low-rise developments were inherently superior because they were better integrated into the existing community. The counterargument here is that Pittsburgh&#39;s low-rises weren&#39;t integrated into the community at all—they were usually places on isolated hilltops or in ravines, and often had only one way in and out. So I don&#39;t know what to make of this.

The other issue is that all this discussion about modernism and art critics—it&#39;s not in the film, I just happen to be familiar with it. This is the film&#39;s biggest flaw; there&#39;s a theory on why the project failed but no discussion of the theory behind why it was supposed to work or in-depth examination of the criticisms of that theory once the failure became apparent. Instead we get mostly reminiscences from former residents interspersed with a few comments from a social scientist. There&#39;s certainly no examination of the counterarguments.

The reason I wanted to write this up here is because the film&#39;s central thesis is intriguing in light of our current housing crisis and homelessness problem. I was riding my bike along the Riverfront trails in Pittsburgh last weekend and I noticed that tents lined the path wherever there was room for them. The previous mayor had a lax attitude toward homeless enforcement but this was different; the tents were well-kept and the people living in them didn&#39;t really look homeless. There was no evidence of drinking or drug use other than the occasional beer, and one ten&#39;s door was open and the inside was reasonably organized. It should also be mentioned that vagrancy downtown was a problem during the Peduto administration but it&#39;s not nearly as bad now, so there&#39;s obviously some additional enforcement going on. I found out later that the people living in these tents have housing vouchers from the county nut there&#39;s nowhere to put them, so they were given tents and permission to set them up until they find apartments. For most of my life, I had been inclined to agree with most of the experts, that public housing was a bad idea for all the usual reasons. But if the result of relying on Section 8 and affordable set asides in market-rate developments just leads to a housing shortage, is it really worse than the alternative? Large projects may be bad, but it&#39;s probably better than sleeping on the street. Furthermore, are they inherently bad, or only bad because of mismanagement and failure to deal with vacancies? These are tough questions, but unfortunately, *The Pruitt–Igoe Myth* doesn&#39;t answer them.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikelhsn/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>