<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Rov_Scam - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-07T15:12:53Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Rov_Scam.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if7s8d3/</id><title type="text">[CW] **Is This the End of Newsmax and OAN?**

This is coming a bit late, but over the</title><updated>2022-07-07T15:12:53Z</updated><author><name>Rov_Scam</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Is This the End of Newsmax and OAN?**

This is coming a bit late, but over the past month or so, a court in Delaware has denied motions to dismiss in Dominion&#39;s lawsuits against Newsmax and Fox News. The court hasn&#39;t ruled on a similar suit against OAN yet but, given that it is, in my opinion, the strongest of the three, I&#39;d be willing to bet that this one moves forward as well. Dominion is suing these media companies for defamation, claiming that statements concerning their Venezuelan ties, role in rigging the 2020 election, etc. have damaged their business to the tune of billions of dollars. 

The reason I&#39;m seriously wondering if these two networks are finished is because, with these rulings, Dominion has cleared the biggest hurdle of the lawsuit. When defamation involves public figures and matters of public interest (as this defamation undoubtedly does), plaintiffs must show that the defendant acted with &#34;actual malice&#34;; that is, they must prove that the defamatory statements were made either with the express knowledge that they were false or with reckless disregard for their truth or falsity. This is a tough standard to meet and is why celebrities haven&#39;t put supermarket tabloids out of business. Media companies in the United States are given pretty wide latitude to report on rumors, allegations, and other items where certainty isn&#39;t exactly bulletproof. But if they have actual knowledge that something is untrue, and publish it anyway, they can be held liable. &#34;Reckless disregard&#34; is much slipperier, but the general idea is that if you have piles of evidence that strongly suggest that something isn&#39;t true you can&#39;t just publish it without cautionary language indicating the uncertainty surrounding it. As a caution, I&#39;m only explaining all this to provide context for how this case may play out. I&#39;m not interested in debating whether it&#39;s fair that something some liberal network said should be considered defamatory, because first, these cases are very fact dependent and I don&#39;t know all the facts about hypothetical MSNBC cockups, and, second, it&#39;s irrelevant unless there&#39;s actually a lawsuit. 

Anyway, this standard is notoriously difficult to meet, mainly because most entities worth suing are sufficiently sophisticated to avoid making false statements of fact. It should also be noted that the decisions don&#39;t conclusively say that the networks acted with actual malice, simply that Dominion has alleged enough facts that a reasonable jury could conclude that they acted with actual malice. I&#39;d also note that I left Fox out of the headline because the case against them appears to be significantly weaker than the cases against Newsmax and OAN, and in any event they are more likely to be able to pay a settlement or verdict. Having failed to get a motion to dismiss, the networks can assert a number of defenses:

**Truth:** I doubt they&#39;ll actually assert this, as it would essentially involve proving that Dominion has ties to Hugo Chavez and created software designed to rig the election. If the networks had any evidence of this they wouldn&#39;t have held onto it to be used in a future lawsuit.

**Statement of Opinion:** Opinions are protected under the First Amendment. However, merely couching a defamatory statement as an opinion isn&#39;t enough to overcome a defamation claim; the courts aren&#39;t going to make it so you can get away with anything as long as you preface it with &#34;I think.&#34; This is one defense the networks are likely to assert, but proving it is going to be difficult. Given the sheer amount of coverage OAN and Newsmax gave to the Dominion allegations (with OAN seemingly airing Mike Lindell documentaries as fast as he could produce them), claiming that they were merely expressing an opinion with no intention of presenting the reporting as factual is going to be a hard sell.

**Privilege:** Occasionally, there are certain situations where one is privileged to make defamatory statements without consequence. These usually relate to official proceedings—court testimony, legislative sessions, etc. The one privilege that Newsmax, in particular, is claiming is a &#34;neutral reportage&#34; privilege that says in essence that when public figures make statements about matters of public concern, news organizations are privileged to report those allegations without fear of defamation. There are two obvious problems with this defense. The first is that it is derived from certain Circuit Court decisions that imply it&#39;s a First Amendment issue. This means that it&#39;s not a recognized common-law defense and isn&#39;t necessarily a protected constitutional right. So Newsmax is arguing that a state court should apply precedent from a Federal court that isn&#39;t even controlling over the entire Federal Court system; in effect, they want a Delaware court to give non-controlling law the force of a constitutional imperative, which isn&#39;t exactly firm footing. The second problem is that even if the court takes them up on their offer, it&#39;s highly unlikely that Newsmax meets the criteria required for protection. Without listing all the elements, it&#39;s clear that the privilege, to the extent that it exists, is intended to protect media agencies who neutrally and dispassionately report the contents of defamatory allegations without taking sides. Newsmax and OAN became All Fraud All the Time for months following the election, and repeatedly had guests like Sidney Powell repeating the allegations to sympathetic interviewers who offered little to no pushback, and in many cases parroted the allegations themselves. It&#39;s unlikely that any reasonable person could have watched either network&#39;s coverage of the election challenges for any period of time and come to the conclusion that they weren&#39;t putting forth any particular point of view. 

**Retraction:** If a defendant retracts the defamatory statements in a timely manner it will usually serve as an effective defense. This is a nonstarter her, however, since Dominion repeatedly asked the networks to issue retractions and not only did the networks refuse, but continued airing defamatory material in spite of these requests.

Given that the Actual Malice hurdle has been cleared and the available defenses aren&#39;t good, I&#39;d say that the chances of a jury verdict are pretty high. The only real question is damages, but given that they&#39;re confident in asking for over a billion dollars, even a significant reduction would still be disastrous for Newsmax and OAN. These aren&#39;t large networks with a ton of cash lying around, and this probably wouldn&#39;t be their only debt. If a jury awards a tenth of what Dominion is asking they&#39;re probably looking at bankruptcy.

The most obvious counterargument to this is &#34;If the networks&#39; cases are so bad, they&#39;ll just settle.&#34; The problem with this is that the networks couldn&#39;t offer any amount of money to make it worth it for Dominion to settle (the exception is Fox, but the case against Fox is much weaker and Fox has more money). Dominion isn&#39;t suing second-tier networks because it expects to get a lot of money. It&#39;s suing them to get vindication and rehabilitate their public image. The biggest issue for Dominion moving forward is that the taint of these allegations makes it difficult for them to get contracts. If a county is looking to replace its voting machines or renew an existing contract with Dominion, there is going to be a certain amount of public pressure to go with another vendor &#34;just to stay on the safe side&#34;. I don&#39;t know the ins and outs of every state&#39;s bidding  procedures to know if a county can be forced into accepting a Dominion contract, but if there&#39;s any room for discretion a county may opt to ignore Dominion entirely just to avoid any possible controversy. The potential damages are unknowable, and Dominion is obviously erring on the high side, and Dominion knows that it can&#39;t possibly hope to recover for all the damage the allegations did. What they can hope for, however, is that a jury verdict stating not only are the allegations unproven or lacking in evidence (as some of the Powell lawsuit dismissals implied), but are demonstrably and indisputable false. False to the point that we&#39;re making those who repeated them publicly pay large sums of money. It&#39;s not perfect, but it&#39;s probably the best Dominion can hope for.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if7s8d3/"/></entry></feed>