<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/russokumo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-21T02:38:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/russokumo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il59ec9/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Why were the Jews not assimilated for over 2000 years? Anyone have a good book o</title><updated>2022-08-21T02:38:32Z</updated><author><name>russokumo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Why were the Jews not assimilated for over 2000 years? Anyone have a good book or blog post recommendation on this question?

I&#39;m fascinated that despite not having sustained physical control of their homeland since Alexander the Great conquered Israel, the Jewish people have survived and persisted as a separate, distinct, culture and religion from both the Greco/Romans,  Christians, as well as the Saracens/Arabs/Turks/Muslims that have dominated their geographic origin/homeland for over 2000 year.

More extraordinarily their descendants (measured by mitochondrial DNA) managed to coalesce in the modern day and regain political dominance of that region.

My suspicion is it has something to do with their belief in exclusive matrilineal descent + a focus on knowledge &amp;amp; learning, which made them useful to the various warlord cultures that had political dominance over areas where Jews lived.

I can think of no other group of people who for over 2000 years have accomplished this feat and avoided assimilation/extermination into or by another more prominent neighboring culture. The closest I can think of are the Parsi Zoroastrians in India, but most of Iran is solidly Shia Muslim and if crusader kings iii is to be believed, by the 1200s, there weren&#39;t any openly public Zoroastrian rulers left in Persia.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/il59ec9/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>