<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/russokumo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T22:16:44Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/russokumo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij42xvx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] What are the &#34;best value&#34; public school districts in the USA?let&#39;s define the nu</title><updated>2022-08-05T22:16:44Z</updated><author><name>russokumo</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">What are the &#34;best value&#34; public school districts in the USA?let&#39;s define the numerator of value as the likelihood that your child achieves top 1% income or prestige in their lifetime relative to the rest of people their age in the country. Let&#39;s define the denominator as how much it would cost you to either buy or rent in that school district for the duration of your child&#39;s schooling.

We will make a very very bold and impossible assumption that the parents have remote jobs and can work anywhere in the country and don&#39;t have family members or friends they care about for network effects.

I don&#39;t have specifics, but my strong suspicion is the top high schools would all be in the flyover country part of America vs somewhere like Scarsdale NY or Palo Alto. Main reason being that undergraduate colleges care about class rank as well as geographic diversity and it&#39;s much easier for an admissions officer to justify giving an offer to the only red headed trombone player with a 1600 SAT from Nebraska, vs the 20 they can find in Lowell high School in SF.


One of the other posters belows question on schools got me curious so thanks for inspiring me!</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij42xvx/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>