<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/russokumo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-23T19:26:18Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/russokumo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilhv3u3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;ve been thinking about two US tax policies that seem to never go away despite </title><updated>2022-08-23T19:26:18Z</updated><author><name>russokumo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;ve been thinking about two US tax policies that seem to never go away despite broad popular support when explained to the public in plain English:
1) carried interest 
2) the step up basis for inheriting equities

The vast vast majority of Americans are not private equity managers (and probably don&#39;t know any....) or rich enough to have any inheritance tax levied on them. Yet the interests of the wealthy have bought the ears of our elected officials. The cost seems very very minimal too, maybe just a couple million a year of campaign contributions to a handful of pivotal senators to save tens of billions in taxes over time.

Even though the pundit class all knows about these, my suspicion is that the public doesn&#39;t care because these things seem like too arcane of details.

This to me is a fundamental unfairness within democracy. Yes technically we are a system of one person one vote, but as wealth can compound in an unlimited way AND wealth can be converted to equal political influence, we are destined to live in effectively an oligarchy.

Yes sometimes the oligarchies views can be swayed through naming and shaming and their offspring indoctrinated, but by and large we are much closer to 1$ 1 vote than 1 person 1 vote. Some among us may even view this as just in the sense that entrepreneurs who provide the most value to society should have a greater influence on society, but we&#39;re setting up a society where it&#39;s far more likely that someone who&#39;s rich is able to become an entrepreneur in the first place, ala Elon musk, Mark Zuckerberg, and Bill Gates. In addition to the genetic advantages of having smart parents, they also were afforded the connections and wealth to enable them to take risks.

With immigration of the best and brightest from around the world + randomness of genetics one generation to the next, there is still some chance of social mobility in the USA.

But I fear we are heading towards more and more of a static society of a late stage empire. Maybe with genetic engineering available and AGI light being owned by Google shareholders soon, we truly will revert to Neo feudalism, but gattaca style. Where everyone in society knows there station and doesn&#39;t bother rising above it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilhv3u3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>