<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SaxifragetheGreen - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T22:45:46Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SaxifragetheGreen" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1ycv6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [The Case Against Judicial Review](https://prospect.org/justice/the-case-against</title><updated>2022-07-13T22:45:46Z</updated><author><name>SaxifragetheGreen</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[The Case Against Judicial Review](https://prospect.org/justice/the-case-against-judicial-review)

Judicial review, first implemented in Marbury v Madison, is the basis of the powers traditionally held by the Supreme Court. This article goes over the history of it, but I can&#39;t get over the slant. It reads like nothing more nor less than sour grapes. Judicial review is bad because it is leading to bad outcomes today, right now. Starting from the end of the article:

&amp;gt;Under any government, there is always a danger of its power being abused. Democratically elected legislatures are not immune from this problem. It must be admitted that, should Republicans take control of Congress and the White House without any constraint from the Court, there’s a strong chance they’d pass all manner of abusive stuff. The Florida legislature, for example, recently passed a bigoted “don’t say gay” bill that blatantly violates the civil rights of LGBT teachers.

&amp;gt;But the risk of theoretically unconstrained congressional majorities must be set against the current fact of the Court steadily stealing the powers of Congress, eroding the freedom of the people—and, of course, doing nothing to protect gay Florida teachers from a feral state legislature. It’s far from the first time American courts have ignored the Bill of Rights, and it won’t be the last.

Bad outcomes, therefore judicial review is bad now, and while it could be worse in the future, we have to do something now.

From earlier:

&amp;gt;A current or future president, in response to some particularly egregious Supreme Court diktat, would explain their problems with the ruling, and insist that they will not obey the decision. They would say that in their opinion, Marbury v. Madison was wrongly decided, that the Court does not get to claim sole power to interpret the Constitution, and that the Constitution has no stipulation about the U.S. being a judicial dictatorship. From now on, if Congress, for example, directs the president to regulate air pollution, then they will do as instructed, rather than obeying the Court’s wishes.

Of course, we have had prior Presidents who have done exactly this! And what does the article have to say about Old Hickory?

&amp;gt;While challenging the judiciary is commonly associated with Andrew Jackson, the two best presidents in history, Abraham Lincoln and Franklin Roosevelt, had no choice but to directly confront the Court in order to advance justice.

While commonly associated with (bad president) Jackson, it&#39;s also been used by (good presidents) Lincoln and Roosevelt!

Now, I&#39;m no fan of Marbury v Madison. I don&#39;t think judicial review should be as powerful as it is today. But this author barely grapples with the fact that it is a sword that cuts both ways. Without judicial review, you don&#39;t get Brown v Board, you don&#39;t get Roe v Wade, you don&#39;t get Chevron v NRDC, you don&#39;t get Wickard v Filburn. Without judicial review you certainly don&#39;t get the two biggest Left wins in the court in the last decade, Obergefell v Hodges and Bostock v Clayton County. The things being specifically being complained about, West Virginia v EPA and Dobbs v Jackson&#39;s WWH, are themselves reversals of previously enacted judicial review!

So I ask the motte, is judicial review good, or bad? Has it outlived its usefulness, or was it ever useful? And when and how should Marbury v Madison be contested, if at all? I had hoped for a more nuanced take on it, but the article I shared got me thinking.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig1ycv6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>