<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SaxifragetheGreen - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-10T18:12:41Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SaxifragetheGreen" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijr0gxb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Today marks four years since Richard Russell stole a plane from SeaTac airport, </title><updated>2022-08-10T18:12:41Z</updated><author><name>SaxifragetheGreen</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Today marks four years since Richard Russell stole a plane from SeaTac airport, did a barrel roll, then crashed into a remote island. RIP Skyking.

This story has always held my attention, and I must admit to a certain amount of wistful fascination with the entire episode. The story of a nobody who does something extraordinary, even though it meant his death. There&#39;s something glorious about it. Despite the need to avoid glorifying a man stealing an airplane to take it on a joyride, I can&#39;t help but admire him. 

There aren&#39;t many other things I can think of that are simultaneously ill-advised and wonderfully glorious. The one that came to mind, that has a similar feeling to me, is Alex Honnold, the man who freeclimbed El Capitan. Like stealing an airplane, freeclimbing El Capitan is ill-advised, and yet undeniably glorious. Obviously Alex didn&#39;t have to steal anything, and Alex didn&#39;t die doing it. Alex planned, and didn&#39;t break any laws. But still. The feeling I get from both resonate, harmonize. Maybe it&#39;s close to the admiration I have for Ted Kaczynski, who more than all else lived his morals and implemented them as he saw fit. Of course, while Alex didn&#39;t kill anyone and didn&#39;t die, and Richard didn&#39;t kill anyone but himself, Ted killed other people, and is still alive (for now). Ted&#39;s not glorious, not like Alex, not like Richard, even. Maybe I&#39;m just a sucker for iconoclasts, and don&#39;t have the moral fortitude to decry their transgressions. Maybe I&#39;m just confused.

I don&#39;t really have a point with this post, other than to mark the anniversary of Richard&#39;s flight. I&#39;d be curious to know if this story affected anyone here like it did me, if anyone can recognize the kind of wistfulness I feel, and if there are any other people or stories who make them feel the same way. Maybe there&#39;s a German word that describes it, one I don&#39;t know.

For anyone not familiar, here are some links.

https://mynorthwest.com/1076542/planes-temporarily-grounded-at-sea-tac-airport-for-security-breach/

https://counter-currents.com/2020/08/sky-king/

https://theamericansun.com/2018/10/06/the-last-flight-of-the-white-man/

https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/beebo-russell-seattle-plane-theft-true-story-1187023/

The &#34;full&#34; audio of the air traffic call: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KNWoomWgYAc</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijr0gxb/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>