<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Schismatic6 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-29T09:41:26Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Schismatic6" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im8j6bl/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Manosphere is not what it used to be. It&#39;s been mostly ran off mainstream sites </title><updated>2022-08-29T09:41:26Z</updated><author><name>Schismatic6</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Manosphere is not what it used to be. It&#39;s been mostly ran off mainstream sites and most classic blogs are since defunct or moved on to other grift. Still there has been an idea I have been developing for a while.

It was always easy to dismiss as toxic masculinity, motivated by misogyny and sexism. This may be to some extent true but I propose a different framing that unites all the disparate factions even though I don&#39;t think they realize so themselves. It&#39;s about the male gender role. It&#39;s no secret that the traditional male gender role is not what it used to be. Between the state and women in the workforce the provider is largely obsolete and the feminism friendly attempts to construct a new one are just unappealing and don&#39;t really address mens desires at all. How the factions differ is their reaction to that.

Redpill sometimes gets accused of being patriarchal and while some are certainly sympathetic to it (though I think part of that faction has split off into the newer tradlarpers) they instead decide feel that women don&#39;t live up to their standards and *enjoy the decline* becoming philanderers instead. The archetype of philanderer did exist but it was never considered something commendable or worth emulating under traditional conventions. The MGTOW are pretty similar, but they decide to quit altogether. MRA try to renegotiate their place using more conventional activist tactics to get the legal recognition framing it in the terms of *rights* in parallel to women. I think what both are really getting at is that women don&#39;t want to hold up their end of the bargain, but still expect men to do theirs and that&#39;s fundamentally unfair. Traditional gender roles might have given men some power that could be abused but it also came with responsibilities that remain unrecognized, even as women got *liberated* from theirs. 

I think this is a discussion we should have, but unfortunately men constructing a new narrative is hostile to modern feminism. When you&#39;re accustomed to privilege equality feels like oppression, as they say.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/im8j6bl/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>