<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/sciuru_ - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-13T21:39:01Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/sciuru_" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik6fadf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] *Status: dreams and visions*

One of the applications of language models is [Que</title><updated>2022-08-13T21:39:01Z</updated><author><name>sciuru_</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">*Status: dreams and visions*

One of the applications of language models is [Question answering](https://paperswithcode.com/task/question-answering/latest) systems. They seem to fit nicely subscription-based business model. Here’s how it works: 

1. You specify the domain and scope of knowledge, that you want to encapsulate 
2. You hire a team of experts and extract knowledge from them (or from a suit of books). Since the model is pretrained for general reasoning, it only needs to fine-tune itself according to specifications from the previous step. The model queries people and processes their answers until ~~they confess~~ target quality is achieved 
3. Subscribers select domain, “number of queries per month” and a multitude of other parameters like “model capacity”, “answer granularity”, “knowledge provider”, “dialogue memory”, etc. 
4. Then you &#34;stream&#34; it, using web or app interface

Towards complete commodification of knowledge, capitalism has been dreaming of, with pipeline and valve. Few features:

1. Linear mode is still available – you can read long chunks w/t querying model piece by piece 
2. Everyone can pack their knowledge into a model and publish it online. What if someone publishes something bad? Right, that’s why each model gets checked and licensed by benevolent third party 
3. You can merge/import data from other models/books/humans; manually override it; you can grow model continuously  
4. Various kinds of knowledge might be embedded: factual, procedural, black-box &#34;tacit&#34; functions and arbitrary uncertainty distributions around them</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik6fadf/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>