<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SecureSignals - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-26T01:13:04Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SecureSignals" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilt8n0u/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Another week another FBI controversy?

[&#34;BREAKING: Mark Zuckerberg tells Joe Rog</title><updated>2022-08-26T01:13:04Z</updated><author><name>SecureSignals</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Another week another FBI controversy?

[&#34;BREAKING: Mark Zuckerberg tells Joe Rogan that Facebook algorithmically censored the Hunter Biden laptop story for 7 days based on a general request from the FBI to restrict election misinformation.&#34;](https://twitter.com/minds/status/1562927481945980928?cxt=HHwWgICwsfOQ0bArAAAA)

Zuckerberg&#39;s exact words are somewhat ambiguous:

&amp;gt;The FBI, I think, basically came to us, some folks on our team and was like &#34;Hey, just so you know, like you should be on high alert. We thought there was a lot of Russian propaganda in the 2016 election. We have it on notice that basically there&#39;s about to be some kind of dump that&#39;s similar to that. So just be vigilant.&#34;

By my interpretation, Zuckerberg is implying that his team acted based on the request from the FBI. Perhaps the FBI will have plausible deniability to assert that this was a &#34;general request&#34; rather than a specific demand to spike this story. Twitter censorship was even more aggressive than Facebook&#39;s, so it would be interesting to know if Twitter received similar requests from the FBI and if any of this communication referred to this story in particular.

Is Zuckerberg mistakenly generating controversy by apparently blaming the FBI for Facebook&#39;s decision to censor the story in the runup to the election? Or is he just being honest in confessing the truth on Rogan&#39;s show? Zuckerberg has always shown more personal hesitancy to engage in censorship, although in the past he has [ultimately folded in the face of enormous pressure](https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-54509975). I think he knows this will create more controversy for the FBI and he&#39;s signaling that he does not want similar requests in future election cycles.

But as we&#39;ve discussed recently, Facebook&#39;s content policy is now run by [ex-CIA](https://mronline.org/2022/07/14/meet-the-ex-cia-agents-deciding-facebooks-content-policy/) so similar requests for the cooperation of Facebook&#39;s moderation team may not even become known to Zuckerberg himself.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilt8n0u/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>