<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SensitiveRaccoon7371 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T22:11:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SensitiveRaccoon7371" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/iji0yyw/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A [new piece](https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/08/15/inside-the-war-betwe</title><updated>2022-08-08T22:11:36Z</updated><author><name>SensitiveRaccoon7371</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A [new piece](https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/08/15/inside-the-war-between-trump-and-his-generals) is making the rounds today on the war between Trump and his generals. Besides offering amusing vignettes such as:

&amp;gt;The President’s loud complaint to John Kelly one day was typical: “You fucking generals, why can’t you be like the German generals?”

&amp;gt;“Which generals?” Kelly asked.

&amp;gt;“The German generals in World War II,” Trump responded.

&amp;gt;“You do know that they tried to kill Hitler three times and almost pulled it off?” Kelly said.

&amp;gt;But, of course, Trump did not know that. “No, no, no, they were totally loyal to him,” the President replied. In his version of history, the generals of the Third Reich had been completely subservient to Hitler; this was the model he wanted for his military. Kelly told Trump that there were no such American generals, but the President was determined to test the proposition.

and

&amp;gt;Milley had already spoken out publicly against the banning of transgender troops, which Trump was insisting on.

&amp;gt;“Mattis tells me you are weak on transgender,” Trump said.

&amp;gt;“No, I am not weak on transgender,” Milley replied. “I just don’t care who sleeps with who.”

the piece also raises all kinds of troubling questions on civil-military relations, the deep state and the extent to which elected officials (like Trump) can be constrained by unelected bureaucrats. According to it, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs Marc Milley led the &#34;Resistance&#34; (TM) inside the Pentagon:

&amp;gt;“Fuck that shit,” Milley told his staff. “I’ll just fight him.” The challenge, as he saw it, was to stop Trump from doing any more damage, while also acting in a way that was consistent with his obligation to carry out the orders of his Commander-in-Chief. Yet the Constitution offered no practical guide for a general faced with a rogue President. Never before since the position had been created, in 1949—or at least since Richard Nixon’s final days, in 1974—had a chairman of the Joint Chiefs encountered such a situation. “If they want to court-martial me, or put me in prison, have at it,” Milley told his staff. “But I will fight from the inside.”

The piece further outlines Milley&#39;s efforts to stymie any attempt by Trump to order the military to &#34;start an unnecessary war overseas&#34; or &#34;be used in the streets against the American people for the purpose of keeping Trump in power&#34;. In particular, it refers to discussions about attacking Iran:

&amp;gt;Miller’s behavior did not look intentional so much as unhelpful to Milley, as Trump kept asking for alternatives, including an attack inside Iran on its ballistic-weapons sites. Milley explained that this would be an illegal preëmptive act: “If you attack the mainland of Iran, you will be starting a war.” During another clash with Trump’s more militant advisers, when Trump was not present, Milley was even more explicit. “If we do what you’re saying,” he said, “we are all going to be tried as war criminals in The Hague.”

&amp;gt;Trump often seemed more bluster than bite, and the Pentagon brass still believed that he did not want an all-out war, yet he continued pushing for a missile strike on Iran even after that November meeting. If Trump said it once, Milley told his staff, he said it a thousand times. “The thing he was most worried about was Iran,” a senior Biden adviser who spoke with Milley recalled. “Milley had had the experience more than once of having to walk the President off the ledge when it came to retaliating.”

&amp;gt;The biggest fear was that Iran would provoke Trump, and, using an array of diplomatic and military channels, American officials warned the Iranians not to exploit the volatile domestic situation in the U.S. 

Seems quite shocking that American officials would engage in back-channel communications with the Iranians to frustrate their own commander-in-chief. The piece details other efforts by Milley to slow-walk Trump&#39;s orders and while the authors justify it by saying he considered them unlawful it seems more appropriate to say that he considered them ill-thought-through and disagreed with them. Which raises the question of whether he should&#39;ve resigned if he felt unable to carry out his duties due to differences of opinion with the president. But the piece explains that he considered resigning but instead chose to stay on the inside to &#34;fight back&#34; against the president. When presented in such a way, his behavior may be viewed troubling, bordering on insubordinate.

Another question raised is the role of the process. The article alleges that Trump ordered an immediate withdrawal from Afghanistan and Somalia without consulting the chairman of the joint chiefs. Milley refused to carry out the order and instead assembled like-minded advisors and went to the White House to convince Trump to walk it back. Are the POTUS&#39; orders legitimate because they come from the president or because they went through the institutionalized process of formulating them? Even though abstractly it&#39;s the former, in the real world it is the process that seems to legitimize the orders. This has interesting implications in all kinds of areas, from democratic governance (is it enough to disrupt the process as on Jan 6 to stop democracy from functioning?) to medical treatments (can we short-circuit the FDA approval process to bring drugs into use faster?).</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/iji0yyw/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>