<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SensitiveRaccoon7371 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-07T18:53:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SensitiveRaccoon7371" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if8qh52/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **So, what went wrong for Boris Johnson?**

Back in 2019 Boris was flying high s</title><updated>2022-07-07T18:53:47Z</updated><author><name>SensitiveRaccoon7371</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**So, what went wrong for Boris Johnson?**

Back in 2019 Boris was flying high securing a huge majority in the elections and seeing off the challenge of Corbynism. He was &#34;getting Brexit done&#34; and successfully broke through the red wall of Labour voters in middle England. With the left sinking more and more in the morass of identity politics, the conservatives were well-positioned to win the working-class voters who were fed up with woke politicians playing to the prejudices of the urban professional-managerial class. In 2020 with the spread of BLM fads in the summer of race riots in America the conservative government had successfully posed as defenders of history and tradition against the ignorant rioters. Their performance on covid was also praised because Brexit enabled the government to avoid being yoked to the inefficient Brussels bureaucracy. Given the continuing culture wars, with their leftist opponents reliably picking the wrong side, it seemed that the conservatives were poised to just keep winning.

Yet today Johnson has resigned. This came after a bunch of his ministers quit the government in the last 48 hours. Boris was stampeded to the exit by his own party, shrugging  in his resignation speech that &#34;them&#39;s the breaks&#34;. Notably for all the comparisons to Trump, this never happened to the latter for the GOP was much more house-trained under Trump than the Tories ever were under Johnson. This has already been described as a slow-moving coup perpetrated by the liberal media with their never-ending drip-drip of various &#34;scandals&#34; and &#34;-gates&#34; which panicked conservative MPs and whetted their appetites for back-stabbing once they smelled the blood in the water. Ultimately, Johnson has only himself to blame because losing control of your own party in a parliamentary system is fatal.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/if8qh52/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>