<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/SkookumTree - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-24T19:45:15Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/SkookumTree" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilmxnyb/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m on the autism spectrum and want to become as graceful as the average neuroty</title><updated>2022-08-24T19:45:15Z</updated><author><name>SkookumTree</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m on the autism spectrum and want to become as graceful as the average neurotypical. I understand that this might be a nearly impossible task; there are neurotypicals out there that almost never make social blunders...and this is not far from average, in my view. I&#39;ve been practicing lots, and have made some new friends...but I still get the feeling that they are basically secretly annoyed by me and only tolerating me out of a sense of pity and politeness. How might I get to the place where I think the average neurotypical is: seemingly effortlessly graceful, never making a mistake big enough to be put into words while sober. Watching two average people talk, to me, is like watching Olympic gymnasts or professional ballerinas. My therapist has been helpful - but she hasn&#39;t given me much that would help me get that level of grace.

Also: I find it interesting that people expect me, at 27, to have had some relationship history even though I am shorter than average and not that good looking - as well as being awkward. I wonder if they expect me to have, at least at some point, have bitten the bullet and been in a relationship with someone who I wasn&#39;t all that interested in or who had very real shortcomings that impacted them every day...maybe they were 300 pounds overweight. Maybe they had a drug or alcohol problem. Maybe they were no shit crazy and wound up in mental hospitals twice a year. IDK what it is. Is there any way that I could figure out how to accept being a nurse and caretaker to someone that is more or less disgusted by me? I&#39;d like to have a family, and if that is what it takes I&#39;d consider it, but it is a hard pill to swallow - being a single father, functionally, while also being a nurse and caretaker for a wife that is committing slow suicide. That takes toughness and discipline.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wwbr8k/wellness_wednesday_for_august_24_2022/ilmxnyb/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>