<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/slider5876 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-12T15:12:53Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/slider5876" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ik05nvf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I found the Richard Hannania breakdown of his readers to be interesting.  Person</title><updated>2022-08-12T15:12:53Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I found the Richard Hannania breakdown of his readers to be interesting.  Personally I thought he drew from more conservative readership.  But it’s actually fairly similar to motte users.  Instead top sources of his readers are Tyler Cowen, Scott Alexander, Bryan Caplan.

https://richardhanania.substack.com/p/survey-results-i-basic-demographics

His likes and dislikes tables (mostly people) rankings is quite interesting.  You can find it under Hannania table PDF here.

https://richardhanania.substack.com/p/survey-results-ii-likes-and-dislikes

I agree with his questioning of sexual harassment and ideas around that where he cited free association as it should be allowed between adults.  If your a libertarian that should make sense to you.  Here’s a few I disagree with the general view on things (apparently from survey results of people like me).

1. Highest ranked big disagreement is Abraham Lincoln.  Comes in as 6th most favorable.  This gets complicated as I dislike slavery but longer term he ended the right of states to secede and with it a lot of the power of State’s Rights.  Personally in an alternative history I would think slavery dies in 30-40 years and a union is re-established while States Rights is watered down forever and eventually when that happened I assume a union was recreated.  Loss of States Rights makes me lower Abraham Lincoln significantly.  Tough call.

2.  Aella making the list is sort of funny.  Probably least known broadly but I guess most have heard of her in this specific community.

3.  Deng Xiaoping.  Way too low.  Probably because of the anti-Chinese bias today (partially earned).  But I would rank him top 10.  Hugely influential and in my opinion successful in eliminating more human misery than anyone else I can think of.

4.  There seems to be a correct interpretation to me that partisan low quality sources are rated lowly.  Looking at ADL/OANN with low rankings.

5.  Assad I rate a lot higher especially in the aftermath.  Simple utilistarianism when Assad dominated Syria was semi-livable.  Now rubble.  Somehow he kept everyone from killing each other.  Which counts for something in my book.

6.  AOC i rank higher.  She’s a meme politician like Gaetz.  Personally think she’s in a process of normalizing and will end up like Nancy Pelosi at 60.  Party leader in the machine.  I don’t have huge negative view of her.

7.  Xi i have a similar bad view of.  And it’s because I’m beginning to question his competency.  Mishandling of COVID and with an authoritarian bent.  I think low competency, bad values, and extreme power makes him a huge threat unlike Deng who had extreme competency.  I would rank him lower from his already low position.  Probably third from bottom.

8.  White Nationalism I rate higher.  Mostly because I don’t know what it means.  And I don’t think the bad version exists at any meaningful level which means it shouldn’t be below things like Xi that has real power.  Same view on Kamala.  Though unlike White Nationalism there’s no strong version that she’s a really bad person.  There’s nothing I dislike about her.  I think she got promoted to a position above her ability.  She shouldn’t be in the lowest tiers.

9.   The Taliban I rate significantly higher.  While they don’t vote on leaders in Afghanistan they seem to have the consent of the governed because no one cared enough to fight them even when they had leftover US guns to stop them.  I will respect a country choosing to be a theocracy provided their shit stays within their own borders.

10.  Weinstein I would also rate higher like Hannania.  On net he made good movies and from a utilitarian perspective he contribute more good than bad.  And I don’t view prostitution as close to as bad as the people he’s listed around him (trading sex for acting jobs).  Though he likely crossed into some non consensual stuff.  I just see a much bigger gap between what he did and Hitler/Stalin.  Xi I would rank next to them.   But still significantly higher because he’s only genocided a little bit instead of entire continents.


Some of my differences are probably just how he did the survey and it didn’t differentiate at the lower end well.  And when you dislike someone like Newsome he gets the same score as someone really bad like Hitler.  A 10 point scale would have likely shown bigger gaps.  The scoring would scare me that we are far closer to civil war but I think that’s just the methodology.  I might dislike a lot of Democrat establishment but not at that level.

Personally was waiting for someone else to post these surveys.  The overlap in communities seemed strong.  I wouldn’t be surprised if he sources ideas here and I’ve had conversations with him.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ik05nvf/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>