<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/slider5876 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-04T17:27:07Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/slider5876" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2uofk/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] There was a post that was awful that got moderated for blasting every new movie </title><updated>2022-09-04T17:27:07Z</updated><author><name>slider5876</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">There was a post that was awful that got moderated for blasting every new movie for being woke.  But being honest I only like consuming old movie/series.  Am I missing something?  Am I just aging and want to consume things from my prime.

I do notice in the past we had movies where male (usually white) battles world and sometimes personal demons.  Male wins.  I like those movies.  Last two days I’ve watched Jerry Maguire and Goodwill Hunting.  Women plays some emotional support role.  Some reason Man on Fire is coming to my head as a movie I like.  Black man has demons, proceeds to conquer them, saves white girl.

Point I’m getting to I believe is in the past all shows were basically man battles world.  Man triumphs while fighting his weaknesses.  I’m trying to come up with a theory for why all modern film sucks.  And I think it’s because I’m a misogynist.

Woke films suck because deep down we all know men have to lead.  Goodwill Hunting had Matt Damon (the genius) having the trust fund Stanford med school girl begging him to be in love.  Sort of like Steve Jobs and his Stanford mba wife who never worked.

This stuff is just real.  World I grew up in men had to lead.  And it’s still the world I know in the business world.  When I struggle in business I lose interest in dating.  Who would want me if I’m a failure?

Maybe I should embrace this non-patriarchal society though I think it’s against human nature and a reason why new media isn’t believable.  In my world if I don’t win then I don’t get the girl and I don’t deserve her.  In woke world world then I guess I get to be house husband.

Edit:  Also own a lot of HBO stock because I thought they had the best content</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/in2uofk/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>