<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Smirking_Basilisk - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-30T12:03:28Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Smirking_Basilisk" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iajark1/</id><title type="text">[CW] I found [these](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/uqp7z6/culture_war_ro</title><updated>2022-05-30T12:03:28Z</updated><author><name>Smirking_Basilisk</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I found [these](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/uqp7z6/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_16_2022/i9sngso/) comments interesting, it seems some people have a hard time imagining tolerance or support without celebration.

Perversion is like smoking tobacco. Not in every way (it might be partially innate, etc.) but in terms of how society should treat it. It&#39;s not without its charms, people should be free to do it in peace, to make art that depicts it positively, etc. and those that give smokers or perverts too much shit should be treated like the assholes, hypocrites and zealots that they are.

On the other hand, imagine if there were mandatory smoker&#39;s pride quasi-religious celebrations every other month, if movies required at least one chain smoker in the main cast and studies showing it to be bad for the lungs were taboo, if you couldn&#39;t speak in public without keeping up with smoker language and kids were groomed into it by preferentially hired smokers, if you were made to feel bad whenever you had a visceral reaction to smoke in your face or if smart, allegedly empathetic people told you that you&#39;re &#34;morally flawed&#34; for refusing to wear their flag.

I suspect that those who view lack of celebration as hatred have a big overlap with those that want tobacco banned from movies or public places, and I wonder how do such people think about themselves? Do they think that everything they are is worthy of evangelism and celebration? Flip between that and scrupulosity?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iajark1/"/></entry></feed>