<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Sorie_K - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-28T16:27:02Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Sorie_K" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0b74z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Last week someone asked that we do a regular policy tracking/analysis thing each</title><updated>2022-07-28T16:27:02Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Last week someone asked that we do a regular policy tracking/analysis thing each week at the Motte and I think that sounds grand, so here&#39;s some updates.

Last night Democratic senators and the Biden team finally hammered out the long awaited deal with Senate final boss Joe Manchin.  The resulting Inflation Reduction Act is tiny compared to the price tag on the original Build Back Better Act but still hits at a lot of major priorities.  The [full text](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122281-inflation_reduction_act_of_2022) is here if you&#39;re interested, a breezy read at 725 pages.  This [one page summary](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122297-inflation_reduction_act_one_page_summary) gives a quick breakdown, and [NYTimes](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/27/us/politics/manchin-climate-tax-bill.html) has a pretty solid summary of the key stuff:

&amp;gt;The package would set aside $369 billion for climate and energy proposals, the most ambitious climate action ever taken by Congress, and raise an estimated $451 billion in new tax revenue over a decade, while cutting federal spending on prescription drugs by $288 billion, according to a summary circulated Wednesday evening.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;. . .  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The two health care pieces would allow Medicare to directly regulate the price of prescription drugs for the first time beginning in 2023. It would also extend through 2025 an expansion of premium subsidies that Democrats first pushed through in 2021 as part of their $1.9 trillion pandemic aid bill, preventing a lapse at the end of the year.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The plan would raise most of its new tax revenue, an estimated $313 billion, by imposing a minimum tax on the so-called book income of large corporations, like Amazon and FedEx, that currently use tax credits and other maneuvers to reduce their tax rates below the 21 percent corporate income tax rate in the United States.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;It would raise another $14 billion by reducing a preferential tax treatment for income earned by venture capitalists and private equity firms, which has long been a goal of Democrats.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;It invests $30 billion in production tax credits for solar panels, wind turbines, batteries and critical minerals processing; $10 billion in tax credits to build clean technology manufacturing facilities; and $500 million to be used through the Defense Production Act for heat pumps and critical minerals processing.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The deal also includes a means-tested $7,500 tax credit to make new electric vehicles more affordable, and a $4,000 tax credit for used electric vehicles, according to a summary of the package. Both credits will be offered only to lower and middle-income consumers.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The measure also includes a methane fee that will start in 2025.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Also included will be $60 billion to address the disproportionate burden of pollution on low-income communities and communities of color, $27 billion for a “green bank” aimed at delivering financial support to clean energy projects and $20 billion for programs that can cut emissions in the agriculture sector.

Relevant to our discussion yesterday about Trump and DeSantis, the bill also includes &#34;comprehensive permitting reform&#34; aimed at making building easier, though not a lot of details have been released so far and I haven&#39;t trawled the bill yet.

I&#39;m pretty into everything I see here at first glance, especially the provision allowing Medicare to negotiate prices and also the investments in electric vehicles and related clean energy technologies (as you might have guessed from my posts ranting about gas reliance always exposing us to international crises).  I see nothing about nuclear power in the summary unfortunately (edit: see u/ChrisPrattAlphaRaptr&#39;s comment for details on what they are doing).

I&#39;m a little surprised at some of the tax stuff - if we&#39;re going after paying back the deficit why focus on carried interest and not capital gains in general, one of Biden&#39;s original pledges?  Presumably lost in compromise I suppose.  I&#39;ve been unconvinced by the arguments that eliminating the capital gains tax will choke off investment since so much of venture capital is from already tax-exempt sources like pension funds, but possibly also they were worried about choking off investment at a time when fears of a recession are already growing.  Note that Manchin also put the kibosh on attempts from the coastal senators to raise the SALT cap, which I consider to be a plus.

Note  also that this bill isn&#39;t guaranteed; Kyrsten Sinema hasn&#39;t weighed in yet and we haven&#39;t actually heard from every other Democratic senator either.

This comes a day after the Senate passing an actually bipartisan (64-33) [industrial policy bill](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/27/us/politics/senate-chips-china.html) aimed at countering China and in particular onshoring the semiconductor industry:

&amp;gt;The bill, a convergence of economic and national security policy, would provide $52 billion in subsidies and additional tax credits to companies that manufacture chips in the United States. It also would add $200 billion for scientific research, especially into artificial intelligence, robotics, quantum computing and a variety of other technologies.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The bill calls for pouring $10 billion into the Department of Commerce — which would also dole out the chips subsidies to companies that apply — to create 20 “regional technology hubs” across the country. The brainchild of Senator Todd Young, Republican of Indiana, and Mr. Schumer, the hubs would aim to link together research universities with private industry in an effort to create Silicon Valley-like centers for technology innovation in areas hollowed out by globalization.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The legislation would steer billions to the Department of Energy and the National Science Foundation to promote both basic research and research and development into advanced semiconductor manufacturing, as well as work force development programs, in an effort to build a labor pipeline for a slew of emerging industries.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;. . .  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The bill also seeks to create research and development and manufacturing jobs in the long run. It includes provisions aimed at building up pipelines of workers — through work force development grants and other programs — concentrated in once-booming industrial hubs hollowed out by corporate offshoring.

I haven&#39;t read nearly as much about this one but interested and heartned to see any piece of major legislation passed with such substantial cross-aisle cooperation.  Apologies for the bare bones analysis but I need to dig into both of these deeper to have much more to say.  Interested to hear what others think.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii0b74z/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/cul</title><updated>2022-07-25T13:31:45Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?context=3) about oil prices a few days ago.

One of the sub-questions I was curious about was why oil companies weren’t investing more in digging new wells.  A few commenters replied that this was probably because of Biden – he opened up his term by cancelling the Keystone XL pipeline, removing permits on drilling on federal lands and saying we should move towards fully green energy.  My reply was that Obama basically did all that stuff too and oil production doubled under him, so are these kinds of regulatory policy moves really that important to investors?

Users u/LeninLovedUncleTom and u/Pulpachair offered more information on how technology breakthroughs and the relatively high price of crude oil opened up the new shale market under Obama and led to that crazy growth.  But there’s still a lot of shale and crude prices are crazy high again and no one’s drilling.  I think [both](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih8bt2a/?context=3) [users](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih89f6l/?context=3) made compelling arguments (if i followed them), substantiated with the articles I can find with quotes from oil leaders, that the primary driver of investment isn&#39;t really regulatory policy, it&#39;s the fact that everyone is too worried about massive market fluctuations.  OPEC cratered prices after the initial shale boom and hurt a lot of investors, and Covid saw barrels going for negative prices.  Who wants to invest in drilling more when the market could switch up on you and completely destroy your profits?  [To quote](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-02-18/shale-wildcatters-send-bullish-oil-price-signal-with-output-restraint):

&amp;gt;“Whether it’s $150 oil, $200 oil, or $100 oil, we’re not going to change our growth plans,’’ Pioneer Chief Executive Officer Scott Sheffield said during a Bloomberg Television interview. “If the president wants us to grow, I just don’t think the industry can grow anyway.’’

I think here this offers us two possibilities, with two questions I’d ask everyone.

1:  If we assume government policy can’t make a huge difference on oil investment relative to the market, and the market experiences such dramatic fluctuations that investors literally won’t invest in drilling more even when it would be profitable, and that this common sense market rationale means we all have to eat high gas prices: is this not an extremely strong argument for trying to divest away from oil?  To invest full scale in nuclear and renewables (edit: and battery storage technology) and microgrids and the infrastructure to make electric vehicles possible and widespread?

Much is talked about the intermittency issues with renewables, but should the fact that Russia and China each control 15% of the world’s oil production, and petroleum sales can always be used as a carrot or stick in conflicts like the current one, and that we don’t have the ability to control OPEC with their further 44% of the world’s production – shouldn’t all this be seen functionally as an broad scale intermittency problem as well?  You can address shortfalls with wind and solar in a number of ways, like using combined heat and gas systems or only using them to complement nuclear power, but in crisis situations where 15% of the world’s oil disappears off of the western markets there doesn’t seem to be any quick fix – our oil companies outright say the won’t drill more no matter what the president does!

I’m well aware this would be a cost intensive and technologically challenging road, and that renewables in particular have other huge limitations and could perhaps never fully fill the gap fossil fuels played, but wouldn’t shrinking our fossil fuel dependency alone go significantly far towards reducing our exposure to these kinds of crises?  Would the eventual problems we might face in a country that invested to the hilt in electric cars, nuclear energy, renewable energy systems and decentralized microgrids be worse than what we’re dealing with now?  Would it be worse than the fact that our country is always vulnerable having the pipe turned off from the outside?

2:  Alternatively, maybe none of the obvious stuff Biden could do would help oil.  But let’s pretend he can - what if he did all the non-obvious stuff as well?  What if Biden completely deregulated oil, cut their taxes down to zero, gave them (more) massive subsidies and promised to insure any losses from market fluctuations, slashed wages, cut all zoning laws, worker’s rights, safety regulations and environmental regulations and finally got domestic oil production to rise.

Would it be worth it?

Sometimes I’m jealous of China’s powerful industrial base.  Then I think about their horrendously polluted waterways and their skies full of smog and their workers paid pittances to labor for crazy hours in often unsafe conditions, and I wonder if it would be worth having to do all that to compete with them on some kind of even footing.

Would it be worth producing two, three, four times as much oil, enough that we have dominance over the world price and never have to worry about this situation again, if we also had to trade away our centuries of hard-fought worker’s rights? If all of our gorgeous national parks were studded with oil wells and refineries and our waterways and skies groaned under the weight of their pollution?  This is an exaggerated example to be sure, but in a world where oil executives outright say the President’s normal policy levers won’t change their investment outlook, it bears worth asking: how much are we actually willing to give up to change that?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>