<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Sorie_K - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-01T17:08:37Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Sorie_K" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iat2rxh/</id><title type="text">[WW] A few months ago I switched from coffee to caffeine pills.  By doing so I&#39;ve man</title><updated>2022-06-01T17:08:37Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">A few months ago I switched from coffee to caffeine pills.  By doing so I&#39;ve managed to way reduce my caffeine intake, the alertness lasts longer and has less jitters.  So I think it was a good move overall.  But strangely I seem to have lost my desire to read?  Previously I read voraciously pretty much every spare moment I had, but now for no clear reason i can&#39;t seem to make it past a few paragraphs without losing my interest.  I&#39;ve had to start listening to podcasts, which i always kind of struggled with, because it seems to be the only way i can cram info into my head.  My desire to write has kind of gone in the same direction as well.  I miss both of those things, but my overall mood and energy throughout the day are so much better that I havent switched back yet.  And instead of reading and writing all the time I&#39;m spending way more time hanging out with people face to face, which is probably good overall.  I think my mood is also just better because im engaging less with politics and the culture war and all the toxicity that comes with that.  I&#39;m at a very weird place where i seem to have sort of inexplicably lost my main lifelong hobby, and it&#39;s definitely bothersome, but I&#39;m not anywhere near as upset about it as I should be?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v2a9l4/wellness_wednesday_for_june_01_2022/iat2rxh/"/></entry></feed>