<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Sorie_K - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T18:56:51Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Sorie_K" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijh7epp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] This is an entry in the Collaborative Analysis of the Inflation Reduction Act, w</title><updated>2022-08-08T18:56:51Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">This is an entry in the Collaborative Analysis of the Inflation Reduction Act, where u/xablor, u/_netstack and I all picked a different section of the bill to drill into in depth. We’re posting everything as top levels here so everyone sees them, but later you can also see all of the fleshed out entries together at the bottom of [this thread](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wc7x7s/collaborative_analysis_of_the_inflation_reduction/). Thanks to u/xablor for coming up with the idea to do this and for setting up the whole collaborative analysis.  My section is taxes.

**PART 1—CORPORATE TAX REFORM**

The corporate tax in the Inflation Reduction Act announces a new tax of 15% on book income, so your earnings prior to taxes, deductions, etc.  Basically, if the 15% tax on book income is higher than what they a corporation owes on their normal taxes, then that corporation has to add the difference between the two amounts on their tax bill and pay the total sum.  The idea here is to target corporations which are paying little to no taxes because of loopholes.

However, this only applies to corporations that have had $1 billion in taxabale income (averaged across the previous three years, unless the company has existed for less than three years, then averaged across however long they have been around).  These corporations can almost be exempt if they are experiencing a change in ownership, or if they had a certain number of (as yet undetermined) consecutive years earning below $1 billion, or if the Secretary of the Treasury feels like it.  Taxes are also levied on global income, so as to account for base erosion, the process of shifting profits from your high tax home country to a subsidiary or parent in a low tax foreign country. This is similar-ish to the way Trump’s Base Erosion and Tax proposal implemented an alternative minimum tax on global income.

For a [critical perspective](https://taxfoundation.org/inflation-reduction-act/), the conservative Tax Foundation argues “The proposed 15 percent minimum tax on corporate book income is the most economically damaging provision in the bill, reducing GDP by 0.1 percent and costing about 23,000 jobs&#34;.  Another [article of theirs](https://taxfoundation.org/biden-corporate-income-tax-rate/) gives a good explanation of the problems of taxing book income.  There might be good reasons why taxable income is lower (or higher) than book income, because of depreciation of tangible investments, because of stock options, because of net operating losses being carried forward – all of which might actually be reasonable and shouldn’t be penalized. The Tax Foundation [offers a more specific breakdown](https://taxfoundation.org/book-minimum-tax-analysis/) of which industries would be affected the most.  Supposedly real estate is number one followed by minining, mostly because they make significant use of depreciation.

All of this makes sense but again, though, this is only a tax on (certain) corporations making over a billion dollars.  In other words, at its most inefficient this tax will only affect at most 135 of the over 6 million companies registered in the US.  Even if all of their caveats are correct, will the tax really have such wide-ranging distortionary affects for the whole economy when its targeted at such a tiny minority of extremely profitable companies?  Would those negative effects outweigh the $313 billion in new revenue and deficit reduction?

One reason to justify being a little nervous is that the liberal Tax Policy Center [is also skeptical](https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxvox/book-minimum-tax-may-discourage-investment-more-rate-hike) about taxing book income rather just raising the ordinary corporate tax for the same reasons. They also point out that while the tax would only hit 300 companies (double my findings but who’s counting), those companies account for about 60% of all capital so if the tax disincentivizes investment the effects could be large.

However, [they take issue](https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxvox/putting-jcts-score-inflation-reduction-act-context) with the Tax Foundation&#39;s broad analysis and projections of the IRA, arguing that their assessment fails to take into the ameliorative affects of other tax credits.  As for the corporate tax, the point to a substantial body of research indicating that now up to 60% of corporate profits are estimated to be “supernormal,” ie profits beyond what you would normally expect that are made possible by rent seeking, patents, specialized expertise, economies of scale, luck, etc. ([1](https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/131/WP-116.pdf), [2](https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.17310/ntj.2016.4.05), [3](https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.17310/ntj.2013.1.09) \- note that the the sources here are the US Treasury and researchers from the famously non-leftist U Chicago). As long as the new tax is lower than 100% of excess profit, it shouldn’t really impact investment and hiring, at least according to the [Congressional Research Service](https://sgp.fas.org/crs/misc/RL34229.pdf) and my understanding of mainstream thinking on the issue (it’s possible I totally misunderstand this).  Furthermore, they [point to growing evidence](https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxvox/rethinking-incidence-corporate-income-tax) that the corporate tax is more progressive than once thought, landing more on the capitalists than on the laborers.

The Tax Foundation seems to basically agree with this – they don’t use the most liberal estimates you can find but they assume that 75% of the burden will fall on capitalists and 25% on laborers.  Tax Policy Center counsels further that the “laborer” category still hides significant progressivity because significant research ([1](https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/publications/rethinking-corporate-income-tax-role-rent-sharing/full), [2](https://www.piie.com/publications/working-papers/slower-productivity-and-higher-inequality-are-they-related), [3](https://www.jstor.org/stable/2586870), [4](https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/089533003769204362)) shows that growing shares of profits are now shared as income with top managers and executives, who are still counted as laborers in this context.  The corollary is that the incidence of the corporate tax that lands on labor is still fairly progressive, landing the highest on these high earners.  For more specific numbers on how this affects the tax incidence you can check these sources ([1](https://ericohrn.sites.grinnell.edu/files/exec_comp/ohrn_tax_breaks_exec_comp_2021_2.pdf%20%20https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/corporate-taxes-and-the-earnings-distribution-effects-of-the-domestic-production-activities-deduction.htm), [2](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0047272721002139), [3](https://academic.oup.com/qje/article-abstract/134/3/1343/5420483?redirectedFrom=fulltext), [4](https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w24598/w24598.pdf)):

&amp;gt;“A study by Eric Ohrn of Grinnell College shows that the five highest-paid executives at the studied firms reaped between 17 and 25 percent of some recent corporate income tax cuts – including changes in depreciation rules and subsidies for domestic production.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Economists at the Federal Reserve Board and the congressional Joint Committee on Taxation found the highest-paid 1 percent of employees reaped 40 percent of the benefits of a corporate tax cut. An additional 19 percent of the benefits of that tax cut went to the highest paid 2 percent to 10 percent of employees.”

After you adjust for executive compensation being counted in the labor category, and for them bearing a vastly disproportionate amount of labor tax incidence, it upturns the Tax Foundation’s assessment that this would “raise taxes on all brackets” and confines the hike to the upper end of the scale.

Where I think this leaves us is that there’s general agreement that a normal corporate tax raise would be preferable than a book income tax in terms of efficiency and distortion.  However, given that this will target a small number of firms receiving excess profits from rent seeking, it’s hard to say how much this will really impact investment and hiring, if at all, and the tax incidence is almost certain to be progressive and to be born mostly by capitalists and the C suite.

automod\_multipart\_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijh7epp/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>