<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Sorie_K - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-25T13:31:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Sorie_K" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/cul</title><updated>2022-07-25T13:31:45Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A follow up from [my post](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?context=3) about oil prices a few days ago.

One of the sub-questions I was curious about was why oil companies weren’t investing more in digging new wells.  A few commenters replied that this was probably because of Biden – he opened up his term by cancelling the Keystone XL pipeline, removing permits on drilling on federal lands and saying we should move towards fully green energy.  My reply was that Obama basically did all that stuff too and oil production doubled under him, so are these kinds of regulatory policy moves really that important to investors?

Users u/LeninLovedUncleTom and u/Pulpachair offered more information on how technology breakthroughs and the relatively high price of crude oil opened up the new shale market under Obama and led to that crazy growth.  But there’s still a lot of shale and crude prices are crazy high again and no one’s drilling.  I think [both](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih8bt2a/?context=3) [users](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/comment/ih89f6l/?context=3) made compelling arguments (if i followed them), substantiated with the articles I can find with quotes from oil leaders, that the primary driver of investment isn&#39;t really regulatory policy, it&#39;s the fact that everyone is too worried about massive market fluctuations.  OPEC cratered prices after the initial shale boom and hurt a lot of investors, and Covid saw barrels going for negative prices.  Who wants to invest in drilling more when the market could switch up on you and completely destroy your profits?  [To quote](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-02-18/shale-wildcatters-send-bullish-oil-price-signal-with-output-restraint):

&amp;gt;“Whether it’s $150 oil, $200 oil, or $100 oil, we’re not going to change our growth plans,’’ Pioneer Chief Executive Officer Scott Sheffield said during a Bloomberg Television interview. “If the president wants us to grow, I just don’t think the industry can grow anyway.’’

I think here this offers us two possibilities, with two questions I’d ask everyone.

1:  If we assume government policy can’t make a huge difference on oil investment relative to the market, and the market experiences such dramatic fluctuations that investors literally won’t invest in drilling more even when it would be profitable, and that this common sense market rationale means we all have to eat high gas prices: is this not an extremely strong argument for trying to divest away from oil?  To invest full scale in nuclear and renewables (edit: and battery storage technology) and microgrids and the infrastructure to make electric vehicles possible and widespread?

Much is talked about the intermittency issues with renewables, but should the fact that Russia and China each control 15% of the world’s oil production, and petroleum sales can always be used as a carrot or stick in conflicts like the current one, and that we don’t have the ability to control OPEC with their further 44% of the world’s production – shouldn’t all this be seen functionally as an broad scale intermittency problem as well?  You can address shortfalls with wind and solar in a number of ways, like using combined heat and gas systems or only using them to complement nuclear power, but in crisis situations where 15% of the world’s oil disappears off of the western markets there doesn’t seem to be any quick fix – our oil companies outright say the won’t drill more no matter what the president does!

I’m well aware this would be a cost intensive and technologically challenging road, and that renewables in particular have other huge limitations and could perhaps never fully fill the gap fossil fuels played, but wouldn’t shrinking our fossil fuel dependency alone go significantly far towards reducing our exposure to these kinds of crises?  Would the eventual problems we might face in a country that invested to the hilt in electric cars, nuclear energy, renewable energy systems and decentralized microgrids be worse than what we’re dealing with now?  Would it be worse than the fact that our country is always vulnerable having the pipe turned off from the outside?

2:  Alternatively, maybe none of the obvious stuff Biden could do would help oil.  But let’s pretend he can - what if he did all the non-obvious stuff as well?  What if Biden completely deregulated oil, cut their taxes down to zero, gave them (more) massive subsidies and promised to insure any losses from market fluctuations, slashed wages, cut all zoning laws, worker’s rights, safety regulations and environmental regulations and finally got domestic oil production to rise.

Would it be worth it?

Sometimes I’m jealous of China’s powerful industrial base.  Then I think about their horrendously polluted waterways and their skies full of smog and their workers paid pittances to labor for crazy hours in often unsafe conditions, and I wonder if it would be worth having to do all that to compete with them on some kind of even footing.

Would it be worth producing two, three, four times as much oil, enough that we have dominance over the world price and never have to worry about this situation again, if we also had to trade away our centuries of hard-fought worker’s rights? If all of our gorgeous national parks were studded with oil wells and refineries and our waterways and skies groaned under the weight of their pollution?  This is an exaggerated example to be sure, but in a world where oil executives outright say the President’s normal policy levers won’t change their investment outlook, it bears worth asking: how much are we actually willing to give up to change that?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihkqcw6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>