<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Sorie_K - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-22T16:44:22Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Sorie_K" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Open question: Is there any way to figure out how much, if any, of the oil price</title><updated>2022-07-22T16:44:22Z</updated><author><name>Sorie_K</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Open question: Is there any way to figure out how much, if any, of the oil price increases we&#39;ve seen could be due to price gouging rather than inflation/supply shocks?

It’s notoriously tricky to figure out where the line between ordinary supply and demand ends and potential price gouging can begin, but I hear accusations flying everywhere so I’d like us to take a try.

While much of the economy looks like it&#39;s facing a downturn, oil companies are still recording record profits, enough so that Congress passed the [Consumer Fuel Price Gouging Act](https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/7688/text) and [President Biden directly addressed a letter](https://www.cnbc.com/2022/06/15/biden-tells-oil-companies-in-letter-well-above-normal-refinery-profit-margins-are-not-acceptable.html) to the seven largest companies addressing their suspiciously high margins.

There are obviously supply shocks constraining the volume of petroleum products which would raise the price, but the President argues the increase is beyond what’s justifiable based on the historical record:

&amp;gt;“Since the beginning of the year, refiners’ margins for refining gasoline and diesel have tripled, and are currently at their highest levels ever recorded,” he said. Biden noted that the last time oil was trading at $120 per barrel the average price of gas at the pump was about $4.25 per gallon. Today, gas prices are 75 cents higher, and diesel prices are 90 cents higher.”

Oil companies respond in turn by saying that they’re already operating near or at max capacity, and increasing refinery capacity takes time.  You can’t just snap your fingers and make more oil during a supply shock. . . and I guess it’s not their fault if that also happens to make them a lot of extra money in the meantime? (As an aside, is there any way to actually verify whether refineries are at max capacity, or do we kind of have to take them at their word?)

[This article](https://www.courthousenews.com/evidence-of-gasoline-price-gouging-is-very-hard-to-find/) at least argues that the price gouging story doesn’t line up, because oil and gas companies have relatively little control over prices at the pump, and gas stations are actually doing poorly financially. This seems to be substantiated [by a chart here](https://realeconomy.rsmus.com/oil-prices-and-price-gouging-deconstructing-the-price-of-gas/) that shows the breakdown of profit margins across producers, refiners and gas stations. But doesn’t this leave open the possibility that oil and gas companies are charging inflated prices to intermediaries, while refineries and gas stations are forced to resell at the lowest feasible point to keep business, thus keeping their profit margins tight while the producers grow fat?

From the courthouse piece:

&amp;gt;Although the U.S. is the world’s largest oil producer, all U.S. companies together account for only 14.5% of global oil production and thus even if they all somehow worked together they would have a very limited ability to sway global markets. The 13 OPEC countries, by contrast, produce a combined 44% of the world’s oil. Russia accounts for 13.1%, and Canada produces 5.8%, according to the U.S. Energy Information Administration.

Of course, factor in that Russia, Iran and Venezuela are out of the picture for US markets and China (normally about equal to Russia at around 15%) is running at reduced capacity.  Maybe all this increases the ability of the American companies to influence price changes, but not by a gigantic amount – it still wouldn’t come close to OPEC’s market share even minus Iran, and we would still need evidence that American companies were behaving in a cartelized manner.

The second hand evidence that does exist seems to be, as noted by the President, that current pump prices are above what they historically have been for the current barrel price, as well as the fact that pump prices didn’t fall in response to the March dip in oil prices (though [this piece argues](https://www.courthousenews.com/evidence-of-gasoline-price-gouging-is-very-hard-to-find/) that oil prices generally rise quickly and fall more slowly).  Furthermore, the oil companies’ complaints that they’re operating at max capacity seem a little self serving given that they don’t actually seem to be investing in digging new wells; instead that money is going right to the fat cats on top:

&amp;gt;A more significant allegation is that U.S. oil drillers are taking advantage of the situation by limiting their production to keep prices high. Instead of plowing profits back into drilling, Exxon, Chevron, BP and Shell spent more than $44 billion on stock buybacks and dividends in 2021 and have pledged up to $30 billion or more in buybacks this year

Why is this?

&amp;gt;The real reason that oil companies aren’t madly drilling, the Dallas Fed says, is because shareholders don’t want them to. After years of aggressively expanding operations that produced boom-and-bust cycles — including enormous losses during the pandemic when oil prices briefly turned negative — shareholders are demanding that energy companies focus on highly profitable assets rather than speculative new ones. And even though prices have spiked recently, especially after the Ukraine invasion, new drilling is time-consuming, and it’s not clear how long the current cycle will last.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In addition, with trillions of dollars flowing into socially conscious ESG (environmental, social and governance) mutual funds, investors are signaling that they want companies to move away from fossil fuels.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;“So far — and I am on the front lines, I see this every day — there is no interest to go in this space,” said Jeffrey Currie, global head of commodities research at Goldman Sachs.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;On the regulatory front, although the Biden administration claims that it’s not holding producers back, environmental and other regulations have made it “nearly impossible to build a new refinery in the United States,” said Jay Hatfield, CEO of Infrastructure Capital Management.

There’s a lot to unpack here.  I am not a finance guy but I guess it seems a little hard to believe that there is “no interest to go in this space” during an extended and indefinite period to wrest control of a huge market share and make a ton of money, but maybe the future really is so uncertain that just makes sense.  As for the claim that regulations have made it impossible to build in the US, we [do still seem to be building them](https://www.eia.gov/tools/faqs/faq.php?id=29&amp;amp;t=6) , though I have no idea if this is considered a bad rate of construction and would like to hear more from others.

Lastly, as a side note, all of the above can be true and still basically align with (at least a watered down version of) what critics are saying: oil companies aren’t investing in boosting production capacity because they’re focused on doing what makes the most possible money for their shareholders rather than what could actually bring prices down at the pump for Americans.  Perhaps that’s just capitalism working as it’s supposed to, but many would say that’s the problem.

Anyone have light they can shed?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih7jtj4/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>