<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Southkraut - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-22T07:33:05Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Southkraut" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5toir/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] tl;dr: Germany notices its &#34;13/52&#34; situation, but it&#39;s far less clear than it se</title><updated>2022-07-22T07:33:05Z</updated><author><name>Southkraut</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">tl;dr: Germany notices its &#34;13/52&#34; situation, but it&#39;s far less clear than it seems.

Disclaimer: I&#39;m getting all my numbers and data interpretation on this one from an article by Junge Freiheit, a notoriously partisan and poorly-regarded right-wing newspaper. It&#39;s the only article on the topic I found that&#39;s not paywalled, and I haven&#39;t the motivation to actually read [the 50-page report](https://www.bka.de/DE/AktuelleInformationen/StatistikenLagebilder/Lagebilder/KriminalitaetImKontextVonZuwanderung/KriminalitaetImKontextVonZuwanderung_node.html). I&#39;m going to assume that they don&#39;t outright misread the data, though there&#39;s probably much in the report that doesn&#39;t fit their narrative.

The German Federal Criminal Police Office recently published their 2021 Federal Crime Report In The Context Of Migration. Here are some CW-relevant numbers.

For violent and sexual crime, there were 40593 German victims of migrant perpetrators, and 11107 crimes with migrant victims and at least one German perpetrator. According to JF, this means that in violent crime between Germans and migrants, migrants were to blame for 78.5% all cases and Germans for 21.5%. Rape sees migrants as rapists in 95.4% of all cases. For murder, it&#39;s 85.7% versus 14.3%.

JF notes that for this report, anyone with a German passport was considered German, and that this includes three quarters of the famous arab crime families in Germany. Presumably this is meant to get the reader to imagine that the numbers might be even more outrageously in disfavor of migrants, but doesn&#39;t that work both ways? Wouldn&#39;t this also wrongly consider foreigners with German passports German victims of foreigner-on-German violence when it is in fact foreigner-on-foreigner?

At this point I&#39;m left wondering what this report is even good for. I briefly skimmed it and it seems that it purely concerns itself with &#34;migrants&#34; in the sense of asylum seekers, official refugees, registered illegal immigrants and the like. Ever since the German cathedral adopted &#34;migrant&#34; as a term describing, in effect, &#34;anyone who can and does excuse himself as not-German in any way&#34;, the term has been seen as somewhat broader than how this report applies it.

I don&#39;t really have a point here. It seems this particular newspaper was eager to construe this report as somewhat equivalent to the famous FBI crime statistics, but it seems to me to fall flat because the situation in Germany lacks any clear black/white distinction.

Sorry for the ramble. It seemed relevant, but I fail to make much of it.

I seems obvious to me at ground level that foreigners are very much more likely to be violent than Germans, and that no matter how much you muddy up the distinction this core truth is evident on observation, but I doubt we&#39;ll ever see useful statistics verifying or contradicting this.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w1s5b7/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_18_2022/ih5toir/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ih1cjyp/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] I&#39;m not seeing a CWR thread for this week. Did I miss something? Are we taking s</title><updated>2022-07-21T11:30:29Z</updated><author><name>Southkraut</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not seeing a CWR thread for this week. Did I miss something? Are we taking some time off?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w10nh1/smallscale_question_sunday_for_july_17_2022/ih1cjyp/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>