<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Spectale - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-02T15:10:21Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Spectale" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iax4pkx/</id><title type="text">[CW] I’m skeptical the court will actually overturn Roe. Now that the shock of the le</title><updated>2022-06-02T15:10:21Z</updated><author><name>Spectale</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I’m skeptical the court will actually overturn Roe. Now that the shock of the leak has passed, ruminating on it bit has dampened my expectations. The rather lackluster response by the left thus far also gives me the feeling I&#39;ll wake up one day and merely shrug at the news that the court didn&#39;t go so far as to break precedent for a social conservative cause. I can&#39;t bring myself to believe social conservatives have or can win until they actually do win.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iax4pkx/"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iafgrus/</id><title type="text">[SQ] Forgive me if this is a bit too silly for this forum, but is anyone else a bit..</title><updated>2022-05-29T14:17:49Z</updated><author><name>Spectale</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Forgive me if this is a bit too silly for this forum, but is anyone else a bit... unnerved that the universe existed for billions of years before anything approaching conscious thought could perceive it? I wonder if it&#39;s at all related to my recent interest in panpsychism. There&#39;s almost something comforting knowing that even after the death of our universe, someone knew it was there. But if the laws of physics at the big bang were slightly different and life unable to form, it would eventually pass into nothingness and no one would know. There&#39;s something almost unsettling about that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iafgrus/"/></entry></feed>