<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-18T14:53:34Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikswpuv/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Culture war in Finland: Stupidest day in Finnish politics for a long time**

C</title><updated>2022-08-18T14:53:34Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Culture war in Finland: Stupidest day in Finnish politics for a long time**

CONTEXT: It&#39;s not a new thing that Finnish PM Sanna Marin, 36, has been frequently seen out and about, drinking and dancing in clubs and such. Of course it&#39;s not a new thing for Finnish politicians to use alcohol or even get into accidents and such while doing so, but this is the new era and everyone has smartphones.

Previously the [major affair was in December](https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-finlands-prime-minister-sanna-marin-apologises-for-going-clubbing-after-coronavirus-exposure-12490903), when she was out late in a Helsinki club even though she had been exposed to Covid and there were still Covid restrictions for various things; even though the restrictions didn&#39;t affect what she, specifically, was doing, it was considered improper. On these evenings she&#39;s been spotted with an entourage of local pop stars and other celebs.

Anyway, last week, she was at one of the major music festivals in Finland, Flow Festival - not the biggest, but a classic hipster festival and certainly &#34;upscale&#34; - and had pics taken [with the attending celebs](https://is.mediadelivery.fi/img/468/7089604209104a472752cf1aa503aeb2.jpg). This caused some tut-tutting about behaving immaturely during great crises in Europe and the world. Whatever.

Now it turns out that one of the members of her entourage took a [video of being a drunk party](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9C-djV-ptEM) with her entourage and posted it on IG - private account for 92 people, to be sure, but of course something like that&#39;s going to get out. The video started spreading yesterday, and the entirety of today has consisted on Finnish social and traditional media obsessing about the clip, specifically about the specific charges of whether her entourage uses cocaine.

Of course PM partying in an entourage that&#39;s on drugs would be scandal in other countries, too, whether they took coke personally or not, but Finland tends to currently be particularly conservative on drugs compared to other Western countries - even pot decriminalization is not really soemthing that most would be consider to be short-term achievable.

Hard drugs are, of course a whole other question. I haven&#39;t used anything stronger than pot in my life and it&#39;s been years since I&#39;ve even smoked, but my understanding is that coke has been a facet of celebrity life at some level. However, it&#39;s only recent years when it has really hit the scene in Helsinki. Usually, the hard drug of choice for Finns has been speed.

Now, none of the celebrities are actually snorting anything up their nose in the video, so what&#39;s the evidence for drug use? Well, apart from the fact that they&#39;re, ya know, smiling and having fun and so on in the video (Finns might drink alcohol, but we do it to get drunk, not to actually have fun), at some parts of the video, some of them shout &#34;Fuck it, this makes me feel good&#34; in reference to something unseen and the word that might be &#34;jauhojengi&#34; (&#34;flour gang&#34;) or something else. Also, some claim that some of the pixels in the video indeed make it look like there&#39;s coke on the table. (Others claim it&#39;s a phone.) One particular claim is even that people on the video must be on drugs since there are so few bottles or glasses seen.

&#34;Flour gang&#34; has instantly became a meme here, even though it&#39;s now unclear 1. whether &#34;flour&#34; is actually Finnish drug lingo, or whether it has ever been used to refer to powder drugs here by anyone and 2. whether the words &#34;jauhojengi&#34; are actually used - the video features people dancing to and singing washed-up pop rapper Petri Nyg책rd&#39;s lyrics for the old hit song &#34;Selv채 p채iv채&#34; (&#34;Sober day&#34;), which is about, as you might guess, drinking. (You can find [translated lyrics](https://lyricstranslate.com/en/selv%C3%A4-p%C3%A4iv%C3%A4-sober1-day.html) here if you really wish.) The word heard as &#34;jauho&#34; might well instead be a reference to &#34;jallu&#34;, or Jaloviina, an iconic Finnish booze brand that&#39;s 50 % brandy and 50 % vodka and features in a metric ton of local music.

Several medias took the whole &#34;flour gang&#34; thing and ran with it, probably one reason being that earlier in the week they were criticized for going too easy on Marin and her government. Now others are attacking media for pushing a theory originally spread (at least on Twitter) by conspiracy theorist accounts that have otherwise taken a pro-Russian narratie. Yes, there are even references to whole thing being a Russian disinfo campaign.

Marin has herself [had to comment on this](https://www.theglobeandmail.com/world/article-finnish-pm-sanna-marin-says-no-drugs-just-lots-of-dancing-at-wild/), saying that she is disappointed in the video leaking, that she only had mild alcoholic drinks and doesn&#39;t use drugs and that she&#39;s willing to even take a drug test (not that it would show cocaine use anyway, more than a few days having passed from the party). Of course it still might turn out one or more of the celeb entourage members have been on drugs, who knows?

All in all, it would probably be the best if the PM quit back on partying or at least chose better friends to avoid embarassing stuff leaking out (also, you know, for general security reasons), the first rule of the Flour Gang is to never talk about the Flour Gang, PMs should find better music to dance to than a local whiteboy 50 Cent and politics here can indeed be as dumb as anywhere else, especially with the social media and stuff.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikswpuv/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>