<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-31T19:05:00Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis</title><updated>2022-08-31T19:05:00Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">So, fellow Europoors, what&#39;s the status of the electricity/cost-of-living crisis in your hoods?

Finland is getting hit less than Central Europe, but getting hit nevertheless. We haven&#39;t been \*quite\* as dependent on Russian power than many other countries - Russian gas was only 5 % of the energy supply, Russians cut the flow already back in May, and in general Russian electricity imports have formed 10 % of the Finnish electricity use. However, prices are still expected to rise very high in the winter, naturally the season when the society most needs electricity and has to import it.

The crisis is particularly - as everywhere else - hitting those living in detached housing. Even though district heating and, lately, geothermal are increasingly popular for heating, and an increasing amoung of air-source heat pumps have been installed there&#39;s still a lot of them relying on direct electric heating, which on current terms translates to &#34;pay up the nose&#34;. Such houses might well see electricity bills hitting well over a thousand a month, unless nothing is done.

Among various issues:

\- Nordic electricity generation is reliant on water power, and though the Nordic countries haven&#39;t seen droughts on the Central European level, these are still affecting water power generation. Finland has imported electricity from Norway, and now the Norwegians are mulling restricting [electricity exports](https://www.helsinkitimes.fi/finland/finland-news/domestic/22095-lintilae-norway-restricting-electricity-exports-would-play-into-putin-s-hands.html).

\- There would still be a chance to avoid the worst of it - if the Olkiluoto 3 nuclear generator goes fully online before the schedule, or at least is not delayed any more. Olkiluoto 3 has been the white whale of nuclear projects for years now, incredibly delayed and costly project that is now in test use, with those tests also frequently facing unplanned downtimes. The current estimate for Olkiluoto 3 finally starting commercial use is December 2022, but we&#39;ll see. In particular having OL3 being online and without issues would lead to stability - less need to worry about whether winter&#39;s particularly cold and how windy/sunny it is for renewables.

\- While browsing Twitter, I&#39;ve seen a fair amount of what can only be described as &#39;schadenfreude&#39; by pro-Russian right-wingers in various countries mocking Europeans with high energy bills and Ukraine flags in the profile photo. There&#39;s next to none of that here, as the entire Finnish society continues to be broadly pro-Ukrainian. I haven&#39;t seen any major political actors suggesting trying to make nice with Russia as a solution, of course it would be hard to do that by our lonesome anyway as long as we&#39;re a part of the EU, and Russians might tell us to pound sand anyway.

\- The environmental aspect is, of course, a big local culture war, especially in a country where much (most?) of the culture war has been environmentalism-related for a long time. It&#39;s not an easy question, non-/anti-environmentalists say that of course when you do things to drive up the costs of polluting the prices of electricity (which cannot really be produced in any way without \*some\* pollution) environmentalists claim that without the environmental measures the situation would be worse, comparing us to Britain where the junking of &#34;green crap&#34; led to end to insulation efforts or to countries that are more dependent on fossil fuels than us.

\- There&#39;s a back-up power reserve including, among others, Finland&#39;s last electricity-generation-oriented coal plant (other coal plants mainly generate heat). It&#39;s pretty certain that if it comes to firing up the power reserve or rolling blackouts, the power reserve is going to be fired up - that&#39;s what reserves are for, after all - but there are calls to do this already at this point with the electric bills going up, and apparently there are difficulties related to this, such as the fact that the said coal plant would need some heavy maintenance to bring back up.

\- much of the price rise is caused by market issues, Finland being a part of the European electric grid and thus being affected by the comparatively larger issues of the other countries, the sheer uncertainty of the situation hiking up the futures, and so on. Of course, if nations like Norway restrict exports, there&#39;s just going to be a domino effect with it being easier and easier for other nations to do the same when necessity calls. It&#39;s hard to see these sorts of crises as anything less than further evidence in the breakdown of globalization, unless it alternatively finally becomes the crisis the European elites can use to enact the European federation.

The government is planning measures to alleviate the crisis. Currently, the news are reporting that they&#39;re considering a measure for a tax rebate on bills over 500€ / month and a cut on the electricity VAT, as well as some less defined measure to help the poorest families and some throw-ins like doubled child benefits etc.

To me, this seems counterproductive - like tailormade to help the most energy-consumptive housing and the least-well off, but leaving large urban middle classes living in flats or in less-consumptive detached housing with only the VAT benefit. If we want to actually avoid rolling blackouts, and unless there&#39;s some measures that will lead to a lot of new electricity fast, it would seem we&#39;d need to find some ways to reduce electricity use while ensuring that this won&#39;t break family budgets. That might mean models like guaranteeing a certain fixed price for electricity use under some ceiling and leaving market prices in force above that.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imk54ww/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>