<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-02T16:21:39Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxepcr/</id><title type="text">[CW] I am not sure if this is CW Roundup material, but it did not feel like it should</title><updated>2022-06-02T16:21:39Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I am not sure if this is CW Roundup material, but it did not feel like it should go elsewhere, so here it goes.

How many have been following the #Swedengate thing? It started with someone posting on Reddit (and this subsequently [screenshotted on Twitter](https://twitter.com/SamQari/status/1529868644846641153)) about how, as a child, they were not offered dinner when playing at their Swedish friend&#39;s place. This was then confirmed as a Swedish (and, to some degree, a general Nordic) custom by other posters. Much bewilderment and condemnation of the Swedish culture as a child-starving horror show has followed, by other Europeans as well as non-Europeans.

I recognize the no-dinner custom from my own Finnish childhood, I do not recollect ever being offered dinner when at one of my friend&#39;s place or vice versa, or ever asking for it. Now, there is some confusion about the specific nature of &#34;dinner&#34;. Even if there is no dinner, I do not remember like there is no food offered to guests \*at all\*, when people visit each other, there is going to be snacks or cake or whatever, even copious amounts of it. Perhaps the Swedes are different? In certain ways the Swedes are the most “Nordic” of all Nordics. At least if you consider how many non-Nordics see Nordics as prim, proper and quietly smugly arrogant, well, that’s how other Nordics see the Swedes.

It is obvious that at other places of the world, if there was a child of some other family playing at your place, they will get invited for dinner as a matter of course. Like with all “social norms,” it is not like they are uniformly observed by the entire society. Looking at local discussions, I have seen many people claim amazement over idea. It should be noted that within Finland, there seems to be an internal division between Eastern Finland and Western Finland, perhaps the main cultural regions of Finland (this division even shows in [Finnish genetics](https://www.fimm.fi/en/research/projects/finnpopgen)). I’m firmly from Eastern Finland, which is less like Sweden and more like the rest of the world, so maybe Westerners are more firm about not serving food to those outside family?

In the end, it all goes back to one of the strongest, yet often conscious, norms of Nordic life: it is shameful for an adult individual to be dependent on another individual, and it is shameful to make another adult individual dependent on you.

This norm leads to the peculiar Nordic idea of individualism meeting collectivism. Of course, the “individualism” part of this is obvious, one can fundamentally obviously see how this norm creates a society of strong individuals (and families). However, the collectivism aspect is that the same norm is a major building block of the welfare state. It is not OK to depend on another \*individual\* or make them dependent on you… but impersonal institutions are a whole another thing!

Everyone needs a helping hand at times, and it is completely different, in this thinking, if the helping hand is provided by a community that you are a part of and contribute to, not a specific person. In the old times, the community would of course usually be your local village/town, or parish (often the same thing), and later strong societies were created around trade unions, which used to function in a manner not unlike a guild in the pre-welfare-state times, with extensive networks of mutual services, ranging from mutual funds to sports to newspapers and such.

Nowadays, the welfare state, usually conceptualized as an entire nation forming a similar community, serves the same role. The expectation is precisely that there is a social contract; when you can work and at your prime, you work hard, and in exchange the state provides the “safety net” for the times when you cannot do this. Debates on where the line goes between something being a legit utilization of this social contract and when it becomes mooching off the society – a cardinal sin – are extremely common in local political debates, and grist for the press.

Now, I specifically mentioned “adults” here, and obviously children need adults to sustain them, and there is nothing wrong with it. However, the idea is then that it is specifically a family’s job to sustain their child. This then creates the second-order effects that are noted here; the other family feels uncomfortable giving a dinner to the child, since it might make the child’s parents feel like the other family is making them moochers. Likewise, the child themselves might refuse dinner, if offered – if they have already internalized the unconscious social norms behind all this.

Once one realizes that this is the norm, it is easy to see why certain other things separating the Nordic countries from others exist. For instance, when people go to bars, they buy their own drinks; buying rounds is rare, unless there is a special event (or you are drunk enough for norms to not matter). People on dates buy their own dinners. Tipping is almost non-existent. Domestic services are not utilized as much as they could be cleaning companies put up little notices on their home pages that you do not need to clean up before the cleaning person comes in.

Adult children leave their parents’ homes as soon as they can after adulthood, and the adults practically push them out the nest. It’s probably also one of the reasons why feminism made such fast headway in the North – Nordic feminism has always been very much a movement oriented around getting women to work so they don’t have to be dependent on their husbands and other men. And so on.

Of course, put it this way and it sounds like total moon logic, considering that the easiest thing to do would be just, you know, feeding the child. This all works out on an unconscious level, and that is one of the reasons these habits are on their way out. Other reasons would be the general “Europeanization” of Nordic cultures, as the EU has a habit of slowly grinding away the edges of all national cultures towards an undefined, bland and gray “European” ideal). Immigration also probably plays a role, my feeling from Twitter comments is that it is immigrant-background Swedes who feel the most strongly the tradition does not exist or that they have not encountered it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/iaxepcr/"/></entry></feed>