<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-25T16:50:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilr6qag/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Culture war in Finland: **Stupidest day in Finnish politics turns into the dumbe</title><updated>2022-08-25T16:50:47Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Culture war in Finland: **Stupidest day in Finnish politics turns into the dumbest week**

So, Finland continues to bask in foreign attention due to the [prime minister&#39;s party scandal](https://alakasa.substack.com/p/the-stupidest-day-in-finnish-politics), with PM Sanna Marin currently ranking higher in [Google Trends than Taylor Swift.](https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?q=%2Fg%2F12vzpszb7,%2Fm%2F0dl567)

Developments during the week:

\- People continue to analyze the Instagram videos of Marin dancing, finding some indications that there might, indeed, have been drug use, ie. some people can faintly be heard talking in Finnish drug lingo and so on. Nothing conclusive, and the police announce that [they don&#39;t suspect foul play](https://news.yahoo.com/finnish-police-not-action-against-095348944.html/) related to videos. [Marin took a drug test](https://yle.fi/news/3-12588465), but since it&#39;s an urine test and not a hair test, critics claim it proves nothing.

\- Some major other local discussions: why wasn&#39;t Marin [formally on holiday when partying](https://yle.fi/news/3-12583726)? what if the Russians had attacked while she was drunk, or if there had been a crisis equivalent to the [MS Estonia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sinking_of_the_MS_Estonia) ship disaster? (Note: Russia has actually sent most of the troops in the Northwestern area to Ukraine, and Finnish crisis laws are written in a way that would nevertheless enable reacting to crises even if she had actually been in complete blackout mode.) Are the celebrities that Marin partied with high-status enough? (They&#39;re basically Instagram influencers and pop stars, and 5-10 years younger than 36-year-old Marin)? Is it all just media effort to get clicks and try to demonstrate they&#39;re not going easy on Marin for being young and female and leftist?

\- Marin was also accused of cheating on her husband (and the father of her child) when a [video turned out](https://www.is.fi/politiikka/art-2000009015380.html) where she&#39;s dancing with a guy (actually locally quite famous actor/singer Olavi Uusivirta) who is totally trying to get his mack on. I wouldn&#39;t say the video shows her cheating, unless she and her husband have agreed the other party can&#39;t even dance with the opposite sex. At least as far as I&#39;ve interpreted it, she&#39;s not really responding to her attempts and (I would guess) gently tells him to stop trying at some point. When asked about this video, Marin said that she thought Uusivirta &#34;was trying to whisper her something&#34;, which is quite silly, but a friend of mine, when we talked about the scandal, said that she probably phrased it that way since if she had said &#34;Olavi Uusivirta was trying to lick my neck even though I said no&#34; it would probably have been a career-ender for him, rather than her.

\- It turns out that two of Marin&#39;s celeb friends took a picture of themselves kissing while topless at Marin&#39;s official residence in Kesäranta, ie. Finland&#39;s Downing Street 11. This was widely considered to be inappropiate due to the official status of the location, as well as due to the idea that there might have been state secrets in the apartment. (One columnist even compared it to January 6, lol. If you want evidence about the mental American colonization of European politics...) [Marin promptly apologized](https://yle.fi/news/3-12589779).

\- There&#39;s a ton of news about this in foreign media, which is a huge thing in Finland in itself, since Finland is a country of 5,5 million people and, as such countries often tend to do, is hugely interested in all the cases where it is mentioned outside of its own borders, as [this meme, for instance](https://memegenerator.net/img/instances/400x/12412665.jpg), indicates. (I&#39;ve heard that New Zealanders, for instance, behave the same way). Foreign coverage, like [this article](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2022/aug/24/finlands-pm-is-a-young-woman-in-power-her-partying-is-the-total-opposite-of-disgrace?CMP=share_btn_fb), seems to range from &#34;look at this hot PM&#34; to &#34;is this a plot by Putin&#34; to &#34;haha, it turns out that Finns are stuffy and conservative for hating their PM for dancing&#34;. As I&#39;ve noted, the actual criticisms aren&#39;t really as much about dancing as about the possibility of drug use in her vicinity and about the crises.

\- [Marin gives a tearful address](https://yle.fi/news/3-12591456) in Social Democratic party meeting, saying &#34;I am a human being. In the midst of the crisis, I have been thinking about Ukraine and about all of you&#34; (the [rest of her speech was about Ukraine](https://yle.fi/news/3-12589250) and shows the hardening of opinions in Finland about Russia, it wasn&#39;t just a random statement).

I&#39;m guessing that if there&#39;s not something new and conclusive turning up, the scandal is going to start dying, but of course something new and conclusive might very well turn up. Finnish social medias have been abuzz with constant suggestions there&#39;s new videos moving on around, including one journalist claiming that a video in the &#34;Thor network&#34; showing drug use, but this turning out to be a prank.

(edit: edited in a paragraph about the dancing video with Uusivirta)</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilr6qag/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>