<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-04T19:28:52Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiyg6o3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW]  Finland’s NATO quest, still probably globally the most important development th</title><updated>2022-08-04T19:28:52Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text"> Finland’s NATO quest, still probably globally the most important development this country is a part of, is advancing. The [US Senate just voted to confirm](https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/03/us/politics/sweden-finland-nato-senate-vote.html) Finland and Sweden as NATO members. Of course, the vote was a bit of a formality with a predestined result and a 95-1 vote, with Josh Hawley the only senator opposing. It should be noted that [Hawley’s perspective](https://www.hawley.senate.gov/hawley-op-ed-why-i-wont-vote-add-sweden-and-finland-nato) is by no means an isolationist one, let alone pacifist, but rather the argument is that the European countries are not pulling their weight on defence and that US should focus on the China threat anyhow.

Now, Hawley is, of course, entitled to his opinion, and it’s hardly my task from Finland to dictate that US has some sort of a duty to be allied to Finland if they don&#39;t wish so (of course, the votes of the other senators and Congress in general indicate otherwise). NATO membership might currently be popular in Finland, but it’s hardly without issues, as recounted [here](https://jacobin.com/2022/04/finland-nato-russia-ukraine-invasion-putin-sweden) – and out of the raised fears, Turkey has certainly proved that it can get [troublesome](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jun/30/erdogan-warns-turkey-could-still-block-finland-and-swedens-accession-to-nato). 

Certainly I&#39;ve seen some pro-NATO voices say that they are less positive on the organization than before Erdogan started issuing his demands and that they don&#39;t consider the organization worth it if it means having to junk longstanding human rights policies, like extraditing people without due process simply because another country demands it.

However, slam-dunk as the US approval was, Hawley’s given reasoning still seem like they need commenting. It’s not a new idea that many in the US think will focus on the Pacific sector and away from Europe is not a new one. However, one would think that such a development would precisely, at least within conventional geopolitical logic, be predicated by Europe becoming militarily more independent from the United States. It’s hard to imagine how adding the Finnish army to the mix would increase this dependence.

While many European countries indeed have not had their defence budgets at 2 % of the GDP, as Hawley himself noted, Finland has just recently [increased this budget considerably](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-05/finland-adds-2-2-billion-defense-spending-in-shadow-of-war) to match this limit. This was during the most left-wing and thus most anti-militarist government constellation that is currently realistically possible in Finland, and the more right-wing and conservative parties in the opposition would, if anything, support even larger military budgets. 

Since much of the new budget spending consists of material procurement with long-term orders, it’s going to be sticky for at least the coming decade. There’s an issue in comparing the military budgets of different countries, as NATO counts several things in military budgets that Finland currently does not count, such as military pensions, as mentioned [here](https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/04/14/what-finland-can-offer-nato/), for example.

Finland has specifically traditionally based its defense mainly on land forces and solutions that are not \*that\* expensive, ie. do not require high-tech weapons platforms. In particular, the FDF has concentrated on building up its artillery, with the [strongest artillery in Western Europe](https://www.hitc.com/en-gb/2022/05/13/finland-has-53rd-strongest-military-but-artillery-capability-sets-them-apart/). Precisely this war in Ukraine has shown that the era for such traditional armies is not in the past, and indeed the current phase of the war, by all accounts, seems to be one where artillery continues to be the king, with Russians blasting away at Ukrainians and Ukraine seeking to even the score using HIMARS. As many have noted, this war is basically exactly the one FDF has always trained for.

Of course, one might reasonably ask still whether FDF would still need copious naval and air support from other countries, chiefly the US. The Finnish Navy is… well, not really the mainstay of the Finnish defence, and the air force, even with F35s, has generally not been expected to hold its own independently against Russia. 

That score is considerably evened by the fact that the pacakge deal also includes Sweden, a country with weak land forces but a stronger navy and particularly air force. The Finnish and Swedish armed forces just fit together quite well, which has been one of the reasons why one of the main alternatives conceived to NATO in Finnish debates has just been a formal defence alliance with Sweden.

All told, while a real case might be made, within American context, for opposing the expansion of NATO, Hawleys’ arguments don’t really give an impression of such a stance - mainly that there’s political credit to be had in portraying yourself as an anti-hawk on Russia in a situation where there is room on the American right for that niche.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiyg6o3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>