<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-13T10:32:20Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/com</title><updated>2022-07-13T10:32:20Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vlopk0/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_27_2022/ie5imbr/?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) thread on vaccines and birth rates collapsing in many countries, since it just struck me (after reading some other discussions about it, admittedly) that it&#39;s quite odd neither me or the other posters considered one very obvious explanation: it&#39;s the vaccinations!

...and by that I mean not the vaccines themselves, but the vaccination process; at least in Finland, the local authorities [explicitly recommended](https://yle-fi.translate.goog/uutiset/3-11750453?_x_tr_sl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;amp;_x_tr_hl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp) that women avoid pregnancy for two months (note: for some reason Google Translate translates it as a &#34;couple of months&#34;, but Finnish text talks about two months) after vaccination. I&#39;m not sure whether other countries had similar recommendations, but I&#39;d imagine at least some did.

Of course, the &#34;birth gaps&#34; noted are longer than two months, but similar recommendations might generally make people get antsy about the prospect of pregnancy, and so might the fact that even people who get vaccinated might well encounter a lot of antivaxx posts about the dangers of vaccination and pregnancy and thus be less willing to get pregnant. Who knows, something like that might ironically create a permanent effect \*even if\* it turns out the vaccine itself does not create major pregnancy risks.

Is there any info about various countries and their official vaccination/pregnancy recommendations, or any other way to test this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>