<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Stefferi - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-14T14:33:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Stefferi" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig4rlyd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Yglesias: [How Hillary Clinton unleashed the Great Awokening](https://www.slowbo</title><updated>2022-07-14T14:33:32Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Yglesias: [How Hillary Clinton unleashed the Great Awokening](https://www.slowboring.com/p/how-hillary-clinton-unleashed-the)

&amp;gt;Part of the issue here is that Democrats have consistently chosen to interpret the fact that Trump is a scumbag as indicating that Trump is an ideological extremist, when these are just different questions. But I think in some ways the bigger and more unconsidered issues have to do with how the 2016 primaries played out. In particular, Clinton got spooked by Bernie Sanders’ stronger-than-expected early showing and decided to respond by outflanking him to the left on social issues. I believe that this backfired and caused Sanders to do better with moderate Democrats than he otherwise would have done and also bolstered his popularity with the general electorate.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;But both Clinton and Sanders seemingly believed that her efforts in this regard were highly effective.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;After the primaries, the Sanders team decided they needed to outflank the establishment by moving even further left on identity issues, and the establishment decided that front-loading identity issues was their ticket to holding an incipient socialist takeover at bay. So while the question in the 2016 primary was something like, “should we move left on identity or on economics?” the answer ended up being, “let’s do both.”

I think this comports with what I observed following, for instance, various Sanders groups in 2016. Sanders started by having, genuinely a bunch of fans who can be described as &#34;Bernie bros&#34; and didn&#39;t have particularly woke views on social issues, even if they probably could be described as generic liberals. Polls showed that Bernie had fans among \*both\* left-wing and moderate Democrats, and served, to some degree at least, as a general stop-Hillary, throw-the-bums-out candidate in the primary; Yglesias fingers Iraq War as the big issue which lessened Hillary&#39;s popularity. Pretty soon Hillary team responded by highlighting social issues (the &#34;Would that end racism?&#34;) speech and, upon losing, Sanders team decided that they must outflank this outflanking in 2020, contributing to a purity spiral.

The title might be wrong, some have stated that the beginning of the &#34;awokening&#34; is in 2012-2013 with Trayvon Martin case and so on, but this doesn&#39;t necessarily conflict with the idea that the 2016 Democratic primary is also a pivotal movement - the 2012-2013 period might have well created the necessary preconditions for the dynamic where the most natural reaction to a challenge is generally trying to outflank the challenger from the left on social issues.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig4rlyd/?sort=confidence"/></entry><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/com</title><updated>2022-07-13T10:32:20Z</updated><author><name>Stefferi</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I just have to return to a [two-weeks-old](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vlopk0/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_june_27_2022/ie5imbr/?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) thread on vaccines and birth rates collapsing in many countries, since it just struck me (after reading some other discussions about it, admittedly) that it&#39;s quite odd neither me or the other posters considered one very obvious explanation: it&#39;s the vaccinations!

...and by that I mean not the vaccines themselves, but the vaccination process; at least in Finland, the local authorities [explicitly recommended](https://yle-fi.translate.goog/uutiset/3-11750453?_x_tr_sl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;amp;_x_tr_hl=fi&amp;amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp) that women avoid pregnancy for two months (note: for some reason Google Translate translates it as a &#34;couple of months&#34;, but Finnish text talks about two months) after vaccination. I&#39;m not sure whether other countries had similar recommendations, but I&#39;d imagine at least some did.

Of course, the &#34;birth gaps&#34; noted are longer than two months, but similar recommendations might generally make people get antsy about the prospect of pregnancy, and so might the fact that even people who get vaccinated might well encounter a lot of antivaxx posts about the dangers of vaccination and pregnancy and thus be less willing to get pregnant. Who knows, something like that might ironically create a permanent effect \*even if\* it turns out the vaccine itself does not create major pregnancy risks.

Is there any info about various countries and their official vaccination/pregnancy recommendations, or any other way to test this?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifz3f8z/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>