<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/stucchio - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-27T12:43:37Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/stucchio" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihufhe3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In 2017 Trump gave a [speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vwa0vC6mBuU) that </title><updated>2022-07-27T12:43:37Z</updated><author><name>stucchio</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In 2017 Trump gave a [speech](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vwa0vC6mBuU) that was very different from most of his other speeches. He talked in great detail about inefficiencies in the federal permitting process - applications being evaluated sequentially instead of in parallel, regulators dragging their feet with delays, no centralized dashboard to figure out where you are in the process.

Unlike most of his speeches, this one fit [Scott&#39;s early characterization of Trump](https://slatestarcodex.com/2016/03/19/book-review-the-art-of-the-deal/): &#34;the effect was that of an infodump from an autistic child with a special interest in real estate development.&#34;

Shortly after saying that, a bunch of reporters ignored the speech he gave and started asking him about racism.

About a year ago, Ron DeSantis passed [HB 1059](https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2021/1059) and no one seems to be talking about it. HB 1059 is important. Things it does:

* Localities have 30 days to respond to your housing permit application. Exceeding 30 days means they have to refund 10% of your application fee per day. (This is single family homes, rules and time periods are a bit different for bigger projects.)
* If your application is declared incomplete, and you make it complete, localities have 10 days to approve/reject. If the city takes 11 days, that&#39;s another 20% off the permit fee.
* Cities must post the entire process on an online dashboard for tracking.
* Counties must post a list of all required attachments, drawings, or other requirements for each type of application, on its website, as well as explicitly outline the procedures for approval/denial. (This makes it very easy to both a) submit a valid application and b) sue if the county denies improperly.)

As per an [analysis in the WaPo](https://archive.ph/aXfCK), it&#39;s working. Permit processing rates (in 30 days) have gone from 47% to 80%, 100% in some places. This is enabling a lot more housing permits.

At this point, it seems that to very little fanfare, Ron DeSantis has become a great champion of YIMBY.

While his culture war antics may get press (and cause YIMBY activities to ignore him cause &#34;ewww&#34;) DeSantis also appears to be a person actively focused on the details of governance. This is something something that should get significantly more attention than it actually does.

“Permit reform doesn’t sound glamorous. They won’t write stories about it; they won’t talk about it, but it is so important,” - Trump</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihufhe3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>