<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/surpriseeggyolk - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-05-29T08:42:13Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/surpriseeggyolk" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaeo3hw/</id><title type="text">[SQ] I have a hard time understanding why many people seem to find golden-rule style </title><updated>2022-05-29T08:42:13Z</updated><author><name>surpriseeggyolk</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">I have a hard time understanding why many people seem to find golden-rule style arguments convincing. Basically why &#34;But what if everyone acted like that?&#34; should be a good rebuttal to anything. For one if everyone suddenly had (or at least expressed) the same preferences many aspects of our economy would stop functioning. Everyone loves pumpkins all of a sudden? Good look finding affordable pumpkins. This example is a little silly but I think you get my point, diversity of preferences isn&#39;t a bad thing.

 The other aspect is someone doing something &#34;bad&#34; like purchasing a ticket for a cheap flight when they could have used the train. This is causally linked to increased greenhouse gas emissions which is causally linked to more extreme weather events, rising ocean levels and so on. But would the decision to not buy the plane ticket cause one less storm? One less nanometer in sea level rise? All other things being equal this specific person´s decision does not matter at all in the grand scheme of things. It only matters if many people choose to change their lifestyle in some pretty dramatic ways. And so far there is very little evidence of that happening at sufficient scale. So why should anyone be obliged to be the first? Why is there a moral duty to do something that seems to only cause you discomfort with zero benefit (since not enough people are likely to join you). 

Of course this is frustrating and it is a kind of a catch-22. Because everyone thinks that not enough people will join few people make the first step, which causes the majority to think that not enough people will join and so on. But does that make the assessment on the individual level wrong? Can you derive a moral duty to act from this? I think you can argue that politicians have a duty to act on this but I really don&#39;t see why individuals with their (individually) low-impact choices should be compelled to do anything but act in their own self-interest.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v053ii/smallscale_question_sunday_for_may_29_2022/iaeo3hw/"/></entry></feed>