<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TaiaoToitu - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T20:56:57Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TaiaoToitu" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im6axzq/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Catching up on a range of things at the moment, so apologies for being so late t</title><updated>2022-08-28T20:56:57Z</updated><author><name>TaiaoToitu</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Catching up on a range of things at the moment, so apologies for being so late to the party on this one: Regarding the discussion around [&#39;What we owe the future&#39;](https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/book-review-what-we-owe-the-future), was there any discussion of discounting future humans I&#39;m the same way we discount future cash flows (though obviously at a different rate)?

The argument about the glass shard strikes me as very odd. Of course it makes a difference if the child comes 5 days hence or a millennia. Within a few years we can probably expect the shard to be buried and rendered harmless. Within a century we can assign a reasonably high probability that the forest track has changed route due to natural subsidences etc. Within a millennia, who knows if any humans will be around at all? So valuing a clear and present threat equally with some theoretical future one seems utterly absurd to me.

Just as the impact of any action we might take is affected by compounding uncertainties, human life is also. Is it not clear that the life of somebody actually alive today is worth more than somebody who&#39;s parents are yet to be born? As one looks further forward, there is less certainty that the hypothetical people your action seeks to aid actually exist! Or even if they do, maybe they are genocidal maniacs that killed your descendants, or otherwise so alien in their values that you wouldn&#39;t Uncertainty in both regards compounds over time.

People obviously care deeply about their grand kids, and thinking of the US Revolution for example, have been willing to make great sacrifices to secure a future for many generations of strangers to come. The discount rate need not be extreme, and probably properly even varies depending on the circumstance (discounting one&#39;s own descendants less steeply than those of your extended family/community/nation/culture/species for example). Of course, one need not do this formally or numerically at all, but if you&#39;re going to build a numerical case for a particular idea, then it seems disingenuous not to at least consider including it as a term.

This sort of thinking is intuitive to me, and I think lines up well as a formalisation of actual human values and behaviour, but I&#39;m curious that I&#39;m not seeing anything like this discussed in the likes of Scott&#39;s OP or follow up &#39;highlights&#39; post for example. Perhaps I&#39;m off base?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wzobg4/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_28_2022/im6axzq/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>