<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Tarnstellung - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-18T22:16:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Tarnstellung" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikutiu1/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [Guessing C For Every Answer Is Now Enough To Pass The New York State Algebra Ex</title><updated>2022-08-18T22:16:58Z</updated><author><name>Tarnstellung</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[Guessing C For Every Answer Is Now Enough To Pass The New York State Algebra Exam](https://medium.com/@newyorkteacher/guessing-c-for-every-answer-is-now-enough-to-pass-the-new-york-state-algebra-exam-93bac55b3e24)

&amp;gt;He wasn’t even present in my classroom for most of three marking periods. At the end of the year, he asked me how he was supposed to pass the state test.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“No problem,” I said. “Just pick all Cs.”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“What?”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;“Try it. I bet it will work.”
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;It worked.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; (...)
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;This problem has a clear solution: make the algebra exam an exam that actually tests a student’s ability to do algebra.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Unfortunately, this solution is difficult to implement. Implementation is difficult because of all the reasons that drove NYSED off the cliffs of insanity in the first place. Look at the incentives. NYSED and local school districts have large financial incentives to graduate as many students as possible. These incentives were put in place by both federal and state legislators who meant well and were trying to encourage good public school performance (good performance == graduation, of course, in their eyes). Teachers and principals have large quality-of-life incentives to pass students. Failing students brings scrutiny, parent and student complaints, superintendent pressure, guidance counselor inquisitions, paperwork, and meeting after meeting. It’s much easier to pass everyone.

TL;DR: The criteria on an exam needed to graduate from high school in New York have been lowered to the point that it can be passed by someone who barely attended class.

I first saw this on /r/slatestarcodex. In [the comments](https://old.reddit.com/r/slatestarcodex/comments/wro3vz/guessing_c_for_every_answer_is_now_enough_to_pass), someone asked why the SAT wasn&#39;t more widely used by universities and employers, given that it is more standardized and objective. A discussion concerning this question would probably move in a &#34;culture war&#34; direction; hence, this post.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikutiu1/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>