<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Texas_Rockets - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T17:46:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Texas_Rockets" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtooq6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;m not sure I agree with the criticisms of Biden&#39;s speech. The speech essential</title><updated>2022-09-02T17:46:36Z</updated><author><name>Texas_Rockets</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not sure I agree with the criticisms of Biden&#39;s speech. The speech essentially functioned to demonize maga republicans. I think his ultimate intent here was to say that a. not all republicans are bad. it&#39;s the maga republicans. and b. that they increasingly pose a serious threat to democracy. i think this also served to actually put a name to that group, because they were previously just regarded as the alt right and there wasn&#39;t much distinction made between republicans and &#39;maga republicans&#39; 

When I read about his speech it seemed to me that he was careful to say that he is not condemning all republicans; it is not that you are a democrat or are evil. 

The narrative surrounding this speech has been that it just fanned existing divisions. but i don&#39;t think that&#39;s the case at all. i think he was trying to alienate those on the far right and create a broader coalition and appeal to more moderate republicans. specifically, i don&#39;t think the intent was to broaden divisions, i think the intent was to frame existing divisions in a more precise light, by saying that it is not left v right it is sane people v maga republicans, which i support. 

and for the record i do agree that maga republicans pose an existential threat to this country. fascism, if you look into it, is actually an incredibly complex political ideology that doesn&#39;t really fit within the current framework of political ideology. so i don&#39;t really use that term. but trump&#39;s supporters are increasingly defined exclusively by the fact that they are loyal to one man and one man only. they increasingly don&#39;t have any platform or foundation outside of unwavering support for trump. just consider how much trump hammered Clinton for a comparatively mild (but still problematic) transgression of keeping classified information safe, and how his supporters were right there with him on that issue. the guy was so dug in on that issue that he actually increased the penalty for that sort of behavior. and he just did not only that exact thing but took it a step further. yet these people are still with him. he also has literally challenged the fundamental legitimacy of any democratic institution that challenged him or did anything but failed to support him. I mean this guy literally said an election was corrupted solely because he lost. his supporters have also demonstrated a willingness to back Trump&#39;s interest with violence. based on their stances, what underlying principles can possibly be said to undergird trump or his supporters&#39; stances? at a certain point we have to b able to recognize something for what it is. and I&#39;ve also heard that republicans are starting to distance themselves from trump after the revelations of the past month, so the timing of this could end up being fairly astute on biden&#39;s part.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imtooq6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>