<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Texas_Rockets - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-16T17:45:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Texas_Rockets" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjpzhs/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I&#39;ve noticed an interesting shift among the progressive movement lately. I think</title><updated>2022-08-16T17:45:29Z</updated><author><name>Texas_Rockets</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I&#39;ve noticed an interesting shift among the progressive movement lately. I think there&#39;s starting to be a recognition that the fervor and policies born in 2020 were fairly flawed, as evidenced by the legacy of ideas like defund the police, and elections in fairly left areas in which people rejected the progressive candidates in places like NYC, NJ, VA, and SF (the [SF one](https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/05/chesa-boudin-recall-san-francisco-crime/629907/) in particular is interesting. Chesa Boudin really served as a microcosm of progressivism who was given free reign, as were the city council elections that took place around the same time, thus his election served to some extent as a referendum on progressivism).

But what&#39;s interesting is that progressives, in self reflecting and having to analyze why this has occurred, have blamed progressive white people. And to a considerable degree the same thing has been occurring with respect to the policies corporations instituted during 2020. Which is so crazy to me. On the one hand, I agree and find overeducated white progressives who come from wealthy families to be among the most insufferable demographics. But on the other, their only real crime is that they listened to what was being demanded of them, that they be allies and use their supposed privilege to advance the views of anti-racists. It&#39;s kind of like they&#39;re being told &#34;Lol you thought we were serious with all of that stuff? What the fuck is wrong with you?&#34; It sort of validates the view that anti-racists have anti-white undercurrents. Like if they did unambiguously have anti-white undercurrents, how would they respond to the recognition of the ideological excesses of 2020? They would blame white people. Like if you’re a white progressive and want to support movements and ideas like that, at this point I don’t know what the fuck you’re supposed to do. If you don’t support it you’re part of the problem as identified by people you agree with, and if you do support it you’re going to be the scape goat when shit goes south and it becomes clear that the policies you supported to advance the ends you were told to advance were deeply flawed.

I think it also reveals a lack of strategy on the part of people working to advance those ideas, even within their own paradigm. Their view is that white people wield disproportionately more institutional power than non-white people do, so if that’s true you would want those people with outsized power and who agree with you to use that power to advance your ends. But instead they are condemning them and de-incentivizing their participation. It just seems very counterintuitive.

I think it really comes down to the fact that activists are insatiable. when they’re actually given the reins, asked what exactly they want, and allowed to implement policies, they don’t actually know. or if they do have proposals it&#39;s always impractically radical stuff that only makes sense to the small group of people who agree with them like just razing institutions and starting over or defunding the police or something equally as bizzare. it reminds me a lot of the occupy wall street people. They’re the dog that caught the car. They aren’t there to actually catch the car, they’re there to chase the car. implementing the change that they desire requires an understanding of things as they are (you have to understand the problem before you can develop a solution), but activists’ characteristic commitment to ideology precludes them from interpreting the world or developing solutions that go even a bit outside the scope of their ideology. Like can anyone seriously envision a series of events and policies that would have caused BLM to be like &#39;welp. that&#39;s pretty much what we were asking for. you did it and solved the problem. guess we can just pack up our shit and go home.&#39; like even over the course of their ideas being implemented over 10 years I can&#39;t envision that occurring. 

Progressive activists are the dog that caught the car, and once they caught the car and fucked it away they blamed it on the person who served as the distraction that slowed the car down and opened the door for the dog to do what it wanted to do. I think this is indicative of intellectual rot and my view is that to some extent the movement has been exposed and they sorta blew it when they had the spotlight.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wos3do/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_15_2022/ikjpzhs/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>