<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TheCoachSpo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T13:20:01Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TheCoachSpo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American R</title><updated>2022-08-01T13:20:01Z</updated><author><name>TheCoachSpo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">The TPUSA conference tipped its hand about the cultural direction the American Right might be moving in. Tons of interviews, speeches, etc from prominent conservatives suggesting that it would be best for America to embrace Christian Nationalism. This raised some alarms; there is strong research connecting Evangelicals to conspiracies such as QAnon (among others) that could eventually lead to danger or even violence (ex: Jan 6th, the 26% of W. Evangelicals who &#34;agree that true American patriots might have to resort to violence in order to save our country.&#34; - PRRI).   
My question: How much of a threat does the Christian Right pose to American democracy and peace? A shrinking demographic who may believe they are losing their country, when paired with their renowned civic activism and news media that reinforces their increasingly conspiratorial beliefs, might just be the recipe for outbreaks of political violence. Needless to say, this trend of the Christian Right has me sincerely concerned.

I also want to quickly get out there that [Gordon Wood](https://moodle2.units.it/pluginfile.php/366505/mod_resource/content/1/Conspiracy%20and%20the%20Paranoid%20Style.pdf) and [Richard Hofstadter](https://harpers.org/archive/1964/11/the-paranoid-style-in-american-politics/) did some pretty well-known work on American/Colonial paranoia, suggesting that the colonists (many of whom had strong religious ties) viewed history as moments caused by individual actors rather than a stream of events. This allows them to attribute moral responsibility to bad actors and in doing so reveals how the good deed/bad deed doctrine of many Christian denominations might make believers more susceptible to conspiracy theories. After all, conspiracies are based on an idea that a small cabal of people are plotting something nefarious, like the Hellish plot of #PizzaGate.  
Woods suggested that this &#34;individual actor&#34; thinking still runs strong in American veins. If so, am I being overdramatic in [this short essay](https://coachspo.substack.com/p/an-american-conspiracy-movement-that) where I claim that Christian Right conspiracies pose a significant threat to American safety?  
A helpful recap of my essay: &#34;I believe there are warning signs around us. The size of the Religious Right is perpetually underrated in America and they are adopting conspiracy theories at a startling pace. What’s more, these theories are dangerous precisely because they promote the idea that White Christians are losing their status and identity. As Professor Walter proposed, when this happens the chance that a nation falls into violence or a Civil War only increases. Perhaps it was no coincidence that during the Insurrection the “Heavenly Father” was prayed to on the senate floor.&#34;</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii5pwd/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>