<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TheColourOfHeartache - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-12T09:45:29Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TheColourOfHeartache" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifu5vwr/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] In the UK the Tories are having a new leadership election. For one reason or ano</title><updated>2022-07-12T09:45:29Z</updated><author><name>TheColourOfHeartache</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In the UK the Tories are having a new leadership election. For one reason or another a lot of minority candidates are in the race and people are talking about it. Much of it is presented as a reply to lawyer, full time virtue signalling tweeter, and [fox killer](https://barristerblogger.com/2019/12/26/should-jolyon-maugham-be-prosecuted-for-bludgeoning-a-fox-to-death/) Jolyon Maugham.

[This article](https://www.thenational.scot/news/20267870.jolyon-maugham-sparks-racism-debate-deleted-tweet-sunak/) covers the origin. 

[Of course the Conservative Party could choose an ethnic minority leader](https://capx.co/of-course-the-conservative-party-could-choose-an-ethnic-minority-leader/) says Sunder Katwala

&amp;gt; That ethnic minorities can reach the top of the political ladder matters – but it would certainly not make either Britain or the Conservative party a post-racial nirvana. While it will take more to shift the Conservatives’ share of the ethnic minority vote, the leadership contest sends a powerful symbolic message about the race to the top. The next challenge will be to develop the substantive agenda to deliver on that promise.

[In a more humourous article about poorly air conditioned leadership speeches](https://archive.ph/8pIpT#selection-1559.0-1559.144) Tim Stanley remarks 

&amp;gt; Actually, I think historians will write that the two notable things about this race were, one, it was incredibly diverse and, two, nobody cared.

Rakib Eshan says [The left’s problem with diversity](https://www.spiked-online.com/2022/07/11/the-lefts-problem-with-diversity/)

&amp;gt; The left’s unhealthy obsession with racial identity and ethnic heritage can only do more harm than good. Treating ethnic-minority people not as individuals but as representatives of ethnic groups will only undermine our multi-ethnic democracy.

&amp;gt; Beyond the identitarian game-playing, Britain is grappling with myriad social and economic problems. From the cost-of-living crisis to the endless backlogs in the NHS, the Tories have left numerous open goals for the opposition. The classic conservative message, that family stability and hard work can insulate people from harsh economic conditions, sounds tin-eared at best amid the current crises. These are the bread-and-butter domestic issues that Tory leadership candidates should be challenged on. But instead, the Conservatives’ opponents have been reduced to race-baiting playground behaviour.

Tomiwa Owolade writes for the New Statesman [It’s absurd to say the Conservative Party isn’t ready for a non-white leader](https://www.newstatesman.com/quickfire/2022/07/its-absurd-to-say-the-conservative-party-isnt-ready-for-a-non-white-leader)

&amp;gt; But the third and most pressing point is this: why shouldn’t an ethnic minority person be a Conservative? If we accept that not all ethnic minority people are the same – which should be the first plank of anti-racism – then we have to accept that they do not all share the same political perspective. And nor should they. Political pluralism should be staunchly defended: it is as important an element of diversity as any other.

--------------------

I&#39;d sum up the whole debate like this:

* The left know the Tories are doing better than Labour on diversity at the top so they&#39;re keeping quiet.
* The right don&#39;t care that much, and are mostly talking about taxes and cost of living. (Except Kemi Badenoch whose mostly talking about free speech and culture) But are willing to take a bit of a victory lap to indulge themselves. 
* While everyone writing about this topic is by definition engaging in culture wars. I think you can say that people who mention the fox are more tribal than people who don&#39;t.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ifu5vwr/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>