<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TheGuineaPig21 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-08T03:11:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TheGuineaPig21" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifapav5/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **More drama in the Canadian Conservative party leadership race**

I&#39;ve written </title><updated>2022-07-08T03:11:24Z</updated><author><name>TheGuineaPig21</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**More drama in the Canadian Conservative party leadership race**

I&#39;ve written several posts on the troubles of Canada&#39;s Conservative party ([here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/sgv76g/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_january_31/hvg0wzx/?context=999), [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/sbg7zr/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_january_24/huo263m/?context=999), [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/k8bxy1/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_december_07/gf783sz/?context=999), and presumably elsewhere as well). They&#39;re in the middle of a leadership campaign right now, with Pierre Poilievre as the favourite. I&#39;ve described him as the Canadian equivalent of Ben Shapiro: young, scrappy, no life experience outside of politics, sort of a partisan attack dog, makes youtube compilations of owning the Libs, etc. He&#39;s primarily being opposed by two more moderate candidates: Jean Charest and Patrick Brown. All three candidates were engaged in a veritable arms race of fundraising and signing up new party members to vote.

Or I should say Poilievre *was* being opposed by two moderate candidates. The Conservative Party announced two days ago that Patrick Brown was [being expelled from the leadership contest](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/patrick-brown-ouster-vassy-kapelos-1.6512385) for vague claims of breaching the Elections Act; today a whistleblower came forward to claim that Brown was knowingly using [private funds to pay campaign staff.](https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/whistleblow-brown-disqualification-payment-1.6514122)

Now this might normally be your typical scandal. But it&#39;s creating a lot of speculation because this isn&#39;t the first time that Patrick Brown has been conveniently ousted for a more &#34;true blue&#34; candidate. In 2018 he was the leader of the Ontario Progressive Conservative party heading into a provincial election he was projected to win in a landslide, when, several months before the vote there [emerged allegations of sexual misconduct](https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/patrick-brown-resigns-ontario-pc-1.4503040), and within hours his entire staff had quit. He resigned the next day despite protesting his innocence, and was ultimately replaced by Doug Ford (brother of the dearly departed Rob, and still the Ontario Premier). Ultimately the allegations against Brown all fell apart under scrutiny, and he [won a settlement against CTV News for defamation.](https://globalnews.ca/news/8670496/patrick-brown-story-ctv-correction/) (This is just gossip, but pretty much everyone in the know thinks this episode was a coup orchestrated by Vic Fedeli to oust Brown and prevent him from becoming Premier).

So for Brown to be the victim of yet *another* conveniently timed scandal raises some eyebrows. In fact, the timing is so convenient that [his name will remain on the ballots](https://www.ctvnews.ca/politics/conservative-party-not-printing-new-ballots-despite-patrick-brown-s-disqualification-1.5976994) despite being disqualified. 

I&#39;m not sure what&#39;s true in this story. I must say I have a bias towards Brown and against Poilievre, and certainly it stinks to high heaven that his is happening to him *again*. This isn&#39;t the only recent conservative leadership campaign in Canada to suffer from these kind of shenanigans; Kenney&#39;s leadership bid in Alberta featured all kinds of skullduggery and there was enough bad blood over Andrew Scheer&#39;s win for the federal party that it caused the loser(?) Maxime Bernier to start a schism. The new rules for the leadership race that strongly encourages trying to sign up as many new members as possible (legitimately or not) may be fostering all kinds of nefarious plots. In any case it makes for top-end political popcorn.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifapav5/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>