<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Then_Election_7412 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-09T20:09:40Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Then_Election_7412" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifih61c/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] I&#39;m not interested in the CW aspects of this and more about the social managemen</title><updated>2022-07-09T20:09:40Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">I&#39;m not interested in the CW aspects of this and more about the social management and relationship building aspects:

Yesterday night I was at a party (purely social, alcohol and some other substances involved) in Oakland with some friends and got a bit bored, so I asked someone what their most controversial opinion was. Their response was that... they thought Trump was a criminal and should be in prison, an opinion that was well-received by the group. Which left me in a bit of a pickle when the question turned around to me. So I chickened out and offered something off the wall about non-practicing pedophiles being condemned too harshly by society. Which was a bit spicier, but it was carefully constructed not to be relevant to any hot button issues that would actually be controversial. (Yes, it&#39;s pretty crazy that I felt like a NAMBLA-adjacent opinion is less controversial than saying something like &#34;school shootings aren&#39;t a major issue in our society&#34; or &#34;1/6 wasn&#39;t really important or a threat to our democracy,&#34; but there we are.)

But it got me to thinking: where can I find real-life friends or social settings where there&#39;s actual space for debate and discussion? Luckily my girlfriend is pretty open-minded, but (at least among the friends I&#39;ve made, mostly professionals in the Bay Area) it seems hard to find social spaces that are open to discussion to contentious topics without them devolving into insults or attribution of bad motives to someone.

Or am I just being overly neurotic here? Maybe I should have just stated something actually controversial instead of hoping someone else would, since I brought it up in the first place? In retrospect it was probably unfair for me to ask someone else to go out on a limb when I was too scared to myself...</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vsj44o/wellness_wednesday_for_july_06_2022/ifih61c/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>