<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Then_Election_7412 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T00:09:45Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Then_Election_7412" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizll0b/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Why was Brittney Griner getting paid millions to play basketball in Russia?

It&#39;</title><updated>2022-08-05T00:09:45Z</updated><author><name>Then_Election_7412</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Why was Brittney Griner getting paid millions to play basketball in Russia?

It&#39;s been well-reported how WNBA players are paid: Griner, one of the better players in the league, made something like $220k/year, a relative pittance compared to players in the NBA who typically make millions. Why the pay gap? Perhaps it&#39;s because of systemic sexism. Perhaps it&#39;s because no one watches WNBA games and the NBA subsidizes it to the tune of $10M/year. But I&#39;m less interested in understanding that than why WNBA players can move to Russia in the off season to make millions.

To state the obvious: Russia is not richer than the US; it&#39;s not more populous than the US; Russians are not more into basketball than Americans; and Russians are not big on feminist signaling compared to the US.

So what&#39;s the story with the seven figure payouts? The obvious answer is that Russian women&#39;s basketball is just money laundering, but it&#39;s not clear how women&#39;s basketball would offer a good vehicle for that. Is it oligarchs bringing over accomplished female athletes for salacious reasons? Maybe, but it&#39;s not like Russia is lacking in ballerinas and figure skaters who are genuinely world class in their spheres (and Griner in particular is not the type to be interested in men). And I can&#39;t buy that it&#39;s genuine interest in the sport.

The best answer I&#39;ve been able to come up with is that it&#39;s just a way for Russian oligarchs to show off and compete with each other, but even if so, why settle on women&#39;s basketball of all things?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iizll0b/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>