<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TheWhiteSquirrel - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-29T23:40:53Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TheWhiteSquirrel" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii70gtf/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Has our concept of fundamental rights in the United States changed since the day</title><updated>2022-07-29T23:40:53Z</updated><author><name>TheWhiteSquirrel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Has our concept of fundamental rights in the United States changed since the days of the Founders and/or Reconstruction?

And by that, I mean rights with *bipartisan support*. Certainly, the Red Tribe rejects many rights that the Blue Tribe asserts, perhaps most loudly the right to abortion. And the Blue Tribe also rejects rights that the Red Tribe asserts, perhaps most loudly the right not to vaccinate. I’m talking about whether we have a universal understanding that the scope of fundamental rights can change—whether we can gain new rights that weren’t there before, even if we disagree on which ones.

I’ve been thinking about this in light of the current Supreme Court majority effectively answering this question “no.” In three of their major, controversial cases last month, they applied a definition of fundamental rights that relies on historical tradition. I could cite multiple examples, but here’s Alito in *Dobbs:*

&amp;gt;\[The Due Process Clause\] has been held to guarantee some rights that are not mentioned in the Constitution, but any such right must be &#34;deeply rooted in this Nation’s history and tradition&#34; and &#34;implicit in the concept of ordered liberty.&#34;

In my reading, Alito’s opinion limits the doctrine of “substantive due process” to those rights that have a historical basis in this country. Substantive due process is the doctrine that courts can identify and protect fundamental rights other than the enumerated ones in the Bill of Rights (and later amendments), and it has been used as the basis for SCOTUS decisions in *Ro*e and *Casey*, as well as gay rights cases, marriage rights cases, and more. Alito would apply it more narrowly, to exclude abortion rights. Kavanaugh assures us (without explanation) that the *Dobbs* decision *definitely* doesn’t threaten other substantive due process rights, but Thomas rejects substantive due process entirely.

I disagree with Thomas (at minimum), but for a different reason. I tend to look at rights first through the Ninth Amendment:

&amp;gt;The enumeration in the Constitution, of certain rights, shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people.

It honestly surprises me that this isn’t invoked more in legal arguments because it just comes out and *says* that there are other rights besides the ones that are spelled out--and by extension, they need to be protected. (For example, Justice Arthur Goldberg used it in his concurrence in *Griswold*, but it wasn’t the controlling opinion.)

In practice, I think this may actually be the same as the substantive due process argument. While it reads as an open-ended grant of rights, in order for the Ninth Amendment to have any teeth, a right has to be identified and protected. Protected how? Presumably by due process. The protection that the government may not “deprive any person of life, *liberty*, or property without due process of law” implies that *any* right must be so protected, not just the enumerated ones. But the usual formulation of substantive due process never even mentions 9A. (If it did, it would be a stronger argument against Thomas.)

Except there’s one complication, one that Alito invokes in *Dobbs*, but I think is more obvious when 9A is in play: *Which* rights?

The Ninth Amendment was written in 1791. The Fourteenth Amendment, which is the last Constitutional word on the subject, in 1868. Should they be interpreted, as Alito says, according to historical tradition of what people said fundamental rights were in 1791/1868?

Other amendments have been interpreted broadly to keep up with the times. The right to free speech has been extended to radio, television, and the internet. The right to bear arms has been extended to repeating firearms and then semi-automatics. The right against unreasonable search and seizure has been extended (albeit less successfully) to electronic communications. Should 9A likewise be interpreted broadly to encompass what people say fundamental rights should be today.

No, that’s not exactly the same thing. And given the Culture War dispute on what “rights” exist or should exist, it seems like a moot point. But I think there is a test we can do to point us empirically toward a real answer:

Are there any rights that *both* tribes (in the United States) agree on today, which are not mere extensions of the enumerated rights in the Bill of Rights (or later amendments), *and* were not recognized in 1868, either because social mores have changed or because technology has advanced?

If we can name such a right, that would be evidence not of substantive due process itself, but rather that the way we *think* about fundamental rights today is consistent with the doctrine of substantive due process, either *per se* or as a consequence of 9A. But I’m having trouble thinking of any. I don’t know if that’s because I’m too deep in the Bill of Rights paradigm, or if there aren’t any, or if there *are*, but by definition they aren’t political issues, but I welcome suggestions on the question.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ii70gtf/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>