<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/thisismymilitaryalt - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-05T14:25:21Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/thisismymilitaryalt" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij22sho/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Here&#39;s a list of fun things I&#39;ve discovered trawling historical documents over t</title><updated>2022-08-05T14:25:21Z</updated><author><name>thisismymilitaryalt</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Here&#39;s a list of fun things I&#39;ve discovered trawling historical documents over the last month:

* A Navy civilian employee during the Kennedy administration filed a series of grievances against her supervisor. The resulting investigation, hearings, and appeals eventually generated nearly 5000 pages of documents, or enough to fill about two banker&#39;s boxes. After losing her final appeal, she then requested copies of all associated material and mailed said material to the White House, along with a letter addressed to JFK in which she asked the President to intercede on her behalf and over-rule the appeals board. Nothing I reviewed indicates whether or not JFK ever personally looked into the matter. May we all be so dedicated to the causes we hold dear.

* The DoD once bought 7-figures worth of locomotives for another country only to discover they were incompatible with that country&#39;s existing rail system.

* Two Admirals spent a month arguing whose department would pay for the installation of a $300 telephone system (roughly $2900 dollars today).

* In a DoD survival guide to [REDACTED], service personnel were advised against accepting a &#34;tribal virgin&#34; a friendly tribal chief might offer them, not for ethical reasons, but because a tribal warrior might challenge them to trial-by-combat.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wgmqqy/friday_fun_thread_for_august_05_2022/ij22sho/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>