<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Tophattingson - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-01T12:56:52Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Tophattingson" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/154969215336</title><updated>2022-08-01T12:56:52Z</updated><author><name>Tophattingson</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">According to [a survey by YouGov](https://twitter.com/YouGov/status/1549692153365991424), over the past four years, and particularly over the last two, opinions on trans issues have moved rightward (for lack of a better term) in the UK. The few positions that didn&#39;t move rightward relate to needing doctor&#39;s approval to legally change gender, or not requiring living as your new gender to legally change gender. However, these are two that were already very unpopular, and remain very unpopular, just slightly less, so it may represent changes only within the segment of the population that is very pro trans rights becoming even more pro.

I&#39;ve long suspected (or had as a concern) that existing legislation and institutional support for trans people, changes largely done out of the public eye, is only sustainable via obscurantism. That is to say, if the wider public knew how far the UK had already gone on this topic, that they&#39;d want to roll it back, and the only reason they&#39;re not rolling it back is because they don&#39;t know. Between high-profile trans people in sports, and the escalation of activism in general, they are now increasingly noticing and not liking it. The real nuclear button on this would be treating refusing to date trans people as transphobic, [because the overwhelming majority of people will refuse to date them.](https://www.researchgate.net/publication/325490626_Transgender_exclusion_from_the_world_of_dating_Patterns_of_acceptance_and_rejection_of_hypothetical_trans_dating_partners_as_a_function_of_sexual_and_gender_identity)

This survey result is certainly interesting. It also counters the idea that there&#39;s an ever-leftward drift on all social issues.

As a side not, I&#39;d be interested if anyone can approximate &#34;what percent of the UK&#39;s population would be banned from twitter / other social media if they were to clearly state their views on trans&#34; from the full survey results.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iii2yg0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>