<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/TracingWoodgrains - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-28T12:39:09Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/TracingWoodgrains" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/im4dege/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] (Sort of) New from me: [Anger At Student Loan Cancellation Is Justified](https:/</title><updated>2022-08-28T12:39:09Z</updated><author><name>TracingWoodgrains</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">(Sort of) New from me: [Anger At Student Loan Cancellation Is Justified](https://tracingwoodgrains.substack.com/p/anger-at-student-loan-cancellation?sd=pf)

This essay will be largely familiar to all who read my thoughts on student loans in the culture war thread [two years ago](https://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/jv161w/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_november_16/gckh5ca/?context=999). Given the current salience of the issue, I thought I should revisit and expand the essay to account for the actual loan cancellation announcement. Partially excerpted below, with a focus on sections not included in my original post:

&amp;gt; In other words, it&#39;s not that one already suffered and got theirs, while the other is suffering. It&#39;s that one got their reward (no debt) and the other got theirs (meaningful university experience), and now the second wants to get the first&#39;s reward too. It&#39;s a pure ant and grasshopper story. City Journal calls this the “chump effect”, policy that punishes those who follow prosocial norms while rewarding those who defect, ultimately degrading social trust and eroding those norms. [...]

&amp;gt; In saying all this, I want to be clear: I have no quarrel with those who got a genuine raw deal from college, those who were deceived by predatory institutions or pressured into attending schools they did not belong at, those who suffered the costs of university while reaping none of the benefits. Nor do I object to people who took out loans, secured upward mobility, and work to pay those loans back taking the write-off that has been offered. The core of my ire is reserved for the Nathan J Robinsons and Briahna Joy Grays of the world, the champagne socialists who agreed to student loans to build influence and prestige before using that influence to change the agreement retroactively—and for the politicians who yielded to pressure and altered the deal for political expediency. People are not grasshoppers for taking loans out or accepting write-offs when offered, but for accepting a cost to gain an edge over others, then turning around to demand those others pay that cost. [...]

&amp;gt; I vocally supported Biden in 2020 and have no regrets about that choice. Between almost any Democrat and Trump, I will pick the Democrat without hesitation, even with risks like this in mind. But my alliance with the left has always been an uneasy one, with no shortage of serious disputes. I am a politically unaffiliated centrist who recognizes that the value of my vote, inasmuch as it exists, lies in its willingness to flip. I have a small platform and a strong personal stake in this issue—while it’s certainly not the biggest issue in politics, it’s one that has a dramatically outsized role in my own life and where my own advocacy energy seems well-placed. I believe the Democrats should lose votes and political capital as a direct result of this cynically timed vote-buying to a larger extent than my own voice can influence, providing an impetus for them to change direction sharply before 2024.

&amp;gt; Given all of this, I will not vote blue in 2022. I cannot support a party that does not even pretend to understand my concerns, one that helps its activists gleefully wrest a bribe from the commons as they cynically claim to speak for the poor, one that arbitrarily frees a relatively advantaged group from their freely entered obligations at the expense of those who avoided those debts—then acts as if all who object are hypocrites worthy of no attention or respect. If this is the direction “progressive” politics is going, I want no part of it.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/im4dege/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>