<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/tricksandcandlewicks - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-05T21:31:36Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/tricksandcandlewicks.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezttog/</id><title type="text">[CW] In other news, [a large farmer&#39;s protest is going on right now in the Netherland</title><updated>2022-07-05T21:31:36Z</updated><author><name>tricksandcandlewicks</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw.html" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">In other news, [a large farmer&#39;s protest is going on right now in the Netherlands](https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/dutch-farmers-protest-by-blocking-supermarket-distribution-centres-2022-07-04/). This bears a similarity to the trucker&#39;s protests in Canada in the mode of operation - large vehicles blockading key roads and chokepoints. The difference here is that the issue they are protesting is much more directly threatening their livelihoods - the Dutch government wants farmers to reduce livestock counts and fertilizer use to reduce Carbon emissions. Naturally, this would be a great blow to the farmer&#39;s incomes and ability to keep the surrounding areas well fed.

In fatter times, I would expect that the Dutch government and the EU could easily get away with crushing this kind of protest. When Europe is already reeling from supply chain issues and the declining availability of cheap Russian gas and covid overregulation harming business, this seems more and more like it could start seriously harming the camel&#39;s back. If people start going hungry and the German economy collapses, that&#39;s probably the end of the EU. 

Speaking as an American, though, I have no idea what local reactions to this protest are - would like to hear some. Or steelmanning all of the recent decisions made by European politicians in regards to climate and energy policies and Russia - these in concert completely baffle me in their capacity for self destruction.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/iezttog/"/></entry></feed>