<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Unreasonable_Energy - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-03T04:38:44Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Unreasonable_Energy" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqr2lz/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I see a lot of negativity directed online at Andrew Yang&#39;s new &#34;Forward Party&#34;, </title><updated>2022-08-03T04:38:44Z</updated><author><name>Unreasonable_Energy</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I see a lot of negativity directed online at Andrew Yang&#39;s new &#34;Forward Party&#34;, including some here on the The Motte, from the general perspective that &#34;obviously third parties can&#39;t work&#34;.  But it&#39;s easy to see that Yang, whatever else he may be, is not an *idiot* -- he must know the structural reasons why third parties can&#39;t gain traction in the American system.  So given that he&#39;s not an idiot, what is trying to achieve here?  What does he *say* he&#39;s trying to achieve, and how does he answer the obvious &#34;spoiler&#34; critique that everyone&#39;s making?

In this [interview with *The New Yorker*](https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/andrew-yangs-third-party-aspirations), Yang&#39;s asked:

&amp;gt; So the idea would be to get Democrats and Republicans to sign up for the Forward Party’s agenda, not to run candidates in the Forward Party to challenge Democrats and Republicans?

and replies

&amp;gt; Having someone run on the Forward Party line would be deeply impractical in the vast majority of districts around the country. We’re going to be supporting candidates who support these principles. I’m sure the vast majority of them are going to be running as Democrats or Republicans, because that’s much more realistic.

His response to the &#34;spoiler&#34; critique, then, is that his party is not, like a traditional political party, generally aiming to actually field potential-spoiler general-election candidates under the Forward Party banner.  It&#39;s more like an &#34;endorsement party&#34; -- a way to coordinate like-minded people around supporting major-party candidates who support certain principles.

But we already have organizations that exist to support major-party candidates without fielding their own -- interest groups create PACs and Super PACs.  Both are legally limited in influence -- PACs are limited in campaign expenditures, and Super PACs are limited by not being allowed to &#34;coordinate&#34; directly with campaigns.  

It sounds to me like Yang wants something like a Super PAC that&#39;s potentially able to coordinate with major-party campaigns, but he doesn&#39;t have a better legal structure than &#34;political party&#34; to operate under.  But what interest group wouldn&#39;t want to be able to start an organization like that?  If an interest group&#39;s forming a new party were a viable political strategy that somehow circumvented the limitations on PACs and Super PACs, why doesn&#39;t any given interest group start their own &#34;political party&#34;, that happens to not field candidates but only exists to direct support toward ideologically-aligned major-party candidates?  

I don&#39;t understand the relevant legal landscape here well enough to say, but it seems like Yang&#39;s project is suffering from people&#39;s assumptions about what a &#34;political party&#34; is supposed to do, when he&#39;s actually trying to create something else.  But if he&#39;s actually innovating some new variety of political organization, what&#39;s stopped other people from doing so in the past?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wda188/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_01_2022/iiqr2lz/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>