<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/urquan5200 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-04T19:41:55Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/urquan5200" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieutf9m/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] I was at the doctor&#39;s office the other day, and I saw a curious poster on the wa</title><updated>2022-07-04T19:41:55Z</updated><author><name>urquan5200</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">I was at the doctor&#39;s office the other day, and I saw a curious poster on the wall. I can&#39;t remember the organization that sponsored the poster, and unfortunately I can&#39;t find it online, but I remember the concept it promoted: it was about **moral injury**, which is an idea I&#39;d never heard of before. I looked it up, and apparently [the core concept](https://moralinjuryproject.syr.edu/about-moral-injury/) is about war:

&amp;gt; Within the context of military service, particularly regarding the experience of war, &#34;moral injury&#34; refers to the lasting emotional, psychological, social, behavioral, and spiritual impacts of actions that violate a service member’s core moral values and behavioral expectations of self or others.

In other words, it&#39;s the deep spiritual and psychological damage that happens when soldiers are ordered to do things that conflict with their personal moral codes: killing people, taking actions that lead to civilian casualties, having to abandon friends on the battlefield to accomplish the mission. Serious, earth-shattering things like that. Some of the deepest horrors of war.

But the poster I saw wasn&#39;t about the experiences of veterans or the terror of the battlefield. It was about &#34;a nurse who feels ashamed of having a medical condition because she&#39;s a nurse.&#34;

To me, this feels like a substantial deviation from the original definition of &#34;moral injury.&#34; An &#34;injury to pride,&#34; maybe. Or perhaps it&#39;s best described as a psychological struggle with unnecessary shame. I&#39;m not saying that a medical professional being ashamed of having a medical condition is a good thing, that there shouldn&#39;t be therapies and programs that help people overcome this unnecessary shame and stigma, or that having posters in doctor&#39;s offices promoting awareness of this problem is a bad idea.

All I&#39;m saying is, maybe it&#39;s not such a good idea to use the same term to describe this phenomenon that we use to describe soldiers facing the terrible moral horrors of warfare.

I know the medical field is hard. Sometimes earth-shatteringly hard. I know it can sometimes feel like a war-zone, a constant fight against death and injury that can never be won, a perpetual Afghanistan withdrawal. I also know it can be especially hard on nurses, who do so much to keep our hospitals and clinics going and are often under-appreciated (is that too much of a cliché?). I know that the job&#39;s so hard that we have a [major nurse shortage](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK493175/) in part due to high rates of burnout. And I know medical professionals often have to deal with belligerent patients, and sometimes they have to take actions -- like restraining or sedating a delirious patient, or holding someone against their will for a psychological evaluation -- that would be unacceptable in normal life.

But it just feels wrong to me, equating the experiences of people in a profession whose cardinal rule is &#34;first do no harm,&#34; with a profession whose cardinal rule, as set out in international law, is [&#34;well you can harm *some* people&#34;](https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2018/06/28/621112394/the-rules-of-war-are-being-broken-what-exactly-are-they). Especially when what&#39;s being compared isn&#39;t the experience of violating one&#39;s moral code and finding one&#39;s ethical conception of the self and maybe even the world being shattered, but the personal shame of a nurse who feels like having a serious illness is unfitting for her. (I use a female pronoun not to claim that all nurses are women, although the [vast majority in the United States](https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/hr/gender-ratio-of-nurses-across-50-states.html) are, but because the original poster I saw depicted a woman as the nurse in question.)

This feels part and parcel of a social tendency that concerns me: the &#34;social traumatization&#34; of society, where more and more life experiences are described in terms of trauma and in increasingly intense ways.

Medical professionals experiencing shame because of a personal diagnosis is a problem, and it&#39;s a problem I hope they&#39;re able to receive help for, so they can move on with their lives and receive proper treatment for the physical ailment. But although it&#39;s a problem, it&#39;s not an &#34;I had to kill a man to survive in the trenches, it was either him or me&#34;-level problem.

Removing the terminological distinctions between these things, I believe, eliminates essential social and psychological information that helps people contextualize their negative experiences and find peace in overcoming them.

automod_multipart_lockme</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ieutf9m/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>