<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ussgordoncaptain2 - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-26T02:15:24Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ussgordoncaptain2" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decl</title><updated>2022-07-26T02:15:24Z</updated><author><name>ussgordoncaptain2</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">A while ago their was a Motte Survey that had the statement &#34;the west is in Decline&#34; which I disagreed with but the modal motte user agreed with.

Therefore I need to tease out what people meant by &#34;the west&#34; and meant by &#34;decline&#34;.

Survey&#39;s are popular so I [made 1](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScbtLqP8cf6ae4C3JeRXXXXNpCBlVF28B9QuDshf9oswPBHXg/viewform?usp=sf_link).

Most of the questions are replicated below.

1. What G20 nations are in &#34;The west&#34; (most notable countries, being Russia, Japan, and South Korea) 

2. What countries are in Decline? 

3. What do people mean when they say &#34;Decline&#34;? Do they mean relative decline or absolute decline?
        
       3a. A country loses her imperial holdings but the mainland grew 5x in the time period, did they &#34;decline&#34;

       3b. A global power grows 5 fold with stable borders but the rest of the world grew 10 fold, did they &#34;decline&#34;  
        3c. A country grows 5 fold in 30 years becoming one of the major powers, but then in the next 30 years grows only 1.5x and falls from 1/3rd as strong to being 2/9ths as strong as the main superpower.


When people say the west is in decline I tend to disagree, with the exception of the fall of the British and French empires, The west has not declined, merely risen slower than contemporaries. Even then since the fall of the berlin wall only 1 nation (china) has risen to surpass the Medium powers of Germany/France/Britan. Though Japan surpassed them as well, Japan also became &#34;west&#34; somehow.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/w7h8wa/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_25_2022/ihnvjn6/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>