<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Valerion - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T18:24:50Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Valerion" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcqjvm/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[SQ] Long-time lurker, and appreciator, of the discussions had in this subreddit. One</title><updated>2022-08-22T18:24:50Z</updated><author><name>Valerion</name></author><category label="SQ" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/sq" term="Small-Scale Question"/><content type="text">Long-time lurker, and appreciator, of the discussions had in this subreddit. One topic that has captured my attention recently is the structure of bureaucracies and mechanisms for accountability and efficiency leading to the question below:

**Are accountability and efficiency for a government organization mutually exclusive? Is there an agency/department (U.S. or non-U.S.) that is regarded as possessing both?**

It strikes me from work in the U.S. public sector that the old observation that the government moves slowly to be true. 

Anecdotally, it seems the slowness stems from countless procedures of reviews to ensure legal and policy compliance. Multiple offices all cover similar portfolios with numerous redundancies and these offices will collaborate to draft policy and regulations. Policy drafts will then undergo legal review by multiple lawyers (with the severity of the policy determining just how high up the bureaucratic lawyer-chain it must go). Further compounding the wait time is after the legal review, you typically have to add on the wait time for a government executive to review the policy, receive a briefing on it (if they desire), and then approve it.

Colleagues and managers claim all of this is to ensure the organizations involved did their due diligence in the name of public interest. To them, fewer layers of review may speed things along, but that arrangement would open said policy/regulation to greater risk, whether in the form of a legal challenge or unintended consequence. I however wonder if there is an example of a government organization with processes that disprove this assertion. Must a government organization move slow to be accountable?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wtsdor/smallscale_question_sunday_for_august_21_2022/ilcqjvm/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>