<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/VeevaHon - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-08T13:07:58Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/VeevaHon" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijfqhxx/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] This is not an opinion based on statistical data, scientific papers or writings </title><updated>2022-08-08T13:07:58Z</updated><author><name>VeevaHon</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">This is not an opinion based on statistical data, scientific papers or writings from a sociologist or psychologist. It is admittedly based on my own observations, with my very biased samples, so please take it with a grain of salt.

As a woman from a south american country who migrated to a Nordic country, I had expectations about what it would be like to live in a more progressive society when it comes to gender roles. Nordic countries are well known for their advances in gender equality, with men and women playing very similar roles in parenting, the work environment, politics, and so on.

And I was not disappointed. To my experience, this is true. However it surprised me to find out there are aspects in which people seem to spontaneously segregate themselves with a strong gender bias, much more than in comparatively more sexist countries such as my homeland.

One of them is in the STEM work field. I have noticed an even lower percentage of women working in this area. And even among those who work in the field, there seems to be a tendency for them to work more in management and other &#34;people oriented&#34; roles instead of pure technical tasks. Similarly, nurses are in their vast majority women. Bus drivers, more mixed than in other countries. And so so on.

When I asked nordic people about the reasons of that phenomenon, many shared the same opinion. With a small pay gap between different work fields, more symmetrical parenting roles at home and similar work-life balance across industries, there is less of an incentive for people to seek jobs that will fit their financial aspirations or parenting schedules. And when people are more free to choose their careers based on their tastes, then the gender imbalance in some fields is just an organic manifestation of the biological vocational differences.

Now, it is hard for me to imagine that the implications of this hypothesis are true. Well, if you are to believe that the nordic gender/professional roles distribution is at least closer to the baseline biologically oriented distribution, then what cultural pressures are driving proportionally more developing countries women towards STEM? An overwhelming societal pressure to be well succeeded financially? Does not seem to be the case. And more developing countries men towards, say, nursing?

Maybe to understand this matter we should look at another social phenomenon. Again, something that I empirically observe and have no data to support. But I feel there is a strong gender segregation that starts much earlier, at school and familiar circles.

It is common to see groups of girls or boys in the street, hardly ever gender mixed. Even in kindergarten hangouts - a common view in nordic streets - isles of pink or blue little dots, no noticeable intersections.

I can&#39;t help comparing that to my own developing country middle class childhood. We were not struck by poverty, by all means. But let&#39;s say my parents had greater concerns than surrounding their little girl with pink and unicorns. My and my peers&#39; reality was wearing oversized hand-me-down clothes and toys from our elder siblings - more numerous than in most families nowadays.

What I observe in families here is more intensive parenting, both in techniques and financial resources. Parents shower their children with pink or blue, reinforcing visual differences. Leisure activities will more often be tailored to each child&#39;s tastes - or at least to what the parents believe their children will like, with a very strong gender bias. Fewer children per family will also mean less chances of having a sibling of the opposite sex. Even play dates will probably be more segregated as parents (unconsciously?) again stimulate same gender interactions.

All in all, I believe that in a similar way that poverty and lack of education drives gender segregation by imposing gender segregated responsibilities from a young age - such as imposition of house chores, different access to education, etc - so does excessively resourceful parenting - by manufacturing worlds of sweet princesses or brave cowboys that are but a reflection of the cultural concept that boys and girls are inherently different in their tastes.

This is not to claim there are no biological differences in men&#39;s and women&#39;s brains that, at least partially, explain some tendencies. There mostly likely are. However I do not believe that it is possible to say that scandinavian or any other &#34;egalitarian&#34; countries are closer to an environmental neutrality that allows these biological differences to be expressed into societal tendencies in a purely organic way. Nor do I claim that a - maybe impossible - gender neutrality in childhood would lead to better outcomes by any metric. But I believe this &#34;segregation by excessive resources&#34; phenomenon should be accounted for when studying gender inequality.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijfqhxx/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>