<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Vorpa-Glavo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-31T21:21:25Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Vorpa-Glavo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] **Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a m</title><updated>2022-08-31T21:21:25Z</updated><author><name>Vorpa-Glavo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">**Biological Sex without Teleology**

Are a bird&#39;s wings &#34;for&#34; flying?

From a metaphysical naturalist understanding of modern biology, the answer has to be no. &#34;For&#34; implies a purpose, and purpose belongs to agents.

An airplane&#39;s wings are for flying - the intentions of engineers ensure that. But birds had no creator, no agent involved in their existence. We might be able to metaphorically talk about a bird being &#34;designed&#34; or &#34;built&#34; for flight, but it is only that: a metaphor.

If we want to limit our description to what can be described based on an physico-empirical view of reality, then a bird&#39;s wing&#39;s **make flight possible** or **allow them to fly**, but we can&#39;t speak about a bird&#39;s wings being &#34;for&#34; anything at all.

So too with the word &#34;need.&#34;

Does a seed &#34;need&#34; water and sunlight and nutrient rich soil? A metaphysical naturalist would say no. &#34;Need&#34; implies that there&#39;s some sort of goal, or right way for a seed to be, but the universe doesn&#39;t care if a seed dies or grows into a giant tree over many eons.

Humans trying to grow seeds might &#34;need&#34; water, and fertilizer and a location with the right amount of sun in order to fulfill that goal, but regarding the seed itself we can only make predictions about the outcomes of different conditions on the seed.

If the seed experiences Scenario A (X units of water delivered at intervals Y, Z units of soil of composition W, V hours of average daily sun exposure, etc.) then it will grow into a big tree, but if the seed experiences Scenario B (no water, no sun, no soil) it will stay a seed and die, with a thousand possible predictions branching off from these two.

So what do we make of &#34;sex&#34; from this standpoint?

I think the radical thing that this line of thinking implies is to stop thinking about &#34;man&#34; and &#34;woman&#34; as some sort of natural pairing.

Just as there are seeds, and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on the seed, so too there are animals and we can make predictions about what effects particular conditions will have on those animals.

If the gamete of animal A finds its way to the gamete of animal B, we might get a zygote, or we might get nothing at all depending on the particular animals involved and the particular gametes.

Things start to come down to categoricity and disciplined pattern formation.

Is a penis &#34;for&#34; a vagina? Is an ovum &#34;for&#34; a sperm? Do men and women have some sort of complimentary relationship?

It is almost certain that humans come pre-installed with social hardware that predisposes them to think of human males and human females as belonging to one type or category in some sense - the human. But if we pull back the curtains, we can see an equally valid way of slicing up reality: men and women are different but &#34;related&#34; things.

Men and women rely on each other to reproduce their own kind. Men can&#39;t make more of themselves without women, and women can&#39;t make more of themselves without men. But why think of them as part of one &#34;species&#34; or &#34;type&#34;? Sure, they share a lot of similarities, and can be contrasted against things like &#34;rabbits&#34; as a whole, even as one can draw parallels between &#34;human males&#34; and &#34;rabbit males.&#34;

I believe it was Bret Weinstein who said that if alien biologists came down to Earth, they would rediscover the concept of sex every day. I don&#39;t exactly take issue with this claim, but I do wonder if the aliens would have the encyclopedia entry &#34;Humans&#34;, or if there would be two encyclopedia entries &#34;[Human-Male]&#34; and &#34;[Human-Female].&#34;

There&#39;s one layer deeper to go here, though. Would the alien biologists even stop there? How would they deal with intersex individuals?

I think a certain form of so-called &#34;binary&#34; thinking is to talk about there being men and women, with intersex individuals being deviations from the norm that can still be forced into one of those two boxes, or filed away into a &#34;freak of nature&#34; box (though we would never call it that with modern social mores.)

But I think this &#34;binary&#34; thinking has exactly the same problem that &#34;needs&#34;- or &#34;for&#34;-based thinking produces: it engages in teleological thinking.

We could imagine that instead of having abstractions at the level of &#34;man&#34; and woman&#34; that the alien biologists have a unique compound word for everything that basically contains every bit of information about that thing known to the aliens.

At this level, maybe the alien biologists could notice patterns between two things, which for us would become categories, but for them remain unabstracted, ungeneralized observations about the entirety of existing things. Maybe these aliens don&#39;t even have the concept of &#34;distinct things&#34; but instead build up observations from correlations of raw sensory data that doesn&#39;t get processed by modules in their brain into &#34;objects&#34; and &#34;animals&#34; and &#34;things&#34;, but instead is dealt with as a Unity with sub-patterns within patterns that can be interacted with and about which predictions can be made.

I think our brain modules do a lot of work in making certain &#34;categories&#34; seem more plausible than others, that is the source of the shadow of teleology projected back out into the world. However, once we see past the shadow, it might genuinely become impossible to pick a point to stop cutting reality at the joints.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imkqyve/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>