<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/Vorpa-Glavo - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-06-03T18:36:07Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/Vorpa-Glavo" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib2espe/</id><title type="text">[CW] Recently, I&#39;ve been listening to interviews with Alok Vaid-Menon, a non-binary a</title><updated>2022-06-03T18:36:07Z</updated><author><name>Vorpa-Glavo</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Recently, I&#39;ve been listening to interviews with Alok Vaid-Menon, a non-binary advocate for the LGBT community. The two that are relevant here are [this one](https://www.aclu.org/bio/alok-vaid-menon) from the ACLU, and [this one](https://podcasts.apple.com/sn/podcast/alok-vaid-menon-does-your-soul-have-a-gender/id1566052074?i=1000545615735&amp;amp;l=fr) from Metaphysical Milkshake.

Now, throughout these interviews Alok makes a number of specific claims about the history of ideas surrounding gender non-conformity, as well as some arm-chair psychologizing of their opponents that I could pick apart or steelman, but I don&#39;t think there&#39;s as much value in that as tackling what I consider the central point of their advocacy: that the &#34;Western gender binary&#34; restricts people&#39;s freedom and autonomy, perpetuates unjust hierarchies, squashes people&#39;s natural spontaneity and playfulness around gender, and reduces people&#39;s self-expression, and that a world without gender (as well as other &#34;binary&#34; forms of thinking) would be better.

I think the minimal, steelmanned description of &#34;the Western gender binary&#34; is something like: the set of societal expectations and rules that coerce or at least push men and women to act, dress and think in certain ways in places in the cultural sphere of the West.

Put this minimal way, I think even if someone has issues with the whole concept of &#34;gender&#34; or thinks this discussion is poisoned by post-modernism and cloudy thinking, they could probably agree that the phrase has a real referrent. Even if the &#34;Western gender binary&#34; is far weaker than it was, say, 100 years ago, it&#39;s still considered notable and &#34;strange&#34; when men wear dresses and put on make up, and there are still particular ways both sexes are expected to act in certain contexts.

I think it is trivially true that people would act in different ways in a society without a &#34;Western gender binary&#34;, and that the &#34;Western gender binary&#34; restricts self-expression. However, are all form of societal coercion that &#34;restrict self-expression&#34; bad?

I can think of several examples of arbitrary societal rules that only survive because some minimal level of coercion happens interpersonally that don&#39;t seem that bad to me.

**Rules of etiquette**: Many etiquette rules are essentially arbitrary. There&#39;s no practical explanation for why walking through the mall flipping off people is bad, but going through the mall showing my pinky to people is just a bit strange and eccentric. Within the lingusitic-symbolic community of the anglophone West we decided that flipping someone off is a sign of anger and disrespect. Does this limit self-expression? Sort of. It limits the particular ways you can convey your ideas, the same way that the arbitrary decision to make the symbols &#34;dog&#34; refer to a specific animal limits the particular ways you can refer to things. But within these arbitrary limitations, a world of self-expression is still open to people. You just have to &#34;learn the language&#34; or accept that people are going to be confused when you try to use your middle finger to mean &#34;good day, sir&#34; and you use &#34;dog&#34; to mean &#34;rainbow.&#34;

**&#34;Neutral&#34; Clothing Rules**: If I wear a robot costume in my day-to-day life, it is considered, at the very least, eccentric. Heck, I would probably have a lot of judgements and opinions of a stranger I met who always wore a robot costume in their everyday life. It is likely that a person who always wore robot costumes would be passed over for certain jobs, and might have trouble getting bank loans and the like. In a certain sense, it seems to me that society coercively punishes robot-costume-guy to a degree similar to many trans or gender non-conforming people, and yet my intuition says that the kind of societal coercion that robot-costume-guy is subjected to isn&#39;t &#34;unjust&#34;, even if it is essentially arbitrary.

One reason to treat robot-costume-guy differently than GNC people might be some belief that gender non-conformance might be taken to generally be a deep expression of a person&#39;s identity, while few people in society consider it reasonable to treat the propensity to wear robot costumes this way. Liberal democracies already carve out a space for certain kinds of religious expression, out of a belief that a person&#39;s deep philosophical convictions are easier to &#34;work around&#34; than directly confront. The amish want to not be part of social security because of their deeply held religious beliefs? Sure, why not? We can make that compromise and avoid the headache of trying to coerce them to participate.

Perhaps a similar argument could be made about gender non-conformity. It&#39;s too much of a headache trying to force everyone to dress and act in certain ways (be they legal or merely social and interpersonal.) So having a legal and social policy of &#34;tolerance&#34; and non-violence against non-conformists might represent a compromise for the sake of the experiment of Enlightenment philosophy and liberal society.

I&#39;ll stop at those two examples for now.

Overall, my main objections don&#39;t come from a specific place of defense of the &#34;Western gender binary.&#34; My main objection is more practical and pragmatic.

I don&#39;t think it is possible to create a society where there is no arbitrary &#34;coercion&#34; of any kind, broadly defined. Humans are tribal animals, and there will always be people making in-group and out-group judgements based on arbitrary distinctions like clothing, behavior, and use of particular linguistic-symbolic signifiers within a culture.

Even if we succesfully removed the &#34;Western gender binary&#34;, we would still be driven to socially coerce people towards and away from particular lifestyles, hobbies, professions and forms of self-expression. I think that is fine as long as people aren&#39;t punished beyond some limit of violence.

As long as the coercion is in the form of &#34;softer&#34; persuassion and not direct violence or harm, I don&#39;t think it is bad or undesirable to have essentially arbitrary rules enforced by society.

If hypothetically corsets were as bad as Hollywood and pop culture said they were, and women were expected to wear them, that would be worth changing. But if women are expected to, say, wear the color pink, then I don&#39;t think that&#39;s necessarily a norm worth tearing down the gender binary for. How is it any different from the restriction against flipping off everyone around you?</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/v0trau/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_may_30_2022/ib2espe/"/></entry></feed>