<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/whenhaveiever - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-17T08:44:43Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/whenhaveiever" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[WW] Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/w</title><updated>2022-08-17T08:44:43Z</updated><author><name>whenhaveiever</name></author><category label="WW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ww" term="Wellness Wednesday"/><content type="text">Follow up for [this comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vhy8hb/wellness_wednesday_for_june_22_2022/id9zyuu/). Has it really been eight weeks?

The pregnancy has been coming along nicely. We&#39;ve had two sets of ultrasounds so far, and our kid is the size of a lemon now. I&#39;ve heard about pregnancy cravings, but I&#39;d never heard of pregnancy aversions. They&#39;re apparently a thing, and it hops from one food to the next, including long-time favorite foods, so finding something that she&#39;s willing to eat can be challenging. But morning sickness barely showed up, and nothing like in the movies, so we&#39;re thankful for that. We&#39;re starting to figure out how to rearrange the house and loosely thinking about names. Instead of paying some $700 for a DNA test now that would tell us the sex, we&#39;ll wait until the week 20 ultrasound to find out for free. In the meantime, I&#39;m more accustomed to using the singular *they* than my mom is, and accidentally had her thinking we were having twins since I kept saying *they*.

I visited my parents (on the other side of the country, so I&#39;m not there very often). I got there in time to help my dad come home from rehab, and help both my parents through a remodel of their ground floor to add a shower plus room for a wheelchair to negotiate through the bathroom. That way dad can have everything he needs without stairs. He eats very little, and when we try to encourage him, he says he &#34;just can&#39;t.&#34; Finding something that *he&#39;s* willing to eat can also be challenging. Because he&#39;s anemic, his doctor put him on prenatal vitamins as a cheap source of easy iron, and with a few things going on in his gut, he&#39;s gotten a few ultrasounds. It&#39;s odd how life rhymes sometimes. Since I&#39;ve been back on this side of the country, dad was in and out of the hospital another time. They suspected a fistula and he was going to get surgery, then they decided he doesn&#39;t have one and just gave him antibiotics. I&#39;ve lost count of how many times he&#39;s been in there in the last year and a half, and while each one is necessary at the time, each time he comes back weaker and has to spend weeks regaining his strength.

We also visited her parents (not as far away as mine, but far enough that it had been awhile). Since that trip, I&#39;ve found it hard to get back to the normal routine. It seems especially more difficult to get up in the morning, and I have to really push myself to get going. I hope it&#39;s just a slump. I think part of it is regretting that I moved away from my parents way back when, and that I&#39;ve spent so much time away from them. I think part of it is in some way realizing that I&#39;m going to be sleeping much less once the baby comes, and so I might as well enjoy it while I can. But I&#39;m also not enjoying it. It makes me feel like crap.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wqhcx8/wellness_wednesday_for_august_17_2022/ikmsgx0/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>