<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/WhiningCoil - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-01T13:14:47Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/WhiningCoil.html" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/ieg58kl/</id><title type="text">[FF] Been a hot minute posting here for me.

Kind of been taking a break from games t</title><updated>2022-07-01T13:14:47Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff.html" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Been a hot minute posting here for me.

Kind of been taking a break from games to build the wife a nice 3 bin composter.  She found some plans online, so I invested in the tools, lumber and hardware to get it done.  I actually really had a blast breaking in a ton of power tools.  Picked up a power saw, power sander, brand new cordless power drill.  Then I got a nice cordless oscillating multitool cause it was on sale.  And a shop vac of course because there is going to be sawdust and garbage everywhere in the workshop.  Oh, and you can&#39;t forget clamps, squares, saw horses, and other misc woodworking must haves.

I really tried to take my time and do this thing correctly.  Sanded and finished all the parts with raw linseed oil.  Because you need to use something all natural that won&#39;t leach into or contaminate the compost.  Each part required 3 coats, with 24 hours of drying time between them, which took forever.  Used a little over 2 quarts.  But the worst part was probably driving by hammer about 200 fence staples to hold the hardware clothe to it.  If I ever do this again, I&#39;m investing in an air compressor and a big ass staple gun.  But nothing is going anywhere with those fence staples in there.

Of course, before I even finished that project, a downburst/tornado, people are still arguing over which, dropped a tree on my car.  Not at all typical for this area, and it&#39;s been a big deal how much damage it caused.  They declared a state of emergency and everything.  I don&#39;t own a chainsaw yet, so I had to cut the tree off my car with a hand saw so the insurance company could have it towed.  Turns out the car is totaled, which is unsurprising.  Not going to bother buying a new one since it was my family&#39;s 3rd car, and oldest, and we really don&#39;t **need** a new one, especially in this market.

So the payout is going to pay off the tree fellers that took down a bunch of other dead and scary looking trees on our property.  The whole county got the same idea more or less.  All day, every day since the storm all you hear is chainsaws and trees falling in the distance.  It was a huge wakeup call.  So now i have a metric fuckton of logs the fellers cut to 18&#34; to split.  Spent some time on that yesterday and had a blast.  Tried a 12lb splitting maul the previous homeowners left here, along with a splitting diamond.  I&#39;m a pretty robust fellow, but swinging 12lb over my head on a fairly heavy handle wiped me super fast.  And the thing wasn&#39;t even that effective.  Wound up just buying a 6lb splitting axe with a fiberglass handle and I&#39;ve been making quick work since.

I strongly recommend the old school manly virtues of building thing and splitting wood.  It&#39;s gotten many an appreciative ogle from the wife.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vosrph/friday_fun_thread_for_july_01_2022/ieg58kl/"/></entry></feed>