<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/WhiningCoil - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-13T01:46:32Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/WhiningCoil" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2r0a7/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[FF] Spent my day install a cell booster on my house.  Ever since a big storm rolled </title><updated>2022-08-13T01:46:32Z</updated><author><name>WhiningCoil</name></author><category label="FF" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/ff" term="Friday Fun"/><content type="text">Spent my day install a cell booster on my house.  Ever since a big storm rolled through knocking everything over, and leading to some debate about whether we experienced a downburst or a tornado, my Verizon signal has been in the toilet.  So, $400 later, and some rather nervous work on a ladder, we now have a serviceable signal again.  It was a constant thorn in our side since moving out to the country, so hopefully that problem is fully well fixed now.

Been seriously binging Xenoblade Chronicles 3 more.  I got seriously side tracked by optional quests, and am now overleveled for the core story in front of me by about 10 levels.  The job system is **ok** so far.  I think what&#39;s hampering my enjoyment is the temporary cap of 10 levels per job I&#39;m currently laboring under.  So my characters max out their jobs rather quickly, and I find myself rotating them to new ones, not because I want to, but because I feel like I have to in order to min max.  And I&#39;m constantly running short of jobs I actually want to switch them into.  I&#39;m looking forward to the cap coming off.

Hit my first tantalizing and obvious reference to previous Xenoblade games, hinting at the world this is taking place in.  The trailer had hinted at things, and I&#39;m curious to see if the hints come to fruition.  But I think the Xenoblade &#34;timeline&#34; is a lot like the Zelda &#34;timeline&#34;.  Mostly bullshit theory crafting around thoughtlessly included references that give the games a unified feel, but aren&#39;t meant for serious theorizing.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wmcsjf/friday_fun_thread_for_august_12_2022/ik2r0a7/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>