<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/xablor - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-11T21:57:44Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/xablor" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijwypi3/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Another entry in the Inflation Reduction Act effort, this time covering some of </title><updated>2022-08-11T21:57:44Z</updated><author><name>xablor</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Another entry in the Inflation Reduction Act effort, this time covering some of the proposed uses of all that money. u/Sorie_K and u/netstack_ ably covered the huge Title I, and I attempted to cover as much of the rest as I could, working backwards. I&#39;m more than out of time, but I&#39;m pleased that I managed to line-by-line Titles II through VIII, some 200 pages, so here&#39;s my attempt at a summary. This will necessarily be high-level; my low-level summaries are available at [https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wc7x7s/collaborative\_analysis\_of\_the\_inflation\_reduction/](https://www.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wc7x7s/collaborative_analysis_of_the_inflation_reduction/), with a top level thread for each title, and summaries under each.

My first impression is of how /sane/ all this seems - accepting the premise that we will all literally die if we&#39;re not net-zero by 2050 (or whatever goal is being set for whatever reason, don&#39;t @ me) - this is a legitimate full-court press to electrify GHG producers, enable consumer and industrial deployment of low-emissions tech and enhanced energy efficiency, deploy renewable energy at scale, adapt to incoming warming and extreme weather, and enable research into new forms of renewable energy. I&#39;m not cynical enough to reliably detect opportunities for patronage and corruption, but I&#39;m sure it&#39;s there, but a LOT of these funds are pretty tightly targeted. They&#39;re even market-y in most places: using them for loan guarantee programs is frequently explicitly allowed, public/private cost sharing is sometimes required. The whole thing reads as though you asked 7 different specialist committees to ask their SMEs to dig out their best ideas, harden them into operationalizable proposals, and then have the lawyers translate it into Congress-flavored legalese.

As a wrinkle that I&#39;m not sure how to fit elsewhere, there&#39;s a good chunk of money allocated for environmental review improvements: S70007 gives 70M to the Environmental Review Improvement Fund under the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council; S60402 gives 30M to the Council on Economic Quality for general operations and review enhancements; S60115 gives EPA 850M for improved review and permitting processes; 40003 gives NOAA 150M for improved review and permitting processes; S50301, -2, -3 gives 375M for improvements to environmental reviews and authorizations to Sec of Energy, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and Sec of Interior; S23001 gets 100M to provide more effective and efficient reviews. This totals 1.575B, casually. I happened to run across a passed Senate Resolution in the Congressional Record for 2022-8-4 that would undo a rule currently requiring environmental impact statements to include indirect and cumulative impacts; it&#39;s S J Res 55 for this Congress, it&#39;s got all 50 Republicans and 0 Democrats, and /I don&#39;t understand why/. It&#39;s referred to House Committee, where it&#39;ll die or get stonewalled, but it&#39;s an interesting opening for construction maximalism, which seems necessary to achieve the construction bandwidth needed for all these large-scale climate projects. I really hope that someone wiser than me can weigh in here, because I have no idea what to make of this development that smells so much of the Shadow Congress quietly getting big things done.

Of the functional goals of the bill given in the one-page summary at [https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122297-inflation\_reduction\_act\_one\_page\_summary](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22122297-inflation_reduction_act_one_page_summary) , these titles only implement #2: &#39;Lowers energy costs, increases cleaner production, and reduces carbon emissions by roughly 40 percent by 2030&#39;. This is is only slightly duplicitous:  there are programs for retrofitting cleaner and more efficient industrial processes, and under ideal conditions and friendly analysis 40% reduction from predicted emissions is achievable, but the energy costs aspect seems to be on the demand side, due to more newer and more efficient appliances, better insulation and sealing, demand-shifting tech, and distributed power generation via rooftop PV and thermal solar.

I didn&#39;t pick up on a lot of opportunities for diversion, patronage, winner-choosing, vote-buying, or similar abuses, though of course the sheer scale makes waste and fraud inevitable. Most Inspector General offices are getting additional funding, which should help. S13103 is specifically for solar and wind facilities serving low-income communities. 22004 is about disadvantaged rural communities. S50121 sets aside money specifically for encouraging work in underserved communities. 50231 is specifically for water supply projects for disadvantaged communities. 60103 targets GHG emissions in disadvantaged communities. 60104 tries to reduce diesel emissions in poor communities. 60105 targets air quality sensors in low-income communities. 60106 targets air quality emissions at schools in poor communities. 60201 is specifically for &#34;Environmental and Climate Justic Block Grants&#34;, and is fairly blatantly loose, including &#34;facilitating engagement of disadvantaged communities in State and Federal public processes&#34;. 60501 tries to fix highways cutting poor neighborhoods in half, improving walkability. Nonprofit orgs are eligible for grants for a few sections, but the purposes are usually tightly scoped. S4001 targets nonprofits &#34;to enable coastal communities to prepare for extreme storms and other changing climate conditions&#34;, which strikes me as usefully loose.

I&#39;m out of words, here, please let fly with comments,  corrections, or followup questions I can work on. Thanks again to u/netstack_ and u/Sorie_K.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wj1cwt/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_08_2022/ijwypi3/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>