<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ymeskhout - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-09-02T19:52:16Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ymeskhout" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu7i4x/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] After Roe v. Wade was overturned, a common argument was to describe pro-life Rep</title><updated>2022-09-02T19:52:16Z</updated><author><name>ymeskhout</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">After Roe v. Wade was overturned, a common argument was to describe pro-life Republicans as &#34;the dog that caught the car&#34;. There&#39;s some indication that this is true, as Republican political candidates are [slowly walking away from strict abortion bans](https://reason.com/2022/08/30/republicans-supported-abortion-bans-for-decades-now-theyve-gone-silent/).

I was obviously aware of the conservative stance on this topic but truthfully I never took it seriously. Because *Roe* had been a question answered on constitutional grounds, it meant no one could do anything about it short of a constitutional amendment that had no chance of passing. Which meant that advocates could jawbone all they want about wanting to ban abortions without ever having to be made to call their bluff. Blake Masters, Senate candidate in Arizona, used to support a national ban on abortion. But recently, he accused his opponent of mischaracterizing his position, and claims that he&#39;s only opposed to &#34;very late-term and partial-birth abortion&#34;. His campaign website was modified to reflect this new position. Bailey, meet Motte.

I noticed a similar reaction when stories like the 10-year-old rape victim in Ohio popped up. If you said you wanted to ban all abortions no questions asked, you necessarily had to support legally forcing that 10-year-old girl to carry to term. That also necessarily means prosecuting anyone who hinders that prohibition (doctors, pharmacists, anyone who facilitates inter-state travel, etc.) [through the typical avenues](https://www.currentaffairs.org/2017/10/people-literally-do-not-understand-what-laws-are-or-how-they-work), which means people with guns and badges threatening to put people in cages.

There&#39;s an easy way to square this circle. If you genuinely believe that abortion is as immoral as murder (without exception) and that the law should reflect that, then you have to support forcing 10-year-old rape victims into carrying their pregnancy to term. This is plainly justified even by conceding that forcing a child to carry her rapist&#39;s baby is atrocious, because the rejoinder would be terminating that fetus&#39; life is an even bigger atrocity. I disagree strongly with those premises (a position I suspect is widely shared), but I at least genuinely respect their consistency. Now that *Roe* is gone, we get to see how many people are willing to grab the dilemma bull by the horns.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/x0hc17/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_29_2022/imu7i4x/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>