<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ymeskhout - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-15T00:39:30Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ymeskhout" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig7axly/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] [I wade into](https://ymeskhout.substack.com/p/what-boston-can-teach-us-about-wh</title><updated>2022-07-15T00:39:30Z</updated><author><name>ymeskhout</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">[I wade into](https://ymeskhout.substack.com/p/what-boston-can-teach-us-about-what) the &#34;what is a woman?&#34; debate and write a long post about the topic. My main point is that I think the argument over definitions is a distraction from more productive discussions.

Excerpt: 

Debates over definition boundaries can be a fun conversational frivolity (Are Pop-Tarts a [sandwich](https://twitter.com/matttomic/status/859117370455060481)? Are Algerians [Latino](https://www.reddit.com/r/LatinoPeopleTwitter/comments/nxhiet/latino_alignment_chart/)? Is *Old Town Road* country music? Etc.) but they’re most often deployed with other goals in mind. Arguments over definitions are often disguised queries for something else entirely. In [Yudkowsky’s example](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/4FcxgdvdQP45D6Skg/disguised-queries), a factory worker is tasked with sorting blue furry egg-shaped objects (called “bleggs”) from smooth red cubic objects (“rubes”) on an assembly line. This job goes fine until the worker encounters a purple egg and has no idea how to sort it. The worker and his supervisor get distracted by the debate over definitions (Can bleggs be purple? Can rubes be furry?) until the *true* purpose of the sorting job gets revealed: bleggs contain vanadium ore, and rubes contain palladium ore, both of which need to be industrially processed differently. The ore processing plants do not give a fuck what color or shape their supply chain materials are so long as they accomplish the purpose they were built for. The question “Is this a rube or a blegg?” therefore is used as a good enough (and presumably cheaper) way of solving the ultimate (and presumably more complicated) logistical question of “Does this need to be processed by the palladium or the vanadium plant?”. But without a shared understanding from both parties for *why* the distinction matters, no answer will communicate any useful information to whoever is asking. It’ll remain a useless question.

Similarly, [if a tree falls in the forest and no one hears it](https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7X2j8HAkWdmMoS8PE/disputing-definitions), does it make a *sound*? Another useless question. Both yes and no can be correct answers, depending entirely on whether your definition of sound is “acoustic vibrations” or “perceived auditory sensation”. Without first establishing *why* the distinction between the two definitions matters, no useful response is possible. Here too it’s possible to get infinitely distracted over which definition is the “correct” one, but the purpose of language ultimately is communication, and the more productive avenue would be to acknowledge that it’s helpful for distinct concepts to have distinct words. You can even make up new words (alberzle and bargulum for example) to avoid future confusion.

Sometimes ambiguity is intentional. Was [January 6th](https://ymeskhout.substack.com/p/the-january-6th-circus) an insurrection? Again, that depends entirely on *why* the distinction matters. The reason this might matter to a federal prosecutor would be maybe to determine whether they should file criminal charges under [18 U.S.C. §2383](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/2383). But outside of that niche analysis, it’s reasonable to be suspicious of questions like this because of the serious negative connotations that *insurrection* inevitably conjures up. The question is very likely intended as a cover to ask “Was January 6th a Very Bad Thing™?”. Whoever asking the question then would have an interest *against* establishing a shared understanding for *why* the distinction matters. Because the goal with dishonest questions like is to score points, not gain information.

I am not the first to notice this deceptive practice. Parrhesia wrote about [the word games used](https://parrhesia.substack.com/p/playing-word-games-with-the-woke) in these types of discussions, most blatantly with the word *racism*. In terms of heavyweight champions in the semantic space, *racism* is a sought-after bruiser. It’s a strong word with serious negative connotations, and everyone is eager to use it to bludgeon their opponents. Asking whether something is or isn’t racist is the mother of all disguised queries. The goal here isn’t to gain information, it’s to find out who to bludgeon.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vwbj4s/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_11_2022/ig7axly/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>