<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ZeStridingTeufel - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-07-08T11:35:02Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ZeStridingTeufel" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifbxzqu/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] We&#39;re gonna witness a global trend of demographic decline, and have received mix</title><updated>2022-07-08T11:35:02Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">We&#39;re gonna witness a global trend of demographic decline, and have received mixed signals about its implications, to say the least. A lot of conservative demographic enthusiasts held that fertility is tied to religiosity, this [thread](https://twitter.com/akhivae/status/1543364479655755777) seeks to refute this assertion. We&#39;re also seeing declining birth rates in both India and Bangladesh. The author also argues [against](https://medium.com/@akhivae/demography-is-not-destiny-the-problem-with-demographic-reductionism-44d092f2e52c) the significance of demographics.

A counter might be that both these societies are facing a  &#34;demographic clog&#34; and home a lot more people than they could afford to. Its also worth noting that in both these countries are moving out of agriculture and more education and other resources are going to be required for children. Not to mention, abortion has been legal in India for decades now. Private schooling is also extremely expensive yet very vital for upward mobility, since the public education infrastructure is kafkaesque, which probably also limits fertility. I think demographic decline is inevitable but perhaps religiosity can slow the decline in sustainable proportions and avoid a South Korea style age quake.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/vr0t4v/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_july_04_2022/ifbxzqu/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>