<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">u/ZeStridingTeufel - r/TheMotte</title><id>https://themotte.srid.ca/</id><updated>2022-08-22T08:16:14Z</updated><link href="https://themotte.srid.ca/u/ZeStridingTeufel" rel="self"/><entry><id>http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence</id><title type="text">[CW] Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](h</title><updated>2022-08-22T08:16:14Z</updated><author><name>ZeStridingTeufel</name></author><category label="CW" scheme="https://themotte.srid.ca/cw" term="Culture War"/><content type="text">Some culture war material from India.

Recently, Independent put out a [piece](https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/british-indians-racism-muslim-islamophobia-b2149026.html?utm_content=Echobox&amp;amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Main&amp;amp;utm_source=Twitter#Echobox=1660996247) that turned a lot of heads in Indian online space. Over the past decade, the political zeitgeist in India has been apparently captured indisputably by Hindu Nationalism in the national capacity, while still struggling in many states. Any strand of liberalism left isn&#39;t really a direction anymore, but pressure from above or outside. The term &#39;South Asia&#39; is not very well liked in India, which is seen by many nationalists as a reductionism of their civilisation to another geographic patch of landmass and above all, a tacit affirmation of the current nation states of India and Pakistan as equally legitimate in inheriting the cultural ethnos of the subcontinent.

But in more recent years, the term has produced another bone to pick. White liberals are largely seen as the new cultural imperialists out to atomise societies and rearrange social relations between the sexes, ethnic groups, etc. They&#39;re also seen as militantly anti-India on matters such as Kashmir, with &#39;South Asian&#39; think tanks being their academic arm to dissipate psyops against India. Finally, they&#39;re perceived to be tacitly pro-Pakistan. The last one is a litmus test for a lot of Indians as to whether its all about values or consumer demographics. Is Hindu Nationalism a genuine concern, or just another cudgel against Indians? If Indians are fair game to be criticised for their attitude towards Pakistanis, the reverse should be axiomatic, correct? Well, BBC and other media are seen as hypocritically smearing India over its domestic problems with communalism, caste, gender, etc., while violent crimes by Pakistani origin men in the UK are obscured, leave alone Pakistan&#39;s own social problems. Last year, NYT&#39;s [job listing](https://www.newslaundry.com/2021/07/08/did-nyts-job-posting-for-a-business-correspondent-in-india-deserve-the-outrage-it-got) for an India correspondent sparked a huge furore in Indian media. The part about India&#39;s South Asian neighbours especially raised eyebrows as to whether the implication was that India is the belligerent actor in the region, when every single one of the [Indo-Pak wars](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Pakistani_wars_and_conflicts) was initiated by Pakistan, one of which even involved a [huge genocide](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1971_Bangladesh_genocide) by the Pakistani Army. This event is not discussed in the media, and Indian syllabi consider every even after Independence as contemporary history, so its not discussed in history textbooks either. But ever since war ignited in Ukraine almost 6 months ago, and India&#39;s repeated refusal to condemn the invasion and continued purchase of Russian oil, 1971 has been resuscitated yet again, as was Soviet support to India at the time. Suddenly, many Hindu Nationalists who were previously indifferent to Russia, turned [Russophilic](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/03/29/india-russia-ukraine-media/). But I think this is largely out of hostility to liberals than anything else.

For now, it looks like Hindu Nationalism is not about to lose its political clout in India and this will continue to leave lots of annoyance with liberals. Even the BJP&#39;s political opponents have caved on key issues like the [Rohingya refugees](http://twocircles.net/2022aug22/446679.html) to pose any competition. In all, the Nehruvian era Congress elites simply did not connect to the subalterns in producing the cultural and economic prosperity that they had wanted, whether in their socialist shade during the Cold War or in their neoliberal shade since 2004. And the vacuum it left behind is no longer its own to fill.</content><link href="http://old.reddit.com/r/TheMotte/comments/wulqxp/culture_war_roundup_for_the_week_of_august_22_2022/ilap2wy/?sort=confidence"/></entry></feed>